<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Adalbert Riedl collection of song and prayer leaflets <date type="inclusive">1770-1932</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Adalbert Riedl collection of song and prayer
                    leaflets</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC785</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="ger"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1770-1932</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dr. Adalbert Riedl (1898-1978) was the longtime director of the Burgenland State
                    Museum in Eisenstadt and the author of Lied-Flugblattdrucke aus dem Burgenland
                    (Song Broadsides from the Burgenland).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Riedl collection contains nearly 700 items, mostly prayers and songs in
                    leaflet or chapbook form. The inclusion of a number of duplicates or slight
                    variants brings the total number of pieces to about 800. The bulk of the
                    collection appears to have been printed in the 19th century. There are a few
                    pieces from the 18th century and a few from the 20th. Perhaps half of the pieces
                    have no place, publisher, or date indicated. The collection is arranged into
                    five series: prayers; religious songs; religious and secular songs and stories;
                    a bound volume of religious songs; and holograph leaflets and chapbooks.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 39</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>