<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Albert Croll Baugh papers <date type="inclusive">1914-1973</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Albert Croll Baugh papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC1244</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1914-1973</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Albert Croll Baugh (1891-1981) was a scholar of English language and literature
                    and medieval studies. He was educated at the University of Pennsylvania. He
                    served on the faculty of the University of Pennsylvania, where he taught Middle
                    English literature and Chaucer, and in 1946 was appointed to the Felix Schelling
                    Memorial Professorship, a post he held until his retirement in 1961. He served
                    as the chair of the English Department from 1944 to 1957. He was the author of A
                    History of the English Language, the editor of A Literary History of England,
                    and the compiler of Chaucer, among other publications. He was also an active
                    member of the Modern Language Association, serving on its editorial board
                    (1930-1941 and 1946-1951), its executive committee (1943-1946), and as its
                    president (1952).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Albert Croll Baugh. Materials include
                    manuscript and typescript scholarly notes; manuscripts, typescripts, and proofs
                    of Baugh's writings; reprints and offprints; a collection catalog of Baugh's
                    books and serials; a small amount of correspondence with colleagues regarding
                    scholarly articles, editing, and research; one letter from his son, a professor
                    at Princeton; notes for an English I course (presumably taught by Baugh); and
                    microfilms, photographs, and photostats of texts. The collection also includes a
                    bound transcript of Ancrene Riwle that was given to Hope Emily Allen.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: Ms. Coll. 689</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>