<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>August Mencken collection of reprints and miscellaneous manuscripts
                            <date type="inclusive">1931-1972</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">August Mencken collection of reprints and miscellaneous
                    manuscripts</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC735</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1931-1972</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>August Mencken (1889-1967) was an American civil engineer and author. He was the
                    younger brother of Henry Louis Mencken, and the son of cigar magnate August
                    Mencken, Sr. His works include First-class Passenger (1938), By the Neck; A Book
                    of Hangings (1942), and The Fair Chanteuse, or, Science is Here to Stay
                    (1958).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes correspondence, clippings, and writings about or
                    collected by August Mencken, Materials include: a copy of "A Model of the
                    Confederate States Cruiser 'Alabama' Built by August Mencken, 1936"; clippings
                    about the Alabama; correspondence related to Mencken's research on the Alabama;
                    correspondence with the Naval Academy Museum about the disposition of his
                    Alabama model; newspaper clippings and articles by and about H.L. Mencken; and
                    reprints of articles on poetry and literature, many of which have authors'
                    inscriptions to August Mencken. Several reprints are accompanied by
                    correspondence to Mencken.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 257</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>