<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charles Godfrey Leland letters <date type="inclusive">1861-1937</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charles Godfrey Leland letters</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC342</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.12 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1861-1937</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles Godfrey Leland (1824-1903) was an American humorist and folklorist. Born
                    in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, he was educated at Princeton University, and in
                    Europe. Leland worked in journalism, traveled extensively, and became interested
                    in folklore and folk linguistics, publishing books and articles on American and
                    European languages and folk traditions. he published a number of books,
                    including Hans Breitmann's Ballads and Aradia, or the Gospel of the Witches.
                    George Henry Boker (1823-1890) was a Philadelphia-based poet and playwright. He
                    founded the Union League of Philadelphia in 1862 and held diplomatic
                    appointments to Turkey and Russia. Leland and Boker, whose fathers were business
                    partners, were close friends from childhood.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of 15 letters from Charles Godfrey Leland to George Henry
                    Boker, 1861 and 1869-1870. Most of the letters were written during Leland's trip
                    to Europe after he resigned from his position as Editor of the Philadelphia
                    Press in 1868. The letters discuss the culture, literature, and social life he
                    encountered during his trip abroad, and contain references to the two
                    correspondents' acquaintances among the literary circles of both America and
                    Europe. The collection includes a typescript of Sculley Bradley's introduction
                    to and edited transcriptions of the collection of letters from the
                    mid-1930s.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 117</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>