<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charlotte Cushman Club records <date type="inclusive">1866-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charlotte Cushman Club records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC418</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>17.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1866-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Charlotte Cushman Club was a club for women actresses in Philadelphia. It was
                    named for Charlotte Cushman, the first woman director of the Walnut Street
                    Theater and an internationally famous Shakespearean actress of the mid-to-late
                    1800s. The club occupied several buildings over its history, including locations
                    at 12th and Locust, 10th and Spruce, and Camac Street.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains administrative records, scrapbooks, photographic
                    materials, and printed materials related to the club. Materials include: the
                    club's by-laws and charter; meeting minutes; yearly reports; membership
                    nominations, dues, and lists; library and museum records, including inventories;
                    files on the yearly Cushman Award such as photos, schedules, budgets,
                    correspondence; financial records for events and for the physical properties,
                    including ledgers, budget and salary records, bills and receipts, investments,
                    and insurance; correspondence between members and with companies and individual
                    actors; Plays and Players scrapbooks (1899-1933) that include playbills and
                    images from productions in Philadelphia, New York, and other northeastern
                    cities; histories of the club; and a copy of Jean Rapp's manuscript "The
                    Philadelphia Theaters" (1990s). There are also photographs and negatives of
                    actors, productions, and the Club's various houses, as well as newspaper
                    clippings, programs and playbills, scrapbooks of newspaper clippings, scripts,
                    invitations and flyers, the club's seal, and a published biography of Charlotte
                    Cushman.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 189</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>