<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charles Mulford Robinson papers <date type="inclusive">1781-1924</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1886-1924</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charles Mulford Robinson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC786</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1781-1924</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1886-1924</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles Mulford Robinson (1869-1917) was a journalist and specialist in town
                    planning. He was the first Professor for Civic Design at the University of
                    Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, which was only one of two universities offering
                    courses in Urban Planning at the time. Robinson was a proponent of the City
                    Beautiful movement and wrote The Fair of Spectacle, an illustrated description
                    of Chicago's World Columbian Exposition in 1893. He went on to write The
                    Improvement of Towns and Cities (1901), the first guide to city planning, among
                    many other publications. He contributed to the planning of a number of American
                    cities, including Denver, Omaha, Columbus, and Honolulu.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of professional and personal papers of Charles Mulford
                    Robinson. Materials include correspondence; scrapbooks of clippings and notes;
                    pamphlets; college class notes; and books. Professional materials include:
                    reports to civic and business clubs and to planning commissions in a number of
                    American cities, including Syracuse, New York, Hannibal, Missouri, St. Joseph,
                    Missouri, Freeport, Illinois, Honolulu, Hawaii, and Greensboro, North Carolina;
                    letters from civic and business clubs and planning commissions regarding his
                    reports and proposals; and scrapbooks of newspaper clippings. Personal papers
                    include manuscript orations, essays, and stories from Robinson's college years;
                    a scrapbook of invitations and newspaper items about his marriage to Miss Eliza
                    Ten Eyck Pruyn; a bible and books of poetry; a copper photograph plate of Mr.
                    Robinson; a small batch of family papers related to Robinson's forbears; and
                    correspondence with Mrs. Robinson, much of it related to the dedication of a
                    memorial to Robinson at the University of Illinois.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 4</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>