<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Chester G. Fuson collection <date type="inclusive">1909-1963</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1909</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Chester G. Fuson collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC416</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.66 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1909-1963</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1909</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Chester Garfield Fuson (1881-1965) was born in Wakeeney, Kansas. He graduated
                    from college with a degree in education. He married Phebe Meeker in December
                    1909. Prior to getting married, Fuson taught education and geography at the
                    Canton Christian College in Canton, China, and assisted Don Sowers, a scientist
                    who conducted a magnetic survey across Asia. After their marriage, the Fusons
                    returned to China, and Chester returned to his position at Canton Christian
                    College. The Fusons became teaching missionaries in 1917 under the Presbyterian
                    Board of Foreign Missions, and continued their work until 1949. They had three
                    sons, Ben, Nelson, and William.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The bulk of the collection pertains to Fuson's participation in the magnetic
                    survey across Asia. Materials include: an original and copy of Fuson's diary of
                    a nine month trip from Peking to Bombay in 1909 and other documentation related
                    to the trip; several reports prepared for possible publication, including "The
                    Old Asian Trail," "Through Chinese Turkestan," and "The Five Great Passes of
                    the Karakorum Route"; the annual report of the Department of Terrestrial
                    Magnetism of the Carnegie Institution of Washington from 1909 which includes a
                    report of the trip; magazine articles from the 1940s and 1960s on Central Asia;
                    photographs taken by Fuson on the trip; a book and reprints of articles by
                    Chester Fuson; and an oversize map of China.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 187</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>