<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Clair Wilcox papers relating to international trade <date type="inclusive">1944-1951</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Clair Wilcox papers relating to international
                    trade</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC777</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1944-1951</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Clair Wilcox (1898-1970) was on the faculty of Swarthmore College from 1927 to
                    1968 and chaired the Department of Economics for 37 years. Professor Wilcox was
                    a distinguished economist who authored six books and, perhaps most notably,
                    chaired the International Trade Conference, which led to the General Agreement
                    on Tariffs and Trade (GATT), the predecessor of today's World Trade Organization
                    (WTO).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of memos and reports related to the negotiations for an
                    international trade organization which led to the General Agreement on Tariffs
                    and Trade. The materials include drafts of tariff proposals and a draft of a
                    trade agreement charter, preliminary and followup reports on the negotiations,
                    and a copy of a memorandum from the Department of State to President Truman
                    asking his approval for tariff cuts negotiated at the Geneva conference, along
                    with dissents submitted by other government agencies. There is also a transcript
                    of Wilcox's testimony to the State Department about the 1947 meeting in Geneva
                    of the Committee for an International Conference on Trade and Employment and a
                    copy of the official report of the U.S. Delegation to this meeting.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 35</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>