<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Curtis W. Davis collection on Leopold Stokowski <date type="inclusive">1938-1983</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Curtis W. Davis collection on Leopold Stokowski</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC732</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>9.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1938-1983</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Curtis W. Davis directed culture programs for National Educational Television. He
                    is the author, with Yehudi Menuhin, of The Music of Man, a book of a television
                    series they completed for the Canadian Broadcasting Corporation in 1979. Leopold
                    Stokowski (1882-1977) was the conductor of the Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra,
                    the Philadelphia Orchestra, the NBC Symphony Orchestra, Hollywood Bowl Orchestra
                    and the Symphony of the Air. He was the founder of the New York City Symphony
                    and The American Symphony Orchestra.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of research materials on Leopold Stokowski for a planned
                    biography by Curtis Davis. The research was conducted in the 1970s and the early
                    1980s. Materials include: clippings and copies of articles about Stokowski and
                    other musicians; taped interviews of people who worked with Stokowski;
                    handwritten notes from these interviews; drafts of the biography; genealogical
                    notes; clippings about Stokowski and obituaries; slides and photographs;
                    Curtis's correspondence related to his research; and transcripts of "The
                    Stokowski Story" a series of interviews conducted by Steve Cohen and broadcast
                    on public radio. The collection also includes a small amount of Stokowski's
                    incoming and outgoing correspondence from the late 1960s and early 1970s
                    (originals and photocopies).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 252</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library: Oliver Daniel Research
                    Collection on Leopold Stokowski (Ms. Coll. 382).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>