<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>David Rockwell Goddard papers <date type="inclusive">1962-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">David Rockwell Goddard papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC424</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1962-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>David Rockwell Goddard (1908-1985) was a plant physiologist, educator, and
                    university administrator. He joined the faculty of the University of
                    Pennsylvania in 1946 as a professor of botany. He later became chair of the
                    Botany Department, and was heavily involved in the creation of a Division of
                    Biology in 1954, of which he became director. His active participation in the
                    administration of the university led to him being named Provost in 1961, a
                    position he held until 1970. He served a four-year term as home secretary for
                    the National Academy of Sciences beginning in 1975. He had previously held a
                    number of significant positions in the Academy, including participating in the
                    Advisory Committee on Science Exchange with the USSR and Eastern Europe (member,
                    1960-1968; chairman, 1966-1968).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes papers related to Goddard's work on several panels,
                    including the Life Sciences Panel, the Commission on Narcotics and Drug
                    Addiction, the Pesticide Panel of the Federal Council for Science and
                    Technology, and the National Academy of Sciences Advisory Committee on USSR and
                    Eastern Europe. Materials include reports, memoranda, newsletters, pamphlets,
                    meeting minutes, and newspaper clippings. There is also correspondence with
                    fellow panel members and members of industry groups and the general public
                    interested in the work of the panels. Goddard's records from the Advisory
                    Committee on the USSR and Eastern Europe (1965-1968) include reports of
                    scientists on visits to the Soviet Union and Eastern Bloc countries as well as
                    proposals and invitations for visits by Soviet scientists to the United States.
                    This section of the collection also includes a report of Goddard's 1966 trip to
                    Hungary.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 192</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Archives and Records Center: David Rockwell Goddard papers (UPT 50
                    G578).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>