<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Donald Grey Brownlow papers <date type="inclusive">1959-2001</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Donald Grey Brownlow papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC744</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>14.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1959-2001</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Donald Grey Brownlow (1923-2006) was a history teacher and author. He served in
                    U.S. military intelligence during World War II and earned a Purple Heart and
                    Bronze Star. He was also awarded the Croix de Guerre from the French government.
                    He earned bachelor's and master's degrees from the University of Pennsylvania.
                    He taught at the Haverford School from 1951-2006 and authored 10 books on
                    military history, including Checkmate at Ruweisat: Auchinleck’s Finest Hour
                    (1977) and The Life and Times of Horst Wessel (1996).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence and interviews recorded by Donald
                    Brownlow. The collection contains recordings of interviews and conversations
                    with eminent people, including Grossadmiral Karl Donitz, Jean Paul Sartre,
                    Admiral Husband E. Kimmel, Field Marshal Sir Claude Auchinleck, Otto von Bulow,
                    and Albert Speer. The collection also contains over 1500 signed letters, whose
                    correspondents include Captain Eddie Rickenbacker, Herbert Hoover, Eleanor
                    Roosevelt, Stirling Moss, John L. Lewis, Hasso von Manteuffel, Captain P.C.
                    Crosley, and Richard O'Connor, among many other state, military leaders, and
                    public figures. A number of the letters are addressed to Dr. and Mrs. Marion
                    Brownlow or to Marion Brownlow. Most of the letters are arranged in a series of
                    31 scrapbooks, dating from 1959 to 1972. There is also a card file index of the
                    correspondence in the scrapbooks, listing sender, date, and a brief description
                    of the letter's contents; photographs of German, British and American military
                    figures and politicians; scrapbooks of photos and clippings on Leni Riefenstahl;
                    a scrapbook of correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, and photographs of Gus
                    Hall; drafts of chapters of Brownlow's book on Auchenleck (The Auk), and
                    corrections and suggestions by Lt. Gen. Sir Neil Ritchie.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 266 and no acc. number</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>