<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Dorothy E. Withrow collection of World War II memorabilia <date type="inclusive">1892-1950</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Dorothy E. Withrow collection of World War II
                    memorabilia</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC406</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.66 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1892-1950</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dorothy E. Withrow (d. 2000) graduated from the University of Pennsylvania with a
                    degree in education.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of World War I and World War II ephemera collected by
                    Dorothy Withrow and [her father?] John Alexander Withrow. World War II materials
                    include: civil defense information bulletins and rules, registration cards,
                    helmet, arm bands, wooden alarm rattle and signs; war bond advertisements and
                    buttons; Office of War Information and U.S. Food Administration bulletins and
                    magazines; German, British, and American propaganda such as flyers and
                    pamphlets; postcards and greeting cards to Dorothy Withrow; issues of the
                    Saturday Review of Literature, 1940-1944; Philadelphia newspapers from 1939,
                    1942, and 1945, and the Manchester Guardian, 1939; posters; receipts for knitted
                    garments for the British War Relief Society; and a 1945 published volume on
                    tanks. World War I materials include: printed addresses and articles from
                    1915-1916; German 100,000 bank note, 1923; Red Cross patches; and a series of
                    pictorial books titled the New York Tribune Photographic History of the Great
                    War. There is also a copy of a 1892 publication titled Historical and Commercial
                    Philadelphia.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 175</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>