<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Dorothy M. Spencer papers <date type="inclusive">undated</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Dorothy M. Spencer papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC343</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dorothy M. Spencer did field work in India from 1939-1942, 1946-1948, and for
                    brief periods in 1951 and 1952, supported by the American Philosophical Society,
                    the American Council of Learned Societies, and the Guggenheim Foundation.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists documentation related to Spencer's work in India.
                    Materials include: manuscript and typed notes such as field notes, notes from
                    interviews, results of psychological tests (Rorschach), transcriptions of police
                    reports, and transcriptions of songs and poems; notes on various topics,
                    including dreams, marriage ceremonies, economics, sacrifices, children's games,
                    witchcraft, animals, and property; index cards to Spencer's Munda materials;
                    records of the Government of India Anthropology Survey; an 8mm movie film
                    labeled "Fiji"; reprints on tribes/Indian anthropology and articles on
                    interpretation of Rorschach tests; and course materials such as student exams,
                    papers, bibliographies, a grade sheet, and blank exam sheets.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 119</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>