<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edwin E. Aubrey notes regarding Simon Patrick <date type="inclusive">1955</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edwin E. Aubrey notes regarding Simon Patrick</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC801</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1955</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Edwin Ewart Aubrey (1896-1956) was born in Glasgow, Scotland, and became a
                    naturalized citizen of the United States in 1918. He earned his Bachelor of
                    Philosophy degree from Bucknell University in 1919. His Master of Arts (1921),
                    Bachelor of Divinity (1922), and Doctor of Philosophy (1926) were all received
                    from the University of Chicago. Aubrey taught at Carleton College, Miami
                    University (Ohio), Vassar College, and the University of Chicago, before
                    becoming the president of Crozer Theological Seminary, Chester, Pennsylvania, in
                    1944. He remained at Crozer until 1949, when he established the Department of
                    Religious Thought at the University of Pennsylvania. Simon Patrick (1626-1707),
                    English divine, was dean of Peterborough in 1679, and Bishop of Chichester in
                    1689, in which year he was employed, along with others of the new bishops, to
                    settle the affairs of the Church in Ireland. In 1691 he was translated to the
                    see of Ely, which he held until his death on the 31st of May 1707. His numerous
                    sermons and devotional writings were highly regarded and influential.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes a typescript project proposal for a Fulbright scholarship
                    (Aubrey died before the proposal came up for consideration). The proposal is
                    titled "The Theology of Simon Patrick (1626-1707)" and includes a bibliography
                    of Patrick's works and chronology of his life. There are also typed and
                    manuscript bibliographic and reading notes and extracts. Some of the notes are
                    arranged chronologically (by period of Patrick's life). There are also reader
                    request slips from Princeton, the Huntington Library, and the University of
                    Pennsylvania.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 54</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>