<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Eric Partridge papers <date type="inclusive">1957-1979</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Eric Partridge papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC780</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1957-1979</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Eric Partridge (1894-1979) was a noted New Zealand-born lexicographer of the
                    English language, particularly of its slang. He published a number of reference
                    works, including A Dictionary of Slang and Unconventional English and A
                    Dictionary of Catch Phrases.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The correspondence consists of correspondence, manuscripts and other materials
                    related to Eric Partridge and his work. Incoming and outgoing correspondence
                    with Eileen M. Wrigglesworth discusses their meetings, goings-on in each of
                    their households, and Partridge's work. Correspondence with Neda M. Westlake (of
                    the University of Pennsylvania Library) relates to the University's purchase of
                    books and manuscripts from Partridge. Other materials include manuscripts and
                    typescripts of reviews, articles, and Christmas greetings written by Partridge;
                    newspaper clippings of reviews; a memorial to Julian Franklyn and a privately
                    published volume of poems by Franklyn; and a heavily annotated copy of A First
                    Dictionary by Walter D. Wright.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 36, 37, 38</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Indiana: A. Brown manuscripts (include letters of Partridge, including some from
                    Wrigglesworth to Partridge); University of Exeter: Papers of Eric Partridge and
                    Paul Beale relating to English slang (MS 138).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>