<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Esther B. Aresty papers <date type="inclusive">1947-1986</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Esther B. Aresty papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC417</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1947-1986</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Esther Aresty (1908-2000) was a culinary historian who wrote on food, cooking and
                    etiquette. Her publications included The Delectable Past (1964), The Best
                    Behavior (1970), and The Exquisite Table (1980), Her large collection of rare
                    cookbooks and manuscripts was donated to the University of Pennsylvania in
                    1996.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes correspondence, manuscripts, and printed materials
                    related to or collected by Aresty. Materials include: incoming and some outgoing
                    correspondence related to publishing and civic activities; some personal
                    correspondence; manuscripts for publications, including Delectable Past and Best
                    Behavior; research materials and drafts of articles on etiquette, domestic
                    servants, and Escoffier; copies of Culinary Review; dealer catalogues for
                    cookbooks; printed materials including cookbooks, pamphlets, and newspaper
                    clippings related to food and cooking; newsletters, correspondence and printed
                    materials from the American Institute of Wine and Food; and a small number of
                    recipes.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 188</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>