<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Eugene Ormandy collection of test pressings and private recordings
                            <date type="inclusive">1937-1977</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Eugene Ormandy collection of test pressings and private
                    recordings</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC736</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1937-1977</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Eugene Ormandy (1899-1985) was a Hungarian-born conductor and violinist. Ormandy
                    came to the US in 1921 and joined the orchestra of the Capitol Theater, becoming
                    its associate music director in 1926. From 1931 to 1936 he became conductor of
                    the Minneapolis Symphony. In 1936 he was invited to become co-conductor of the
                    Philadelphia Orchestra, sharing the podium with Leopold Stokowski. He was made
                    music director in 1938. During the 44 years of his tenure, the orchestra made
                    many recordings with RCA and with Columbia Records, toured frequently, and
                    broadcast performances on radio and television. Although he retired as conductor
                    of the Philadelphia Orchestra at the end of the 1979-1980 season, he continued
                    to appear as conductor laureate and guest conducted all over the US and in
                    Europe.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of test pressings and private recordings. Test pressings
                    include performances by the Minneapolis Symphony conducted by Eugene Ormandy and
                    of performances by unidentified orchestras and conductors (though they are
                    likely to be by Eugene Ormandy). The private recordings are of performances by
                    the NBC Symphony Orchestra conducted by Arturo Toscanini. These recordings
                    include works by Schubert, Mahler, Wagner, Bach, Bruckner, Schoenberg, Jolivet,
                    and Michael Tippett and range in date from 1937 to 1977. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 258</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>