<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Francis Campbell Macauley autograph collection <date type="inclusive">1479-1882</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Francis Campbell Macauley autograph collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC378</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.66 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1479-1882</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Francis Campbell Macaulay built an extraordinary collection of early editions of
                    Dante, Petrarch, Boccaccio, and Tasso, which he bequeathed to the University of
                    Pennsylvania in 1896.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is an autograph collection compiled by Francis Campbell Macauley. The
                    collection is composed of letters by scientists, politicians, and men of
                    letters, and fragments with signatures. The collection reflects Macauley's
                    interest in Italian literature, and includes letters from Lodovico Ariosto,
                    Fortunato Cavazzeni Pederzini, and Allessandro Torri. Other notable names in the
                    collection are Alexandre Dumas, Robert Morris, and Millard Fillmore. The
                    collection also includes several letters to Macauley regarding the Dante
                    Society, The collection also includes five volumes of Macauley's notes for a
                    vocabulary of the dialect of Nice.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 15</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>