<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Frederic M. Bird 19th-century sermons and speeches <date type="inclusive">1859-1908</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Frederic M. Bird 19th-century sermons and
                    speeches</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC718</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1859-1908</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Frederic Mayer Bird was educated at the University of Pennsylvania, the Hartwick
                    Lutheran Theological Seminary, and the Union Theological Seminary. He was
                    ordained in the Lutheran church in 1861 and during the Civil War he served as a
                    chaplain in the army. In 1869 he was ordained in the Episcopal church. After
                    holding several posts, he was appointed Professor of Psychology, Christian
                    Evidences, and Rhetoric at Lehigh University, in Pennsylvania (1881-1886). Bird
                    was editor of Lippincott's Magazine from 1893 to 1898.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Frederic Mayer Bird. Materials include:
                    sermons, addresses, and articles; letters of condolence; newspaper clippings;
                    galley proofs; and a handwritten draft of a work on hymnody. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 234</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>