<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>George William Brown research on 19th-century missionary work in
                        India <date type="inclusive">1924-1932</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">George William Brown research on 19th-century missionary
                    work in India</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC743</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1924-1932</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>George William Brown (1870-1932) received his Ph.D. in Sanskrit, Hebrew, and
                    Arabic from Johns Hopkins University under the direction of Maurice Bloomfield.
                    Brown taught at Central Christian College, before going to Harda and Jubbulpore
                    in South India, where he worked as a missionary of the Disciples of Christ for
                    16 years. From 1917 to 1921 he was Professor of Semitic languages at the College
                    of the Bible, Transylvania University, and from 1921 to 1927 he was Dean of the
                    Faculty and Professor of Indology at the College of Missions at Indianapolis.
                    Brown was a founding member of the Linguistic Society of America. His son, W.
                    Norman Brown, was also a noted Sanskrit scholar.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of George William Brown. Materials include:
                    research notes and a typescript for a history of the Disciples of Christ in
                    India; research notes for and typescripts of "History of Missions in India";
                    notes on Hittites, Dravidians, Elamites, Etruscans, Sumerians, Hurri, Churri and
                    the Mittani and Dravidian languages; a review of a Nepali etymological
                    dictionary; notes on the Synoptic Gospels; typescript of an analysis of the
                    Tulsi Das Ramayana; and a series of lecture notes on China, linguistic and
                    language study, comparative philology, and the Old Testament. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 265</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>