<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>George Allan Dash collection <date type="inclusive">1939-1970</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">George Allan Dash collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC725</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>17.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1939-1970</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>George Allan Dash, Jr. (1908-2000) was an arbitrator who worked on labor
                    arbitration cases for the American Arbitration Association, the Federal
                    Mediation and Conciliation Service, and the New Jersey State Board of Mediation.
                    He also served on the US Wage Stabilization Board and the US Emergency Board
                    (convened in 1961 to arbitrate a dispute between Pan-Am and the Flight Engineers
                    International Association).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of decisions and awards from cases heard by G. Allan Dash,
                    Jr., arbitrator. The materials date from 1939 to 1970 and cover labor-management
                    disputes in a wide variety of companies and industries. Companies for whom Dash
                    decided multiple cases include: Honeywell, Goodyear Tire and Rubber Co., U.S.
                    Rubber Co., Bendix, and General Motors. The collection also includes a small
                    number of printed agreements for a variety of cases and companies.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: transferred from Lippincott Library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 242</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>