<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>George W. Norris scrapbooks <date type="inclusive">1875-1963</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">George W. Norris scrapbooks</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC691</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.58 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1875-1963</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>George William Norris (1875-1965) was a professor of clinical medicine at the
                    University of Pennsylvania and chief of Medical Service "A" at Pennsylvania
                    Hospital. He received his bachelor's degree from the University of Pennsylvania
                    in 1895 and his M.D. in 1899. He served in World War I as a member of the Major
                    Medical Corps in the Pennsylvania Hospital Unit. He was an amateur
                    photographer.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes photographs and other materials related to Norris's work
                    and career. There are two photograph albums that mainly feature family and
                    friends and places associated with these people; there are also photos and
                    printed materials related to travel in Haiti, Venezuela, and other locales. Many
                    of the photographs were taken by Norris and include commentary from Norris.
                    There is also an album of published(?) landscape photographs, as well as many
                    portrait photographs by Norris. The collection includes one scrapbook of
                    letters, photographs, certificates, awards, calling cards and other items
                    (including a few photographs) and a narrative account of a trip to Guatemala in
                    1963.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 208</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>