<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>George Seldes collection <date type="inclusive">1845-1997</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1930-1990</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">George Seldes collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC2275</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>85 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1845-1997</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1930-1990</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>George Seldes (1890-1995) was an influential American investigative journalist
                    and critic of the media and corporate power. He began his career in journalism
                    when he was 16, working as a reporter for the Pittsburgh Leader. After a year at
                    Harvard, he went to Europe to cover World War I. He remained in Europe after the
                    war, working as a correspondent for the Chicago Tribune. He met and wrote about
                    Freud, Alfred Adler, Isadora Duncan, Mussolini and Lenin. He left the Tribune in
                    1928 and worked as a freelancer, covering, among other things, the Spanish Civil
                    War. He is the founder of In Fact, a weekly progressive newsletter, which he
                    edited from 1940 to 1950. One of the early issues of the newsletter addressed
                    the hazards of smoking and the suppression of this information by the mainstream
                    press. He was the author of more than a dozen books, including You Can't Print
                    That, Lords of the Press, The Great Quotations, The Great Thoughts, and his
                    memoir, Witness to a Century. Seldes was married to Helen Larkin Wiesman
                    (1905-1979). He was the brother of Gilbert Seldes, the critic and author.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of George Seldes. The bulk of the materials
                    are professional papers relating to his publication of his books and of In Fact.
                    These papers include subject files of newspaper and magazine clippings; research
                    notes; news bulletins; typed extracts of writings by others; typed and annotated
                    drafts of articles by Seldes; manuscripts of Fads and Fascism, Sawdust Caesar,
                    Tell the Truth and Run, You Can't Print That, Great Thoughts, Great Quotations,
                    and other books; promotional materials for his publications; printed issues of
                    In Fact and clippings of clippings of articles by Seldes in various newspapers
                    and magazines; and correspondence with publishers, fellow journalists, readers,
                    and other interested parties. Notable correspondents include Emma Goldman, J.
                    Edgar Hoover, Ashley Montague; Norman Vincent Peale, William Shirer, Upton
                    Sinclair, and Walter Winchell. There is some personal correspondence to George
                    and Helen Seldes, as well, including letters from his niece Marian Seldes and
                    her daughter Katharine Andres, and from Sylviane and Alvah Bessie. The
                    collection includes a small number of photographs and newspaper and magazine
                    profiles of Seldes. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>