<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Gerald Clifford Weales papers <date type="inclusive">1958-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Gerald Clifford Weales papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC739</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1958-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Gerald Weales (b. 1925) is a theater scholar, critic, and Professor Emeritus of
                    English at the University of Pennsylvania. He received his bachelor's, master's,
                    and doctoral degrees from Columbia University. His books include The Jumping off
                    Place: American Drama in the 1960s, American Drama since World War II, Canned
                    Goods as Caviar, and Religion in Modern English Drama. For 25 years his theater
                    reviews were published in Commonweal, and he has also published in many other
                    journals, including the Nation, the Gettysburg Review, the Tulane Drama Review,
                    the Quarterly of Film Radio and Television.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of typescript drafts and galleys of books written by Gerald
                    Weales. Most of these drafts are only lightly annotated with copy edits and
                    proofreaders's marks; the short stories are more heavily annotated. Book
                    manuscripts include: American Drama Since World War II, Arthur Miller: Death of
                    a Salesman, Religion in Modern English Drama, Canned Goods as Caviar, Tale for
                    the Bluebird, and The Complete Plays of William Wycherly. Manuscripts of essays
                    and chapters include: "Ruggles of Red Gap," "Steamboat Round the Bend,""
                    It's a Gift," and "Ronald Ribman: Artist of the Failure Clowns." Manuscripts
                    of play and screenplays include: "Ethics, Incorporated," "The Hero at Home,"
                    "The Western Hero," and "The Hero and Homicide."</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 261</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>