<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Hector Bolitho correspondence <date type="inclusive">1948-1953</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Hector Bolitho correspondence</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC720</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1948-1953</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Hector Bolitho (1897-1974) was a New Zealand native and the author of more than
                    fifty books, largely nonfiction. He is most noted for his biographies of the
                    British royal family: Albert the Good and the Victorian Reign (1932); Albert,
                    Prince Consort (1964); and The Reign of Queen Victoria (1948). One of his few
                    novels, Judith Silver, also received critical acclaim in 1929. In addition to
                    authoring books, Bolitho was a frequent contributor to magazines in England, the
                    United States, Germany, Pakistan, and several other countries, and he lecture
                    extensively in the United States.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Hector Bolitho. Materials in the collection
                    include: correspondence between Bolitho and Aga Khan regarding a biography of
                    Jinnah and an autobiography by Kahn; research materials related to Bolitho's
                    book, Jinnah, Creator of Pakistan: correspondence with Lord Mountbatten of
                    Burma, General Lord Ismay, and Colonel Majeed Malik; obituaries; typed copies of
                    letters by Jinnah; and notes from interviews. Other items in the collection
                    include bound volumes of research notes on Jinnah, Pakistan, and Aga Khan. These
                    volumes include newspaper clippings, typed extracts, and articles. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 237</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>