<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Hedgerow Theatre records <date type="inclusive">1935-1949</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Hedgerow Theatre records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC702</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1935-1949</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Hedgerow Theatre was founded in 1923 by Jasper Deeter in Rose Valley,
                    Pennsylvania. Deeter’s creative energy drew many talented actors, playwrights,
                    and directors to Hedgerow, earning Hedgerow an international reputation and the
                    distinction of being the first resident repertory theatre in the country.
                    Hedgerow became a meeting ground for major actors of stage and screen in the
                    1920s and 1930s and is considered the precursor to such innovative theatre
                    companies as People’s Light and Theatre Company and Freedom Theatre. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of photographic images and papers of the Hedgerow Theater
                    Repertory Company. The bulk of the collection consists of negatives and
                    photographs of actors, productions, sets, and the theater building. Photographs
                    date largely from the late 1930s and early 1940s. This collection also includes
                    a small number of publicity materials for the theater. Materials include program
                    copy and press releases for various productions, including Candida, Twelfth
                    Night, The Inheritors, and Beyond the Horizon.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 216 and 226</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>