<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Helen, Ira, and Michael Wolfert papers <date type="inclusive">1924-2001</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Helen, Ira, and Michael Wolfert papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC728</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>37 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1924-2001</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Ira Wolfert (1908-1997) was a writer and journalist. In 1930, he received a
                    bachelor's degree from the Columbia University School of Journalism. He worked
                    for the North American Newspaper Alliance in the 1930s and 1940s; he was a war
                    correspondent during World War II, and in 1943 he received a Pulitzer Prize for
                    a series of articles he wrote about a sea battle off Guadalcanal. He also wrote
                    fiction, and was the author of the acclaimed 1943 novel Tucker's People. His
                    wife, Helen X. Herschdorfer Wolfert (1901-1985) was a poet. She was a graduate
                    of Hunter College, and taught in the New York City schools for ten years. Her
                    works include two volumes of poems: Landlady and Tenant and Music, as well as
                    articles, poems, and reviews published in magazines such as Poetry, Harper's
                    Bazaar, the New Republic, and The Nation. The couple's son, Michael Wolfert
                    (1936-2001), was a novelist.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Helen and Ira Wolfert and of their son Michael
                    Wolfert. Helen and Ira Wolfert materials include: typed and handwritten
                    manuscripts of stories, poems, plays, novels, and reviews; notes for writings;
                    articles and clippings; copies of published articles, reviews, and poems;
                    personal and professional correspondence; financial materials; diaries;
                    photographs and negatives. Of note are letters between the Wolferts during Ira
                    Wolfert's time as a war correspondent. Michael Wolfert materials include
                    typescripts; handwritten notes for writings; diaries; clippings and extracts of
                    news items; financial materials; and a small amount of correspondence.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 244</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>