<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Henry Miller letters to Tambimuttu <date type="inclusive">1942-1952</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Henry Miller letters to Tambimuttu</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC327</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1942-1952</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henry Miller (1891-1980) was an American author and painter. He was best known
                    for his controversial novels Tropic of Cancer (1934) and Tropic of Capricorn
                    (1939), which were banned in the United States for obscenity. Meary James
                    Thurairajah Tambimuttu (1915-1983) was a Tamil poet, editor and critic. In 1938,
                    he started Poetry London, a small, but influential magazine that he edited until
                    1949. He founded several other poetry journals and also published a number of
                    his own writings.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of Miller's letters to M. J. Tambimuttu, written between
                    1943 and 1952. The letters discuss publication of Miller's writings (articles,
                    books, open letters), sales and exhibitions of his paintings, funding for his
                    life as an artist and writer, and the works of contemporary authors. The
                    collection also includes two watercolors by Miller, clippings of "An Open
                    Letter" from the New Republic, an announcement for a show of his paintings, and
                    a photograph of Miller at Big Sur.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 106</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>