<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Holden Furber collection <date type="inclusive">1759-1946</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1759-1829</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Holden Furber collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC414</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1759-1946</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1759-1829</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Holden Furber (1903-1993) was the 21st president of the Association for Asian
                    Studies and a scholar who specialized in the history of India during the time of
                    the British Raj. He received his doctorate from Harvard in 1929 and at the same
                    time attended Oxford University, where he was completed a bachelor's degree in
                    1925 and a master's degree in 1930. Furber lectured at the University of Madras
                    in 1948, before moving to the University of Pennsylvania, where he served as
                    Professor of History until 1973.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of material relating to 18th century British India.
                    Materials include: contemporary handwritten documents and letters concerning,
                    among others, Sir John MacPherson, Governor General, 1784-1786; Governor of
                    Bombay Jonathan Duncan, 1795-1802; Major F. R. MacDonald, 1791-1799; and General
                    Stuart, Commander-in-Chief, 1796-1800. There is correspondence to Henry Dundas
                    relating to British parliamentary matters; correspondence to and from Robert
                    Dundas relating to India and British parliamentary matters; a Catalogue of Lord
                    Melville's Miscellaneous East India Papers consisting largely of correspondence;
                    a Record of Testimony Related to Lord Melville's Impeachment (1805); and Sir R.
                    Woodford Phillipine Company correspondence. The collection also includes several
                    pages from the Bombay Courier and India Gazette; lists of claimants for
                    pensions; printed accounts, bills and correspondence of the East India Company;
                    framed item with two letters from Simeon Cary; and a bound typed manuscript of
                    Furber's John Company at Work (1946).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 184</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>