<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Hope Emily Allen collection <date type="inclusive">1928-1954</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Hope Emily Allen collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC402</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1928-1954</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Hope Emily Allen (1883-1960), noteworthy medieval scholar, is best known for her
                    research on the 14th century English mystic Richard Rolle and for her discovery
                    of the Book of Margery Kempe. Allen received her bachelor's and master's degrees
                    from Bryn Mawr College. She later did graduate work at Radcliffe and Cambridge.
                    Allen described herself as an "independent scholar," and she never accepted an
                    academic teaching appointment. Her writing falls into three overlapping groups:
                    her early work on the Ancrene Riwle, her insight into the study of Richard
                    Rolle, and her research on the cultural background of the Book of Margery
                    Kempe.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of microfilm, photostats, and other materials related to
                    Allen's research. There are microfilm copies of Medieval manuscripts in British
                    and European libraries and of modern serials, as well as photostats of Medieval
                    manuscripts. Works and authors represented in the collection include the Ancrene
                    Riwle, Orcherd of Syon, St. Bridget, Richard Rolle, and Blessed Mechtild. The
                    collection also includes a small amount of Allen's correspondence related to the
                    progress of her research in Europe and acquisition of materials, and receipts
                    for transcription and copying services.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 171</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Bryn Mawr College:
                    Hope Emily Allen papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>