<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Howard Fast collection <date type="inclusive">1936-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Howard Fast collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC382</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>16.58 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Howard Melvin Fast (1914-2003) was a Jewish American novelist and television
                    writer, who wrote also under the pen names E. V. Cunningham and Walter Ericson.
                    He was convicted of contempt of Congress in 1950 for refusing to cooperate with
                    the House Un-American Activities Committee. He served three months in jail and
                    was blacklisted. His most well known book was Spartacus.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes manuscripts, typescripts, correspondence and other
                    materials related to Fast's writing and activism. The collection contains
                    original typescripts, printer's copies, and galley proofs of many of Fast's
                    novels and typescripts of his screenplays. Some drafts are annotated by Fast,
                    while others have copy edits. Materials include: correspondence with publishers
                    and royalty statements, mostly from the early 1990s; letters from Fast to Bette
                    Cohen, 1936 (his future wife); photocopies of correspondence with a variety of
                    notable figures, including Upton Sinclair, Eleanor Roosevelt, Paul Robeson, and
                    Erica Jong relating to his reviews of works by fellow authors and his political
                    activities and reporting (1937-1992); posters and handbills for Fast's 1952 run
                    for Congress; and copies of Fast's FBI files. There are also scrapbooks of
                    clippings of articles by and about Fast, reviews of his work, stories about his
                    activism; book announcements and book jackets; photocopies of articles by Fast,
                    including his articles in the Daily Worker, the New York Observer, and the New
                    Times; photographs of Fast and his family; sketches of costume designs, in ink,
                    marker, and gouache; a small number of miscellaneous personal papers; a draft of
                    a dissertation on Fast by Frank Campenni, with some correspondence between
                    Campenni and Fast; handwritten notes for Frenzy; and printed materials,
                    including copies of the Saturday Evening Post, World Over, the New Masses, the
                    Communist, Soviet Literature Review, and other pamphlets and journals.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 152</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>