<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Israel Stiefel papers <date type="inclusive">1898-1966</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Israel Stiefel papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC412</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1898-1966</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Israel Stiefel (1898-1966) was born in Odessa and emigrated to the United States
                    in the early 1920s. Stiefel served in the Pennsylvania Senate from 1936-1964,
                    representing the 5th Senatorial District in Philadelphia, and becoming Chairman
                    of the Democratic Senate Caucus. He was active in introducing legislation
                    promoting historic preservation, conservation, and aid to medical education,
                    among his other causes. Stiefel also taught at the University of Pennsylvania
                    and at Temple University.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Israel Stiefel. Papers from Stiefel's
                    student days include papers written for undergraduate and graduate courses,
                    course notes, examinations, and diplomas. Family papers include Stiefel's
                    immigration and naturalization papers, and those of his of his mother Ethel and
                    his sister Soshana. There are also a small number of telegrams and letters from
                    family members. Papers related to Stiefel's senatorial career include
                    correspondence with constituents and other government employees and politicians;
                    acts and amendments; scrapbooks and clippings on elections and legislation;
                    addresses; and political memorabilia and photographs. The collection also
                    includes papers related to his adjunct professorship at Temple; legal digests
                    and notes for lectures; scrapbooks and clippings related to his activities
                    involving the Jewish community and his membership in B'nai Brith; publications
                    and addresses; and photographs and memorabilia from his visits to Israel. A
                    number of letters and printed documents in the collection are in Hebrew and a
                    few are in Russian.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 183</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>