<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>J. G. Rosengarten collection <date type="inclusive">1763-1992</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1763-1908 </date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">J. G. Rosengarten collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC835</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1763-1992</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1763-1908 </unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph George Rosengarten was born in 1835. He graduated from the University of
                    Pennsylvania in 1852. In 1856 he was admitted to the bar, and in 1857 traveled
                    to Heidelberg to study Roman law. During the Civil War Rosengarten served on the
                    staff of General John F. Reynolds. He was the author of The German Soldier in
                    the Wars of the United States and The Sources of German-American History.
                    Rosengarten was a member of the Board of Trustees of the University of
                    Pennsylvania and a chairman of the Trustee's Library Committee. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of manuscripts and correspondence by or collected by
                    Rosengarten. Extra-illustrated bound works by Rosengarten include an interleaved
                    copy of The German Soldier in the Wars of the United States, with documents and
                    letters mounted, German Allied Troops in the War of Independence, General Count
                    de Rochambeau and The Chateau de Rochambeau. Correspondence includes letters to
                    Rosengarten, some related to manuscripts or letters sent to him (many are notes
                    of thanks for copies of his book French Colonists and Exiles in the United
                    States), and letters collected by Rosengarten -- most from the Revolutionary War
                    period, in French, German, and English. Corespondents include: Madame de Stael,
                    Tallyrand, Francois Chateaubriand, Frederick II of Prussia, James Hamilton,
                    Francis Hopkinson, John Jay, and George Clinton. There is a bound manuscript
                    copy of Popp’s Journal, 1777-1783 by Joseph G. Rosengarten and a bound
                    collection of German manuscripts dealing with the Revolutionary War in the U.S.
                    [1776-1782], including diaries of Caspar Recknagel, Andreas Wiederhold and
                    reports on the Battle of Trenton, which include maps, illustrations, and charts
                    (some of the maps have been removed and unfolded). The collection also includes
                    a 1992 translation of The Diary of Caspar Recknagel (translation by Bruce E.
                    Burgoyne) and negatives and photographs of manuscript pages, maps, and
                    engravings.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 66</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Archives and Records Center: Joseph G. Rosengarten papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>