<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Jim West collection <date type="inclusive">1992-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Jim West collection </unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC428</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1992-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James L. W. West III is Edwin Erle Sparks Professor of English at Penn State
                    University. He holds a B.A. and Ph.D. from the University of South Carolina. He
                    is a biographer, book historian, and scholarly editor. He has written on William
                    Styron, F. Scott Fitzgerald, and Theodore Dreiser. He was the textual editor of
                    Dreiser's American Diaries, 1902-1926, the editor of Dreiser’s Jennie Gerhardt:
                    New Essays on the Restored Text, and the editor of the 1992 University of
                    Pennsylvania Press edition of Jennie Gerhardt.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of drafts of West's historical notes and textual
                    introduction for the University of Pennsylvania edition of Jennie Gerhardt; and
                    photocopies of two manuscript editions of the novel: the composite manuscript
                    held by the University of Pennsylvania and the carbon typescript in the Barrett
                    Collection at the University of Virginia. The photocopied Dreiser manuscripts
                    are marked with West's notes on variations between the two texts. The collection
                    also includes a photocopy of Dreiser's "Russia Diary" of 1927.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 196</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library: Theodore Dreiser papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>