<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Muirhead Macfarlane manuscript collection <date type="inclusive">1922-1929</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Muirhead Macfarlane manuscript collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC693</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1922-1929</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Muirhead Macfarlane (1855-1943) was a Scottish botanist. He held several
                    different academic positions at the University of Edinburgh before emigrating to
                    the United States in 1893, where he became a professor of botany at the
                    University of Pennsylvania. He held this position until his retirement in 1920.
                    He also served as the director of Penn's Botanic Garden and played a leading
                    role in organizing and diversifying it. Macfarlane is most well known for his
                    first book, The Causes and Course of Organic Evolution; A Study in Bioenergics
                    (1918). He also wrote many other works including The Evolution and Distribution
                    of Flowering Plants, The Evolution and Distribution of Fishes and The Quantity
                    and Sources of Our Petroleum Supplies.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of manuscripts for several publications by Macfarlane.
                    Titles include: Fishes the Source of Petroleum, 1922 (typescript); A Report from
                    the Spec. American Petroleum Institute, 1925; The Evolution and Distribution of
                    Asclepiadaceae; "The Fishes of the Ancient Mediterranean Basin in Relation to
                    Supplies of Petroleum," 1923 (manuscript); and Quantity and Sources of Our
                    Petroleum Supplies, 1929 (typescript).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 21</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>