<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Nichols &amp; Sons records <date type="inclusive">1770-1820</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Nichols &amp; Sons records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC824</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1770-1820</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Nichols, was an apprentice to William Bowyer the younger (1699-1777), one of
                    London’s most learned and influential printers. In 1766 Nichols became Bowyer’s
                    partner and inherited the business on Bowyer’s death. He continued Bowyer’s
                    tradition of printing for private gentlemen, learned societies and the Palace of
                    Westminster and, in 1778, purchased a share in the Gentleman’s Magazine, a
                    popular monthly periodical specializing in literature, history and the arts. The
                    Nichols family edited and printed the magazine until 1856. His son, John Bowyer
                    Nichols entered the firm in 1796 and conducted the business beginning in
                    1803.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>These 131 letters are from the files of the London publishing firm of John
                    Nichols and Sons. The letters are from authors and business firms having
                    dealings with the publisher. They represent only "K" and "L" from the files,
                    and cover the period from 1770 to 1820. There are some copies of Nichols'
                    answers. The letters in general have to do with biographies, articles for
                    Gentlemen's Magazine and Legal Antiquities, illustrations for articles, and
                    requests for books.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 63</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>