<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Lukacs collection <date type="inclusive">1947-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Lukacs collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC383</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>21.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1947-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Lukacs (b. 1924) was born in Budapest and came to the United States in 1946.
                    Until his retirement, he taught history at Chestnut Hill College near
                    Philadelphia. He also held visiting professorships at Columbia, Johns Hopkins,
                    Tufts, and the University of Pennsylvania. A prolific writer, Lukacs's
                    best-known works include The Duel, Five Days in London, The End of the Twentieth
                    Century and the End of the Modern Age, A Thread of Years, and Historical
                    Consciousness.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of manuscripts, correspondence and photographs related to
                    Lukacs's life and work. There are typescripts and uncorrected and corrected
                    proofs for a number of Lukacs's books, articles, and reviews, including The Last
                    European War, Outgrowing Democracy, Philadelphia: Patricians and Philistines,
                    and Budapest, At the End of An Age. There is correspondence with colleagues and
                    fellow historians, publishers and editors (1947-2006). A portion of the
                    correspondence is in Hungarian, with a few letters in German and French. There
                    are also a small number of photographs of notable Philadelphians.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 153</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>