<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph E. Gillet papers <date type="inclusive">1920-1955</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph E. Gillet papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC750</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="spa"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1920-1955</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Eugene Gillet (1888-1958) was born in Belgium, and received his Ph.D. in
                    1910 from the University of Liege. He emigrated to the United States in 1913 and
                    became a citizen in 1918. He worked as an instructor in German at the University
                    of Wisconsin from 1913 to 1915 and served in the infantry during World War I.
                    After the war, he worked in the Foreign Service Department of the National City
                    Bank in New York where he learned Spanish. He traveled to Spain to further his
                    study of the language and while there he became interested in Spanish drama.
                    From 1921 to 1924 he was assistant professor of romance languages at the
                    University of Minnesota. In 1924 he joined the faculty of Bryn Mawr College, as
                    an associate professor and head of the department of Spanish. He directed
                    doctoral dissertations at Bryn Mawr and at the University of Pennsylvania. He
                    retired from Bryn Mawr in 1949.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of research materials and papers of Joseph E. Gillette.
                    Materials include: photostats of Spanish texts, some with typed transcriptions
                    and translations; handwritten research notes; correspondence with colleagues,
                    mostly relating to his publication on Torres Naharro; reviews of his work on
                    Torres Naharro; and a photograph and a memorial of Archer Huntington of the
                    Hispanic Society of America.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 270</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>