<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Hergesheimer collection <date type="inclusive">1951-1956</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Hergesheimer collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC833</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1951-1956</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Hergesheimer (1880-1954) was a prominent American novelist and short story
                    writer of the early 20th century. His first novel, The Lay Anthony, was
                    published in 1914. He enjoyed great popularity through the 1910s and 1920s, but
                    his style of writing fell out of favor in the 1930s and his popularity
                    declined.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscripts of Joseph Hergesheimer. The manuscripts are
                    fragmentary. Some contain poetry, and a number of them include multiple drafts
                    of the same passage. Quite a few appear to relate to F. Scott Fitzgerald. The
                    collection also includes bibliographies of Hergesheimer's books and magazine
                    articles, autobiographical passages and a reminiscence of James Branch Cabell by
                    Hergesheimer, an inventory of Mrs. Hergesheimer's collection of books by H. L.
                    Mencken, and several letters from Mrs. Hergesheimer to a friend.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 65</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>