<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Castaldo scores, papers, and sound recordings <date type="inclusive">1953-2001</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Castaldo scores, papers, and sound
                    recordings</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC741</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953-2001</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Castaldo was an American composer and longtime president of the
                    Philadelphia Musical Academy (later known as the Philadelphia College of the
                    Performing Arts). He studied composition at New York University, the New School,
                    and the Manhattan School of Music. He joined the Philadelphia Conservatory of
                    Music in 1954, becoming the school's president in 1966, a position he held for
                    17 years. During his tenure the school changed its name to the Philadelphia
                    College of Performing Arts and later merged with the Philadelphia College of
                    Art. Castaldo also founded the Philadelphia Composers' Forum and was
                    composer-in-residence at the Grand Teton Music Festival. Castaldo's works have
                    been performed by Andre Watts, Susan Starr, the Philadelphia Orchestra, the
                    Baltimore Symphony Orchestra, and several esteemed string quartets. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of scores and papers of Joseph Castaldo. The bulk of the
                    collection is made up of scores and parts of his works, including Ancient
                    Liturgies, Landscapes, and Where Silence Reigns (and many more). Other materials
                    include two scrapbooks that consist largely of newspaper clippings, programs,
                    and announcements; files related to performances of particular works, including
                    programs, announcements, reviews, and correspondence; manuscript drafts of
                    Castaldo's Creative Studies in Music; audio cassette and reel-to-reel recordings
                    of a number of Castaldo's works; diplomas and certificates; and obituaries of
                    Castaldo and memorial programs. The collection also includes a small amount of
                    incoming and outgoing correspondence between Castaldo and publishers, concert
                    organizers, orchestra librarians, and other musicians. Some of this
                    correspondence relates to Castaldo's tenure at the Philadelphia College of the
                    Performing Arts.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 263</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>