<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Julian A. Sterling collection related to S. Weir Mitchell <date type="inclusive">1914-1973</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Julian A. Sterling collection related to S. Weir
                    Mitchell</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC699</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1914-1973</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Julian A. Sterling was a surgeon at the Albert Einstein Medical Center in
                    Philadelphia. Silas Weir Mitchell (1829-1914) was an American physician and
                    writer. He studied at the University of Pennsylvania and received his M.D. from
                    Jefferson Medical College in 1850. During the Civil War he worked with patients
                    suffering from nervous injuries and maladies, and at the close of the war became
                    a specialist in neurology. In this field Weir Mitchell's name became prominently
                    associated with his introduction of the rest cure for nervous diseases,
                    particularly hysteria. His medical texts include Injuries of Nerves and Their
                    Consequences and Fat and Blood. Mitchell also wrote several historical novels
                    including Hugh Wynne, Free Quaker, The Adventures of François, and The Red
                    City.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of clippings and articles related to the life of S. Weir
                    Mitchell. The items were collected by Julian A. Sterling, M.D. Materials include
                    copies of Mitchell's published articles, newspaper clippings, a typescript
                    biographical sketch, a memorial booklet, and two bas relief portrait plaques of
                    Mitchell. The collection also includes Sterling's correspondence regarding the
                    collecting of these items.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 214</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>