<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Kanji Dwarkadas papers <date type="inclusive">1919-1965</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Kanji Dwarkadas papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC745</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1919-1965</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Kanji Dwarkadas (b. 1892) was a prominent Indian labor reformer. He was a member
                    for Labour in the Bombay Legislative Council (1921-1923); member of the
                    Industrial Dispute Committee and of the Prostitution Inquiry Committee (1922);
                    one of the founding members of the All-India Trade Union Congress; treasurer and
                    secretary of the All-India Home Rule League and member of the National Home Rule
                    League (during the period when Annie Besant was that group's president);
                    founding member of the Children's Aid Society (established 1927) and later
                    secretary of that group (1938-1941). His published works include Forty-five
                    Years with Labour, Ruttie Jinnah; the Story of a Great Friendship, and Ten Years
                    to Freedom.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Kanji Dwarkadas, including correspondence
                    and manuscripts of articles, letters to the editor, and reports of interviews.
                    The correspondence relates to Dwarkadas's involvement in Indian politics, trade
                    unions, and children's and women's welfare. Correspondents include: Annie
                    Besant, Sir C. P. Ramaswami Aiyer, D. G. Pole, Shiva Rao, P. K. Telang, C. R.
                    Attlee, Jinnah, Arthur Nethercot, and many others. Other materials in the
                    collection include minutes from the Children's Aid Society, the Prostitution
                    Committee, the Home Rule for India League; and reports by various individuals
                    related to Indian politics and economic and social issues.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 267</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>