<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Lawrence Robert Klein papers <date type="inclusive">1956-1991</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Lawrence Robert Klein papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC2264</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>39.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1956-1991</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Lawrence Robert Klein (born 1920) is a Nobel Prize-winning American economist. He
                    earned his bachelor's degree from the University of California, Berkeley, in
                    1942 and his Ph.D. in economics from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology
                    in 1944. After positions at the University of Chicago, University of Michigan,
                    and Oxford University, he joined the Department of Economics at the University
                    of Pennsylvania in 1958. He was named the Benjamin Franklin Professor of
                    Economics and Finance at the Wharton School in 1968. In the early 1960s Klein
                    became the leader of the major "Brookings-SSRC Project", to construct a
                    detailed econometric model to forecast the short-term development of the
                    American economy. He also founded Wharton Econometric Forecasting Associates
                    (WEFA) and was the initiator of their LINK project. He was awarded the Nobel
                    Prize in Economics in 1980.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the professional papers of Lawrence Klein. Much of the
                    material in the collection relates to Klein's work on Project LINK. Materials
                    include incoming and outgoing correspondence, drafts of Klein's papers,
                    articles, reports, and addresses; reprints and photocopies of papers and reports
                    by others; notes, minutes, and reports from various conferences and symposia;
                    student papers, dissertations, and letters of recommendation; and course
                    syllabi, exam questions, and lecture notes.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>