<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Miscellaneous ephemera regarding Walt Whitman <date type="inclusive">1884-1973</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Miscellaneous ephemera regarding Walt Whitman</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC381</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1884-1973</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Walt Whitman (1819-1892) was a prominent American poet, essayist, and and
                    journalist.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes materials related to Walt Whitman and the Norton
                    Comprehensive Reader's Edition of Leaves of Grass, edited by Sculley Bradley and
                    Harold Blodgett. Materials include: typescripts and manuscripts from the
                    edition, as well as annotated drafts of introductory essays, poems and passages
                    excluded from the original publication of Leaves of Grass; photocopies of
                    articles on Whitman compiled for possible inclusion in the critical response
                    section of the edition; correspondence between Bradley, Harold Blodgett, and
                    John Benedict (editor at Norton) about the publication, especially the critical
                    response section; reprints of articles on Whitman; exhibition catalogs; book
                    sales catalogs; and a 1884 copy of The Critic, which included Whitman's essay
                    "A Backward Glance on My Own Road."</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 151</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library: Walt Whitman Collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>