<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Mortimer-Beasley papers of Rev. Frederick W. Beasley <date type="inclusive">1806-1912</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Mortimer-Beasley papers of Rev. Frederick W.
                    Beasley</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC717</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1806-1912</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Frederick Williamson Beasley, Jr., (1845-1871) received his bachelor's degree
                    from the University of Pennsylvania in 1866 and an honorary Doctor of Divinity
                    degree in 1868. He was rector of All Saints Church in Lower Dublin,
                    Pennsylvania. His father, Frederick Beasley (1777-1845), was ordained a deacon
                    in the Episcopal Church in 1801 and a priest the following year. After serving
                    as rector of several congregations in New Jersey, New York, and Maryland,
                    Beasley accepted a position at the University of Pennsylvania as Professor of
                    Moral Philosophy and Provost of the University, where he remained until 1928. He
                    received an honorary Doctor of Divinity degree from the University in 1815.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This small collection of Frederick Beasley papers includes correspondence to
                    Beasley; poems and addresses by the Reverend, including a bound handwritten
                    address entitled "Volcanoes and Earthquakes"; a copy of "University of
                    Pennsylvania Catalogue of Matriculates of the College, 1749-1893"; several
                    guidebooks to Philadelphia (1889-1899); and auction catalogs related to the sale
                    of the Bancker collection of broadsides. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Sarah B.M. Mortimer</p>
                <p>Accession number: 233</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library: Beasley family papers (Acc.
                    169)</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>