<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Octave Delepierre collection <date type="inclusive">1835-1879</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Octave Delepierre collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC734</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="fre"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1835-1879</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Octave Delepierre (1804-1879) was a Belgian historian and diplomat. He
                    studied law and practiced in Brussels before joining the diplomatic service. In
                    1849, he was appointed Consul-General of Belgium at London. He published on a
                    range of subjects, including history, ancient literature, national bibliography,
                    and archaeology.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscripts and correspondence of Octave Delepierre.
                    Materials include: writings on literature, including his "Portefeuille d'un
                    Bibliophile"; proverbs collected by Delepierre; translations by Delepierre,
                    including George Varrentrapp's De l'emprisonnement individuel; a bibliography of
                    works by and works edited by Delepierre; extracts from books and reading notes
                    made by Delepierre; notes and essays on various subjects; and sketches on
                    tracing paper. The collection includes a small number of letters; correspondents
                    include: Ernest van Bruyssel, Felix-Victor Goethals, and M. L. Polain.
                    Manuscripts are in French, English, and Latin.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 254</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>