<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Otto Edwin Albrecht materials for history of music in Boston, New
                        York and Philadelphia <date type="inclusive">1926-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Otto Edwin Albrecht materials for history of music in
                    Boston, New York and Philadelphia</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC389</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1926-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Otto Edwin Albrecht (1988-1984) was a professor and curator of the music library
                    at the University of Pennsylvania. He earned his bachelor's degree from Penn in
                    1921, and after studying at the University of Copenhagen, he returned to teach
                    French at the University and at the same time completed his master's degree
                    (1925). He earned his doctorate in French from Penn in 1931. He taught French at
                    the University and lectured in the music department. In 1937, Albrecht became
                    curator of the music library. He is the author of A Census of Autograph Music
                    Manuscripts of European Composers in American Libraries (1953). He retired in
                    1970. The University renamed the music library in his honor, and he continued as
                    the curator there until his death.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists primarily of typed and manuscript notes compiled from New
                    York, Boston, and Philadelphia newspapers from 1800-1840. The notes include
                    listings of musical events, musical societies, publications, teachers, and
                    instrument makers and dealers. Newspapers surveyed include the New York Herald,
                    the Aurora General Advertiser, Poulson's Daily American Advertiser, the Boston
                    Gazette, and the Independent Chronicle. The collection also includes a small
                    amount of correspondence related to Albrecht's work on a census of European
                    music held in collections in the United States, and the building of a music
                    microfilm archive (a project funded by the Oberlaender Trust). There are also
                    music catalogs, publishing announcements, programs, and bulletins.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 158</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>