<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Paul Eldridge collection <date type="inclusive">1910-1978</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Paul Eldridge collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC388</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1978</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Paul Eldridge (1888-1982) was a novelist, poet and writer of short stories. He
                    also taught in New York City high schools from 1914-1946. His books included My
                    First Two Thousand Years, Salome, and The Homecoming.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes correspondence, manuscripts and other materials related
                    to Eldridge's writing and career. Materials include: manuscripts, typescripts
                    and carbons of poems, stories and essays; scrapbooks of clippings related to
                    Eldridge's writing and other activities; correspondence with other authors,
                    publishers, critics, and admirers including George Sylvester Viereck (Eldridge's
                    co-author), John Thomas Head, Tom Kennedy, and E. Haldeman-Julius; book jackets;
                    photographs; issues of newspapers and periodicals in which his columns appeared,
                    including the Answer, the American Freedman, the Jewish Review, Progress
                    Monthly, Progressive World, Critic and Guide, and Jewish Forum; typescripts of
                    "Sparks in the Wind," Eldridge's column for the Answer; correspondence to
                    Sylvia Eldridge from others; and a typescript of Eldridge's 1913 thesis for the
                    University of Paris on William Cullen Bryant, in French.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 157</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>