<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Society for Alleviating the Miseries of Public Prisons
                        records <date type="inclusive">1787-1883</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Society for Alleviating the Miseries of Public
                    Prisons records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC419</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1787-1883</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Philadelphia Society for Alleviating the Miseries of Public Prisons was
                    established in May 1787 with the goal of improving the conditions of the Walnut
                    Street Prison. In its earlier days, the society gave relief to prisoners in the
                    form of money and clothing, donated bibles, and visited prisoners. By the 1820s,
                    the society focused on changing the overarching policy of the prison from group
                    confinement to the Pennsylvania System of solitary confinement and the new
                    Eastern State Penitentiary. The members also visited county prisons across and
                    the state and sought just penal legislation. The society continued to grow in
                    numbers and, as the society entered the twentieth century, it became involved in
                    numerous studies hoping to gain a better understanding of the causes of
                    criminality and the most effective and just paths to punishment and
                    reformation.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of the Philadelphia Society for Alleviating the
                    Miseries of Public Prisons. Materials include: reports from the society's agents
                    to the Committee on County Prison (1862-1883), reports from the Visiting
                    Committee to the Society, and reports to the Committee on Discharged Prisoners;
                    minutes of the Committee on County Prison, 1856-1864; a manuscript by James J.
                    Barclay relating to prison discipline, circa 1828; a scrapbook of newspaper
                    clippings on prison discipline, 1843-1845; a 1787 memorial to the Pennsylvania
                    State and House of Representatives requesting an act of incorporation; and an an
                    account book of the Journal of Prison Discipline. The reports include case
                    descriptions, summaries of visit made to prisoners (broken down by offense), and
                    information about prisoners discharged from the prisons.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 19</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Pennsylvania Prison Society Records, 1787-1966 (collection
                    1946).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>