<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Stock Exchange and Philadelphia Clearing House records
                            <date type="inclusive">1836-1950</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Stock Exchange and Philadelphia Clearing House
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC2265</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>58.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1836-1950</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Philadelphia Stock Exchange was established in 1790 and is the oldest stock
                    exchange in the United States. The Philadelphia Clearing House was organized in
                    1858, with seventeen banks as members. It was the second association of its kind
                    in the United States, New York having established one in 1853. Robert L.
                    Montgomery, William J. Clothier and George F. Tyler were the original members of
                    the firm of Montgomery, Clothier &amp; Tyler. The firm was admitted to the New
                    York and Philadelphia stock exchanges in 1907.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes records of a number of Philadelphia financial and
                    business concerns. The collection includes bound and unbound volumes of printed
                    daily stock quotations and sales from the Philadelphia Stock Exchange, dating
                    approximately from 1877 to the 1920s and from 1945 to 1950. Records of the
                    Philadelphia Clearing House include: bound and unbound business volumes of
                    runner's statements; daily records; daily statements; weekly statements
                    (1864-1941); consolidated bank ledgers; and balance and receipts. Most series
                    date approximately from 1858 to 1887. Other documentation related to financial
                    concerns includes records of the National Bank of the Republic, including
                    dividends book, representative accounts, bad debts accounts, and minutes
                    (1865-1898); and records from the General Securities Company, dating from 1916
                    to 1927, which contain minutes (including articles of incorporation) and
                    correspondence, including several letters to Theodore Roosevelt, Jr.
                    Documentation of individual businesses includes a number of bound business
                    volumes of Montgomery, Clothier &amp; Tyler, dating approximately from 1907 to
                    1920. These comprise firm accounts, customer accounts, ledgers, deposit ledgers,
                    and blotters. Additional records include: minutes of the Lehigh Valley Coal and
                    Oil Co. (1889-1902); a Beech Valley Coal and Iron Co. stock ledger; minutes of
                    the Radnor Development Company (1912-1923); Mary Binney Montgomery estate
                    account book, 1917; and scrip, check, and credit books from the [N.B. &amp; L.]
                    Railroad Co (all blank except for several scrips from 1836). The collection also
                    includes several volumes in German, labeled "Politischen comites der deutschen
                    gewerkschaften": minutes and receipts and expenditures (1866-1944).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Philadelphia Stock Exchange papers (coll. 3070).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>