<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rachel Dunaway Cox papers <date type="inclusive">1897-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rachel Dunaway Cox papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC719</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1897-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Rachel Dunaway Cox (1904-1996) was a professor of education and psychology at
                    Bryn Mawr College from 1944 to 1971. She was chair of the Department of
                    Education and Child Development and the director of the Child Study Institute. A
                    leader in the field of child development, she published studies focusing on
                    youth and young adults for academic publications, and occasionally also wrote
                    articles for popular magazines. Her husband, Reavis Cox (1900-1992), served on
                    the faculty of the University of Pennsylvania's Wharton School from
                    1935-1971.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains personal and a small amount of professional papers of
                    Rachel Dunaway Cox and Reavis Cox. Materials include: correspondence with family
                    (Dunaway and Cox families) and friends; Rachel Dunaway Cox's diaries from high
                    school, college, and later years; Reavis Cox diaries from 1922 and 1925; travel
                    journals and travel ephemera from trips to Europe and Asia; photographs;
                    greeting cards; school memorabilia of Rachel Dunaway Cox, and Rosemary and David
                    Cox; a published volume by Reavis Cox titled Distribution in a High-level
                    Economy; a small number of professional papers of Rachel Dunaway Cox, including
                    notes for research on adult personality; and several printed articles and drafts
                    of speeches.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 235</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Archives and Records Center: Reavis Cox papers; Bryn Mawr College:
                    Rachel Dunaway Cox papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>