<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Richard Bartlett Gregg papers <date type="inclusive">1930-1933</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Richard Bartlett Gregg papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC685</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1930-1933</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Richard Bartlett Gregg (1885-1974) was a social philosopher said to be America's
                    first major theorist of militant nonviolence. His theories influenced Martin
                    Luther King, Jr. and civil-rights theorist Bayard Rustin. Gregg traveled to
                    India in the 1920s to seek out Gandhi and learn about the Indian independence
                    movement. His publications include Gandhiji's Satyagraha or Non-violent
                    Resistance (1930) and The Power of Non-violence (1934). He also wrote The Value
                    of Voluntary Simplicity (1936).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains documentation related to civil disobedience in India,
                    1930-1933. Materials include: letters to Gregg from Mira Behn (Madeleine Slade)
                    reporting on her activities and those of Gandhi; letters from Gandhi, Nehru,
                    Roger Baldwin, Pyarelal Nair, and others; letters from Gregg to Gandhi, Roger
                    Baldwin, P. J. Nehru, and The Nation magazine; weekly reports from India,
                    summarizing Government acts and speeches, arrests, and civil disobedience
                    actions; reports related to the May 1932 Bombay riots; bulletins from the India
                    League and the International Committee for India describing events in the
                    country; and copies of the Bombay Congress Bulletin and the Bombay University
                    Bulletin.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 201</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Swarthmore College,
                    Peace Collection: Mohandas K. Gandhi papers (include letters written to Gregg by
                    Gandhi). </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>