<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert Milton Speer correspondence <date type="inclusive">1861-1872</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert Milton Speer correspondence</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC794</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1861-1872</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert Milton Speer (1838-1890) was a Democratic member of the U.S. House of
                    Representatives from Pennsylvania. He attended Cassville Academy, taught school,
                    studied law, and was admitted to the bar in 1859. He was elected assistant clerk
                    of the Pennsylvania State House of Representatives in 1863. Speer served in the
                    U.S. House of Representatives from 1871-1875. He was not a candidate for
                    renomination in 1874. He resumed the practice of law and in 1876 became one of
                    the proprietors of the Huntingdon Monitor. He was an unsuccessful candidate for
                    election in 1880 to the Forty-seventh Congress. His wife was Martha Ellen
                    McMurtrie.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of letters to Robert Milton Speer. The letters are from
                    clients and those seeking legal assistance, supporters of his political career,
                    and family members. Subjects include legal matters and the war; the 1868
                    presidential election; Speer's election to Congress and party politics; and
                    requests for legal aid or favors. The collection includes letters of E. S.
                    McMurtrie, D. E. McMurtrie, J. North, and C. C. North (E. S. McMurtrie was in
                    partnership with Speer; the McMurtries and Norths were Speer's in-laws). Letters
                    from family members regard family estate matters that Speer handled for them and
                    his political career and party politics.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 47</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Bryn Mawr College:
                    Speer family papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>