<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert Dechert papers regarding the ownership of the William Clark
                        papers <date type="inclusive">1956-1960</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert Dechert papers regarding the ownership of the
                    William Clark papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC356</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1956-1960</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert Dechert (1895-1975) was a Philadelphia lawyer and collector of rare books.
                    He gave his significant collection of Americana to the University of
                    Pennsylvania in 1962. The Clark papers (67 pieces) were found by Minnesota
                    Historical Society among the papers of General John H. Hammond. The U.S.
                    Government brought suit against the descendants of Hammond, claiming that the
                    records were government property.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of correspondence, legal documents, and reference
                    materials related to litigation in the U.S. District Court and U.S. Court of
                    Appeals regarding the ownership of the William Clark papers. The collection
                    includes copies of most of the briefs filed in the U.S. District Court and U.S.
                    Court of Appeals in connection with this litigation; clippings and articles
                    about the set of manuscripts and the case; and correspondence between Dechert
                    and various individuals interested in or involved with the case. The
                    correspondence traces Dechert's efforts to collect as much material about the
                    case as he could.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 133</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: American
                    Philosophical Society: Lewis and Clark Expedition Documents concerning the
                    William Clark Papers discovered in 1953; Yale University, Beinecke Rare Book and
                    Manuscript Library: William Clark Field Notes (WA MSS S-897). </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>