<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert Ernest Spiller papers <date type="inclusive">1914-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert Ernest Spiller papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC367</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>39.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1914-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert E. Spiller (1896-1988) was a scholar of American literary history. He was
                    educated at the University of Pennsylvania, receiving a bachelor's degree in
                    1917, a master's in 1921 and a Ph.D. in 1924. The majority of Robert Spiller’s
                    teaching career was spent at Penn, where he taught from 1920 to 1967. He was
                    also on the faculty of Swarthmore College from 1921 to 1945. Spiller wrote and
                    edited many books and articles, including Fenimore Cooper: Critic of His Times
                    (1931), The Collected Works of Ralph Waldo Emerson, and Milestones in American
                    Literary History (1977). He was one of the editors of the Literary History of
                    the United States series.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes materials related to Spiller's teaching, scholarship and
                    other professional and personal activities. Materials about research projects
                    include files on James Fenimore Cooper, including photostat copies of letters
                    from and about Cooper, photographs of people and places, a reel of film and
                    engravings; reprints by Spiller and others; and files on Ralph Waldo Emerson,
                    including minutes, correspondence, work schedules and timetables, drafts of
                    notes on Emerson's essays, and other research materials. Materials related to
                    the Literary History of the United States include minutes, correspondence,
                    outlines and instructions to authors, chapter drafts and proofs, bibliography,
                    financial records, publicity information and reviews. Materials related to
                    Spiller's teaching and scholarship include correspondence; manuscripts and
                    proofs of books, chapters, essays and addresses, including Late Harvest and
                    Milestones in American Literary History; reviews of his writings; and University
                    of Pennsylvania English Department records, including minutes, reports,
                    newsletters, bulletins, and some correspondence. There are also early writings
                    (plays, poetry, prose); letters to parents from school and from abroad,
                    1914-1929; postcards; family photographs; address books and appointment books;
                    an undated manuscript (appears to be 18th century) in a mixture of Latin and
                    Greek; a typescript of an interview with Spiller in 1983; and records of various
                    professional activities, including seminars and lectures abroad, MLA committees,
                    Guggenheim Fellowship, seminars at Swarthmore, American Council of Learned
                    Societies projects, and a Nobel symposium.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 142, 142A, 142B, 142C, 142D, 142E</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Delaware: Robert E. Spiller Collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>