<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rudolf Serkin papers <date type="inclusive">1922-1991</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rudolf Serkin papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC726</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>62 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1922-1991</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Rudolf Serkin (1903-1991) was a renowned pianist and teacher. He was born in
                    Bohemia and made his public debut at 12 with the Vienna Philharmonic. From 1918
                    to 1920 he studied composition with Arnold Schoenberg. Throughout the 1920s and
                    early 1930s he lived in Berlin and performed throughout Europe. With the rise of
                    the Nazi party, Serkin left Berlin for Switzerland. In 1935, he married Irene
                    Busch. In 1936 he launched his solo concert career in the U. S. with the New
                    York Philharmonic under Arturo Toscanini. Shortly after the onset of World War
                    II in 1939, the Serkins and the Busch family emigrated to the United States,
                    where Serkin joined the Curtis Institute of Music in Philadelphia as a piano
                    professor. From 1968 to 1976 he served as Director of the Curtis Institute. In
                    1951, Serkin and Adolf Busch founded the Marlboro Music School and Festival, and
                    Serkin served as its artistic director from 1952 to 1991. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of professional and personal paper of Rudolf Serkin. The
                    professional papers in the collection relate to his performing career as well as
                    his teaching and administrative work at the Curtis Institute of Music and the
                    Marlboro Festival. Materials related to Serkin's performing career include:
                    programs and reviews (1930s-1980s); correspondence with colleagues, program
                    organizers, fellow musicians, record companies, and fans; itineraries and tour
                    information; appointment calendars; royalty records; and publicity photos and
                    press releases. Curtis Institute materials include: correspondence from faculty,
                    students, and board members; schedules; memos about student and school matters;
                    budgets; programs; and a copy of a commencement speech by Serkin. Materials from
                    the Marlboro Festival include: correspondence; programs and schedules; planning
                    documents, budgets and financial reports; and applications and invitations to
                    perform at the Festival. There are also minutes and memos from professional and
                    cultural organizations with which Serkin was involved, including the American
                    Academy of Arts and Sciences. Among the correspondents in the collection are
                    cellist Pablo Casals, violist Alexander Schneider, violinist Adolf Busch,
                    artistic manager Arthur Judson, and recording executive Goddard Lieberson.
                    Personal papers include: correspondence from friends and family, including his
                    son Peter Serkin; drawings by Serkin's grandchildren; family snapshots; birthday
                    greetings; records related to his farm; household budgets; and financial
                    records. Some of the personal correspondence is in German.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 243</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>