<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Samuel Stehman Haldeman correspondence <date type="inclusive">1840-1880</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Samuel Stehman Haldeman correspondence</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC426</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1840-1880</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Samuel Stehman Haldeman (1812-1880) was an American naturalist and philologist.
                    In 1851 he was appointed Professor of the Natural Sciences at the University of
                    Pennsylvania. In 1855 he joined the faculty of Delaware College but in 1868, he
                    returned to the University of Pennsylvania as the first chair of its Comparative
                    Philology department, remaining at the University until his death. Haldeman
                    published and lectured on a variety of topics, including malacology,
                    orthography, geology, philology, and chemistry.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists primarily of Haldeman's correspondence, 1840-1880. Topics
                    include philology, phonography, ethnology, natural history, and archaeology.
                    Notable correspondents include William Wagner, Richard Owen, Noah Webster,
                    Melvil Dewey, and C. &amp; G. Merriam. The collection also includes invitations
                    to lectures at the University of Pennsylvania, and a small amount of
                    correspondence from the University relating to Haldeman's appointments to
                    professorships in Comparative Philology and Natural History.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 194</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>