<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sculley Bradley collection <date type="inclusive">1853-1973</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sculley Bradley collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC380</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1853-1973</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Sculley Bradley (b. 1897), was a professor of English and American Literature at
                    the University of Pennsylvania. With Gay Wilson Allen of New York University,
                    Bradley oversaw the editing of The Collected Works of Walt Whitman. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains correspondence and other items authored or collected by
                    Sculley Bradley. Materials related to Bradley's Critical Study of Whitman
                    include: notes, research materials (reprints, photographs, newspaper and
                    magazine clippings, postcards, and illustrations), and annotated galleys of
                    Leaves of grass: A Textual Variorum of the Printed Poems (New York University
                    Press, 1980). There is also a poster of a Whitman poem and several reprints of
                    the Long Islander Whitman anniversary page. The collection includes personal
                    correspondence between Sculley Bradley and James T. Farrell (1948-1959). There
                    is also correspondence largely related to Bradley's editorship of the General
                    Magazine and Historical Chronicle, regarding requests for articles and poems.
                    This section also includes some drafts of articles and poetry. Correspondents in
                    this section include Archibald MacLeish, James Thurber, John Dos Passos, and
                    David McCord. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 150</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>