<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sculley Bradley censorship files <date type="inclusive">1948-1967</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sculley Bradley censorship files</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC953</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1948-1967</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Edward Sculley Bradley (1919-1967) was a professor of English and American
                    Literature and a vice-provost at the University of Pennsylvania. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes documentation related to various censorship cases.
                    Materials include correspondence with Arthur Farmer of Stern and Reubens,
                    Attorneys, regarding the defense of Philadelphia booksellers for the sale of
                    God's Little Acre by Erskine Caldwell, Sanctuary and Wild Palms by William
                    Faulkner, and Studs Lonigan by James T. Farrell (1948-1950); correspondence with
                    Manuel Lee Robbins of Stern and Reubens with Bradley's comments and testimony in
                    the book trail of Find Me a River by Robert Lowry and Duke by Hal Ellson
                    (1950-1953); correspondence with Robbins with Bradley's comments and testimony
                    in the book trail of Find Me In Fire by Robert Lowry (1953-1954); correspondence
                    with Robbins with Bradley's comments and testimony in the book trail of Down All
                    Your Streets by Leonard Bishop (1953-1954); newspaper clippings and magazine
                    articles, correspondence and Bradley's notes related to the book trials of
                    Tropic of Cancer by Henry Miller (1962) and the conviction of Eros magazine
                    publisher Ralph Ginzberg (1966); and a 1948 Judge Bok decision on the
                    Philadelphia booksellers case.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 88</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>