<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sinhalese book manuscripts <date type="inclusive">1640-1925</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sinhalese book manuscripts</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC393</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1640-1925</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Items donated by Dr. Casey A. Wood (1856-1942), founder of the Library of
                    Ornithology at McGill University and collector of manuscripts, W. W. Hyde of the
                    University of Pennsylvania, and Dr. James B. Thompson.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of ola leaf books (palm leaf pages with wooden covers) and
                    other artifacts. Items in the collection include: a 17th century ola on diseases
                    and their treatments in Pali-Sinhalese; a 1905 ola of stories and fables about
                    Shiva in Tamil; part of a treatise on arithmetic, undated; a fragment of a Pali
                    (Buddhist) manuscript on strips of palm leaves (unbound); and a typed
                    description of ola leaf books and how they are made. The collection also
                    includes: fragments of biblical text in Hebrew on vellum or parchment, undated;
                    fragments from Exodus, Genesis, and Deuteronomy; a small accordion palm leaf
                    volume, undated (unidentified script); accordion paper text in an unidentified
                    script, undated; and a large leather roll with ink script (possibly Hebrew) and
                    a wooden scroll handle.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 163 and 163A</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, South Asia Collection: Penniman-Gribbel collection of Sanskrit
                    Manuscripts (includes some Singhalese).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>