<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sophia Mumford papers <date type="inclusive">1892-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sophia Mumford papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC737</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>20 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1892-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Sophia Wittenberg Mumford (1899-1997) was the wife and sometime editor of the
                    critic and historian Lewis Mumford. Sophia Wittenberg, went to work after high
                    school as a secretary and then became an editor at The Dial, where she met Lewis
                    Mumford. After her marriage in 1921, Mrs. Mumford gave up a budding career as an
                    editor to help further her husband's literary and academic aspirations. The
                    couple had two children: Geddes Mumford (1925-1944) and Alison Mumford Morss
                    (1935-1993).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Sophia and Lewis Mumford, consisting of family
                    papers of the Mumford and Wittenberg families and some works by and about Lewis
                    Mumford. Family papers include: correspondence between Lewis Mumford and his
                    mother, between Lewis and Sophia Mumford, from Geddes Mumford to his family and
                    others, and between the Mumfords and Evelyn Huber; letters of William Wittenberg
                    (Sophia's father); and letters of condolence to Sophia Mumford on the death of
                    her husband. There are also several albums of photographs of the Mumford and
                    Wittenberg families; daybooks of E. C. Mumford (1892-1895), primarily consisting
                    of menus; and diaries of Sophia Mumford kept between 1961 and 1980. Materials
                    related to Lewis Mumford's work include manuscript drafts of several books:
                    Green Memories, Findings and Keepings, The Bridge, and The Mumford-Leibovitz
                    Letters. This section of the collection also includes Mumford's personal notes
                    on his mother, daughter, and son; and reprints and clippings of articles on
                    architecture, urbanism, atomic power, fascism, and many other subjects. There
                    are also photographs and lantern slides of cities and buildings in Europe and
                    the US; and several maps and city plans. The collection also contains papers
                    concerning the Lewis Mumford centennial commemoration and documentation related
                    to the disposition of and access to the Mumford papers, including Sophia
                    Mumford's correspondence with biographer Donald Miller and with University of
                    Pennsylvania librarians. Other materials in the collection include a manuscript
                    on architecture by Carl Ludwig Franck; newspaper clippings about Lewis Mumford;
                    and audio cassettes and 16' vinyl recordings of readings of Mumford's works
                    (read by Mumford and by others). </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 259</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library: Lewis Mumford papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>