<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Telegraph Books collection <date type="inclusive">1970-1972</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Telegraph Books collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC408</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Victor Bockris (b.1949) is an English-born, U.S.-based author, primarily of
                    biographies of artists, writers, and musicians. He graduated from the University
                    of Pennsylvania in 1971. While in Philadelphia, he founded Telegraph Books. He
                    moved to New York City in 1973 and became an associate of Warhol and Burroughs.
                    He worked for Warhol at the Factory and published many pieces in Warhol's
                    magazine Interview, often in collaboration with Andrew Wylie, now best known as
                    a literary agent. He has written about Lou Reed (and The Velvet Underground),
                    Andy Warhol, Keith Richards, William S. Burroughs, Terry Southern, Blondie,
                    Patti Smith, and Muhammad Ali. He also helped write the autobiographies of John
                    Cale and Bebe Buell.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers related to Telegraph Books. Materials include:
                    typed manuscripts with annotations and published volumes including The Rest by
                    Aram Saroyan, Seventh Heaven by Patti Smith, Cars by Brigid Polk, and Thumbprint
                    by Tom Weatherly; taped interviews with Andrew Wylie, Lee Harwood, and Patti
                    Smith, including transcriptions; correspondence with authors including Andrew
                    Wylie and Aram Saroyan; correspondence regarding orders and publications. The
                    collection also includes magazines, newspapers, flyers, and several photographs
                    of authors.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 177</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library: Victor Bockris collection; The
                    University of Texas at Austin, Harry Ransom Center: Victor Bockris and Andrew
                    Wylie Collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>