<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas S. Gates, Sr., papers <date type="inclusive">1835-1950</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1927-1950</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas S. Gates, Sr., papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC387</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1835-1950</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1927-1950</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas Sovereign Gates (1873-1948) was an American investment banker and
                    educator. He was the president of the University of Pennsylvania from 1930 until
                    1944, and was the father of United States Secretary of Defense Thomas S. Gates,
                    Jr. Born in Philadelphia, Gates was a student at University of Pennsylvania.
                    Prior to his election as university president, Gates had served for ten years as
                    a Trustee of the University and as Chairman of the University of Pennsylvania
                    Fund.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of scrapbooks of newspaper clippings, correspondence,
                    invitations, photographs, and speeches relating to the career of Thomas S. Gates
                    in business and as president and trustee of the University of Pennsylvania. The
                    scrapbooks also includes early family records, such as photographs, school
                    records and an 1835 printed address by Thomas Sovereign. The collection also
                    includes two bound memorials to Gates from the American Philosophical Society
                    and the University of Pennsylvania.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 156</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>