<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas S. Gates, Jr., papers <date type="inclusive">1902-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas S. Gates, Jr., papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC748</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1902-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas Gates, Jr., (1906-1983) served in several positions in the U.S. government
                    over his long career. He was Secretary of the Navy from 1957-1959 and Secretary
                    of Defense from 1959-1961. He was ambassador to China from 1976-1977. His
                    father, Thomas S. Gates, Sr., was President of the University of Pennsylvania
                    from 1930-1944.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains materials related to Gates's military and government
                    service, as well as his other professional and personal activities. Materials
                    include: night order books and other log books related to naval operations
                    during World War II; correspondence, including letters from Eisenhower;
                    appointment books and call logs; numerous awards, citations, medals from army,
                    government and diplomatic service; materials related to Gates's assignment to
                    China; and albums that include family photographs, photographs from military
                    service, and mementos given to Gates during trips to various countries.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 269</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>