<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas Forster papers <date type="inclusive">1793-1837</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas Forster papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC747</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1793-1837</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Colonel Thomas Forster (1762-1836) was agent of Erie County for the Harrisburg
                    and Presque Isle Land Company, collector for the Port of Erie from 1799 to 1836,
                    and government agent for the construction of the breakwater in Erie harbor.
                    Forster led a volunteer regiment during the Whiskey Insurrection was was the
                    first surveyor of the City of Erie.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Thomas Forster. Materials include: account
                    books; bills and receipts; check registers; articles of agreement and
                    indentures; summaries of legal cases; and correspondence largely related to
                    financial matters and to the Port of Erie and the Erie and Waterford Turnpike.
                    The collection also includes recent handwritten transcripts of many of the
                    documents in the collection. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 268</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Pennsylvania State
                    Archives: Thomas Forster Collection, 1799-1825 (manuscript group 51).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>