<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas Lask papers <date type="inclusive">1910-1979</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas Lask papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC396</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1979</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas Lask was the poetry editor of the New York Times.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists primarily of correspondence with poets and editors about
                    reviews of volumes of poetry in the New York Times and submission of poems for
                    inclusion in the paper. Notable correspondents include Delmore Schwartz, Allen
                    Ginsberg, Henry Miller, Tambimuttu, Richard Aldridge, and I. A. Richards.
                    Letters from contributors (or would-be contributors) are often unaccompanied by
                    copies of the submitted poems. The collection does include copies of a
                    manuscript by Joseph Brodsky, several printed volumes by Jonathan Williams, and
                    manuscript and typescript poems by a number of other poets. The collection also
                    includes a small batch of letters from Edwin Arlington Robinson to J. Edith
                    Monahan at Macmillan, from 1929-1931, and several biographical and memorial
                    booklets on Robinson. There are also photographs of Charles Reznikoff and his
                    family.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 166</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>