<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thorsten Sellin papers <date type="inclusive">1792-1985</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1920s-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thorsten Sellin papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC2266</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>30.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1792-1985</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1920s-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thorsten Sellin (1896-1994) was a sociologist and one of the pioneers of
                    scientific criminology. He came to prominence in the 1920s and 1930s for his
                    studies in the use of criminal statistics at local, state, national and
                    international levels, and helped draft the U.S. Uniform Criminal Statistics Act
                    in 1944. He received his master's and doctoral degrees from the University of
                    Pennsylvania. He taught at Penn from 1922-1967 and served as chair of the
                    sociology department from 1944-1959. His books include Culture Conflict and
                    Crime (1938) and The Death Penalty (1959).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Thorsten Sellin. Materials include
                    correspondence with colleagues, publishers, and professional organizations;
                    handwritten and typed manuscripts of articles and books, including Slavery and
                    the Penal Code, The Death Penalty, and Crime and Treatment in the Legislation of
                    1932; addresses and remarks; writings by other criminologists; minutes, notes,
                    and reports of a number of professional organizations, including the
                    International Association of Penal Law, the International Society of
                    Criminology, and the Institute for Research on Crime and Delinquency; and
                    reprints and pamphlets on prisons, delinquency, capital punishment, and many
                    related topics. The collection also includes a small batch of correspondence of
                    Amy J. Sellin; memorabilia, including photographs, cabinet cards, and ephemera
                    from the opening of the Sellin Center in 1985; certificates and plaques; and a
                    framed 1792 broadside in German. There are materials in Swedish, German,
                    Italian, French, and Spanish.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>