<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Vera Dreiser papers <date type="inclusive">1895-1960</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Vera Dreiser papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC698</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1895-1960</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Vera Dreiser (1908-1998) was a psychologist and the niece of author Theodore
                    Dreiser. Vera Dreiser had a clinical psychology practice, and from 1962 to 1966
                    she was staff psychologist of the California Institution for Women. In 1976 she
                    co-authored, with Brett Howard, a book about her uncle entitled My Uncle
                    Theodore.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Dreiser family papers and memorabilia and professional
                    papers of Vera Dreiser. The bulk of the collection consists of papers relating
                    to the literary estate of Theodore Dreiser. These include correspondence with
                    publishers and agents related to contracts, royalties, and US and foreign
                    literary rights; royalty statements and contracts. Also included is
                    correspondence of Helen Dreiser and her sister Myrtle Butcher regarding the
                    estate. There are also some records relating to rights to compositions by
                    Theodore Dreiser's brother, the composer Paul Dresser. Family papers and
                    ephemera include: letters to Vera Dreiser from Myrtle Butcher, Helen Dreiser,
                    James T. Farrell, Shailer Lawton; and from other family members and friends; a
                    scrapbook of clippings about Edward Dreiser; a baby book for Vera Dreiser and
                    her daughter Sheri Dreiser Scott; a souvenir book of Paul Dresser's compositions
                    (1895-1898); locks of hair from several members of the Dreiser family (including
                    Vera, Helen, Mai, and Sheri); and two plaster busts of Theodore Dreiser. Vera
                    Dreiser's professional papers include files related to Vera Dreiser's clinical
                    psychology practice, patient files and appointment books (1956-1959).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 213</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library: Theodore Dreiser papers; Emory
                    University: Theodore Dreiser collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>