<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Walter Hart Blumenthal collection <date type="inclusive">1899-1960</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Walter Hart Blumenthal collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC703</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1899-1960</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Walter H. Blumenthal (1883-1969) was a historian whose subjects included the
                    American colonial and revolutionary periods, Native Americans, bibliomania, and
                    Shakespeare authorship. He received his bachelor's degree from the University of
                    Pennsylvania in 1903. His published works include Women Camp Followers of the
                    American Revolution, Paging Mr. Shakespeare, and In Old America: Random Chapters
                    on the Early Aborigines.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Walter H. Blumenthal. Materials include a
                    notebook containing Blumenthal's entrance examination to the University of
                    Pennsylvania on the subject of Greek and Roman history, 1899, with maps and a
                    plan; a binder of typescripts of poetry entitled "Exit Laughing"; a
                    bibliography of Blumenthal's early writings (1919-1938); a collection of
                    typescript stories, lightly annotated, with a preface by Louis Golding, circa
                    1930; photostats of a catalog of the sale of the Stowe collection (including a
                    Shakespeare portrait); a copy of "Spurious Shakespeare Portraiture," an
                    article by Blumenthal, reprinted from The American Book Collector, 1960; and
                    negatives and photographs of prints, paintings, and sculptures of
                    Shakespeare.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 217</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: American Jewish
                    Historical Society: Walter Blumenthal papers (P-83).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>