<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wharton School Industrial Research Unit collection on International
                        Trade Secretariats <date type="inclusive">1971-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wharton School Industrial Research Unit collection on
                    International Trade Secretariats</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC729</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>17.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Industrial Research Unit of the Wharton School of the University of
                    Pennsylvania was founded in 1921 with a mission to "study the economic and
                    social problems of business." From its inception to World War II, the
                    Department attracted worldwide attention for its pioneering studies of
                    industrial relations. The department contributes articles to professional
                    industrial relations and legal journals around the world, and it publishes book
                    on labor relations, human resources, and employment policy. In the mid 1970s,
                    the Unit formed the Multinational Research Advisory Group. In 1990, the
                    institution was renamed "The Center for Human Resources". The present center
                    is focused on the study of human resources and labor and personnel management.
                </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of information on various national and international trade
                    federations compiled by the Wharton School Industrial Research Unit between the
                    1970s and 1990s. Materials include: newsletters, bulletins, reports, policy
                    statements, press releases, and memoranda from the trade federations.
                    Federations represented in the collection include: International Transport
                    Workers Federation (ITF); International Confederation of Free Trade Unions
                    (ICFTU); International Federation of Chemical, Energy and General Workers Unions
                    (ICEF), International Metalworkers Federation. The collection also includes
                    newspaper clippings and photocopies of clippings and articles about trade
                    unions; and correspondence between faculty of the Industrial Research Unit and
                    members of various trade union federations. Some materials are in German,
                    French, and Spanish. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 245</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Archives and Records Center: Wharton School Industrial Research
                    Unit Records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>