<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William M. Calder collection <date type="inclusive">1975-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William M. Calder collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC711</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William M. Calder III is a professor of classics and comparative literature at
                    the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign and an author of numerous books.
                    Calder received his Bachelor's and Master's degrees from Harvard and his Ph.D.
                    from the University of Chicago. Calder has edited or co-edited a bibliography
                    and several volumes of letters of Ulrich von Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, a noted
                    scholar of ancient Greece and its literature.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of William M. Calder, III. Materials include:
                    reprints by Calder and others on Ulrich von Wilamowitz-Moellendorff; photocopies
                    of Wilamowitz correspondence with Max Fränkel and others, some with
                    transcriptions (in German); and correspondence with colleagues, much of it
                    related to Wilamowitz.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 228</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>