<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William Norman Brown collection <date type="inclusive">1891-1982</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1930s-1960s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William Norman Brown collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC392</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1891-1982</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1930s-1960s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Norman Brown (1892-1975) founded the South Asia Studies department at the
                    University of Pennsylvania, the first in the United States, in 1948. From 1916
                    to 1919 Brown held the position of the Harrison Research Fellow at the Penn.
                    After holding positions at Johns Hopkins and Prince of Wales College in Jammu,
                    India, he returned to Penn to accept the chair of Sanskrit. He then steadily
                    expanded South Asia educational offerings at the Penn, resulting in a full South
                    Asia Studies department. He also organized the American Oriental Society in
                    1926.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of South Asia-related materials created or collected by
                    William Norman Brown. Materials include: manuscripts of articles and addresses
                    on Indian politics, religion, language, and art; photographs and negatives of
                    Sanskrit texts and illustrated manuscripts; photographs of W. Norman Brown;
                    notes on South Asian linguistics and vocabulary; and notes on miscellaneous
                    South Asian subjects. There is a small amount of correspondence with colleagues
                    and publishers, including some letters from Ananda K. Coomaraswamy. There are
                    also manuscript and typescript drafts of articles on U.S. foreign policy,
                    possibly by Charles Henry Burr, a 1891 copy of Poet-Lore including an article by
                    Burr, and two photographs, possibly of Burr.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 162</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Archives and Records Center: W. Norman Brown Papers (UPT
                    50/B879).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>