<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wistar and Horner Museum records <date type="inclusive">1822-1864</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1840s-1850s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wistar and Horner Museum records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC754</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1822-1864</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1840s-1850s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Edmonds Horner (1793-1853) was Dean of the Medical Faculty and a
                    professor of anatomy at the University of Pennsylvania. He was also curator of
                    the Wistar Museum, appointed by Caspar Wistar in 1818. Horner and Wistar's
                    collections were combined to form the Wistar and Horner Museum. The Wistar and
                    Horner Museum collections were further expanded under the curation of Dr. Joseph
                    Leidy, who acquired animal specimens as well as fossil and anthropological
                    samples. The collections were transferred from the University of Pennsylvania to
                    the Wistar Institute of Anatomy and Biology, established by Isaac Wistar, in
                    1892.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of volumes and papers related to the Wistar and Horner
                    Museum. Materials include: printed catalogs of the museum's specimens, one with
                    manuscript annotations by Horner; reports on additions to the collection by
                    Joseph Leidy; a manuscript list of additions to the museum's collection (1855);
                    correspondence to Leidy from Caldwell K. Biddle, secretary and treasurer of the
                    University's Board of Trustees, regarding the finances of the museum; receipts
                    for museum purchases and receipts for wages paid to museum staff; museum
                    accounts kept by Horner, and later Leidy (1822-1854); Horner's lists of rules
                    for Demonstrators in the Department of Anatomy; agreements between Leidy and
                    Horner regarding Leidy's position as Horner's private assistant and as the
                    curator of the museum (1845 and 1847); a dissecting class book, 1849-1864,
                    listing students and their home states.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 28</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>