<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>AIDS Library of Philadelphia records <date type="inclusive">1987-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Urban Archives</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">AIDS Library of Philadelphia records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC322</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Urban Archives<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>36 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1987-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The AIDS Library of Philadelphia serves the community through delivery of
                    information on HIV, such as treatments, nutrition, and history of the pandemic,
                    and referrals to regional and national resources. This information is provided
                    through a variety of media including books, periodicals, medical journals,
                    videos, audio cassettes, CD-ROM, and the Internet. In addition, the AIDS Library
                    regularly hosts events on HIV related issues. The mission of the AIDS Library is
                    to improve access to health and support services, prevent HIV transmission, and
                    raise the public awareness of HIV/AIDS related issues.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records and reference materials of the AIDS Library/AIDS
                    Information Network. Office records include: correspondence and memos; financial
                    information; board minutes; budget, fundraising, and development records; office
                    policies and guidelines; volunteer records; and some personnel files. Reference
                    materials include: newspaper clippings; magazines containing stories about
                    HIV/AIDS; newsletters from a variety of health and activist organizations,
                    including AIDS Treatment News, We The People, and AIDS Insurance News; programs
                    and other materials from international and national AIDS conferences; treatment,
                    research, and resource guides for people with HIV/AIDS; brochures, pamphlets,
                    and flyers from a number of AIDS organizations; audiovisual resources on AIDS
                    treatment, caregiving, and research, including audiocassettes, vinyl LPs, CDs
                    and DVDs; and artifacts, including buttons, t-shirts, and condoms. The
                    collection contains records of Jenny Pierce, Jean Hofacket, and Dominick
                    D'Ortenzio.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1048</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>