<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Andrew McKay papers <date type="inclusive">1935-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Andrew McKay papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2240</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>16.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1935-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Andrew (Andy) McKay worked in radio and the early years of television, including
                    with Ernie Kovacs.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of film and television broadcast-related materials assembled
                    by Andrew McKay. Items in the collection include: actor files consisting of
                    newspaper and magazine articles and images, movie advertisements, filmographies
                    and film synopses, and programs of film series at museums and universities;
                    correspondence with other collectors and film and broadcast publications,
                    organizations, and distributors, as well as individuals involved in the film
                    industry; photos of film sets, stars, and directors; programs from the MoMA and
                    Theodore Huff Memorial Film Society; files on television personalities, in
                    particular; clippings and stills from the Mike Douglas Show; letters to Mildred
                    Martin, film editor at the Philadelphia Inquirer from various stars and other
                    people in the film industry; lists and indices of McKay's film attendance; an
                    index file of movie industry figures and collectors; film catalogues; and a
                    small amount of information related to McKay's career in entertainment.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>