<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Arnold Snyder papers <date type="inclusive">1953-1964</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Arnold Snyder papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2085</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>69.76 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953-1964</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Arnold Snyder was born in Philadelphia and attended Temple University, preparing
                    for a career in journalism. Snyder worked as a news writer and producer at WTTM,
                    ABC radio in Trenton, N.J., before joining ABC-TV News in 1955. Snyder covered
                    the major news events of the 1960s and 1970s, and went on to design and
                    implement STAIRS (Storage, Tracking, and lnformation Retrieval System), a system
                    for organizing and accessing news footage on videotape.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of this prominent news broadcaster are comprised primarily of
                    videotapes, but also include correspondence, typescripts, news releases, and
                    reports. The typescripts for a news show, "It Looks To Me," come primarily
                    from 1953-1954 when Snyder worked for WTTM Radio in Trenton, N.J. The
                    correspondence and press releases reflect Snyder's interest in politics, which
                    includes press materials from the 1964 Democratic Convention. The collection
                    also contains 426 3/4-inch videotapes from network news shows such as Nightline
                    and PBS shows such as Nova, Frontline, and Bill Moyers Journal, 1981-1986. There
                    is a videotape explaining STAIRS (Storage Text &amp; Information Retrieval
                    Systems), a library system initiated by Snyder for ABC News. The collection does
                    not contain many materials associated with Snyder's prominent television career.
                    The typescripts of Snyder's radio broadcasts focus on New Jersey politics and
                    Cold War politics.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>