<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Arthur Hall papers <date type="inclusive">1955-1983</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Arthur Hall papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2263</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1955-1983</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Arthur Hall (1934-2000) was an internationally known dancer and choreographer. He
                    founded the Afro-American Dance Ensemble in Philadelphia in 1958, and was its
                    artistic director for thirty years. He also founded the Ile Ife Black
                    Humanitarian Center on Germantown Avenue in 1968. He was a movement specialist
                    for the National Endowment for the Arts and an instructor of dance at Dartmouth
                    College. Hall's major works include his direction of the ballet Orpheus, A City
                    Called Heaven, Aida, Fat Tuesday &amp; All That Jazz, and Eulogy for John
                    Coltrane, which was staged at Dartmouth College, where he was an adjunct
                    professor. He also choreographed What's Going On, a ballet set to the music of
                    Marvin Gaye. Late in his life, Arthur Hall moved to Camden, Maine, where founded
                    and served as the artistic director of Ile Ife Films and the Arthur Hall
                    Collection and International Dance Center.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a small collection of materials related to Arthur Hall's career as a
                    dancer and to his Afro-American Dance Ensemble. Materials include: a scrapbook
                    of correspondence, press releases, and programs (1969-1972); an album of
                    photographs of Hall and other dancers, primarily from the mid-1950s; catalogs
                    and brochures related to the arts in Philadelphia; articles about Hall and the
                    Afro-American Dance Ensemble; copies of Dance Magazine Annual from 1975 and
                    1977; newsletters of the Ile Ife Center for the Arts and Humanities (1976-1977);
                    and playbills and posters.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Arthur Hall Afro-American Dance Ensemble.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">African American dancers.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Dance companies--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photograph albums</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Ile Ife Foundation:
                    Arthur Hall Collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>