<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Beck Engraving Company records <date type="inclusive">1892-1957</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Beck Engraving Company records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2243</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1892-1957</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Beck Engraving, inc. gained a national reputation for four color plate printing,
                    the Bassani Halftone process, and became one of the first sheet-fed gravure
                    plants in the U.S. Beck Engraving was incorporated in 1898 and the company
                    expanded its operations to New York City in 1910.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The records of this New York/Philadelphia fine art printing firm span most of the
                    20th century documenting the evolution of the business over time through ledgers
                    (1902-1957), cash journals, insurance records, inventories and appraisals, audit
                    reports, production reports, leases and contracts, tax returns and reports,
                    pasteups, photographs of plant facilities and personnel, negatives, promotional
                    materials, in-house mechanicals, block prints from Guatemalan artist, Carlos
                    Sierra Franco, color prints of the work of Jules Guerin, and a group of 40
                    French woodcuts published by H.C. Perleberg of Philadelphia. There is a small
                    amount of correspondence from Charles W. Beck, Jr. and financial records from
                    the Fidelity Appraisal Co., Penn Process Co., Inc., and Wolf and Company. An
                    addition to the collection consists primarily of 20 copper printing
                    plates--depicting early 19th cent. American battleships--and a box of early
                    correspondence regarding the predecessor company, Philadelphia Photo-Engraving
                    Co.; some company literature; and some photographs of the engraving-printing
                    facilities.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>