<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Bernard C. Carlitz bookselling archives <date type="inclusive">1946-1988</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Bernard C. Carlitz bookselling archives</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2054</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1946-1988</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Bernard Conwell Carlitz was a Philadelphia rare bookseller who served as
                    president of the Antiquarian Booksellers of Philadelphia during the 1950s.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of this Philadelphia rare book dealer include invoices, receipts,
                    ledgers, tax returns, a poster, three wooden advertising signs, an oil painting
                    by Carolyn Fiedler, and a small amount of correspondence. These materials
                    document business transactions conducted, from a number of Center City
                    locations, by this Philadelphia book dealer over a forty year period. The
                    financial records document business relationships with other book dealers and
                    auctioneers during this time. There is an addition to this collection which
                    includes a publishing contract between Prime Press and Herschel Levit and a
                    pamphlet highlighting Levit's work, as well as some scattered files from the
                    Antiquarian Booksellers of Philadelphia, an organization which Carlitz led
                    during the 1950s. These materials include an organizational constitution, a
                    number of their auction catalogs, and some notes and clippings pertaining to an
                    exhibit of the organization put up during 1956. Additionally the collection
                    contains several photographs of Carlitz.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>