<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Boris Blai personal papers <date type="inclusive">1915-1983</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Boris Blai personal papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2050</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1915-1983</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Boris Blai was born in Rovno, Russia in 1893 and learned sculpture studying with
                    Auguste Rodin in Paris. In 1917 Blai immigrated to the U.S. and he taught art at
                    the Oak Lane Country Day School, an affiliate of Temple University. In 1935 Blai
                    founded the Tyler School of Art located on the estate of Stella Elkins Tyler, a
                    former student of his. During his 25 year tenure as Dean of Tyler Art School
                    Blai created numerous sculptures and expanded upon his philosophy of art as an
                    antidote for neuroses.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of this prominent American sculptor and art educator document both
                    Blai's personal life and his relationship with five different schools: the Long
                    Beach Island Foundation of the Arts, the Boris Blai College of Contemporary
                    Arts, Florida Southern College, Ocean County College, and Glassboro State
                    College. The materials associated with these institutions includes minutes,
                    press releases, course descriptions, and photographs. Blai's personal papers
                    include correspondence, catalogs (exhibition), clippings, certificates, awards,
                    handbills, postcards, telegrams, posters, sketches, and scrapbooks. The
                    collection also contains materials relating to Blai's association with the Oak
                    Lane Country Day School, the Tyler School of Art, and his early years in France.
                    Prominent correspondents include R. Tait McKenzie and Stella Elkins Tyler.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>