<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Bread and Roses Community Fund records <date type="inclusive">1971-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Urban Archives</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Bread and Roses Community Fund records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2332</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Urban Archives<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>52 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The People's Fund was founded in 1970 to raise money for Philadelphia area groups
                    working for progressive social change. In 1977 the organization established the
                    Bread &amp; Roses Community Fund as a nonprofit tax-exempt community fund. Bread
                    &amp; Roses raises money from individuals to provide grants, technical
                    assistance and leadership development to support community-based organizations
                    in the Delaware Valley that are taking collective action to bring about social
                    change. For fundraising, Bread and Roses conducts direct mail solicitations of
                    individual contributions and organizes fundraising events.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains documentation related to various grant programs of the
                    People's Fund and Bread and Roses, as well as organizational records and
                    research files. Grant programs represented in the collection include Community
                    Funding Board grants (1980-1994), Donor Advised grants (1977-1994), Emergency
                    grants (1984-1989), and Discretionary grants (1986-1987). Grant files include
                    accepted and rejected grant applications, contact information, grant agreements,
                    reports, and supporting materials, such as newsletters, brochures, and meeting
                    minutes from the grantee organizations. Other organizational records include:
                    annual meeting minutes, 1978-1993; minutes, reports, and memoranda from the
                    steering committee, selection committee, campaign committee, and other
                    committees; press releases; planning files for special events; and printed
                    material, including brochures, newsletters, pamphlets, appeal letters, and
                    progress reports. There are also research files on socially responsible
                    investing, 1979-1990, including newsletters, brochures, studies, articles,
                    directories, and prospectuses.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>