<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Cross-town Expressway records <date type="inclusive">undated</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Urban Archives</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Cross-town Expressway records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC1169</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Urban Archives<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent> linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>see http://www.phillyroads.com/roads/crosstown/ Plans for the Crosstown
                    Expressway were devised as early as 1930, when the Philadelphia City Planning
                    Commission made references to a Center City "ring road" that would provide for
                    smoother traffic flow. While specific mention was made in this report of a route
                    along Vine Street, no specific mention was made of the route south of the
                    central business district. In 1947, Robert B. Mitchell, the executive director
                    of the Philadelphia City Planning Commission, recommended the construction of a
                    Center City highway loop as one of the elements for a restructured city. The
                    Crosstown Expressway was to be the southern part of the Center City loop that
                    also comprised of the Schuylkill Expressway (I-76), the Delaware Expressway
                    (I-95) and the Vine Street Expressway (I-676). At the time, the proposed Center
                    City highway loop was designed to solve not only chronic congestion, but also
                    the threatened obsolescence of the business center. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p/>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 976</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>