<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>David Weiss-Stymean Karlen papers <date type="inclusive">1949-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">David Weiss-Stymean Karlen papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2093</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>92.58 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1949-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>David Weiss was born in Philadelphia and graduated from Temple University before
                    embarking on a literary career which has produced a number of successful
                    historical novels. Weiss' novel, Naked Came I, has been published in 13 editions
                    and 25 languages. Weiss also wrote fictional biographies of Mozart, Isadora
                    Duncan, and Christopher Wren. For a dozen years Weiss collaborated with David O.
                    Selznick on screen treatments. A Philadelphia native, Stymean Karlen moved to
                    New York in the 1930s where her plays For This Relief Much Thanks and The
                    Eleventh Commandment brought her to the attention of Cheryl Crawford (The Group
                    Theater), Clifford Odets, and John Gassner. With their encouragement and support
                    she enrolled in The Group Theater, shared an American Theater Play Contest
                    selection with Langston Hughes, and was awarded a Rockefeller Grant for writing.
                    Her interest eventually turned more to painting and poetry, interests she
                    combined in creating over 2000 "portrait poems." She successfully held
                    exhibitions in New York, Los Angeles, La Jolla among other centers. Her poetry
                    was published in Voices, The Yale Poetry Review, Beloit Journal, The Westminster
                    Review, and Poetry among others, as was also an essential part of many of the
                    historical novels of her husband, David Weiss. Karlen and Weiss were married for
                    53 years.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>David Weiss materials include extensive typescripts of manuscripts by Weiss, some
                    heavily annotated. Manuscripts include Tender Loving Care, I, Rembrandt, Guilt
                    Maker, Sacred and Profane, Forever &amp; After, Juliet's War, Picasso, Letters
                    to the World, Isadora Duncan, the Loves of Alma Maria. The collection also
                    includes: notes for his Mozart novels; galley proofs, typed lists of
                    corrections, and author's comments; correspondence with publishers and agents,
                    often with reader's comments on the works; personal correspondence, including
                    several letters from Anthony Quinn; financial and legal records, including
                    royalty statements, contracts, and story options; clippings of reviews and
                    advertisements for Weiss's books; and reader's reports by Weiss and others for
                    the Selznick Co. Stymean Karlen materials include: numerous illustrated
                    "portrait poems" on paper and Bainbridge board; paintings on board in wood
                    frames; typescripts of plays, poems, and novels; and a small number of letters
                    from staff at Temple University Special Collections about the receipt of donated
                    papers and the online exhibit of Karlen's artwork. The collection also includes
                    a plaster bust, possibly of David Weiss or his father.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>