<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>David Spector papers <date type="inclusive">1959-1976</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1969-1976</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">David Spector papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2242</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1959-1976</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1969-1976</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>David Spector was a student activist who graduated from the University of
                    Pennsylvania in 1974.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of a late 1960s University of Pennsylvania political activist
                    including correspondence, interviews, notes, manuscripts, newspaper clippings,
                    periodicals, and audio tapes. Much of the material focuses on a dispute between
                    Spector and the university administration over political organizing. Prominent
                    correspondents include Howard Lesnich and Martin Meyerson. Temple University
                    holds other collections concerning American social/political activism,
                    1960-1985. The collection includes community newspapers, printed material and
                    background information, including the West Philly Grafffiti Sheet, Community,
                    University City News, Spruce Hill Community Association, and West Philadelphia
                    Corporation. There are also University of Pennsylvania administration and
                    student publications and reports, including copies of the Daily Pennsylvanian,
                    Almanac and Disorientation, a report of the Task Force on University Governance
                    (1970), course guides, endowment and annual giving reports, and trustee lists.
                    The collection includes materials related to housing and neighborhood
                    development for West Philadelphia and University City, including the planned
                    construction of the University Hilton hotel. The Community Involvement Council
                    at Penn is the main organizing body for activities around these issues, and
                    files include reports, memos and statements, legal papers, correspondence, news
                    coverage and handwritten notes from Spector. Among other documents relating to
                    Philadelphia residents' response to the Vietnam War is a document is titled the
                    "Penn Papers," produced by the Schuylkill River Express. There are also a
                    number of books and pamphlets related to American foreign policy.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>