<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Dennis Barone papers <date type="inclusive">1966-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Dennis Barone papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2233</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1966-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dennis Barone -- educator, writer and editor -- was born in New Jersey and
                    educated at Bard College and the Univ. of Pennsylvania, receiving his Ph.D. in
                    1984. He taught at various colleges and was appointed Asst. Prof. of English and
                    American Studies at St. Joseph College in 1986. He founded Tamarisk Press in
                    1975 and edited it until 1985. He then served on the editorial board of
                    Confrontation, 1985/86. Barone has published several volumes of poetry/fiction
                    including Echo of the imperfect (1982); The house of land (1986) and Code
                    (1989). He has also published essays on American literature in academic
                    journals.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Personal papers of Pennsylvania writer/editor and the archives of the Tamarisk
                    Press. Papers include both personal and professional letters as well as
                    published and unpublished manuscripts of poems, stories, plays, and essays.
                    Complete drafts of The emblem of form and The house of land. Drafts of essays
                    for an anthology on Paul Auster which Barone edited. Numerous letters written to
                    Barone from students, editors and colleagues/friends. Correspondents include
                    Toby Olson, Susan Howe, Louis Cabri (ed. Hole mag), Charles Bernstein, Gilbert
                    Sorrentino, Gil Ott, Larzer Ziff, John Burnett Payne, Barry Schwabsky and John
                    Taggart. The archives of Tamarisk Press consist of letters from writers;
                    submitted manuscripts; contract awards; Tamarisk reviews; ads; and listings.
                    Records also include taped intervidws with various writers conducted by Baron,
                    such as Gilbert Sorrentino, Robert Kelly and Daisy Aldan. Other material
                    consists of photographs, collages, cover designs and some financial records.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>