<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Ellen Forman papers on the South Street Dance Company <date type="inclusive">1972-1991</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Ellen Forman papers on the South Street Dance
                    Company</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2236</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>20.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1972-1991</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Ellen Forman (1945-1990) was a pioneer of modern dance in Philadelphia. Forman
                    co-founded and directed the South Street Dance Company from 1974 until 1990. She
                    was well known for her reconstruction and performance of the dances of Isadora
                    Duncan, as well as her own choreography. She produced and performed in a series
                    of five annual concerts from 1985-1990 entitled “Body/Language” which showcased
                    innovative artists’ work which connected movement and text.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection documents the South Street Dance Company and Forman's involvement
                    with it. Records include: business records, including board of director meeting
                    minutes, financial and development records, payroll records, grant award
                    letters, contracts, and mailing lists; records related to specific programs,
                    including "Dance By the Sea," "Your Spirit at the Window, a Solo Tribute to
                    Isadora Duncan", and records of the company's performances with young
                    audiences; press releases, programs, flyers, posters, clippings,and reviews;
                    correspondence, including thank you notes from school children, letters from
                    subscribers, journalists, and staff of other arts organizations; photographs,
                    slides, video and audio recordings, props and costumes and a mannequin.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>