<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Ernest Earnest personal papers <date type="inclusive">1924-1982</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Ernest Earnest personal papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2059</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1924-1982</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Ernest P. Earnest taught English at Temple University for 40 years, from 1927 to
                    1969. From 1946 to 1951, he headed the Temple campus in Havertown, Delaware
                    County, one of several campuses created in the aftermath of World War II to
                    accommodate returning veterans. Earnest's published works include several books
                    on the history of literature and the city of Philadelphia. His books include a
                    biography of John and William Bartram, The Uses of Prose, and The Volunteer Fire
                    Company: Past and Present.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of this Philadelphia university teacher and writer include manuscripts
                    for both published and unpublished works focusing on Earnest's interests in the
                    history of literature and Philadelphia subjects, such as botanist John Bartram
                    and volunteer fire companies. The collection also includes readers comments on
                    his work, correspondence with his agent and publishers, English exam questions,
                    programs, photographs, and clippings.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>