<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Farm journal advertising files <date type="inclusive">1937-1976</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Farm journal advertising files</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2062</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>128 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1937-1976</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Philadelphia-based Farm Journal was established in 1877 by Wilmer Atkinson.
                    Throughout its history it has been known for its innovative publishing and
                    advertising techniques. At its peak, the publication had a circulation of almost
                    3.7 million.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of company files of the Advertising and Production
                    Departments of Farm Journal magazine. The materials date from the 1940s to the
                    early 1970s. Included are: internal correspondence and correspondence with
                    advertisers; production reports and statistics; advertising surveys, reports,
                    and statistics; "job jackets" containing order information, production
                    specifications, and proof copies of printing jobs; purchase orders and contracts
                    for advertisements; coupon commission reports; promotion samples for Farm
                    Journal and some of the magazine's advertisers, including posters, cards,
                    pamphlets; subscription and renewal data; annual reports; audits; scrapbooks of
                    Farm Journal publicity materials, press clippings, and "house ads" from trade
                    magazines; a copies of the journal and special editions.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>