<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Frank C. P. McGlinn political collection <date type="inclusive">1812-1998</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1928-1998</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Frank C. P. McGlinn political collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2072</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>86.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1812-1998</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1928-1998</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Born in 1914, Francis C. P. McGlinn graduated from William Penn Charter School in
                    1933, the University of North Carolina in 1937, and the University of
                    Pennsylvania Law School in 1940. He served in the military during World War II,
                    receiving a Purple Heart when he was injured in 1944. After the war, he worked
                    at the law firm of Pepper, Bodine, Stokes and Hamilton and Sheetz. He left the
                    practice of law to work as an executive for the Al Paul Lefton Co., an
                    advertising firm, from 1953-1957. Following his tenure at the Lefton Company,
                    McGlinn worked as an officer at The Fidelity Bank where he eventually became
                    executive vice president (1971-1978). McGlinn left The Fidelity Bank for the
                    Western Savings Bank where he served as vice president (1978-1980) and senior
                    vice president (1980-1982). McGlinn also served on the board of trustees of
                    Temple University (1954-1971), the board of trustees of the Free Library of
                    Philadelphia as well as a host of other civic and philanthropic organizations. A
                    Republican since 1932, McGlinn excelled as a fund-raiser and a financial adviser
                    for the state and national Republican Party. In various capacities, he served on
                    the executive boards of the Republican National Finance Committee (1964-1979)
                    and the Republican Finance Committee of Pennsylvania. In addition to those
                    roles, McGlinn worked on the executive committee of the Republican State
                    Committee of Pennsylvania, served as a delegate-at-large to the Republican
                    National Conventions from 1964-1976.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of McGlinn's political ephemera collection and personal
                    political documents and correspondence as an active Pennsylvanian Republican.
                    Materials include: minutes, memos, agendas, and financial summaries from
                    meetings of the various finance committees on which McGlinn served; delegate
                    packets from the Republican National Convention; invitations to presidential
                    inaugurations; fundraising flyers and brochures; political pamphlets;
                    newsletters, and magazines; clippings of news stories, editorials, and political
                    advertisements; correspondence; campaign literature for various candidates for
                    state and national offices; photographs; ephemera such as buttons, bumper
                    stickers, hats, and ribbons; autographs from political notables (presidents,
                    presidential candidates, senators, cabinet members, and others); commemorative
                    glassware and plates; and recordings of addresses by Roosevelt, Eisenhower,
                    Wilkie, and other political addresses. Also includes collected political
                    ephemera from the 19th and early 20th century, including pamphlets, broadsides,
                    and cabinet cards; framed photographs and posters; buttons and ribbons; and
                    printed materials and ephemera related to the centennial (1876) and
                    sesquicentennial (1926) celebrations.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>