<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Frank Brookhouser personal papers <date type="inclusive">1929-1975</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Frank Brookhouser personal papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2052</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1929-1975</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Frank Brookhouser was born in 1912 and attended high school in Ford City, Pa.
                    where he began his career in journalism as editor of the high school newspaper.
                    Brookhouser took a degree in journalism from Temple University and began working
                    for the Philadelphia Inquirer in 1939. In 1952 Brookhouser moved to the
                    Philadelphia evening bulletin where he penned a column entitled "Man About
                    Town," which ran until 1973. He wrote six books and over 400 short stories,
                    many of which were reprinted in the O. Henry Award and other anthologies.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of this Philadelphia newspaperman include materials related to his
                    columns in the Philadelphia Inquirer and the Philadelphia Evening Bulletin,
                    spanning his 50 year career which began in Ford City, Pennsylvania. This part of
                    the collection includes clippings and typescripts. The second part of the
                    collection documents Brookhouser's career as a short-story writer, which
                    includes correspondence, manuscripts, pamphlets, photographs, and tear sheets.
                    Prominent correspondents include Nelson Algren, Joan Crawford, Frank Sinatra,
                    Dave Garroway, James Michener, Allan Swallow, and Cornel Wilde.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>