<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Friends Neighborhood Guild records <date type="inclusive">1910-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Urban Archives</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Friends Neighborhood Guild records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2333</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Urban Archives<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>19.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Friends Neighborhood Guild is a settlement house serving the Poplar section
                    of North Philadelphia. The organization was founded in 1879 and was originally
                    called the Friends Beach Street Mission. In 1899, the organization was renamed
                    the Friends Neighborhood Guild. The Guild was involved in the redevelopment of
                    East Poplar. In 1950, the Guild started the Friends Self Help Cooperative, one
                    of the most successful housing cooperatives in Philadelphia. The cooperative
                    subsequently purchased Penn Towne, a Redevelopment Authority housing project at
                    Seventh and Fairmount Streets. The Guild also established Operation Poplar, an
                    extensive outreach program that involved the Guild in housing, community
                    organizing, juvenile counseling, urban renewal, small businesses, and other
                    facets of neighborhood life.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains administrative records, scrapbooks, photographs, slides,
                    and audiovisual materials of the Friends Neighborhood Guild. Materials include:
                    board minutes, agendas, and reports; annual reports, 1984-1990; correspondence,
                    including appeals, thank you letters, and correspondence with staff of community
                    organizations and city agencies; agreements with agencies and organizations such
                    as the Energy Coordinating Agency; grant proposals and grant reports; files on
                    aid recipients; minutes, memoranda, financial information, and correspondence
                    related to the Friends Rehabilitation Program (2001-2004), the Greater
                    Philadelphia Federation of Settlements, and the Philadelphia Housing Authority;
                    and some routine office forms and files. These records include the files of two
                    executive directors, Phillip G. Fazah and Francis Bosworth. There is a good deal
                    of information about the organization's finances, including: budgets and monthly
                    reports 1933-1956; pension plan and payroll files; personnel retirement records;
                    general ledger and journal, 1984-1986; audits, 1990s; and copies of invoices,
                    receipts, and checks, 1980s-1990s. Scrapbooks, 1954-55 and 1960-61, contains
                    clippings, programs, flyers, and photographs. There are also photographs and
                    slides of Friends Neighborhood Guild events and activities (ranging in date from
                    the early 20th century to the 1990s), as well as videos and audiocassettes from
                    various social welfare organizations and programs, including the United Way and
                    the Children's Defense Fund.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Swarthmore College,
                    Friends Historical Library: Friends Neighborhood Guild records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>