<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Germantown Settlement records <date type="inclusive">1955-1990</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Urban Archives</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Germantown Settlement records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC909</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Urban Archives<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>100.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1955-1990</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1884 an organization was formed and named Morton Street Day Nursery and Free
                    Kindergarten with a later change to Morton Street Day Nursery and Working
                    People's Aid, Inc. In 1920 a different organization was formed under the name of
                    Americanization Committee of Germantown to provide language and culture
                    instruction to immigrants. Changes in this organization's concerns lead to a
                    name change to Germantown Community Center. In October, 1934, the Morton Street
                    Day Nursery and Germantown Community Center merged to form the Germantown
                    Settlement with headquarters at 324 High Street. Over the years the Settlement
                    has provided a variety of services to constituents within its service area. This
                    includes community organization within the Morton area and the provision of
                    services to the elderly. A branch office in the Wister area was opened in 1957
                    at 48 E. Penn Street. A satellite office was later opened in the Olney area.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of organizational records for Germantown Settlement. Many
                    of the papers appear to have come from the office of Emanuel V. Freeman,
                    Executive Director. The collection contains minutes of the Board of Directors,
                    with agendas and committee reports (1969-1986), as well as minutes of staff
                    meetings and various Settlement programs. Office files include: financial
                    records such as check registers, expense reports, budgets, purchase orders, and
                    receipts; personnel policies; personnel files; and work schedules and time
                    sheets. Program records include planning and financial records for Late Start,
                    Day Camp programs, Children's Learning Center, and Transit Aide, as well as
                    records related to renovations of Settlement houses. There are a significant
                    number of Settlement case records and referrals from the 1980s, in addition to
                    client intake forms and assistance records for the Corporation for Aging. The
                    collection also contains records of the Germantown Settlement's involvement in
                    various community development programs and organizations, such as the Greater
                    Philadelphia Federation of Settlements, the Philadelphia Corporation for Aging,
                    the Office of Housing and Community Development, the Philadelphia Development
                    Partnership, and the Philadelphia Civic Center. These records include minutes,
                    correspondence and memoranda, reports, and newsletters. The collection also
                    contains scrapbooks of clippings from the 1950s.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 832</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>