<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Health/PAC records <date type="inclusive">1960-1984</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Health/PAC records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2066</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>77.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-1984</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Health PAC is the Health Policy Advisory Center of the Institute of Policy
                    Studies. It began in mid-1967 as a result of concern for the state of urban
                    health affairs in New York City. People felt the need for an advisory and
                    technical assistance center for the general public and for all concerned groups
                    wanting a more advanced and publicly accountable health service system. It
                    served with an advisory center, a data center, a social analysis lab and
                    development center, a technical assistance center, and a communications
                    center.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The archives of Health PAC consist of subject files on all topics of health,
                    reports on different hospitals in New York City and other urban locations,
                    studies of health care systems in foreign countries, articles and reports on
                    financial and medical accountability; information on national health institutes;
                    Department of Health statistics; meeting minutes of various health care planning
                    and advisory committees; bibliographic files; proposals; articles in rough
                    draft; book reviews; position papers; pamphlets and flyers; newsletters and
                    publications from community and national organizations; financial records; and
                    correspondence. Major topics include free clinics, costs of medical care,
                    insurance and HMOs, medical education, patients' rights, mental health, and
                    aging.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>