<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Helen Oakes papers <date type="inclusive">1961-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Urban Archives</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Helen Oakes papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC1217</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Urban Archives<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>45.66 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1961-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Helen Oakes has studied and been involved in the Philadelphia school system since
                    the 1960s. She played active roles in many organizations committed to improving
                    and restoring public education including the Citizens Committee on Public
                    Education in Philadelphia and the West Philadelphia Schools Committee. Mrs.
                    Oakes was appointed to the Board of Education in Philadelphia in 1982 and served
                    as a member until 1989. While on the Board of Education, she worked as a member
                    of the Desegregation Task Force and the Task Force on Teacher Selection. Mrs.
                    Oakes also wrote and published The Oakes Newsletter for nineteen years from 1970
                    to 1989.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains papers related to Helen Oakes' involvement with variety
                    of educational institutions and issues. Board of Education subject files address
                    a wide range of topics, including AIDS, dropouts, charter schools, attendance,
                    affirmative action, effective schools, pregnancy prevention, school
                    reorganization, superintendent selection, the Educational Home Rule Charter.
                    Subject files include articles, printed reports, studies, statistics, and some
                    memoranda and correspondence. There are also records related to the compilation
                    of School-by-School Statistical Analysis of Philadelphia's Public Schools, 1965,
                    1975-1981, as well as printed School District of Philadelphia directories,
                    financial reports, policies, and teaching guides. The collection also contains
                    newspaper clippings, 1964-2002, and records related to Oakes' reelection to the
                    Board of Education. Rhoads Elementary School files include notes from classroom
                    observations and from staff meetings and discussions with staff, reports, copies
                    of mailings to parents and memos to staff, and correspondence from staff members
                    to Oakes. The files related to The Oakes Newsletter include mailing lists,
                    accounting information, tax forms, incoming and outgoing correspondence,
                    reference materials for articles, notes on classroom observations and notes from
                    discussions with educators. The collection includes files related to
                    organizations with which Oakes was involved such as the Council for Educational
                    Priorities, Citizen's Committee on Public Education, Philadelphia Voter
                    Education Project, and the League of Women Voter's Education Committee. These
                    files include minutes, printed materials, and memoranda. There are some records
                    in the collection related to the sale of the papers of Floyd Logan, founder and
                    president of the Educational Equality League.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 995</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>