<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Henry Dexter Learned personal and professional papers <date type="inclusive">1919-1964</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Henry Dexter Learned personal and professional
                    papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2069</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1919-1964</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henry Dexter Learned joined the faculty of Temple University as head of the
                    Department of French in 1930, and served as chairman of the Department of Modern
                    Languages from 1936 to 1946 before retiring as Emeritus Professor in 1960. He
                    wrote extensively on the phonetics of children's speech and on romance
                    languages, was assistant editor of Webster's New International Dictionary from
                    1929 to 1934, and served the U.S. government in military code work during World
                    War II. In 1954, he organized the "Cruiser Olympia Association, Inc." to have
                    the cruiser Olympia, Admiral Dewey's flagship in the Spanish-American War,
                    declared a national monument. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of Philadelphia foreign language educator are dominated by research
                    materials, notes, and manuscripts on phonology and for an Anglo-Norman
                    dictionary and an Anglo-French bibliography. The collection contains other
                    materials relating to Learned's pursuit of national monument status for Admiral
                    Dewey's cruiser, the U.S.S. Olympia. The collection includes correspondence from
                    the Cruiser Olympia Association, Inc. The collection includes personal and
                    professional correspondence, reprints, clippings, articles, maps, drawings,
                    woodcuts, telegrams, photographs, slides, negatives, poems, and a printing
                    block.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>