<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Innes-Kirkbride family papers <date type="inclusive">1794-1990</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1890-1946</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Innes-Kirkbride family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2068</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1794-1990</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1890-1946</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Thornton Innes II (1843-1913) was a Philadelphia printer. His wife was
                    Eleanor (Ellen) Baldwin Kirkbride (1850-1932). They had two sons, William
                    Thornton Innes III (b. 1874) and Edward Kirkbride Innes. Both sons joined Innes
                    and Sons, their father's printing firm, and William Innes III eventually became
                    its head. The company also had a publishing arm, the Innes Publishing Company.
                    In addition to his work in printing and publishing, William Innes III was a
                    noted authority on tropical fish, and author of several books on the subject,
                    including Goldfish Varieties and Tropical Aquarium Fishes, first published in
                    1917. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of family papers, photographs, and artifacts of the Innes
                    and Kirkbride families of Philadelphia. Types of materials in the collection
                    include correspondence, photographs, genealogies and family histories, diaries,
                    military papers, obituaries, certificates, manuscripts, sketches, indentures,
                    pamphlets, newspaper clippings, and ephemera. Correspondence includes letters to
                    and from members of the Baldwin and Kirkbride families (1794-1845); and letters
                    from the Innes family (1843-1866), particularly William T. Innes, William T.
                    Innes II, and William T. Innes III, Ellen S. Kirkbride Innes, and Mary W. Innes.
                    Documentation related to specific family members includes diaries, 1905-1941, by
                    Mary W. Innes and Eliza Kirkbride Innes documenting daily activities and one
                    volume summarizes world events. William T. Innes III (1874-1969) papers include
                    correspondence, medical records, appointment books, a ledger of fish-related
                    purchases and miscellaneous documentation related to a variety of topics, as
                    well as photographs of Innes as Benjamin Franklin. Eleanor S. Kirkbride papers
                    include a commonplace book and journal. The collection includes pamphlets, book
                    jackets, gift cards, and other examples of the work of Innes &amp; Sons Printers
                    (1311 Sansom Street). Photographic images of family members in the collection
                    include tintypes, snapshots, black and white prints, cabinet photographs,
                    negatives, and stereo prints. There are also a number of artifacts, postcards,
                    tradecards, prints and pencil and ink drawings.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Temple University,
                    Special Collections: William T. Innes papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>