<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James and Evelyn Kenny collection <date type="inclusive">1949-1986</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James and Evelyn Kenny collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2253</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1949-1986</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Evelyn Smith Kenny (d. 1971) was born in Schenectady, New York, moved to New York
                    City and studied with the Ballet Rousse. She was a student of Catherine
                    Littlefield and a member of the corps de ballet of Radio City Music Hall. In
                    1945 she married James Kenny (d. 1982). They became famous as an ice skating
                    ballet team and toured the US with Sonja Henie's Ice Revue. James and Evelyn
                    later opened the Little Dance Shop in Wayne, Pennsylvania, a dance school which
                    later became known as the Devon Festival Ballet. They had a daughter, Susan.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of a scrapbook and personal effects of James and Evelyn
                    Kenny. The scrapbook contains newspaper clippings about Evelyn and James Kenny,
                    the Little Dance Shop, and obituaries of both of them; it also includes
                    photographs, programs, and a small number of letters. The collection also
                    includes two pairs of toe shoes: one pair was worn by Evelyn at age 3-4 and
                    later by her daughter, Susan, while the other pair is modified with metal spikes
                    for use in ice ballet (a feature patented by Kenny). There is also a letter from
                    a lawyer about the patent for the shoes.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>