<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James Doyle papers on Carlos Montenegro and Bolivian politics <date type="inclusive">1942-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James Doyle papers on Carlos Montenegro and Bolivian
                    politics</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2058</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="spa"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1942-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James J. Doyle was a student at Temple University in the 1970s. He studied with
                    Dr. William Sharp, focusing on South American history and politics. One figure
                    Doyle researched was Carlos Montenegro, who was a Bolivian nationalist and
                    diplomat, director of the Sintesis Economica Americana, and one of the founders
                    of the Movimiento Nacionalista Revolcinario (MNR).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of James Doyle's academic research on Bolivian statesmen
                    and politics, with a particular focus on Carlos Montenegro. Materials include
                    original correspondence to and from Montenegro and other figures; typescripts by
                    Montenegro; photographs; newspaper clippings; Doyle's manuscript notes and
                    drafts; Doyle's correspondence with academic advisors; photocopies of articles
                    and book chapters; audio cassette recordings of interviews; published volumes on
                    Bolivian politics and history by Carlos Montenegro, Augusto Cespedes, and
                    others; and a small number of pamphlets and posters.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>