<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Jewish Labor Committee records <date type="inclusive">1973-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Urban Archives</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Jewish Labor Committee records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC1102</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Urban Archives<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>25.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Jewish Labor Committee, Philadelphia Metropolitan Area was established in the
                    mid 1950s. The organization is a local affiliate of the National Jewish Labor
                    Committee started in 1934 to provide aid to Jews during the Nazi occupation of
                    Europe. The JLC works with various trade unions and outside agencies to address
                    various issues affecting the Jewish community in Philadelphia. Through
                    coordinated efforts with the National Office, in New York City, the agency
                    played a key role in state campaigns for civil rights legislation, in historic
                    civil rights marches of the 1950s and 1960s and the Leadership Conference for
                    Civil Rights. The JLC continues to strengthen the American Jewish community's
                    support of labor's domestic, economic and social positions, and to work with
                    local unions in their support of a secure state of Israel.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains subject and organization files of the Philadelphia office
                    of the Jewish Labor Committee. Subject files include newspaper clippings, policy
                    statements, press releases, copies of legislation, newsletters, and
                    correspondence. There are some files related to personnel and a director search.
                    The collection also contains some records related to the national biennial
                    convention of the JLC, including memoranda, programs, reports, and draft
                    resolutions. Organization files include minutes, correspondence, memoranda,
                    monthly reports (1973-1981), news clippings, policy statements, press releases,
                    newsletters, and conference programs. Organizations represented include the
                    AFL-CIO, Jewish Community Relations Council, A. Philip Randolph Institute,
                    Philadelphia Committee in Support of Solidarity, Philadelphia Federation of
                    Teachers, National Trade Union Council, Negro Trade Union Leadership Council,
                    Labor Council for Latin American Advancement, and the Ethnic Labor Coalition.
                    The Ethnic Labor Council files include information related to the James H. Jones
                    book scholarship. The collection also includes a number of newsletters and
                    journals including Jewish Frontier, Safer Times, AFL-CIO Legislative Alert, and
                    Workmen's Circle Call. The collection includes materials in Hebrew, Polish, and
                    German. Many files were generated by Alex Wollod, Regional Staff of Philadelphia
                    JLC, as well as Rosalind Spigel, Mike Perry, and Ted Kirsch.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 943</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>