<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John W. Mosley photographs <date type="inclusive">1886-1968</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1930s-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John W. Mosley photographs</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2254</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>95 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1886-1968</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1930s-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John W. Mosley (1907-1969) was an African-American photographer. Mosley was born
                    in Lumberton, North Carolina. His father was a Baptist minister and also worked
                    as a barber. Mosley attended Johnson C. Smith College in Charlotte, North
                    Carolina. His interest in photography began in the 1920s, and when he moved to
                    Philadelphia in 1934, he was hired at the Barksdale Photography Studio. Soon
                    after relocating to Philadelphia, Mosley's photographs began appearing in
                    African-American newspapers throughout the eastern United States. He was witness
                    and chronicler of many changes in politics, culture, sports, and fashion from
                    the late 1930s to the late 1960s. Many of his photographs were taken in
                    Philadelphia and Atlantic City, New Jersey, but Mosley also worked in New York,
                    Baltimore, and Washington D.C. He photographed many of the prominent figures in
                    the African-American community, including Marian Anderson, Martin Luther King,
                    Jr., Paul Robeson, Cab Calloway, W.E.B. DuBois, and Langston Hughes.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of photographs, negatives, and contact prints by John W.
                    Mosley. Major subjects include social events and ceremonies, churches, sports,
                    performing arts, clubs and organizations, political events, and accidents and
                    fires. There are many photographs of individuals and groups. The collection also
                    includes event programs, a few of which include names of persons photographed at
                    the events; a wedding photo album; a small number of cabinet cards, dating back
                    to 1886; and several copies of Charles L. Blockson's book The Journey of John W.
                    Mosley.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">African American photographers.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">African Americans--Pictorial works.</subject>
                <geogname encodinganalog="651">Philadelphia (Pa.)--History--Pictorial
                    works.</geogname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Cabinet photographs</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Negatives (Photographic)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>