<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph C. Carter personal papers <date type="inclusive">1929-1992</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1946-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph C. Carter personal papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2055</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1929-1992</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1946-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Carter (1909-1995) was a professor of journalism at Temple University.
                    During his 30 year tenure, Carter was distinguished for his promotion of high
                    school journalism through the Temple High School Press Tournament. In 1958,
                    Carter began work on a biography of Temple founder Russell Conwell, which was
                    published in 1981. Carter was the founder and director of Temple's William J.
                    Blitman Reading Room, which later became the Blitman Library. Carter was the
                    editor of Temple's "Faculty Record" from 1947 to 1960.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of this Philadelphia university educator are dominated by his personal
                    interest in the life of Russell Conwell, founder of Temple University. The
                    collection includes research materials and correspondence with the relatives of
                    Johnny Ring, Conwell's Civil War aide; including John Q. Ring and Mary Ault
                    Ring. The collection also contains a 3 volume history of the Blitman Journalism
                    Library at Temple, a bound copy of "Publicity for Young Actress Jayne Mansfield
                    and the Philadelphia Film 'The Burglar'" compiled by Carter in 1976, and a
                    bound copy of issues of the "Faculty Record", 1947-1960, with some
                    correspondence pasted in. Some of the materials found in the collection relate
                    to Carter's teaching career at Temple. The materials include artifacts,
                    articles, copyright certificates, memorabilia, microfilms, negatives, notes,
                    periodicals, photographs, and telegrams. There are typescripts of Carter's The
                    Acres of Diamonds Man and Magnolia Journey. The collection also includes
                    miscellaneous correspondence related to Carter's career and particular writings,
                    with readers, colleagues, and institutions (1960s-1992).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>