<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Kariamu Welsh papers <date type="inclusive">1965-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Kariamu Welsh papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2235</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>35 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1965-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Kariamu Welsh is a Professor in the Boyer School of Music and Department of Dance
                    at Temple University and Director of the Institute for African Dance Research
                    and Performance (IADRP). She received her MA. H. in choreography from SUNY
                    Buffalo in 1975 and her D. Arts in Dance History and Choreography from New York
                    University in 1993. Dr. Welsh has been a member on the faculties of SUNY
                    Buffalo, The University of the Arts and Swarthmore College. Welsh was the
                    founding artistic director of the National Dance Company of Zimbabwe from
                    1981-1983. She has been the recipient of three Senior Fulbright Scholar Awards
                    and has received many choreography awards and fellowships including the National
                    Endowment of Arts Choreography Fellowship, the New York State Council on the
                    Minority Choreography Fellowship, the Creative Artist Public Service Award (NY),
                    and the Pennsylvania Council on the Arts dance historian fellowship.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of professional and personal papers of Kariamu Welsh.
                    Teaching and academic administrative materials include: student papers and
                    exams; letters of recommendation for students; correspondence from students;
                    faculty records, such as memoranda, meeting minutes, and tenure reviews;
                    stationery from the Institute for African Dance Research and Performance; and
                    copies of the International Journal of African Dance. Materials related to
                    Welsh's scholarship and writing include: newspaper clippings on dance companies,
                    her writings, and on subjects she was interested in; articles and dissertations
                    by other authors; publicity materials for her published works and performances,
                    including book jackets, flyers, posters, and programs; programs, flyers, and
                    playbills for a variety of dance performances by other companies; copies of Sage
                    (a Scholarly Journal on Black Women), in which Welsh had a piece published; and
                    sound recordings of music to accompany dances. Personal materials include a
                    small amount of personal correspondence, papers and notes from her high school
                    and college years and poetry by Welsh (primarily from the 1970s).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>