<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Lyn Lifshin papers <date type="inclusive">1953-2007</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Lyn Lifshin papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2071</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>277 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953-2007</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Lyn Lifshin was born in Burlington, Vermont, in 1942 and published her first book
                    of verse in 1968. Since then Lifshin has published over 40 books of poetry and
                    several anthologies. Her focus is on feminism and the institution of
                    marriage.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of this contemporary American feminist poet consist of voluminous
                    correspondence, notebooks, card files, manuscripts, newspaper clippings, and
                    audio recordings. The collection includes draft manuscripts for many works,
                    including an anthology, Ariadne's Thread: A Collection of Contemporary Women's
                    Journals, and Tangled Vines: A Collection of Mother and Daughter Poems. One
                    prominent correspondent is Toni Ortner-Zimmerman. The collection includes
                    printed materials, such as announcements, newsletters, and flyers for many
                    poetry organizations and publications, particularly women's poetry
                    organizations. There is a small amount of juvenilia and documentation related to
                    Lifshin's school years.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>