<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Mark Satin correspondence files for New World Alliance/New Options
                            <date type="inclusive">1977-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Mark Satin correspondence files for New World Alliance/New
                    Options</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2241</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Mark Satin (b. 1946) is a U.S. lawyer, author, and the editor of the online
                    political periodical Radical Middle Newsletter. The New World Alliance emerged
                    in 1979 as a result of cross-country networking by Satin, as a means of
                    activating social change organizations nationwide. The organization's platform
                    is aimed at the issues of global peace, cooperative economics, energy
                    conservation, holistic health, environmental preservation, and appropriate
                    science and technology. The platform emphasized accomplishment of these goals
                    through public education and political organizing around these issues, promoted
                    through seminars, workshops, and forums, as well as the publication ofa
                    tri-weekly newsletter, Renewal, and later a monthly newsletter, New Options. In
                    1992 New Options suspended publication and all other organizational
                    activities.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists primarily of correspondence and other documentation
                    related to Satin's New Options newsletter. Materials include: correspondence
                    from readers with general comments about the newsletter or in response to
                    specific articles; correspondence from contributors and members of the
                    newsletter's Board of Advisors; issues of the Renewal Newsletter #1-26 and
                    related correspondence from readers and contributors; correspondence from
                    members of political and social protest organizations; the Canadian and U.S.
                    editions of Satin's book New Age Politics and correspondence from readers; and
                    correspondence and other documents related to New World Alliance, including the
                    group's platform. In addition to voluminous correspondence with New Age social,
                    political, environmental, and spiritual organizations concerning issues of
                    import to their constituencies, there is also regular correspondence with Gerald
                    Goldfarb, Richard Perl, and Marc Sarkady.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>