<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Melville S. Green papers <date type="inclusive">1947-1979</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Melville S. Green papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2065</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>17 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1947-1979</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Melville S. Green was born in 1922 and studied physics at Columbia and Princeton.
                    Between 1954 and 1968 Green presided over departments at the U.S. National
                    Bureau of Standards. From 1968 Green taught at Temple University, where he
                    published over 65 articles, focusing on phase transition and critical phenomena.
                    Dr. Green was active in Jewish affairs and human rights, especially regarding
                    the rights of Soviet Jewish dissidents.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of this prominent physicist document his scientific research, his life
                    as an academic, his lifelong activities with Jewish affairs,and his personal
                    life and travels. A sizeable portion of the collection concerns his research and
                    academic affairs, including correspondence, manuscripts, lectures, notes,
                    speeches, pamphlets, and audio tapes. A second major series documents Green's
                    participation in Jewish affairs with organizations such as the Academic
                    Committee on Soviet Jewry and the Allied Jewish Appeal of Philadelphia. Green's
                    work to permit the emigration of Soviet scientists is documented in
                    correspondence with the Union of Concerned Scientists. The third major series
                    documents Green's extensive travels to Israel, Japan, Europe, and Mexico,
                    through extensive correspondence files. Prominent correspondents include Cyril
                    Domb, co-author of a monographic series on Phase transition and critical
                    phenomena, and A.V. Voronel, a Soviet scientist. This series includes
                    correspondence, handbills, leaflets, photographs. The collection also includes
                    minutes and telegrams. There are also materials associated with the 1973
                    Conference on renormalization theory. The collection also documents Green's
                    tenure as an instructor at Temple University, which includes lecture and
                    research notes, as well as student files and correspondence.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>