<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Natalie Hinderas papers <date type="inclusive">1953-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Natalie Hinderas papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2258</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>16.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Natalie Leota Henderson Hinderas (1927-1987) was a concert pianist and professor
                    of music at Temple University. In 1945, Hinderas received her BS in Music from
                    Oberlin Conservatory as their youngest student. She did her post-graduate work
                    at the Julliard School of Music with Olga Samaroff and at the Philadelphia
                    Conservatory with Edward Steuermann. In the 1950s and 1960s, Hinderas toured
                    America, Europe, the West Indies, Africa, and Asia, and was signed by NBC to
                    perform in recitals and variety shows at NBC-owned stations around the U.S. In
                    1966 she joined the faculty of Temple University's College of Music, where she
                    rose to the rank of full professor. In 1971, she became the first
                    Afican-American to perform a subscription concert with the Philadelphia
                    Orchestra. She also performed with the Los Angeles Philharmonic orchestra, the
                    Cleveland, Atlanta, New York, San Francisco, and Chicago symphony orchestras.
                    Throughout her career, she promoted and recorded works by black performers and
                    composers, among them R. Nathaniel Dett, William Grant Still, John W. Work, and
                    George Walker. She received a number of awards and degrees including the Martha
                    Baird Rockefeller fellowship and an honorary doctorate degree from Swarthmore
                    College.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers and audio recordings of Natalie Hinderas.
                    Materials include: programs for performances, appearances, and competitions;
                    correspondence related to her performing and recording career; family
                    correspondence; music scores; audio tapes of performances by Hinderas and
                    others; audio tapes of interviews with others; reviews of her performances;
                    articles, clippings, and promotional materials on other performers and
                    composers; articles on topics related to music; financial records; photographs
                    of Hinderas, her performances and tours, her husband Lionel Monagas, her
                    daughter Michele Monagas, and other artists; notebooks and appointment books; a
                    1981 business diary related to Hinderas's work on "The Music Room" and
                    selected performances; correspondence, notes and bibliographies related to
                    "America Through Music"; a collection of postcards; and school records of
                    Michele Monagas from kindergarten through high school.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Temple University. Faculty.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">African American musicians.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Pianists--United States.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Financial records</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Notebooks</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scores</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Sound recordings</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>