<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Nathan Cronheim papers <date type="inclusive">1919-1975</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1950s-1970s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Nathan Cronheim papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2056</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>33.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1919-1975</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1950s-1970s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Nathan Cronheim was born in Staunton, Va., on May 17, 1908, and he graduated from
                    Penn State University in 1931 with training in both architecture and
                    engineering. Cronheim's first job was as a draftsman for the Philadelphia firm
                    of Howe &amp; Lescaze. During World War II Cronheim worked with Louis Kahn on
                    several housing projects. Between 1946 and 1966 Cronheim completed some of his
                    most significant projects in partnership with Leonard Weger. During this time
                    Cronheim designed the air-conditioning systems for the U.S. Capitol and the
                    Marshall Fields Dept. Store in Chicago.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of this prominent Philadelphia architect/engineer include the files
                    for numerous design jobs which contain architectural drawings, blueprints,
                    correspondence, clippings, floor plans, contracts, construction estimates,
                    pamphlets, brochures, manuals, newsletters, photographs, reports,
                    specifications, and site plans. The graphic and written materials in this large
                    collection document the entire design process including the job files for many
                    Philadelphia area industrial and public projects, such as Picatinny Arsenal, the
                    Northern Metal Co., the General Chemical Co., Stone Container Co., the Frankford
                    Arsenal, Hercules Cement Co., the France Packing Co., the Joseph J. Greenburg
                    School, and the Selinsgrove State School &amp; Hospital. Most of these materials
                    date from the period of Cronheim's partnerships with Leonard Weger (1946-1966)
                    and with Joseph D. Kuo (1967-1972), while there are no materials from Cronheim's
                    brief relationship during the war years with Louis Kahn.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>