<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Paul Eberman personal and professional papers <date type="inclusive">1938-1973</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Paul Eberman personal and professional papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2060</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1938-1973</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Paul W. Eberman came to Temple University as Dean of the College of Education in
                    1963. He stepped down as Dean in 1973, and taught at the college until his death
                    in 1978. Before coming to Temple, he taught at the University of Wisconsin, the
                    last five years as its Associate Dean in the School of Education, where most of
                    the materials in this collection were compiled. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Eberman's papers contain a diverse group of materials pertaining to his classes,
                    chiefly predating his career at Temple. They include notes and typescripts of
                    lectures, exam sheets, instructional materials, bibliographic instruction, and
                    course evaluations. His research on handwriting instruments dates from 1950 to
                    1953. His analysis of teacher education in Nigeria in 1962-1963 led to the joint
                    venture between Temple and UNESCO to establish a graduate education program for
                    teachers in that country some 14 years later. Personal papers included are
                    Eberman's academic transcripts and Aviators Flight log book, 1943-1946.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>