<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Pennsylvania Ballet records <date type="inclusive">1963-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Pennsylvania Ballet records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2076</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>94.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1963-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Pennsylvania Ballet was established in 1963 by Barbara Weisberger through a
                    Ford Foundation initiative to develop regional professional dance companies. The
                    company performed in the national spotlight for the first time in 1968 at City
                    Center in New York, a highly successful debut that led to a decade of national
                    touring, appearances on PBS' acclaimed Dance in America series, and a stint as
                    the official company of the Brooklyn Academy of Music during the 1970s. From
                    1987 to 1989, Pennsylvania Ballet forged an alliance with Milwaukee Ballet in an
                    unprecedented venture to create one company. The new organization, with 43
                    dancers and a greatly expanded repertoire, was the first in the country to offer
                    its dancers year-round employment. The premier classical ballet company in the
                    Philadelphia region, Pennsylvania Ballet is currently comprised of 42 dancers.
                    During the Company's 40-year history, it has commissioned original ballets from
                    such choreographers as Merce Cunningham, Christopher d'Amboise, Trey McIntyre,
                    Matthew Neenan, Kevin O'Day, David Parsons, Val Caniparoli, Christopher Stowell,
                    Dwight Rhoden, Meredith Rainey, Kirk Peterson, and Lynne Taylor-Corbett, as well
                    as the 40th Anniversary commission of Swan Lake by Christopher Wheeldon. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Pennsylvania Ballet Company. The
                    collection comprises publicity materials and office records. Publicity materials
                    include: season programs, playbills, posters, and announcements; scrapbooks of
                    press clippings; and photographs and slides of dancers and productions;
                    materials related to radio and television publicity; and press releases. Office
                    records include copies of memoranda and fundraising records of the board of
                    trustees; corporate donor lists; income statements; contracts and agreements
                    with dancers and choreographers; biographical information on and photographs of
                    corps members and guest artists; tour information, such as itineraries,
                    schedules, and promotional materials; copies of Dance Magazine and other
                    publications; and videos of PA Ballet dance performances. Names appearing in
                    office files include Barbara Weisberger, Artistic Director, Robert Altman,
                    Managing Director, and Benjamin Harkarvy, Associate Artistic Director. The
                    collection also includes a costume jacket.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>