<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Peter Segal papers <date type="inclusive">1926-2005</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1980s-2000s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Peter Segal papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2083</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1926-2005</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1980s-2000s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Peter Segal was born in 1949 in Philadelphia and graduated from Temple University
                    with a bachelor's degree in Business Administration in 1971. He earned both a
                    Master’s in Music History and a Doctorate of Musical Arts from Temple and
                    received diplomas from the Accademia Chigiana and Conservatorio Antonio Vivaldi
                    (Italy) and University of Santiago de Compostela (Spain). As Director of Guitar
                    Studies at Temple University from 1973 to 1993, Segal mentored over 200 graduate
                    and undergraduate students in preparation for careers in the musical arts. Segal
                    was also taught at the University of the Arts from 1973 to 1991. Segal was a
                    member of the Philadelphia Classical Guitar Society since its foundation in 1967
                    and served as its President, Treasurer and Director of Programming.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists primarily of guitar scores and documentation related to
                    Segal's research and performing career. Materials include: transcriptions,
                    copies, and published guitar scores by others; photographs of Segal, framed
                    photos and diplomas; press clippings and reviews; ephemera related to concerts;
                    scores, correspondence and press materials related to Spanish composer Joaquin
                    Rodrigo and Segal's transcription of some of his works; Segal's dissertation;
                    video recordings of Segal's performances; miscellaneous audio recordings; and
                    microfilm of a Vivaldi score.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>