<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadanco records <date type="inclusive">1978-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadanco records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2077</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1978-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Philadelphia Dance Company (Philadanco) founded by Joan Myers Brown in 1970,
                    is a modern contemporary dance company that tours nationally and
                    internationally. For 34 years, the company has traveled the country and the
                    world, performing before sold-out audiences of diverse people of all ages,
                    creed, ethnicity and cultural traditions. Philadanco were the pilot dance
                    company to be part of the Pennsylvania Comprehensive Education Training Act,
                    arts training program. Philadanco were one of the first companies to hire
                    dancers on a 52 week salary, the first to own housing for its dancers and the
                    first to own a debt-free facility. The company also established the
                    International Association of Blacks in Dance which addresses the special needs
                    of the African American dance community, and produces an annual conference.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of programs and publicity materials for Philadanco.
                    Materials include season programs; playbills; flyers, invitations, and
                    announcements; videos of commercials and public service announcements; newspaper
                    clippings of reviews and news stories related to Philadanco; booking information
                    packets; t-shirts, buttons, bumper stickers, and other artifacts; and
                    photographs and transparencies. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>