<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Lesbian and Gay Task Force records <date type="inclusive">1978-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Lesbian and Gay Task Force records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2078</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>167 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1978-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Philadelphia Lesbian and Gay Task Force was a human rights advocacy
                    organization focused on law, public policy, and the development of public
                    education and mass media. Founded in 1978, the Task Force supported the rights
                    of all oppressed minorities, with a particular focus on the civil and human
                    rights of gay men and lesbian women and transgendered and/or bisexual people.
                </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Philadelphia Lesbian and Gay Task Force.
                    Materials include: incoming and outgoing correspondence; minutes, agendas, and
                    planning documents of the board; financial records; policy and program
                    recommendations; surveys, studies, and reports; speeches; various publications
                    by the PLGTF, including the Bulletin (1980-1985); videos and audio cassettes of
                    meetings and radio and television productions; legal briefings and court
                    transcripts; and ephemera. The collection also documents PLGTF’s participation
                    in the petition to deny license renewal applications of Philadelphia commercial
                    and non-commercial radio and television stations (1989-1994).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>