<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Planning Commission records <date type="inclusive">1953-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Urban Archives</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Planning Commission records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC1118</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Urban Archives<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.91 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains files of several members of the Philadelphia City
                    Planning Commission related to planning in Urban Renewal Areas throughout the
                    city, primarily dating from the mid 1960s to the early 1990s, with a few older
                    materials. Records were generated from the offices of John Mitkus (Executive
                    Director), David Knapton, David Hamme, and John Higgins (planners), as well as
                    other members of the Commission. Records include: meeting minutes, agendas, and
                    notes; correspondence and memoranda; reports; planning and market studies; fact
                    sheets, location descriptions, and neighborhood histories; crime and demographic
                    statistics; development proposals; contracts and architectural and site plans;
                    newspaper clippings; schedules for city infrastructure projects; and some
                    information about property ownership. Areas covered include Pennsport,
                    Southwark, South Central, Eastwick, Southwest Philadelphia, Ellsworth, South
                    Philadelphia, Germantown, and Moyamensing. The collection also includes files on
                    the Philadelphia Naval Shipyard and the proposed Crosstown Expressway.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 959</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia City
                    Records: City Planning Commission, Record Group 145 </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>