<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Dance Alliance records <date type="inclusive">1987-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Dance Alliance records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2248</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1987-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Founded in 1971, Philadelphia Dance Alliance is a non-profit, organization whose
                    membership includes dance artists, dance students, dance companies, independent
                    choreographers, university and college dance departments, dance studios and
                    dance aficionados. They provide a variety of programs and services to
                    professional dancers and students of dance. DanceLINK, founded in 1994, is a
                    consortium of dance organizations from Chicago, Florida, Minnesota, and
                    Philadelphia.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials from Philadelphia Dance Alliance. Records
                    include: newsletters (1995-2002); membership directories; flyers and programs;
                    and photographs. Independent Choreographers Exchange materials include: minutes
                    of meetings, reviews, programs, flyers, and printed promotional material, and
                    contracts. There are also records related to PDA's participation in the
                    DanceLINK consortium. These records include: grant applications; written and
                    recorded assessments of applicants; and audio and video tapes of performances.
                    Other arts alliances that are represented in the collection include:
                    Neighborhood Dance Exchange, Philadelphia Dances, and Dance Advance.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>