<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>PHLCORP, Inc. records <date type="inclusive">1901-1984</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">PHLCORP, Inc. records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2232</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>24.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1901-1984</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>PHLCORP is a Philadelphia-based holding company formed out of the remains of
                    Baldwin United Corporation, a bankrupt insurance company. Companies owned by or
                    merged into the Baldwin United Corporation include: Baldwin Piano and Organ
                    Company, College Park Corporation, Family Leisure Centers, Inc., Ellington Piano
                    Company, Gresch Musical Instruments Company, Offshore Marine Corporation, and
                    the Sperry and Hutchinson Co. These companies were primarily U.S. based, and
                    operated in the areas of transportation, insurance, musical instrument
                    manufacturing, and trading stamps.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Documents and corporate records of the predecessors of PHLCORP (namely Baldwin
                    Piano Company and United Corporation), of their various transformations, and of
                    companies owned and merged. Materials include: minute books of shareholder and
                    board meetings; stock certificates; articles of incorporation and by-laws;
                    financial volumes, such as accounts payable and check registers; appraisals of
                    manufacturing facilities; legal documents such as trust agreements and leases; a
                    scrapbook for the Baldwin Piano Company, including notices of meetings,
                    advertisements, memoranda, and board resolutions.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>