<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Richard Williamson Ellis papers <date type="inclusive">1916-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Richard Williamson Ellis papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2061</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>121 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Richard W. Ellis was a typographer, book designer, and printer. Ellis was born in
                    Washington, D.C. in 1894 and he pursued an education in metallurgy before going
                    to work as a printer. In 1924 Ellis started the Georgian Press, the beginning of
                    an illustrious career in book designing and printing. From his shop in Westport,
                    Connecticut Ellis printed over 50 books. After 1935, Ellis worked for Haddon
                    Craftsmen in Camden, for Curtis Publishing in Philadelphia, as well as Golden
                    Hind Press, Kingsport Press, and the Limited Editions Club during the latter
                    years of his career. His works include fine art editions of Candide, Heart of
                    Darkness, The Pennsylvania German Fraktur of the Free Library of Philadelphia,
                    and The Four Gospels and the Acts of the Apostles. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of this prominent American type and book designer include advertising,
                    book covers, clippings, correspondence, ephemera, financial records, invoices,
                    letterheads, galley proofs, memorandums, pamphlets, photographs, proofs,
                    receipts, and sketches. This voluminous collection spans the entirety of Ellis'
                    professional career, arranged principally around his job files, which document
                    the printing of a book from the design phase to the actual printing and
                    distribution. The collection includes job files for over twenty-five books.
                    Ellis' personal life is documented through extensive family correspondence and
                    photographs. The job files include correspondence, financial records, memos,
                    pasteups, sketches, proofs, and advertising, from Ellis' employers over a 50
                    year period including; Cheshire House, Curtis Publishing Company, Haddon
                    Craftsmen, Inc., Georgian Press, Golden Hind Press, Kingsport Press,and the
                    Limited Editions Club. The correspondence includes letters from Walter P.
                    Chrysler, Gustav Davidson, Frederic Goudy, Mitchell Kennerley, Frank French,
                    R.H. Kress, Christopher Morley, Arthur W. Rushmore, Jesse Satenstein, and Edwin
                    Wolf II. The collection also includes two cabinets of type specimens;
                    Ellis'extensive library of printed materials related to type and book designing;
                    and collections assembled by Ellis on the work of Frank French, Mitchell
                    Kennerley, and Frederic Goudy. Artifacts and furniture housed in the
                    Templana-Conwellana Reading Room include a type cabinet and type drawers, a
                    glass-fronted display case, Tibetan wood cut block, photo-engraved line block,
                    Ben Franklin/Franklin Chess Club plaque, monotype caster type matrix, Georgian
                    Press Visitor's Guest Book (1920s-1930s), a lithographic stone, framed
                    broadsides and manuscripts, Bewick wood-engraved blocks, and a desk-top display
                    holder.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>