<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Russell Weigley papers <date type="inclusive">1962-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Russell Weigley papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2090</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>31 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1962-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Russell F. Weigley (1930-2004) was a noted military historian. His research and
                    teaching interests centered on American and world military history, World War
                    II, and the American Civil War. Weigley taught at Penn from 1956 to 1958, and
                    from 1958 to 1962 at Drexel University. He then joined the faculty at Temple
                    University as an associate professor and remained until his retirement in 1999
                    as Distinguished University Professor. He was also a visiting professor at
                    Dartmouth College and the U.S. Army War College at Carlisle, Pennsylvania.
                    Weigley's graduate teaching emphasized military history defined in a broadly
                    comprehensive way, including operational, combat history but also extending to
                    the larger issues of war and its significance; to the history of ideas about
                    war, peace, and the armed forces; and to the place of the soldier in the state
                    and in society. His books included The American Way of War: A History of United
                    States Military Strategy and Policy (1973), Towards an American Army: Military
                    Thought from Washington to Marshall (1962), and Eisenhower's Lieutenants: The
                    Campaign of France and Germany, 1944-1945 (1981).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of papers related to Weigley's academic and professional
                    career. Materials include: incoming and outgoing correspondence with students,
                    colleagues, editors of publications, and members of historical/military history
                    organizations; typescripts, lightly annotated; lecture notes, programs and
                    announcements for lectures; reader/reviewer reports; papers, articles,
                    dissertations by others, and research materials; course materials such as exams
                    and syllabi; letters of recommendation; departmental reports, class lists,
                    minutes of committees (tenure, university policy), and records of his
                    involvement with the Middle States Accreditation Committee at Temple; videos on
                    historical subjects; and documentation related to various topics, such as a
                    medal of honor for Theodore Roosevelt, a "History of Philadelphia Project",
                    and World War II memorials.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>