<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Ruth Wright Hayre collection of Richard Robert Wright papers <date type="inclusive">1840-1971</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1920-1971</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Ruth Wright Hayre collection of Richard Robert Wright
                    papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2255</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1840-1971</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1920-1971</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Richard Robert Wright, Jr. (1878-1967) was a bishop of the African Methodist
                    Episcopal (A.M.E.) Church. He served as editor of the Christian Recorder,
                    business manager of the A.M.E. Book Concern, and president of Wilberforce
                    University. He was well known for his literary works in A.M.E. Church history
                    and American sociology. Ruth Wright-Hayre (1910-1998), the daughter of R.R.
                    Wright, Jr., was the first full-time African American teacher in the
                    Philadelphia public school system, the first African American senior high school
                    principal, as well as the first female president of the Philadelphia Board of
                    Education. For her advocacy programs in support of urban teenagers in
                    Philadelphia, Ms. Hayre received honors and awards from dozens of local and
                    national organizations, including the University of Pennsylvania and the NAACP.
                    Her memoir, written with Alexis Moore and Ed Bradley, is entitled Tell Them We
                    Are Rising: A Memoir of Faith in Education.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection documenting the career of R.R. Wright, Jr. as a bishop of
                    the A.M.E. Church and as a professor and president of Wilberforce University and
                    to his involvement in politics. Materials in the collection include: newspaper
                    articles by and about Wright (1936-1966), scrapbooks of news clippings, and
                    printed material related to church activities and to the presidential campaigns
                    of 1936 and 1940; a photo album from Wilberforce University and miscellaneous
                    photographs; printed programs, reports, brochures, newsletters and magazines;
                    bound copies of the Christian Recorder (1943-1947); announcements for church,
                    cultural, and political programs and events; correspondence related to and from
                    R.R. Wright and the General Board of the church, related to church activities
                    and finances; a small number of financial records, including receipts, check
                    stubs, and a ledger; The collection also includes movies from South Africa,
                    Haiti, Cuba, St. Croix, and Santo Domingo.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">African Methodist Episcopal Church.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Wilberforce University.</corpname>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Wright, Richard R. (Richard Robert), b.
                    1878.</persname>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>