<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Safe Energy Communication Council records <date type="inclusive">1980-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Safe Energy Communication Council records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2081</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>63 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1980-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Safe Energy Communication Council (SECC) was a national, non-profit council of
                    ten environmental and public interest media groups. Founded in 1980, SECC
                    educated the public and the media about energy efficiency and renewable energy's
                    potential to produce a larger share of our nation's energy, as well as the
                    economic and environmental liabilities of nuclear power. SECC provided local,
                    state, and national organizations with technical assistance through media skills
                    training and outreach strategies.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The records of this now defunct group include: press releases; correspondence and
                    proposals related to fundraising; public opinion polls on nuclear power;
                    materials related to various campaigns, including the ALMR (Advanced Light
                    Metals Reactor) and Ohio/Sacramento Municipal Utilities Department campaigns;
                    financial records; meeting minutes of the board of directors (on paper and on
                    audio cassette); PSAs and [promotional/educational] video and audio recordings
                    and slide presentations; cassette and video recordings of meetings and events;
                    press clippings; letters to the editors of various publications; media kits; and
                    SECC publications.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>