<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Settlement Music School records <date type="inclusive">1911-1988</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Urban Archives</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Settlement Music School records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC1116</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Urban Archives<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>34.66 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1911-1988</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Settlement Music School is a private organization whose purpose is to provide
                    music instruction for children and adults regardless of ability to pay. In its
                    early years a major function was to assist immigrants in finding employment. The
                    school was incorporated in 1913, and moved into its present building on Queen
                    Street in 1917. Branches in Germantown and Frankford were established in 1951.
                    Although founded primarily for the benefit of school-aged children, Settlement
                    developed a conservatory division offering pre-professional training that was of
                    sufficient stature to serve as the nucleus of the Curtis Institute of Music,
                    established in 1924.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of records, sound, and visual recordings related to
                    Settlement Music School and various performances. Administrative records include
                    Board and Executive Committee minutes (primarily from 1975-1986, but with
                    miscellaneous older minutes), reports, copies of the school's by-laws, and
                    memoranda. There is correspondence and memoranda from the school's directors and
                    other school staff. Teaching materials include: course lists and syllabi;
                    teachers' timesheets; and student records, such as registration forms,
                    schedules, grade sheets, scholarship application letters, attendance and absence
                    records. Performance- and event-related materials include: correspondence and
                    memoranda, schedules, programs, guest lists, and other planning records, as well
                    as 19 boxes of audio reels of performances, and some radio spots, 1955-1987.
                    Many of the reels are accompanied by printed concert programs. The collection
                    also includes several films and video recordings. There are a number of printed
                    and publicity materials, such as brochures, clippings and press releases from
                    Settlement Music School and miscellaneous printed materials from conferences and
                    other community organizations. The collection also includes a letterfile box of
                    correspondence of James P. Carson, Secretary of the Carson College for Orphan
                    Girls.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 957</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>