<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Seven Days records <date type="inclusive">1974-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Seven Days records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2084</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>23.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1974-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Seven Days first appeared in 1975 under the direction of David Dellinger, a
                    defendant in the Chicago Seven trial and a veteran of the 1960s political
                    protest movement, and was published until 1980 as an alternative weekly news
                    magazine, providing a voice for the American Left. The magazine achieved a
                    circulation of 40,000 without corporate advertising.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The records of this alternative political periodical, published in the 1970s,
                    include correspondence with writers and readers, financial records, memoranda,
                    article manuscripts, editorial files, press releases, reprints, reports,
                    newspaper clippings, photographs, cartoons brochures, flyers, and book catalogs.
                    These materials document the social and political concerns of its editor, David
                    Dellinger, and the 1960s political activist, including issues such as civil
                    rights, abortion, draft resistance, migrant labor, public housing, alternative
                    life styles, and American foreign policy in Africa, Vietnam, Central America,
                    and the Middle East. The most prominent correspondents include Peter Biskind,
                    Virginia Blaisdell, Eva Cockcroft, Elizabeth Hess, George McGovern, William
                    Reich, Peggy Somers, Mike Shuster, Jim Woodward, and Peter Wollheim. The records
                    also include a portion of Dellinger's papers, which relate to the publication of
                    Seven Days. Temple University holds other collections concerning American
                    social/political activism, 1960-1985.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>