<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sigma Pi Phi Alpha Boule Chapter records <date type="inclusive">1908-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sigma Pi Phi Alpha Boule Chapter records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2257</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1908-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Sigma Pi Phi is generally considered to be the first African-American
                    Greek-lettered organization. Sigma Pi Phi was founded in Philadelphia, in 1904.
                    Sigma Pi Phi, also known as the Boulé ("council of noblemen"), has over 5,000
                    members and 112 chapters throughout the United States and the West Indies.
                    Unlike many other fraternities, it does not have any college chapters, and its
                    members already have received college and professional degrees at the time of
                    their induction. Shortly after the establishedment of the fraternity, the
                    founders looked to other cities in which to expand the fraternity and thus
                    establish a national organization. The Philadelphia chapter became known as
                    Alpha Boulé, with subsequent chapters named Beta Boulé, Gamma Boulé, and so on.
                    The founders of the fraternity include Henry M. Minton and Algernon B.
                    Jackson.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains records related to the Alpha Boule chapter of the Sigma
                    Pi Phi fraternity. Materials include: minutes (1956-1992, with some gaps);
                    correspondence; annual reports; financial records; photographs; governance
                    documents such as constitution and bylaws; guidelines for rituals and
                    ceremonies; a scrapbook of early correspondence, minutes, and other documents;
                    curriculum vitae of members; and Alpha Boule stationery. There is correspondence
                    and other documents from: Henry M. Minton, Daniel B. Taylor, Jr., Melvin Chisum,
                    and E. Theodore Jones. The collection also includes taped interviews of members
                    of the fraternity conducted by Dr. Melvin J. Chisum from 1986-1988.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">African American fraternal organizations.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">African Americans--Education (Higher)</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Greek letter
                    societies--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Bylaws</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Constitutions</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Financial records</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Interviews</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Sound recordings</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>