<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Socialist Review records <date type="inclusive">1968-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Socialist Review records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2086</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>74.9 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1968-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Socialist Review is a left-wing political and cultural journal. It began
                    publication in January 1970 as Socialist Revolution, led by New Left historian
                    James Weinstein and edited by the collective Agenda Publishing Company in San
                    Francisco. In 1977 the California collective merged with collectives in Boston
                    and New York and the name of the periodical changed to Socialist Review. During
                    this time editorial duties passed to David Plotke of Yale and Jeffrey Escoffier.
                    Over time Nancy Chodorow, author of The Reproduction of Mothering and Howard
                    Winant, co-author of Racial Formation in the United States, participated in the
                    collective. In 2002 the journal's name was changed again, to Radical Society: A
                    Review of Culture and Politics.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The archives of this 1970s leftist periodical includes correspondence,
                    interviews, financial records, article drafts, newspaper clippings, and
                    photographs. The materials represent both the Socialist Review and its
                    predecessor, Socialist Revolution. The collection includes a detailed index of
                    Numbers 1-96 and contributors, as well as unpublished manuscripts. The published
                    manuscripts document issues such as feminism, gay rights, American labor laws
                    and legislation, environmental protection, nuclear disarmament, socialism in the
                    United States and France, and women's rights. The prominent correspondents
                    include Nancy Chodorow, Noam Chomsky, Michel Foucault, Karl E. Klare, David
                    Plotke, Albert Szymanski, James Weinstein, and Eli Zaretsky. There are also
                    meeting minutes that note the editorial board's discussions of politics,
                    strategy for the journal, and editorial decisions; financial documentation
                    including budgets, grant proposals and reports, fundraising, insurance and tax
                    information, and cash receipts and disbursements; copies of Socialist Revolution
                    and Socialist Review (complete from vol. 1 #1, 1970, to vol. 19, # 3, 1989); and
                    illustrations, and ad copy.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>