<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Tabb Bishop papers <date type="inclusive">1996-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Tabb Bishop papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2262</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Charles L. Blockson Afro-American Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1996-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Tabb Bishop was a lobbyist with the Philadelphia-based consulting firm S. R.
                    Wojdak &amp; Associates, where he worked on issues related to Philadelphia city
                    government until 2002. Prior to joining the firm, he served as executive
                    director of the Philadelphia Delegation in the Pennsylvania House of
                    Representatives and worked on several major policy initiatives involving
                    economic development, public transportation, housing, education, and
                    environmental justice. Bishop served as Deputy Chief of Staff at Temple
                    University from 2002 to 2007. In 2007 he left Temple to assume the newly created
                    position as director of public policy for Verizon Philadelphia.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers related to Tabb Bishop's work as a lobbyist for
                    S.R. Wojdak Associates. The issues on which Bishop worked included housing,
                    predatory lending, a proposed new football stadium, and a ban on sales of spray
                    paint to minors. Materials in the collection include: reports and position
                    statements; reference materials on issues; correspondence and memos; contact
                    information, such as business cards, telephone directories, and lists of members
                    of Mayor John Street's cabinet and various government committees; Bishop's
                    appointment calendars for 1996 and 2001; receipts; a video, possibly of an
                    interview with a journalist; and several artifacts.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Housing--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Loans--Corrupt practices.</subject>
                <geogname encodinganalog="651">Philadelphia (Pa.)--Politics and
                    government.</geogname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>