<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Temple University Trustees records <date type="inclusive">1893-1940</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Temple University Trustees records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2053</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1893-1940</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The original charter of 1888 entrusted the management of Temple College to 13
                    members of the Board of Trustees. An amendment to the charter in 1907 increased
                    the number of trustees to 25 and included the Governor of Pennsylvania and the
                    Mayor of Philadelphia as ex-officio members. Today the Board of Trustees is
                    comprised of 36 voting members, 24 of whom are elected and 12 of whom are
                    appointed by officials of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. In addition to its
                    36 members, the Governor of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, the Secretary of
                    Education of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, and the Mayor of the City of
                    Philadelphia serve as non-voting Trustees.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains records related to the early history and governance of
                    Temple University. The collection includes correspondence and early legal
                    documents such as deeds, bonds, constitution and bylaws, and mortgage
                    agreements. The collection also includes transcripts of hearings, memos and
                    minutes, correspondence, and a scrapbook of newspaper clippings related to
                    concerns about the Dean of the Medical School and the dismissal of one of the
                    faculty members at the Medical School (and subsequent resignation of several
                    Trustees). There is correspondence of three Board secretaries -- Edwin Hoffman
                    (incoming only), Grant Osborne (incoming and outgoing), and George Welsh
                    (incoming and outgoing) -- relating to faculty, academic unit, facilities, and
                    other matters. Elmer Brown correspondence (incoming and outgoing) relates to
                    issues addressed during his tenure as Vice President of the board. There are
                    also various printed materials related to Samaritan Hospital, Garretson Hospital
                    and other Temple affiliates and activities.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>