<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>The Other Side magazine records <date type="inclusive">1965-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Urban Archives</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">The Other Side magazine records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC315</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Urban Archives<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>36 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1965-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Other Side magazine, a progressive Christian publication that addressed
                    social justice issues such as race, economic justice, gender, and gay and
                    lesbian concerns, launched in 1965 as Freedom Now. It published its last issue
                    in September 2004. The magazine was originally published by Anne and Fred
                    Alexander, and edited for many years by Dee Dee Risher.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains administrative and editorial files, as well as printed
                    and audio materials related to The Other Side and Freedom Now. Editorial, board,
                    and office files date largely from mid 1990s to 2004. Editorial files include:
                    meeting minutes and issue planning notes; author correspondence; contracts; some
                    manuscripts; circulation printouts; subscription lists; an article processing
                    manual and reprint request log; a notebook of manuscripts received, and several
                    reader surveys. There are subject files on a number of topics, such as abortion,
                    food, politics, prayer, spirituality, refugees, poverty, and transgender issues.
                    Board records contain meeting minutes, notes, memoranda, and long range planning
                    materials. Office files include budgets, staff meeting minutes, memoranda to
                    staff, and planning records for events. There is a complete run of issues of
                    both Freedom Now (1965-1969) and The Other Side (1969-2002), as well as
                    microfilm of The Other Side, 1986-2003. The collection contains issues of a
                    number of other independently published magazines, including The Post American,
                    Second Stone, The Door, and Open Hands. The collection includes awards and
                    plaques received by The Other Side, audio tapes of speeches and seminars, and
                    some computer disks. Some files are from Dee Dee Risher.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1009</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>