<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas Nelson &amp; Sons corporate minute books and ledgers <date type="inclusive">1871-1971</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas Nelson &amp; Sons corporate minute books and
                    ledgers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2088</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1871-1971</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Masnel Corporation, a publishing firm specializing in Bibles, was formerly known
                    as Thomas Nelson and Sons. The latter was established in 1870 and was
                    incorporated in 1903 as a New York Corporation. In 1931, Thomas Nelson and Sons
                    merged with Thomas Nelson &amp; Sons. The firm moved to New Jersey in 1958 and
                    was incorporated there. In 1969, the name and assets of Thomas Nelson and Sons
                    were sold and the new name became Masnel Corporation. Masnel Corporation
                    voluntarily dissolved itself as a New Jersey Corporation in 1970.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Records of Thomas Nelson and Sons including: incorporation certificates and
                    subsequent liquidation records, bank records, leases, appraisals and audits;
                    equipment records -- receipts and invoices for machinery including invoices for
                    the printing plates of The Revised Standard Version of The Bible; tax returns
                    filed from 1959 to 1968; payroll records and correspondence regarding union
                    arbitration. Holdings also include fourteen volumes of minutes of meetings of
                    Stockholders and Board of Directors; a volume of stock certificates; contracts;
                    balance sheets (1871-1948); and two corporate seals. There is a small number of
                    records related to the Masnel Corporation.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>