<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Tom Purdom papers <date type="inclusive">1965-1991</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Tom Purdom papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2079</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1965-1991</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas Edward Purdom (b. 1936) is a science fiction writer. His first science
                    fiction story appeared in the August, 1957 Fantastic Universe. Over the years,
                    he has published stories in all of the leading science fiction magazines and in
                    various anthologies, and his works have been translated into French, German,
                    Spanish, and Chinese. His titles include: I Want the Stars (1964), The Tree Lord
                    of Imeten (1966), Five Against Arlane (1967), The Barons of Behavior (1972), and
                    Reduction in Arms (1971). He lives in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Purdom was a
                    charter member of Science Fiction Writers of America and has served as that
                    organization's vice president and on its public relations and grievance
                    committees. In addition to writing science fiction, he also worked as a science
                    writer for the University of Pennsylvania News Bureau, and as an editor for
                    Doing It Right publications, which published safety and instructional manuals
                    which were distributed to high school vocational arts students around the
                    U.S.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscripts, correspondence, and papers of Tom Purdom.
                    Papers include typed manuscripts of a number of short stories, novels,
                    instructional guides, and nonfiction articles; galley proofs and typed drafts of
                    stories by various authors published in the anthology Adventures in Discovery;
                    professional correspondence with editors and fellow authors and some personal
                    correspondence; reference materials for his nonfiction writing projects;
                    clippings about various science-related topics; newspapers and magazine articles
                    on the 1969 moon walk. The collection also includes correspondence and other
                    materials related to the Science Fiction Writers of America, particularly
                    Purdom's work on the Public Relations and Grievance Committees and planning of
                    SWFA events, correspondence regarding a proposed non-fiction anthology on
                    science and science fiction, and a folder of material on bicycling as a form of
                    urban transportation.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>