<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Uriel G. Foa personal papers <date type="inclusive">1953-1989</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Uriel G. Foa personal papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2063</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953-1989</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Uriel G. Foa, a social psychologist and professor emeritus at Temple University,
                    was born in Parma, Italy, and received doctoral degrees from the University of
                    Parma and Hebrew University in Jerusalem. He was a co-founder and executive
                    director of the Institute of Applied Social Research in Jersualem and chairman
                    of the department of psychology at Bar-Ilan University before coming to the
                    United States in 1965. Dr. Foa, a specialist in interpersonal relations, joined
                    the Temple faculty in 1971. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Uriel G. Foa. Materials include
                    correspondence, reprints, manuscript notes and drafts of articles, copies of
                    articles by students and colleagues, grade books, research proposals, course
                    syllabi, curricula vitae, bibliographies, and teaching assessments. The
                    correspondence includes letters about publications (reprint requests,
                    correspondence with publishers, editors, and reviewers), arrangements for
                    conferences, letters of recommendation for Foa, letters from students. There is
                    a small batch of receipts and business cards from Foa's time in Israel. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>