<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>West Mount Airy Neighbors records <date type="inclusive">1977-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Urban Archives</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">West Mount Airy Neighbors records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC314</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Urban Archives<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>32.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>West Mt. Airy Neighbors is a Pennsylvania non-profit organization that was
                    founded in 1959 to create and sustain West Mt. Airy as a racially integrated
                    community. It was founded by George Schermer, the first Director of
                    Philadelphia’s Human Relations Commission, and other neighbors concerned about
                    white flight and block busting. Committees of the Associaton work on issues of
                    concern to the community, including planning, city services, community
                    relations, and housing. The current boundaries of the organization's service
                    area are Fairmount Park on the West, Cresheim Valley Road on the North, Johnson
                    Street on the South, and Germantown Avenue of the East.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes records of West Mount Airy Neighbors from the offices of
                    David T. Moore, Administrator, Laurie Beck Tarver, Executive Director, Nancy A.
                    Goldenberg, Executive Director, and Marilyn Shane, President. Records document
                    administrative, personnel and financial matters, the board of directors, event
                    planning, and the work of various committees, including Executive, Advisory,
                    Membership, Arts &amp; Culture, Zoning, Schools, and Beautification. The
                    Association's work on fundraising, publicity and development, volunteering,
                    community organizations, zoning, safety, beautification, housing, and roads is
                    documented through minutes, agendas, memoranda, notes, reports, and clippings. A
                    number of printed materials are present, including flyers, announcements,
                    posters, newsletters, and West Mount Airy community and business directories.
                    The collection also contains records related to various events, including Mount
                    Airy Day planning materials, 1983-2002, and materials related to the Pelham
                    Anniversary Celebration, 1992-1993. There are subject files on a variety of
                    topics, people, city offices and programs, and other community organizations.
                    The collection also contains several studies and reports, most notably a 1989
                    survey of neighbors and East Mount Airy Neighbors/West Mount Airy Neighbors
                    joint committee reports.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1002</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>