<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William J. Campbell Bookstore records <date type="inclusive">1833-1955</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William J. Campbell Bookstore records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2091</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>60 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1833-1955</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The William J. Campbell Bookstore, founded in 1850 in Philadelphia by John
                    Campbell, an English bookseller, also specialized in publishing local history
                    and legal tracts. In 1874 William J. Campbell assumed direction over operations
                    with the death of his father. In 1931 William's son John J. replaced his father
                    and served at the helm until the store closed in 1951. The firm was instrumental
                    in assembling the Franklin imprints collection at Yale and the Curtis Collection
                    at University of Pennsylvania. John J. Campbell's son is William M. Campbell.
                    William A.K. Martin (1817-1867) was a Philadelphia-born landscape, marine, and
                    historical painter, whose work, Palermo, was shown at the Pennsylvania Academy
                    in 1853. Henry A. Martin was a Philadelphia legal/naval print dealer. He was the
                    uncle of John J. Campbell, and the Campbell firm was one of his principal
                    clients. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The archives of the oldest family-operated bookstore in Philadelphia including
                    personal and business correspondence, clippings, financial records, day books,
                    legal documents, book catalogs, drawings, portrait engravings, maps,
                    photographs, pamphlets, advertisements, sheet music, glass negatives, notebooks,
                    postcards, newsletters, scrapbooks, brochures, and posters. The collection
                    reflects the family's interest in Americana, local history, and legal
                    literature. The collection contains the business papers of the founder, John
                    Campbell; the personal letters of William M. Campbell; the business
                    correspondence of William J. Campbell, 1895-1951, and his letterbooks,
                    1903-1925. As a noted publisher of Americana, Philadelphia/Pennsylvania history,
                    and legal literature, the collection also contains manuscripts, photographs,
                    brochures, and Campbell catalogs, 1866-1951. William J. Campbell was an officer
                    of the City History Society of Philadelphia and the collection includes four
                    boxes of materials such as organizational correspondence, newsletters,
                    postcards, clippings, and scrapbooks, primarily for the 1920s. The collection
                    also contains documents and photographs associated with Fairmount Park and
                    Germantown. Correspondents also include Frances Campbell. The collection also
                    contains two separate collections; the first, the correspondence of a
                    Philadelphia legal/naval print dealer, Henry A. Martin; and the second, the
                    correspondence of 19th century Philadelphia artist, William A.K. Martin and
                    various members of his family, including his father, Captain John Martin, and
                    his brother James F. Martin. The Henry A. Martin materials date from 1900 to
                    1927. The papers include a series of letters between Martin and the William J.
                    Campbell Bookstore. Much of the correspondence is from Martin to John J.
                    Campbell, and to William J. Campbell, from Chicago, Pittsburgh, Buffalo,
                    Detroit, Cleveland, and Washington, D.C., as Martin traveled on collecting
                    tours. Also included in the collection is family correspondence of William A.K.
                    Martin. There are letters from Martin, as well as from the painter's father,
                    Capt. John Martin; his brother, James F. Martin, a Philadelphia merchant dealing
                    in wheat, oil, sugar, mackerel, and iron; the painter's son, Wm. A.K. Martin,
                    Jr.; and a number of other relatives including Frances Martin and Eleanor
                    Furlong. W.A.K. Martin's interests in European painting and his relationship
                    with other artists in Nicaragua and Cuba are reflected in his letters. The
                    letters of W.A.K. Martin, the artist, span the years 1833-1866.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, University Archives: William James Campbell papers; Historical
                    Society of Pennsylvania: City History Society of Philadelphia papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>