<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>W. Wayne Babcock professional papers <date type="inclusive">1899-1971</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">W. Wayne Babcock professional papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2045</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.9 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1899-1971</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dr. W. Wayne Babcock spent most of his illustrious career at the Temple
                    University Medical School, where he came in 1903 at the request of Russell
                    Conwell, university president. Babcock remained the head of the Dept. of Surgery
                    for 40 years prior to retiring in 1943. Babcock published over 300 articles, as
                    well as a textbook on surgery for physicians and students, in 1928. Babcock's
                    most notable contribution to the field was his introduction of steel wire
                    sutures and spinal anesthesia. In 1947 Babcock received the Master Surgeon Award
                    from the International College of Physicians &amp; Surgeons, and in 1954 the AMA
                    presented him with the Distinguished Service Medal.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of this nationally prominent Philadelphia surgeon and medical educator
                    include manuscripts, lectures, speeches, correspondence, photographs, reports,
                    case files, awards, journal articles, audio tapes, and account books. The case
                    histories and account books provide documentation of his treatment of disease
                    and his relationship with his patients. The collection documents Babcock's
                    contributions to the surgical profession and his relationship to the American
                    Medical Association, the International College of Physicians &amp; Surgeons, and
                    the Babcock Surgical Society. There is a small amount of correspondence created
                    by his wife Marion. There is a small batch of letters to Dr. and Mrs. Babcock
                    from Fred H. Bloomhardt (a fellow surgeon from Philadelphia) from his time in
                    France during World War I. The collection also includes photographs from annual
                    meetings and dinners.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>