<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Youth Liberation records <date type="inclusive">1970-1981</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Temple University - Special Collections</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Youth Liberation records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TU-Sp.ACC2092</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Temple University - Special Collections<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>17.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1981</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Youth Liberation was an organization founded in 1971 by fifteen-year-old Keith
                    Hefner and other Ann Arbor teenagers. Its central aims included student control
                    of education, the free development of youth culture, and an end to
                    discrimination against youth, with related emphases on gay rights for young
                    people, environmentalism, and an end to the Vietnam War. Youth Liberation served
                    as a principal informational and organizational hub for a host of similar
                    efforts around the country, and also allied with older radicals in Ann Arbor-
                    and Detroit-area organizations such as the White Panther Party and the Human
                    Rights Party. The group's publications arm, the Youth Liberation Press, began in
                    1969 as a separate entity known as the High School Independent Press, based in
                    Chicago, Illinois. After a short stint from 1970-1972 in Houston, Texas, where
                    the press began publishing FPS, a news service for youth, the press moved to Ann
                    Arbor and merged with Youth Liberation of Ann Arbor. In addition to FPS, the
                    press put out several collections of essays in book and pamphlet format. Youth
                    Liberation functioned from Spring 1970 to Fall 1979, a when a crucial member
                    departed for New York City.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes both administrative records and published materials.
                    Administrative records of Youth Liberation and CHIPS include letters to readers,
                    reader and student newspaper questionnaires, mailing lists, and correspondence
                    from creators of student newspapers. The collection contains number of issues of
                    FPS, as well as text copy and reference materials for articles in FPS. The
                    collection also includes issues of many high school underground newspapers and
                    other youth publications (1970-1981). Titles include Youth Awareness Press,
                    Weekly Reefer, School Break, and the 5% Press.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Temple University,
                    Special Collections: CHIPS records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>