<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Anne Wertsner Wood slide collection <date type="inclusive">1940-1976</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Anne Wertsner Wood slide collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1852</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1940-1976</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Anne Wertsner Wood (1907-2004) was a horticulturist, writer and lecturer. She was
                    a graduate of Ambler College (now Temple University Ambler). For six years, in
                    the 1930s, Mrs. Wood headed the floriculture department at the Pennsylvania
                    School of Horticulture for Women. In 1949 she married Harry Wood, a widower with
                    two children who was horticulturist and grounds superintendent at Swarthmore
                    College. The couple gardened at their home in Swarthmore. For 16 years Mrs. Wood
                    was field secretary at the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society, advising
                    neighborhood gardeners. From 1958 to 1988 she conducted garden tours all over
                    the world and lectured on gardening and flower arranging. She was the author of
                    The Flower Show Guide and Make Your Own Merry Christmas.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of slides gathered by Anne Wertsner Wood of gardens,
                    nurseries, flowers, plants, and people in Europe and the United States from 1940
                    to 1976. The collection also includes slides of Christmas decorations,
                    Philadelphia gardens and prominent Philadelphians, and people associated with
                    the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society. Most of the slides are in cardboard
                    mounts, but there are also a few glass mounts.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Gardens--Europe.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Gardens--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia Region.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Gardens--United States.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Slides (Photographs)</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society: John Wister slide collection and Philadelphia gardens
                    slide collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>