<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Board of Directors of Horticultural Hall minutes <date type="inclusive">1866-1909</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Board of Directors of Horticultural Hall
                    minutes</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1844</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1866-1909</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Pennsylvania Horticultural Society is America’s first horticultural society
                    and was formed in 1827 as a not-for-profit membership organization. The
                    Committee on a New Hall was established in 1865 by D. Rodney King, the president
                    of the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society. This committee was charged with
                    raising funds for the construction of the society's first Horticultural Hall. In
                    1866, King appointed directors of the new Horticultural Hall. The board included
                    King, W.L. Schaffer, and Henry A. Dreer. The first Horticultural Hall was lost
                    to fire in 1881. A new hall was completed in 1882; this building burned down in
                    1893. The society's third Horticultural Hall was completed in 1896. The third
                    Hall was sold in 1917. Much of the work of the board was carried out by the
                    Building and Finance committees, which reported their progress at monthly
                    meetings of the board. There were annual meetings and special meetings for the
                    stockholders of Horticultural Hall.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the minutes of the Board of Directors of
                    Horticultural Hall, 1866-1881 and 1887-1909. The minutes document the monthly
                    meetings of the board, which oversaw the planning, construction, and maintenance
                    of the first Horticultural Hall. There are some minutes that relate to the
                    second and the third Horticultural Halls. The minutes include reports from the
                    Building committee, as well as some financial information about rental income
                    for the hall and records of some of its expenses. In addition to minutes of
                    monthly meetings, the first volume includes the group's by-laws and minutes of
                    annual and special meetings of stockholders (1866-1876).</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Exhibition buildings--Pennsylvania.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>