<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>J. Liddon Pennock collection <date type="inclusive">1901-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">J. Liddon Pennock collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1856</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1901-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>J. Liddon Pennock (1913-2003) was a noted Philadelphia horticultural and floral
                    designer. For many years, he ran his family's business, a Center City flower
                    shop that provided floral decorations for countless society weddings as well as
                    the Nixon White House. In 1966, Pennock turned the business over to his
                    employees and focused his energies on Meadowbrook Farm, his 25-acre estate,
                    where he established a successful retail nursery and garden shop. He joined the
                    Council of the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society in 1947, and served as its
                    president from 1954-1957. He was actively involved with the Philadelphia Flower
                    Show, both as an exhibitor and as an advisor. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials collected by and about J. Liddon Pennock. Items
                    include: printed volumes on gardening and landscape design, several inscribed by
                    the authors or givers; papers related to his estate Meadowbrook and the bequest
                    of that estate to the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society, including appraisals
                    of the furnishings and an auction catalog; a scrapbook compiled by the staff of
                    the Morris Arboretum for his 80th birthday, which includes photos, personal
                    letters, and information on the naming of a new variety of Enkianthus perulatus
                    "J.L. Pennock"; photos and slides of Pennock, the interior and gardens of
                    Meadowbrook, and other gardens; a scrapbook on the 1971 wedding of Tricia Nixon
                    and Edward Cox, for which Pennock designed the flowers; his bible; copies of a
                    1993 management contract for the running of the nursery and plant sales business
                    at Meadowbrook; a genealogical chart of the Pennock family; and artifacts,
                    including his library seal, protractors and stencils.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Meadowbrook Farm (Meadowbrook, Pa.)</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Gardens--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia Region.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Horticulturists.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Genealogies.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Slides (Photographs)</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>