<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Wister slide collection <date type="inclusive">1930-1940</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Wister slide collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1853</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.29 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1930-1940</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John C. Wister (1887-1982) was a landscape architect. He graduated from Harvard
                    University and studied at the Harvard School of Landscape Architecture and the
                    New Jersey Agricultural College. He served in Europe during World War I, and in
                    his spare time visited gardens and leading horticulturists. He was one of the
                    founders and the first president of the American Iris Society, and served as
                    secretary of the American Rose Society for many years. He belonged to many other
                    horticultural, scientific, and conservation organizations. He was the first
                    director of the Arthur Hoyt Horticultural Foundation, and designed and created
                    the 240-acre public garden at Swarthmore College. He was the author of four
                    books: The Iris, Lilac Culture, Bulbs for American Gardens, and Four Seasons in
                    Your Garden.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The John Wister slide collection comprises two series of color lantern slides:
                    The Gardeners, photographs of suburban Philadelphia gardens, identified by name
                    of property owners; and a general collection that includes views of gardens,
                    sights, and specific plants from Europe and the U.S. There are 35mm slide
                    reproductions of many of the lantern slides in the collection.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Gardens--Europe.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Gardens--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia Region.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Lantern slides.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Slides (Photographs)</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society: Philadelphia gardens collection, Anne Wertsner Wood slide
                    collection, and Pennsylvania Horticultural Society glass plate slides and
                    negatives collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>