<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Letitia E. Wright research materials for "Colonial garden at
                        Stenton described in old letters" <date type="inclusive">1911-1921</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Letitia E. Wright research materials for "Colonial garden
                    at Stenton described in old letters"</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1838</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1911-1921</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Mrs. William Redwood Wright was born Letitia Ellicott Carpenter on April 7, 1861.
                    She was the daughter of George Washington Carpenter and Mary Rodman Fisher, and
                    was a direct descendent of James Logan, who left England in the late seventeenth
                    century to settle in the colonies as William Penn’s Chief Secretary and
                    Counselor. She was an expert on wildflowers, and was involved in several
                    horticultural and conservation organizations, including the First Garden Club of
                    Philadelphia, of which she was a charter member. She is noted for her careful
                    study and restoration of the Stenton Garden, originally planted by James Logan.
                    Her monograph, "Colonial Garden at Stenton described in Old Letters," was
                    published by the Site and Relic Society of Germantown in 1915.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of typescript research notes, transcripts of letters, and
                    drafts of Letitia E. Wright's article on James Logan and the gardens at Stenton.
                    Included are transcripts of letters between John and Anna Blackburne and James
                    Logan, and between John Forthergill and William Logan, and transcripts of plant
                    and seed lists. There are various drafts and fragments of drafts of Wright's
                    article, "Colonial Garden at Stenton described in Old Letters." The collection
                    also includes a mounted photo-reproduction of a letter from Anna Blackburne,
                    notebooks kept by Wright during her research for this article, a typescript list
                    of botanical books in the Logan Library, lists of plants at other gardens,
                    manuscript and typescript descriptions of plants, and a manuscript transcription
                    of A Catalogue of the Plants in the Garden of John Blackburne, Esq.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Gardens--History--18th century.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Gardens--United States--History.</subject>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Logan family papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>