<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society slide collection <date type="inclusive">1958-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society slide
                    collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1829</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>68.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1958-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Pennsylvania Horticultural Society is America’s first horticultural society
                    and was formed in 1827 as a not-for-profit membership organization. The
                    Pennsylvania Horticultural Society offers lectures and workshops, publishes the
                    magazine Green Scene, and hosts the yearly Philadelphia Flower Show. First held
                    in 1829, the Philadelphia Flower Show has grown to be the world's largest indoor
                    flower exhibition. Proceeds from the Philadelphia Flower Show support the
                    Pennsylvania Horticultural Society's urban greening program, Philadelphia Green,
                    which supports the development and ongoing care of community gardens,
                    neighborhood parks and high-profile public green spaces in Philadelphia. In
                    1975, the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society launched the City Gardens Contest,
                    in which Philadelphia residents compete in several gardening categories. The
                    Pennsylvania Horticultural Society is also home to the McLean Library, a
                    collection of over 15,000 books on gardening and plant care, botany, and urban
                    greening.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection of slides (and some photographs) falls into four main groupings:
                    the Philadelphia Flower Show and other shows produced by the Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society; Pennsylvania Horticultural Society's urban greening
                    programs and city gardening projects and contests; Pennsylvania Horticultural
                    Society educational slide shows and garden tour slides; and Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society meetings, staff, and publicity material. Many of the
                    slides were donated to the archives by the PHS public relations department.
                    Slides documenting the Philadelphia Flower Show, from the early 1940s to the
                    late 1990s, comprise roughly 24 linear feet. The images include displays of
                    major exhibitors, individual entries of plants and floral arrangements, show
                    attendees and staff, awards, and show construction. Some sections of the Flower
                    Show slides are arranged by topic, and are more loosely arranged by year. These
                    materials include a photo and slide album of the construction and set-up of the
                    show, and transparencies of individual arrangements and blooms from the 1983 and
                    1989 shows. Other Pennsylvania Horticultural Society shows documented in the
                    collection are the Junior Flower Show (1981 to 1995), the Harvest Show (1982 to
                    1994), and the Chrysanthemum Show. Images of the society's urban greening
                    programs and Philadelphia garden projects make up approximately 37 linear feet
                    of the collection and include an album of slides of Philadelphia Green projects,
                    gardens in Norris Square, at City Hall, and the Azalea Garden in Fairmount Park.
                    The City Gardens contest images document contest entries from 1990 to 1997. The
                    slides are arranged alphabetically by the name of the contestant, and then
                    chronologically. There are also slides of gardens featured in "Portraits of
                    Philadelphia Gardens" by Louise and James Bush-Brown. The collection includes
                    several slide shows (about 1 linear feet of material), some with lecture notes.
                    Topics include garden tours conducted by members of the Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society in South Africa, the Pacific Northwest, and the Caribbean.
                    The history of the Philadelphia Flower Show is documented in a slide show
                    created by Ed Lindemann (the show's designer from 1984 to 2000). There is also a
                    slide show on the art of botanical illustration created by Tina Henry. Finally,
                    there are roughly two linear feet of slides and photographs documenting the
                    society's institutional activities and staff, including images of annual
                    meetings, the McLean Library, staff photographs, and a selection of slides
                    documenting a variety of the society's programs, events, members, and staff
                    assembled for publicity purposes.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="611">Philadelphia Flower Show.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Green (Program)</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Botanical illustration.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Flower shows--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Gardens--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia Region.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Horticulture--Societies, etc.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Urban renewal--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Slides (Photographs)</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society: Philadelphia Flower Show photographs and slides.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>