<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society artifacts <date type="inclusive">1851-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society artifacts</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1848</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1851-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Pennsylvania Horticultural Society is America’s first horticultural society
                    and was formed in 1827 as a not-for-profit membership organization. The
                    Pennsylvania Horticultural Society offers lectures and workshops, publishes the
                    magazine Green Scene, and hosts the yearly Philadelphia Flower Show. First held
                    in 1829, the Philadelphia Flower Show has grown to be the world's largest indoor
                    flower exhibition. Proceeds from the Philadelphia Flower Show support the
                    Pennsylvania Horticultural Society's urban greening program, Philadelphia Green,
                    which supports the development and ongoing care of community gardens,
                    neighborhood parks and high-profile public green spaces in Philadelphia. The
                    Pennsylvania Horticultural Society is also home to the McLean Library, a
                    collection of over 15,000 books on gardening and plant care, botany, and urban
                    greening.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of artifacts and memorabilia related to the Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society and the Philadelphia Flower Show. Items include: a
                    Pennsylvania Horticultural Society member's ceramic mug from 2006; a 1995 18th
                    Century Garden ornament and two 1994 Poinsettia glass Christmas ornaments,
                    accompanied by advertisements from Green Scene describing the ornaments; sets of
                    notecards depicting plates from Robert Thornton's Temple of Flora and other
                    horticultural images; and a seal of the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society.
                    Flower Show artifacts include: two seals from Philadelphia Flower Show, Inc.; a
                    brass plaque from the Flower Show; a cloth banner from the 175th anniversary
                    Flower Show in 2004; two keepsake ceramic rose figurines made by Boehm for the
                    Philadelphia Flower Show; and a silver cup awarded by the Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society to Jonathan Sherwood for his Camellia Isabell Hartley and
                    a published biography of Sarah Palmer Sherwood The collection also includes
                    approximately 25 medals awarded to individuals by the society for horticultural
                    achievements and by other gardening associations to the Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society. Medal recipients include Caleb Cope and James Boyd.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="611">Philadelphia Flower Show.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Horticulture--Societies, etc.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Artifacts.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Awards.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>