<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society library records <date type="inclusive">1829-1894</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society library
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1849</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1829-1894</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Pennsylvania Horticultural Society is America’s first horticultural society
                    and was formed in 1827 as a not-for-profit membership organization. The McLean
                    Library, formed shortly after the founding of the Pennsylvania Horticultural
                    Society, currently holds over 15,000 volumes on gardening and plant care,
                    botany, and urban greening. The collection serves the needs of amateur and
                    professional horticulturists, landscape architects, garden historians, and
                    researchers. It is used by the public and by the society's members and
                    volunteers. The collection supports the horticultural and urban greening
                    activities of the staff. The McLean Library's holdings include the Mary Helen
                    Wingate Lloyd Collection, which consists of significant European and American
                    gardening imprints from the 16th-20th centuries, and the Society's archives.
                </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>These volumes document the holdings and accounts of the Library of the
                    Pennsylvania Horticultural Society. Records include: an accession book, undated,
                    listing title, author, place of publication, date, and size for the first 531
                    volumes in the library's holdings; a library catalogue in manuscript from 1839,
                    which lists holdings alphabetically and numerically by accession number, and
                    which also contains some circulation records, memoranda of books donated to the
                    library (1829-1841), and minutes of the Council of the Society from 1831 to
                    1834; a library catalogue in manuscript from 1894, which lists holdings by
                    topic, by author, by title, and by accession number; two librarian's account
                    books (1839-1885 and 1839-1864), which record circulation of holdings among
                    members, income from appropriations from the Society's funds and library fines,
                    expenses (primarily book purchases), and memoranda relating to the establishment
                    of the library copied from the Society's minute books; and an inventory of the
                    Mary Helen Wingate Lloyd collection with bibliographic, provenance, and binding
                    information for each title. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Horticultural libraries.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Libraries--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Library catalogs.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Account books.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>