<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Flower Show photographs and slides <date type="inclusive">1927-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Flower Show photographs and slides</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1832</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>28.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1927-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Philadelphia Flower Show is the world's largest indoor flower exhibition,
                    encompassing 33 acres and drawing over 250,000 visitors annually. The
                    Philadelphia Flower Show was first held in 1829 in Masonic Hall on Chestnut
                    Street. From 1927 until the mid 1960s, management of the Flower Show was under
                    the auspices of Philadelphia Flower Show, Inc., a professional group of
                    nurserymen and growers. In 1964, Philadelphia Flower Show, Inc., because of
                    difficulties locating an exhibition space, decided to halt production of the
                    show for two years. The Pennsylvania Horticultural Society, under the direction
                    of Ernesta D. Ballard, feeling that yearly continuity of the show was necessary,
                    hosted the show in the 23rd Street Armory. In 1966 the show moved to the Civic
                    Center, and in 1968, the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society became the show's
                    official producer. In 1996 the Flower Show moved to its current location in the
                    Pennsylvania Convention Center.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of photographs, slides, and negatives from the Philadelphia
                    Flower Show, from 1927 to 2006. Photographs include general views of the
                    exhibition and its attendees, displays of major exhibitors, first through third
                    place winners for each judging of competitive classes, opening ceremonies, and
                    awards presentations. Notable figures in the photographs include Frank Rizzo,
                    Ernesta Ballard, and Grace Kelly. Also included are slides of the construction
                    of the exhibition in 1977.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Flower shows--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photograph albums.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Slides (Photographs)</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society: Pennsylvania Horticultural Society slide collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>