<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Flower Show minute books <date type="inclusive">1927-2005</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1927-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Pennsylvania Horticultural Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Flower Show minute books</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1847</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.42 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1927-2005</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1927-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Philadelphia Flower Show, currently the world's largest indoor flower
                    exhibition, was first held in 1829 in Masonic Hall on Chestnut Street. From 1927
                    until the mid 1960s, management of the Flower Show was under the auspices of
                    Philadelphia Flower Show, Inc., a professional group of nurserymen and growers.
                    In 1964, Philadelphia Flower Show, Inc., because of difficulties locating an
                    exhibition space, decided to halt production of the show for two years. The
                    Pennsylvania Horticultural Society, under the direction of Ernesta D. Ballard,
                    feeling that yearly continuity of the show was necessary, hosted the show in the
                    23rd Street Armory. In 1968, the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society became the
                    Flower Show's official producer.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of minutes of the Philadelphia Flower Show, Inc., from its
                    inception in 1927 to 1996, when it was reorganized with the Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society as its sole member. The collection includes the charter
                    and by-laws of the organization, minutes of monthly, annual, and special
                    meetings, and a small number of legal documents and correspondence. The minutes
                    of monthly meetings between 1927 and the mid-1960s record the planning of the
                    yearly Flower Show, and feature reports from the Hall Plan, Rose Exhibit,
                    Private Growers, Jurors, and Budget and Advertising committees, among others.
                    Minutes from the mid-1960s on discuss other activities of the group, primarily
                    the plan to build a new Horticultural Hall in Fairmount Park. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Pennsylvania Horticultural Society.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Flower shows--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Bylaws.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Pennsylvania
                    Horticultural Society: Philadelphia Flower Show financial records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>