<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Society for the Extension of University Teaching records
                            <date type="inclusive">1890-1892</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Society for the Extension of University Teaching
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1025</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1890-1892</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American Society for the Extension of University Teaching (originally known
                    as the Philadelphia Society for the Extension of University Teaching) was
                    founded in 1890 by William Pepper, Provost of the University of Pennsylvania.
                    The Society's aim was to extend educational opportunities to women and men who
                    were unable to attend a university. The Wagner Free Institute of Science became
                    involved in the University Extension movement early on in its development, with
                    Thomas Lynch Montgomery serving briefly as the local secretary for the
                    program.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of correspondence and speeches relating to the
                    activities of the American Society for the Extension of University Teaching in
                    Philadelphia from 1890 to 1892, including courses conducted at the Wagner Free
                    Institute of Science. Also included are a few items relating to specific
                    courses, such as an outline of a lecture and examination questions. Most of the
                    correspondence is addressed to Thomas Lynch Montgomery.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 91-020</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science: director's files (90-001 and 89-055) contain some further records on
                    the American Society for the Extension of University Teaching.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>