<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Annals of the Wagner Free Institute of Science <date type="inclusive">1855-1884</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Annals of the Wagner Free Institute of Science</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC970</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.10 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1855-1884</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Incorporated by William Wagner in 1855, the Wagner Free Institute is a natural
                    history museum and educational institution in Philadelphia that is dedicated to
                    providing free public education in the sciences. William Wagner originally
                    offered free lectures and classes in his home and at Spring Garden Hall. He
                    later constructed an Institute building, which opened to the public in 1865.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This volume is William Wagner's record of the founding and running of the Wagner
                    Free Institute of Science between 1855 and 1884. It includes a brief history of
                    the Wagner Free Institute of Science, and minutes of the meeting at which the
                    Institute was incorporated. The volume serves as a day book for the Institute,
                    with detailed entries of lectures delivered, records of attendance, lists of
                    faculty, gifts and purchases, and notes on the building and its maintenance. The
                    collection also includes letters from William Wagner to various members of the
                    Board of Trustees, which have been removed from the volume and are housed in a
                    separate folder.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 89-020</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science: William Wagner lectures (89-015) includes a series of Wagner's
                    lectures. These may correspond to lectures noted in the Annals.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>