<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Bulletin of the Wagner Free Institute of Science <date type="inclusive">1926-1958</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Bulletin of the Wagner Free Institute of
                    Science</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1182</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1926-1958</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Incorporated by William Wagner in 1855, the Wagner Free Institute is a natural
                    history museum and educational institution in Philadelphia that is dedicated to
                    providing free public education in the sciences.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Bulletin was published from 1926 until 1958. Volumes 1-4 are bimonthly.
                    Volumes 5-33 are quarterly. The first issue begins, "With this issue, the
                    Wagner Free Institute of Science of Philadelphia begins the publication of a
                    Bulletin announcing the results of scientific investigations under its auspices
                    and reports of educational work." Volumes 1-7 contain some or all of the
                    following sections: Announcements, Courses, Closing Exercises, Faculty and
                    Trustee Lists, Faculty Changes, Historical Note, Facilities for Instruction, In
                    Memoriam, Institute News and Notes, List of students receiving certificates,
                    Museum Notes, Museum Talks, Necrology, Personal Note, Publication Lists,
                    Research Laboratory Notes, Scientific Articles, Westbrook Lectures. These
                    sections contain news of the happenings at the Institute, new museum specimens
                    and exhibits, and studies in progress. Beginning with vol. 7, numbers 1, 2, and
                    4 typically contain one scientific article per issue. Institute news is never
                    included again. No. 2 is usually a synopsis of the Westbrook lecture series of
                    that year. No. 3 is the annual announcement (a.k.a. course catalog.) Benjamin
                    Franklin Howell wrote many of the articles, and they largely describe specimens
                    at Princeton University. Most articles are illustrated by photographs, maps,
                    graphs, or charts. The annual announcements are little changed through the
                    years. Beginning with vol. 6, the annual announcement contains brief resumes of
                    the faculty. Each announcement is illustrated with photographs of the building,
                    museum, and auditorium. Beginning with vol. 24, photographs of class field trips
                    are included. Bound copies are also available.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 98-049</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>