<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Eugene Bolt curatorial files and Mineral Catalogue projects <date type="inclusive">1989-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Eugene Bolt curatorial files and Mineral Catalogue
                    projects</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1185</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1989-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Incorporated by William Wagner in 1855, the Wagner Free Institute is a natural
                    history museum and educational institution in Philadelphia that is dedicated to
                    providing free public education in the sciences. Eugene A. Bolt was Curator at
                    the Wagner Free Institute of Science from 1989 to 1994. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of materials Bolt's office. Included are records that
                    document the research and implementation of the Mineral Collections Cataloging
                    project undertaken at the Wagner in 1989-1990. There are data collection
                    worksheets for 11 cases of mineral specimens, and a printout of an inventory for
                    one of the cases. Also included are correspondence and other documents from
                    1990-1994 concerning the transfer of the Academy of Natural Science's mineral
                    collection to the Wagner. Finally, there are newsletters and correspondence from
                    various local area mineralogical societies, and reprints and photocopies of
                    articles on mineralogy.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 98-053 and 98-055</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>