<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Leidy teaching charts <date type="inclusive">1870-1885</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Leidy teaching charts</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1047</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>9.66 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1870-1885</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Leidy (1823-1891) was one of the preeminent figures in the development of
                    American science in the nineteenth century. He was a physician, naturalist,
                    anatomist, and scientific illustrator. Following William Wagner's death in 1885,
                    Leidy assumed the role of President of the Faculty of the Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science, with special direction of the Biology Department. Leidy was Chairman
                    of the Board of Curators at the Academy of Natural Sciences in Philadelphia, and
                    is a central figure in that institution's history. He also taught courses at the
                    University of Pennsylvania and at Swarthmore College. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of 133 pencil, ink, and gouache drawings on cardboard
                    with canvas mountings, 1 lithographic print (O.C. Marsh), and 1 press-type on
                    cardboard chart of a later date. The teaching charts were constructed and used
                    by Joseph Leidy while he was a professor of natural history at Swarthmore
                    College (1870-1885). Although none of the charts are signed, most bear labels in
                    Leidy's hand and the images have been identified as being created or copied from
                    texts by him, while others possibly were copied under Leidy's supervision.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 92-005</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences: Multiple collections of Joseph Leidy records</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>