<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Willcox collection of fossil shell illustrations <date type="inclusive">1898-1898</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Willcox collection of fossil shell
                    illustrations</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC975</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.10 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1898-1898</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Willcox (1829-1918) was a noted geologist and a long-term member of the
                    Board of Trustees of the Wagner Free Institute of Science, serving as the
                    chairman of the Committee on the Museum from 1885 until his death.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This volume contains illustrations of 38 fossil shells collected by Joseph
                    Willcox. The original illustrations have been pasted into the volume. In his own
                    description from the title page of the book, Willcox says: "This book contains
                    original drawings of some of the fossil shells collected by me in North Carolina
                    and Florida. They were made with pen and ink by Dr. J.L. McConnell of
                    Washington, D.C. They have been reproduced in the plates of the Transactions of
                    the Wagner Free Institute of Science. Joseph Willcox. Philadelphia, May 26th,
                    1898." The volume contains index of all drawings, listing each shell's name and
                    where it was found. A letter from James B. [Secord] expressing admiration of
                    Willcox's and McConnell's work is pasted to the rear endpaper of the volume.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 89-045</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences: James C. McConnell drawings of fossil shells (Collection 303).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>