<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Leidy papers <date type="inclusive">1859-1891</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Leidy papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1022</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1859-1891</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Leidy (1823-1891) was one of the preeminent figures in the development of
                    American science in the nineteenth century. He was a physician, naturalist,
                    anatomist, and scientific illustrator. Following William Wagner's death in 1885,
                    Leidy assumed the role of President of the Faculty of the Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science, with special direction of the Biology Department. Leidy was Chairman
                    of the Board of Curators at the Academy of Natural Sciences in Philadelphia, and
                    is a central figure in that institution's history. He also taught courses at the
                    University of Pennsylvania and at Swarthmore College.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a miscellaneous collection of letters, newspaper clippings and reports.
                    Of note are 17 letters (1887-1890) from Leidy to Joseph Willcox concerning the
                    Institute's publications, collections, and general Institute business; news
                    clippings concerning Leidy's illness and death; a manuscript titled "Fossil
                    flora of Lagrange, Ala." (1866) by W. Spillman; and a manuscript titled "A
                    list of plants collected in the Minta Mts., and near Fort Bridges, Wyoming
                    Territory" by Leidy and revised by Thos. L. Porter (1872); as well as a report
                    written by Leidy to the Trustees of the Wagner Free Institute of Science in 1890
                    regarding his trip to Europe to purchase specimens.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 91-005</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences: Multiple collections of Joseph Leidy records</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>