<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Leidy letters and drawings <date type="inclusive">1845-1898</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Leidy letters and drawings</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC976</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1845-1898</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Leidy (1823-1891) was one of the preeminent figures in the development of
                    American science in the nineteenth century. He was a physician, naturalist,
                    anatomist, and scientific illustrator. Following William Wagner's death in 1885,
                    Leidy assumed the role of President of the Faculty of the Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science, with special direction of the Biology Department. Leidy was Chairman
                    of the Board of Curators at the Academy of Natural Sciences in Philadelphia, and
                    is a central figure in that institution's history. He also taught courses at the
                    University of Pennsylvania and at Swarthmore College.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains various drawings by Joseph Leidy and holograph letters
                    by Joseph Willcox and Joseph Leidy. The 89 drawings of various animal
                    structures, created between the mid 1840s and the mid 1870s, have been
                    reproduced in part in Leidy's Fresh-water rhizopods of North America (United
                    States Geological Survey, v. 12, 1879). The volume also contains Willcox's short
                    introduction, which is a recollection of the last days of Dr. Leidy's life.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 89-050</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science: Joseph Leidy pictorial material (91-001) is an unbound collection of
                    Leidy's drawings (mostly rhizopods, but some other zoological illustrations);
                    Academy of Natural Sciences: multiple collections of Joseph Leidy records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>