<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert Chambers collection relating to William Wagner and the
                        history of the Wagner Free Institute of Science <date type="inclusive">1798-1980</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1820-1910</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert Chambers collection relating to William Wagner and
                    the history of the Wagner Free Institute of Science</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1002</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1798-1980</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1820-1910</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection of documents relates chiefly to William Wagner (1796-1885), his
                    businesses, and the Wagner Free Institute of Science gathered from Institute
                    records by Robert Chambers, the Institute's director from 1945-1980. Papers and
                    records on the life of William Wagner document his employ as a supercargo for
                    Stephen Girard from 1810-1819; his businesses Snowden &amp; Wagner from
                    1819-1825 and the Lennoxville Steam Saw Mill from 1825-1828; his collection of
                    specimens and writings; as well as his marriages to Caroline Moore Say and
                    Louisa Binney (1814-1898). Documents of the Wagner Free Institute of Science
                    chiefly cover its early founding by William Wagner and its expansion after his
                    death. The bulk of the records, 1884-1900, concern the Institute's finances,
                    development of the museum, university extension program, establishment of a
                    branch of the Free Library of Philadelphia, museum and library acquisitions, and
                    early publication history of the Transactions of the Wagner Free Institute of
                    Science. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 90-015 </p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science: William Wagner European travel journal (89-005); William Wagner
                    personal papers (89-010 and 93-004); William Wagner and personal papers (98-051)
                    contains some personal correspondence of William Wagner; William Wagner business
                    papers (89-001) is the largest accumulation of Snowden and Wagner and William
                    Wagner, Merchant materials.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>