<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Samuel George Gordon papers <date type="inclusive">1913-1947</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Samuel George Gordon papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1003</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.48 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1913-1947</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Mineralogist, crystallographer, lecturer, collector, research scientist, and
                    member of the staff of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, Samuel
                    Gordon took his first course in mineralogy with Edgar T. Wherry at the Wagner
                    Free Institute of Science, 1911-12. He went on to train himself by private
                    study, taking special courses at the University of Pennsylvania and elsewhere.
                    This training culminated in a six months sojourn in Heidelberg, Germany, where
                    he studied with Victor Goldschmidt, 1926-27. His specialized interest in
                    crystallography resulted in the publication, with Victor Goldschmidt as senior
                    author, of the Crystallographic Tables, as the Academy of Natural Science of
                    Philadelphia Special Publication, no. 2. Gordon studied possible collecting
                    localities where minerals could be found to round out the Academy's Vaux
                    collections. His expeditions included trips to the Andes of Peru, Bolivia, and
                    Chile, 1921; the Julianehaab District of Greenland, 1923; Bolivia and Chile,
                    1925; and the Chilean Expedition of 1938.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of several parts. Collection 90-020 contains 1)
                    professional correspondence, alphabetically arranged, chiefly for the years
                    1933-1947; 2) Gordon's annotated thesis for the Philadelphia Mineralogical
                    Society titled "Classification of Minerals" (1913); 3) notebooks titled
                    "Krystall Messung I," "Krystall Messung II" (1926), "Lothrorh Practicum,"
                    and one untitled notebook of mineralogical tables, all of these notebooks are in
                    German; 4) materials related to Gordon's collecting expeditions, including
                    visas, general correspondence, expense sheets, an herbarium sheet prepared by
                    Harry Trudell bearing the title with blue pencil to which a photograph of Gordon
                    and motorcycle have been affixed; 5) miscellaneous materials including
                    photographs of jade in an envelope titled "Jade by Samuel Gordon for
                    Frontiers." Collection 92-013 consists of proof sheets for an article entitled
                    "Mineralogy of Pennsylvania," published by the Academy of Natural Sciences,
                    1922. The proof sheets are lightly annotated and several pages are missing.
                    Collection 92-014 is a reprint of Gordon's "Penroseite and Trudellite: two new
                    minerals," first published in the Proceedings of the Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia, Vol. LXXVII, 1925, pages 317-324.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 90-020; 92-013; 92-014</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science: other Gordon reprints are in the Harry W. Trudell papers
                    (92-017).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>