<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wagner Free Institute of Science printer's plates <date type="inclusive">1883-1883</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wagner Free Institute of Science printer's
                    plates</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1188</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1883-1883</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Incorporated by William Wagner in 1855, the Wagner Free Institute is a natural
                    history museum and educational institution in Philadelphia that is dedicated to
                    providing free public education in the sciences. William Wagner originally
                    offered free lectures and classes in his home and at Spring Garden Hall. He
                    later constructed an Institute building, which opened to the public in 1865.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of a set of 12 printing plates, on copper mounted onto
                    wooden blocks. These plates were used to print various documents, including the
                    1883 announcements of the Wagner Free Institute of Science, rosters of the
                    trustees and faculty, the Institute's Act of Incorporation, and a record of the
                    transfer of deed from William and Louisa Wagner to the Institute. Three plates
                    are dated 1883; the others are undated.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 98-059</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>