<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wagner Free Institute of Science director's journal <date type="inclusive">1956-1981</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wagner Free Institute of Science director's
                    journal</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1157</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.01 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1956-1981</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Incorporated by William Wagner in 1855, the Wagner Free Institute is a natural
                    history museum and educational institution in Philadelphia that is dedicated to
                    providing free public education in the sciences. William Wagner originally
                    offered free lectures and classes in his home and at Spring Garden Hall. He
                    later constructed an Institute building, which opened to the public in 1865. The
                    Institute's current programs and services include adult and children's
                    programming offered onsite and at locations around Philadelphia, the Institute's
                    library and archival collections, and a permanent display of the museum's
                    specimen collections. Since 1891, the specimen collections have been displayed
                    according to Darwinian principles of evolution, the organizational scheme
                    selected by renowned biologist Joseph Leidy during his tenure as head of the
                    Institute's scientific and educational programs in the late 19th century.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of two notebooks kept from 1956 and 1981, possibly by
                    Robert Chambers, Director of the Wagner Free Institute of Science from
                    1945-1980. In these books, the writer notes building maintenance and employee
                    matters, notable visits, installation of exhibits, open houses and other special
                    events held at the Institute, and incidents involving break-ins, vandalism, and
                    unruly patrons.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Wagner Free Institute of Science.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Natural history libraries.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Natural history museums.</subject>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 97-028</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>