<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wagner Free Institute of Science director's files <date type="inclusive">1910-1981</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wagner Free Institute of Science director's
                    files</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC004</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1981</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Incorporated by William Wagner in 1855, the Wagner Free Institute is a natural
                    history museum and educational institution in Philadelphia that is dedicated to
                    providing free public education in the sciences. William Wagner originally
                    offered free lectures and classes in his home and at Spring Garden Hall. He
                    later constructed an Institute building, which opened to the public in 1865. The
                    Institute's current programs and services include adult and children's
                    programming offered onsite and at locations around Philadelphia, the Institute's
                    library and archival collections, and a permanent display of the museum's
                    specimen collections. Since 1891, the specimen collections have been displayed
                    according to Darwinian principles of evolution, the organizational scheme
                    selected by renowned biologist Joseph Leidy during his tenure as head of the
                    Institute's scientific and educational programs in the late 19th century. During
                    the time period covered by these records, the Director of the Wagner Free
                    Institute of Science oversaw the daily running of the Institute's educational,
                    library, and museum activities. The Director reported to the Board of Trustees,
                    and that body made decisions about the Institute's financial expenditures,
                    policies, and programs. Administrators during the time period covered by this
                    collection include: John Rothermel, Director, 1903-1924; Carl Boyer, Curator,
                    1924-1928, and Director, 1928-1945; and Robert Chambers, Director, 1945-1980.
                </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains committee reports on Finance and Property (1952-1981),
                    the Westbrook Free Lectureship (1910-1936), the Department of Chemistry
                    Endowment (1926-1929 and 1948, 1955), the Library (1939-1976), and the Museum
                    (1929-1980). It also includes reports of special committees, correspondence with
                    other organizations, other miscellaneous materials related to the Institute.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 00-02</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science: this collection includes several folders of Westbrook material which
                    relate to the Westbrook Free Lectureship (93-003). Other collections that
                    include significant amounts of director's records include: director's files and
                    business records (90-010), Actuary and Librarian records (91-040), director's
                    reports (98-045 and 00-01), and other director's files (90-001 and 89-055,
                    91-030, 91-035, 93-005, and 99-109).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>