<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wagner Free Institute of Science pictorial material <date type="inclusive">1896-1954</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wagner Free Institute of Science pictorial
                    material</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1191</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1896-1954</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Incorporated by William Wagner in 1855, the Wagner Free Institute is a natural
                    history museum and educational institution in Philadelphia that is dedicated to
                    providing free public education in the sciences. William Wagner originally
                    offered free lectures and classes in his home and at Spring Garden Hall. He
                    later constructed an Institute building, which opened to the public in 1865. The
                    Institute's current programs and services include adult and children's
                    programming offered onsite and at locations around Philadelphia, the Institute's
                    library and archival collections, and a permanent display of the museum's
                    specimen collections. Since 1891, the specimen collections have been displayed
                    according to Darwinian principles of evolution, the organizational scheme
                    selected by renowned biologist Joseph Leidy during his tenure as head of the
                    Institute's scientific and educational programs in the late 19th century.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection of pictorial materials from the Wagner Free Institute of Science
                    contains color and black and white photographs, color and black and white
                    negatives, glass plate negatives, postcards, engravings, a hand-colored
                    photograph, Xerox copies, framed articles, and matted and framed photographs and
                    engravings. Subjects represented in this collection include the faculty and
                    staff of the Wagner Free Institute of Science, famous men (and one woman) of
                    science, pictures of specimens including shell, rocks, minerals, and insects,
                    agriculture, geology, and children's education events. The collection includes 2
                    certificates; 11 engravings; 1 museum directory; 138 negatives; 1 oil; 67
                    photographic postcards; 64 photographs; 1 printer's film proof, 6 prints; 11
                    reprints, 2 watercolors.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 98-062</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science: there is another collection of pictorial material (93-001).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>