<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wagner Free Institute of Science museum accession books <date type="inclusive">1885-1989</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1885-1966</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wagner Free Institute of Science museum accession
                    books</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1155</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1885-1989</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1885-1966</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Incorporated by William Wagner in 1855, the Wagner Free Institute is a natural
                    history museum and educational institution in Philadelphia that is dedicated to
                    providing free public education in the sciences. William Wagner originally
                    offered free lectures and classes in his home and at Spring Garden Hall. He
                    later constructed an Institute building, which opened to the public in 1865.
                    Since 1891, the specimen collections have been displayed according to Darwinian
                    principles of evolution, the organizational scheme selected by renowned
                    biologist Joseph Leidy during his tenure as head of the Institute's scientific
                    and educational programs in the late 19th century.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the Museum accession books of the Wagner Free
                    Institute of Science, in four volumes: vol. 1 - 1885-1907 (331 p.); vol. 2 -
                    1908-1966 (165 p.) (5 entries added in 1989); vol. 3 - 1892-1905 (164 p.); and
                    vol. 4 - 1946-1950 (20 p.). The itemized listings in these books include
                    accession date, accession number, specimen name, locality, source, quantity, and
                    price. Volume 3 lists the specimens in the Wagner Collection. Volume 4 was kept
                    by Curator Henry B. Roberts, and contains the note "Material noted in this book
                    upon receipt and later listed in catalog books by numbers after determination,
                    decision, as to what to do with material, etc. 27 nov. 58." All volumes have
                    notations made by Henry B. Roberts.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 97-017</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>