<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wagner Free Institute of Science scrapbooks <date type="inclusive">1847-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wagner Free Institute of Science scrapbooks</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC974</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1847-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Incorporated by William Wagner in 1855, the Wagner Free Institute is a natural
                    history museum and educational institution in Philadelphia that is dedicated to
                    providing free public education in the sciences. William Wagner originally
                    offered free lectures and classes in his home and at Spring Garden Hall. He
                    later constructed an Institute building, which opened to the public in 1865. The
                    Institute's current programs and services include adult and children's
                    programming offered onsite and at locations around Philadelphia, the Institute's
                    library and archival collections, and a permanent display of the museum's
                    specimen collections. Since 1891, the specimen collections have been displayed
                    according to Darwinian principles of evolution, the organizational scheme
                    selected by renowned biologist Joseph Leidy during his tenure as head of the
                    Institute's scientific and educational programs in the late 19th century.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of seven scrapbooks documenting the activities of the
                    Wagner Free Institute of Science. The volumes are chiefly arranged
                    chronologically, covering the period from the late 1840s to 1980. Items in the
                    scrapbooks include newspaper clippings; lecture announcements, tickets, programs
                    and invitations; announcements of meetings of the Philadelphia Natural History
                    Society; photographs of classes and field trips; and pamphlets relating to legal
                    actions in which the Wagner was concerned. Also included are a series of
                    articles on the Institute's nature hikes that appeared in the Philadelphia
                    Record and the Evening Bulletin.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 89-040</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>