<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wagner Free Institute of Science director's files and business
                        records <date type="inclusive">1858-1938</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1885-1924</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wagner Free Institute of Science director's files and
                    business records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1001</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1858-1938</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1885-1924</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Incorporated by William Wagner in 1855, the Wagner Free Institute is a natural
                    history museum and educational institution in Philadelphia that is dedicated to
                    providing free public education in the sciences. William Wagner originally
                    offered free lectures and classes in his home and at Spring Garden Hall. He
                    later constructed an Institute building, which opened to the public in 1865.
                    Since 1891, the specimen collections have been displayed according to Darwinian
                    principles of evolution, the organizational scheme selected by renowned
                    biologist Joseph Leidy during his tenure as head of the Institute's scientific
                    and educational programs in the late 19th century. During the period of time
                    covered by these records, the director of the Wagner Free Institute of Science
                    oversaw the daily running of the Institute's educational, library, and museum
                    activities. The director reported to the Board of Trustees, and that body made
                    decisions about the Institute's financial expenditures, policies, and programs.
                    Administrators during this time include: Thomas Lynch Montgomery, Actuary and
                    Librarian, 1886-1903; John Rothermel, Director, 1903-1924; and Carl Boyer,
                    Curator, 1924-1928, and Director, 1928-1945.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>These records detail the financial, administrative, and program aspects of the
                    Wagner Free Institute of Science and the William Wagner estate from 1858 to
                    1938, with the bulk of the records dating from 1885 to 1924. The records appear
                    to be from three administrators: Thomas Lynch Montgomery, John Rothermel, and
                    Samuel Wagner, President of Wagner Free Institute of Science, 1885-1921, and
                    President Emeritus, 1921-1937. Materials in this collection include trustee
                    minutes, correspondence, library and museum reports, records relating to the
                    building and grounds, receipts, bank books, canceled checks, and rental
                    documents.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 90-010</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science: other collections that include significant amounts of Trustee
                    records include: Record of the Trustees (89-025 ), Minutes of the Board of
                    Trustees (89-030), and Communications to the Board of Trustees (91-025). Other
                    collections that include significant amounts of director's records include:
                    director's files and business records (90-010), Actuary and Librarian records
                    (91-040), director's reports (98-045 and 00-01), and director's files (90-001
                    and 89-055, 91-030, 91-035, 93-005, 99-109, and 00-02).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>