<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William Healey Dall collection <date type="inclusive">1850-1920</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William Healey Dall collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC081</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1850-1920</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Healey Dall was a noted natural historian, paleontologist, and
                    malacologist. In 1865 he was appointed as a member of the Scientific Corps to
                    the Western Union Telegraph Expedition to Alaska and the Yukon. From 1871-1884,
                    Dall worked for the United States Coast Survey. In 1884 he was appointed as
                    Paleontologist with the United States Geological Survey, a position he held
                    until 1925. Dall's greatest scientific contributions were in the field of
                    malacology. Working on both fossil (Tertiary) and living mollusks, he described
                    over 5300 species. In 1893, the Wagner Free Institute of Science elected Dall
                    Honorary Professor of Invertebrate Paleontology. In recognition of his
                    contributions to science the Trustees of the Institute awarded Dall a medal on
                    June 7, 1899. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The William Healey Dall collection consists of a medal, scientific instruments,
                    and a photograph. The medal of the Wagner Free Institute of Science was awarded
                    to Dall in 1899 for his "investigations and writings in paleontology." It is
                    the only medal ever awarded by the Institute. The collection of scientific
                    instruments belonging to Dall includes, a dissecting kit Dall used on his first
                    expedition to Alaska in 1865, a pocket thermometer, a pocket compass, a pocket
                    barometer/altimeter, and a fire-lighter. The card photograph of Dall is from
                    "Geo. Prince, Artistic Portraits, Penn Ave. &amp; 11th St., Washington, D.C."
                    that was probably taken when he was in his thirties.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: All items in collection donated by Whitney and Barbara Dall.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 02-001, 02-002, 02-003</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>