<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William Wagner European travel journal <date type="inclusive">1841-1842</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William Wagner European travel journal</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC967</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1841-1842</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Wagner (1796-1885) was a philanthropist and naturalist. At the age of 16,
                    he was apprenticed to the financier Stephen Girard. In 1816 he was sent as an
                    assistant supercargo on a two-year trading voyage, during which he collected
                    many shell, plant, and fossil specimens. After leaving Girard's employ, he went
                    into business as a shipping merchant with Charles A. Snowden. This partnership
                    was dissolved in 1825, and Wagner continued as a merchant in his own firm. He
                    retired from business in 1840. In 1847, he began to deliver lectures on
                    scientific topics, and, finding that interest in these lectures was strong,
                    founded the Wagner Free Institute of Science in 1855.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of four travel journals kept by William Wagner during
                    his two year honeymoon in Europe with his wife Louisa Binney Wagner. Volume 1
                    contains entries for travel from Philadelphia to London and Manchester; volume 2
                    contains material on Manchester, Dublin, Belfast, Hamburg, Berlin, Leipzig, and
                    Dresden; volume 3 covers Prague, Vienna, Trieste, Greece, Rome, and Pompeii; and
                    volume 4 contains entries for Florence, Leghorn, Geneva, Milan, Como, Zurich,
                    Basel, Manheim, Strasbourg, and Paris. In the diaries Wagner describes his daily
                    activities as well as various European sights and monuments in extensive detail.
                    He also describes visits and conversations relating to the development of his
                    collections. Volume 3 contains several loose and tipped in sketches of
                    architectural features, boxes, and furniture, as well as a color drawing based
                    on an artist's rendition of the eruption of Mount Etna. Two loose items from a
                    later period are in the back of volume 4: an exchange agreement from the
                    Academie Imperiale de Metz from 1857 and a short Philadelphia Inquirer article
                    about the Wagner Free Institute of Science from 1955.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 89-005</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science: the Robert Chambers collection (90-015) (Box 5, folder 61) contains
                    a series of letters of introduction given to William Wagner for his honeymoon
                    trip to Europe in 1841-1842. The William Wagner personal papers (89-010)
                    contains Wagner's handwritten lists that mention contacts for fossils in
                    Europe.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>