<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William Wagner business papers <date type="inclusive">1824-1880</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Wagner Free Institute of Science</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William Wagner business papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">WFISp.ACC1006</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Wagner Free Institute of Science<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1824-1880</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Wagner (1796-1885) was a philanthropist and naturalist. At the age of 16,
                    he was apprenticed to the financier Stephen Girard. In 1816 he was sent as an
                    assistant supercargo on a two-year trading voyage, during which he collected
                    many shell, plant, and fossil specimens. After leaving Girard's employ, he went
                    into business as a shipping merchant with Charles A. Snowden. This partnership
                    was dissolved in 1825, and Wagner continued as a merchant in his own firm. He
                    retired from business in 1840. In 1847, he began to deliver lectures on
                    scientific topics, and, finding that interest in these lectures was strong,
                    founded the Wagner Free Institute of Science in 1855.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of some of William Wagner's business papers. Included
                    are financial papers, documents relating to legal matters, rental and insurance
                    papers, business correspondence and some financial records of the Wagner Free
                    Institute of Science. This collection includes the deed to the land on which the
                    Institute was built.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 90-035</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science: other collections with William Wagner business papers include:
                    Samuel Wagner collection (89-060), Emma Garman's collection of William Wagner
                    business papers and miscellaneous records of the Wagner Free Institute of
                    Science (91-015), other William Wagner business papers collections (89-001,
                    90-005, 98-050), and William Wagner business and personal papers (98-051).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>