<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>George Byron Gordon director's office papers <date type="inclusive">1910-1928</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania Museum of Archaeology and
                        Anthropology</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">George Byron Gordon director's office papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC024</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent> linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1928</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>George Byron Gordon was born August 4, 1870, at New Perth, Prince Edward Island,
                    Canada. He was the son of James and Jane MacLaren Gordon. He was educated at the
                    University of South Carolina for one year (1888), and thereafter at Harvard
                    University, where he obtained his Ph.D. in 1894. In 1892 he was assistant to
                    John G. Owens on the Harvard excavations at Copán, Honduras. After the death of
                    Owens in 1893, Gordon took over the leadership of the expedition for the next
                    six seasons, until 1900. In 1903 Gordon joined the staff of the University of
                    Pennsylvania Museum as Assistant Curator of the Section of General Ethnology.
                    Since the position of curator of the section was honorary (held by William Henry
                    Furness III), Gordon carried out most of the tasks of the department. He was
                    made Curator of the Section in 1905. In 1905 and 1907, Gordon led two
                    expeditions for the Museum to Alaska. On both trips he traveled with his
                    brother, MacLaren Gordon. The results of these expeditions were published in In
                    the Alaskan Wilderness (Philadelphia: John C. Winston Company, 1917). Gordon was
                    the first to establish regular courses in Anthropology at the University of
                    Pennsylvania. In 1886 and 1887 Daniel G. Brinton had offered selected courses in
                    the field, and the Department of Anthropology was not officially established
                    until 1913 by Frank G. Speck, but Gordon offered courses, both graduate and
                    undergraduate, every semester from 1907 to 1915. In 1910, the management of the
                    University of Pennsylvania Museum having outstripped the capacities of a
                    volunteer Board of Managers, George Byron Gordon was appointed Director of the
                    institution. With the help of Charles Custis Harrison (Provost of the University
                    of Pennsylvania, 1894-1911; Vice-President of the Museum, 1911-1916; and
                    President, 1917-1929) and Eckley B. Coxe, Jr. (President of the Museum’s Board
                    of Managers, 1910-1916), Gordon oversaw the largest period of growth in the
                    history of the Museum. Three wings were added to the original 1899 museum
                    building: the Harrison Rotunda (1915), the Coxe Egyptian Wing (1926), and the
                    Administrative Wing (1929). The collections saw a multifold increase, as well as
                    the Museum’s involvement in the field. Some of the major expeditions carried out
                    under Gordon’s directorship include Memphis (Mit-rahineh) and Thebes (Dra Abu
                    el-Naga) in Egypt, Ur in modern Iraq, Beth Shean in modern Israel, and the
                    Amazon Expedition. He also established The Museum Journal, the institution’s
                    magazine and the forerunner of today’s Expedition magazine. Gordon had a very
                    keen collector’s eye. When purchasing collections he always chose the best
                    specimens and drove a hard bargain with antiquities dealers, who, however,
                    respected his connoisseurship and sought him out when they had a rare piece to
                    sell. He became an expert of great breadth in archaeology, history, and art.
                    Although he was trained in Central America, he undertook ethnography in Alaska,
                    wrote about the history of London (Rambles in Old London; Philadelphia: George
                    W. Jacobs &amp; Co., 1924), and made perhaps his most lasting reputation putting
                    together the Museum’s Chinese collections, which rank among the best in the
                    world. In 1926 the University of Pennsylvania conferred upon Gordon the honorary
                    degree of Doctor of Science. In January 1927, Gordon slipped and fell down the
                    stairs after dinner at the Racquet Club of Philadelphia. He never regained
                    consciousness, and died six hours later. He was buried at Laurel Hill Cemetery,
                    Philadelphia, in the Harrison family plot. Gordon was unmarried and had no
                    children. At the time of his death he was survived by two brothers, James Kelso
                    Gordon of British Columbia and Charles Gordon of Australia (his brother MacLaren
                    was killed in France during World War I); and three sisters, Margaret Gordon and
                    Ada Gordon of Portland, Oregon, and Harriet L. Smith of British Columbia. Gordon
                    had been a member of the American Philosophical Society, the Franklin Inn Club,
                    the Lenape Club, the Rittenhouse Club, the Explorer’s Club of New York, the
                    American Anthropological Association, the American Ethnological Society, the
                    Authors Club of London, and a Fellow of the Royal Geographical Society. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p/>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 0001.03</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>