<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William Davenport papers <date type="inclusive">1938-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania Museum of Archaeology and
                        Anthropology</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William Davenport papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC337</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1938-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Hunt Davenport (1922-2004) was a lifelong seaman. Born on May 26, 1922 in
                    Upland, California, USA, and raised in Cucamonga, Calif., Davenport stowed away
                    on a boat bound for Singapore at the age of 14. He reportedly spent time in jail
                    for this stunt, and graduated from Chaffey Union High School (Ontario, Calif.)
                    in 1939. He then studied art and photography at the Art Center School (Los
                    Angeles, Calif.) for one year before joining the military. Davenport served
                    throughout the Pacific during World War II, as a Deck Officer and Master with
                    the U.S. Army Transport Service (1941-46) and as an Ensign, Lt. in the U.S.
                    Naval Reserve (1942-45). Following his military service, Davenport ran a
                    shipping company, a photography business and advised the Chinese merchant
                    marines. He eventually returned to higher education, graduating with honors in
                    1952 from the University of Hawaii (Honolulu) with a degree in anthropology. He
                    pursued interdisciplinary graduate studies in anthropology and behavioral
                    sciences at Yale University, where he received his PhD in 1956 under the
                    direction of Sidney Mintz. His dissertation focused on Jamaican fishing
                    communities (1954-55). Davenport continued to teach at Yale until 1963, when he
                    accepted a dual-position at the University of Pennsylvania’s Anthropology
                    Department and Museum of Anthropology and Archaeology. He would spend nearly his
                    entire career at Penn, with the exception of three years at the University of
                    California Santa Cruz as professor and director of the Center for South Pacific
                    Studies (1969-72), and visiting professorships at Bryn Mawr, University of
                    Hawaii and Wesleyan. As curator of the Oceanian section of the Penn Museum,
                    Davenport helped mount the exhibition “Sculpture and Artifacts from the Eastern
                    Solomon Islands” (Dec. 1967-May 31, 1968), which featured numerous art objects
                    collected by him during his 1964 summer and 1965-66 field trips to Santa Ana and
                    Santa Catalina Islands. Davenport also designed the museum’s permanent Polynesia
                    Hall exhibit in 1983, and mounted seven other major exhibits as curator or
                    co-curator. He served briefly as Associate Director of the Museum, from 1979 to
                    1980. He retired from Penn in 1992, and was inducted into Penn’s Twenty-Five
                    Year Club in 1996. During his long career, he was also a fellow at the Center
                    for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Palo Alto, Calif.) in 1971-72, a
                    member of the Council of the Smithsonian Institution (Washington, D.C.) from
                    1976-84, and an associate at the Bishop Museum (Honolulu, Hawaii) from 1953-60
                    and 1980-2004. Davenport’s field research took him to the Santa Cruz Islands,
                    Guadalcanal and San Cristobal Islands, and other Solomon Islands; the Moluccas
                    and Sulawesi in Indonesia; and Sarawak in Malaysia; among other locations. He
                    authored four books and more than 60 articles and reviews on subjects including
                    social organization, art, economics, archaeology, religion and ritual, and more.
                    His final book on figure sculpture of the Santa Cruz Islands was published
                    posthumously in 2004. He died of leukemia on March 12, 2004, at the age of 81.
                    He was survived by his sister, Mary Yohalem (New York City, N.Y.), two nieces
                    Jennifer and Deborah Salt (both California) and great-nephew Jonah Greenberg
                    (then residing in Beijing, China). He and his wife Pearl (Yim) Davenport
                    divorced in the 1960s, and she preceded him in death. He married his second wife
                    Nancy (Ingersoll) Davenport in 1968. They eventually separated, but Nancy helped
                    to shepherd his final book to publication after his death. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The William H. Davenport Collection spans the period from 1952-2002 and contains
                    materials primarily related to his field research, professional activities,
                    student mentoring, and articles and publications. The collection is divided into
                    seven series: Correspondence; Field Notes; Manuscripts &amp; Publications;
                    Teaching; Personal; Maps &amp; Drawings; and Audiovisual Materials. Series I.
                    Correspondence (1952-2005) – This series is arranged alphabetically by
                    correspondent, and thereunder chronologically, and includes mostly professional
                    correspondence with students, former students and colleagues. In some cases,
                    Davenport saved and attached copies of his own replies. Correspondence relating
                    to field research is generally filed by person, not expedition, with additional
                    subject folders for “Santa Cruz Islands, General” and “Solomon Islands,
                    General.” Very little of his correspondence is solely personal in nature, but
                    his graduate students sent him long missives during their time in the field. A
                    letter to Mac Marshall (in folder “M Correspondence #1”) details Davenport’s own
                    graduate studies at Yale, and how funding and mentoring issues resulted in a
                    dissertation about Jamaica, not the Pacific. Series II. Field Notes (1950-1991)
                    – This series is arranged chronologically by expedition (see chronology above
                    for overview of his research expeditions). Davenport saved small card-files of
                    research notes for his expeditions in Jamaica and the Solomon Islands, using
                    Human Resources Area Files (HRAF) categories to organize his notes. The HRAF
                    publications he used during 1958-60, 1965-66 and 1974-76 research are included
                    in this series. Davenport also kept small notebooks of genealogical data and
                    other field notes, as listed. Series III. Manuscripts &amp; Publications
                    (1959-2001) – This series is arranged chronologically, and contains a small
                    number of published works that are rare or difficult to obtain. Among his
                    unpublished works are two monographs for which he couldn’t find a market: “The
                    Inventor from Tahiti” about Henri Rey, and an untitled and unfinished work about
                    the Santa Cruz Islands. (Expedition published a shorter Davenport article about
                    Henri Rey posthumously in 2004, and Davenport published a number of shorter
                    articles about Santa Cruz.) Series IV. Teaching (1968-1992) – This small series
                    is arranged by Penn course number. Some handwritten notes for class are
                    included, as well as syllabi. Series V. Personal (1938-1999) – This small series
                    is arranged in rough chronological order by topic. Though the collection has
                    relatively few personal papers, this series includes documents related to his
                    career as a seaman, his studies at U of Hawaii and Yale, miscellaneous
                    professional awards, his art collection and his estate. Series VI. Maps &amp;
                    Drawings (1965-1974) – This series includes all nonphotographic visual
                    materials, and is arranged by subject. It includes informants’ pencil, crayon
                    and ink drawings of fish, birds, people and myths, often with labels in another
                    language. There are also drawings of tattoos, canoe motifs and woodcarving
                    motifs. Oversized materials include sketch maps of Santa Ana, San Cristoval and
                    Santa Cruz Islands; other maps of the Solomon Islands and Sulawesi; and kinship
                    diagrams of the Pala, Vaenga, Noole, Malo and Banua groups. Series VII.
                    Audiovisual Materials [(1946-1982)] – This series includes photographic prints,
                    slides and negatives, as well as film and audio cassettes. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1133</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>