<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Union League of Philadelphia House Committee records <date type="inclusive">1863-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Union League of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Union League of Philadelphia House Committee
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TULSp.ACC2314</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Union League of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>44 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1863-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Union League of Philadelphia was founded in 1862 as a patriotic society to
                    support the policies of President Abraham Lincoln. It evolved to its current
                    identity as a non-sectarian and non-partisan private club. The House Committee
                    was established as a Standing Committee at least by 1871 and continues to the
                    present. It has had a wide range of responsibilities including membership
                    services and privileges, activities, employee relations, operations (including
                    restaurant) and building maintenance and contents. It is at times unclear what
                    falls within some of these different areas--membership services may include food
                    and beverage, but food and beverage may also fall within operations.
                    Consequently, the organization of the subseries is somewhat arbitrary. Although
                    the House Committee once had oversight of various parties and other
                    entertainment at the League, this was transferred to the Entertainment Committee
                    in 1979. The Superintendent/General Manager reported to the House Committee for
                    many years.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The series has been arranged into six subseries: Minutebooks, General Files,
                    Member Services/Privileges, Employee Relations, Operations, and Building. The
                    Minutebooks subseries contains 15 volumes. The content of the minutes describe
                    personnel actions, purchases, work on the building and treasurer's reports to
                    the House Committee. The General Files subseries includes includes notices and
                    other information on dining, member services, and minutes. There are also a few
                    reports, including a report on a study of the food and beverage operations. The
                    Member Services/Privileges subseries is comprised mainly of member directories,
                    1863-2008. The directories include basic information on officers and members,
                    including name, address, and year joined. This subseries also includes receipts,
                    forms, notices, and other recordkeeping related to member accounts; guest
                    registers, 1952-2003 (some gaps), listing the name and city, state, and/or
                    country of origin for League guests; and printed materials from other clubs with
                    whom the Union League had reciprocal agreements. The Employee Relations
                    subseries includes four volumes, dated between 1872 and 1936, of employee lists
                    that record dates of service with occasional notes about employees; files and
                    time cards of a random sample of employees (bulk years 1966-1982); miscellaneous
                    announcements; and records and files related to the 25 Year Club, Blood Donor
                    Club and Christmas Fund. The Operations subseries consists primarily of menus
                    and wine lists for the Union League restaurant, and programs, menus, and printed
                    materials for non-Union League-sponsored events held at the League (some items
                    are autographed). The subseries includes a small amount of marketing material,
                    as well as several logbooks related to routine operations such as cash on hand.
                    The Building subseries includes reports, plans, correspondence, and other
                    information related to renovations of the Union League building and strategic
                    planning. The subseries includes member surveys and a focus group report related
                    to the 2003 strategic planning effort.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>