<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Union League of Philadelphia Activities/Guest Committee records
                            <date type="inclusive">1865-1998</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Union League of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Union League of Philadelphia Activities/Guest Committee
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TULSp.ACC2315</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Union League of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>55.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1865-1998</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Union League of Philadelphia was founded in 1862 as a patriotic society to
                    support the policies of President Abraham Lincoln. It evolved to its current
                    identity as a non-sectarian and non-partisan private club. The Guest Committee
                    was one of the original committees listed in the 1872 annual report. Over time,
                    the Guest and House Committees were responsible for arranging programs. In 1979
                    the Guest Committee formed an Entertainment sub-committee, and in 1984 the Guest
                    Committee was renamed Activities Committee.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The series has been arranged into six subseries: Affinity/Recreation, Armed
                    Services, Entertainment, Junior Committee, Ladies Luncheon, and Public
                    Affairs/Guest Speakers. The subseries within the Activities series are based on
                    1998 subcommittee assignments. Most of the subseries contain chronological files
                    related to a particular group's activities. The files in most of the subseries
                    consist primarily of printed materials for events, such as announcements,
                    invitations, programs, and tickets. Some files include minutes, correspondence,
                    clippings, member directories, newsletters, or menus. Within the Public
                    Affairs/Guest Speakers subseries, many of the items are autographed by the
                    speakers. There are some printed addresses for Lincoln Day festivities. Files
                    related to Union League anniversaries and events surrounding the U.S.
                    Bicentennial include committee correspondence and printed materials. The Ladies
                    Luncheon Committee contains financial information including bank statements,
                    canceled checks and invoices. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>