<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Union League of Philadelphia Committee on Youth Work and Abraham
                        Lincoln Foundation records <date type="inclusive">1946-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Union League of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Union League of Philadelphia Committee on Youth Work and
                    Abraham Lincoln Foundation records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TULSp.ACC2321</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Union League of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>20.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1946-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Union League of Philadelphia was founded in 1862 as a patriotic society to
                    support the policies of President Abraham Lincoln. It evolved to its current
                    identity as a non-sectarian and non-partisan private club. The Committee on Boys
                    Work was established in 1946, holding its first dinner in 1947 to award Good
                    Citizenship medals and certificates to boys, base don recommendations by various
                    charitable agencies. Annual dinners were attended by sports figures,
                    entertainers, and public figures. Winners of the Good Citizenship awards were
                    eligible for scholarships awarded by the Scholarship Committee. established in
                    1955. In 1971 a non-profit foundation, Boys Work Foundation, was created to
                    raise money for the Scholarship Fund and to make grants to agencies engaged in
                    youth programs. The trustees were appointed by the Union League President and
                    were responsible for accepting contributions and investing funds temporarily,
                    without the intention to establish endowments. In 1986 the names were changed to
                    Committee on Youth Work and Youth Work Foundation in order to include girls as
                    candidates. The Abraham Lincoln Foundation was established in 1995 as a
                    non-profit organization "to maintain and exhibit the Corporation's collections
                    of artwork, Civil War and other books, and other articles of historical
                    importance, to maintain parts of the Union League Building...and to educate
                    students and others in the subjects of art, history and music and other
                    topics."</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Committee on Youth Work files, 1946-1992, include solicitations, invitations,
                    programs, and other printed material, with some minutes, correspondence,
                    financial and other working files reflecting the different subcommittees:
                    activities, dinner arrangements, door prizes, photographs, membership support,
                    letters and notices, agency coordination, special guests, public relations,
                    speaker, and executive committee. There are also award recipient information
                    cards, 1948-1961, 1973, and 1980-1981, including (variously) name, address,
                    birth date, school, and sponsoring agency. Foundation files, 1971-1989, include
                    agency applications, acknowledgments, and other correspondence, member
                    appointments, minutes, and financial reports. There are three scrapbooks
                    (1978-1980) documenting the Committee on Boys' Work Annual Good Citizenship
                    Awards. The scrap books include printed materials including form letters.
                    invitations and programs etc. Scholarship Fund Committee/Foundation files,
                    1956-1965, include applications of unsuccessful candidates and correspondence
                    with applicants and others regarding awarding of scholarships. Applications
                    include photograph, name and occupation of parent, family income, home value and
                    mortgage, certificate of agency head, remarks of parent or guardian, certificate
                    of principal or head master, school record and SAT scores. There are also some
                    miscellaneous minutes and other materials. Abraham Lincoln Foundation records
                    include: Trustee, Executive Committee, and Collections Committee minutes,
                    1997-present; proposal for stewardship of Civil War Museum and Library,
                    1999-2000; material relating to performance of "While Lincoln Lay Dying,"
                    2000, based on James Tanner manuscript.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>