<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Union League of Philadelphia Library, Art, and History and Archives
                        Committee records <date type="inclusive">1865-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Union League of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Union League of Philadelphia Library, Art, and History and
                    Archives Committee records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TULSp.ACC2317</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Union League of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>40 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1865-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Union League of Philadelphia was founded in 1862 as a patriotic society to
                    support the policies of President Abraham Lincoln. It evolved to its current
                    identity as a non-sectarian and non-partisan private club. The Library Committee
                    was one of the original Standing Committees. Its responsibilities have changed
                    through time, including oversight of the publications which it assumed in 1893
                    and which was reassigned to Member Services in the late 1980s. At one time the
                    Library Committee was also responsible for securing photographs of members. With
                    the centennial observation in 1962, Max Whiteman was brought in and he
                    eventually took charge of the library, art, artifact, and archives collections.
                    In 1988 the Committee on Art, Archives, and History was absorbed into the
                    Library Committee.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The series is arranged into three subseries: Library, Art, and History and
                    Archives. The Library subseries includes minutes of the Library Committee;
                    selected correspondence, financial statements, and annual reports; printed
                    materials for library-sponsored events, including Library Hours; information on
                    accessions and acquisitions; published catalogues of the library's collection;
                    and copies of the library's newsletter, Vita Libris. The Art subseries includes
                    minutes, correspondence, published catalogues, appraisals and information on
                    loans. The History and Archives subseries includes pamphlets and articles on
                    Union League history; published histories; printed materials and other files
                    related to House Tours; files from the League's Oral History Project; files
                    related to the publication of the Tanner manuscript While Lincoln Lay Dying; and
                    miscellaneous research materials on various historical topics.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>