<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Union League of Philadelphia Member Relations Committee records
                            <date type="inclusive">1885-1998</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Union League of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Union League of Philadelphia Member Relations Committee
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TULSp.ACC2318</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Union League of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>32.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1885-1998</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Union League of Philadelphia was founded in 1862 as a patriotic society to
                    support the policies of President Abraham Lincoln. It evolved to its current
                    identity as a non-sectarian and non-partisan private club. In an effort to boost
                    declining membership, a Membership Development Committee was appointed in 1982.
                    This Committee became a part of a newly established Standing Committee in 1988,
                    Member Relations, which was responsible for: recruiting new members,
                    facilitating assimilation of new members, monitoring member usage, targeting
                    areas for improvement and enhancements to stem resignations, and encouraging
                    spousal use. It also became responsible for oversight of Clubs Tables and all
                    communications, including marketing, public relations, and the Bulletin/Banner.
                    Its work overlapped with the Activities Committee through its encouragement of
                    Club Tables as well as Junior member activities. The Banner was also the
                    responsibility of Activities at one time, and also the House Committee. The
                    House Committee shared some entertainment responsibilities with Member
                    Relations. Member Relations worked closely with the Admissions Committee, which
                    is separately appointed according to the By-Laws.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The series has been arranged into three subseries: General, Club Tables, and
                    Bulletin/Banner. The Club Tables subseries consists primarily of information on
                    the different club tables; the amount of documentation varies by club. These
                    materials include correspondence, meeting minutes, printed announcements, member
                    information and directories, attendance reports, financial records (such as bank
                    statements, receipts, and reports), club histories, menus, and ephemera. The
                    subseries also contains some information related to club tables in general,
                    including statistics and announcements. The Member Relations subseries contains
                    bound volumes of member directories, files dedicated to membership development
                    (which include printed information about the Union League), an outside study
                    looking at the communications of the Union League, some minutes, and committee
                    memoranda. The Bulletin/Banner is a comprehensive run of the monthly publication
                    from 1944 through May 2008.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>