<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Union League of Philadelphia political activities records <date type="inclusive">1864-2008</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Union League of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Union League of Philadelphia political activities
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TULSp.ACC2322</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Union League of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>9.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-2008</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Union League of Philadelphia was founded in 1862 as a patriotic society to
                    support the policies of President Abraham Lincoln. It evolved to its current
                    identity as a non-sectarian and non-partisan private club. The Union League's
                    political activities centered primarily around presidential campaigns,
                    supporting Republican candidates, although there were occasions when the League
                    became involved in gubernatorial and mayoral campaigns, as well as other
                    national and local issues. During the world wars, the League raised funds in
                    support of the war effort. From time to time committees were appointed such as
                    the Committee on National Activities, 1918; Committees on Public Affairs, 1945;
                    Committee for Patriotic Action, 1961; and Political Activities Committee, 1962.
                    In 1893 an attempt to amend the By-Laws to make Republican Party affiliation a
                    condition of membership in the League failed, but by resolution all candidate
                    applications required Republican Party voting. In 1975 this stipulation was
                    removed from the application.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The series is arranged into four subseries: Presidential Campaigns; United States
                    Presidents; State, Local, General Political Activity; and War Activities. The
                    Presidential Campaigns subseries includes printed materials, solicitations,
                    contributor records, and occasional correspondence related to the League's
                    efforts on behalf of Republican presidential candidates. The most extensive
                    files are for the 1960 presidential campaign. The United States Presidents
                    subseries includes printed materials related to celebrations of presidential
                    birthdays and occasional presidential visits. There is some correspondence to
                    and from various Republican presidential candidates/presidents, but most is of a
                    routine nature. The subseries also includes a resolution book related to the
                    death of President James Garfield. The General Political Activity subseries
                    contains general files related to political campaigns or specific candidates.
                    Committees include the Republican Finance Committee of Pennsylvania, Committee
                    for Patriotic Action, Political Activities Committee and The Ladies Fund Raising
                    Committee. A great deal of the content of the files is comprised of encouraging
                    members to vote, and fundraising letters in support of the Republican Party.
                    There are some campaign artifacts for the Shafer/Broderick ticket. The War
                    Activities subseries documents League activities during World War I and World
                    War II. There also a file related to the Spanish-American War which includes
                    bulletins documenting specific war activity.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>