<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Union League of Philadelphia Civil War collection <date type="inclusive">1861-1902</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Union League of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Union League of Philadelphia Civil War
                    collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TULSp.ACC2324</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Union League of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1861-1902</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Union League of Philadelphia was founded in 1862 as a patriotic society to
                    support the policies of President Abraham Lincoln. It evolved to its current
                    identity as a non-sectarian and non-partisan private club. In 1962 the Union
                    League decided it would form a collection of Civil War materials and published
                    its intention. At least one acquisition was made as a result of this effort.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The series has been arranged into three subseries: Union League Military, Other
                    Military, and Ephemera. Union League Military materials include: Col. Harmanus
                    papers related to the 196th Regiment Pennsylvania, 5th Union League, including
                    letters, ordnance receipts, reports and muster rolls; Lt. Col. Jacob M. Davis
                    papers related to the 213th Regiment Pennsylvania, 7th Union League, including
                    special and general orders, correspondence relating primarily to furlough
                    requests, Company returns and tri-monthly reports, and Court Martial case
                    reports including charges (mostly Absent Without Leave), specifications,
                    findings, and sentences, as well as Reports of the Guard; an Adjutant General's
                    Office Clothing Book for the 183rd Regiment Pennsylvania, 4th Union League, Cos.
                    A, B, C, D; and miscellaneous muster rolls and bounties for 1st, 2nd, and 3rd
                    Union League Regiments. Other Civil War papers include: soldier's letters to
                    Hannah Eliza Delp from cousins and friends; David S. Hall Morgan letters; John
                    Martin Steffan letters; Robert M. Green record books, clippings, transcripts and
                    other material relating to the history of the 124th Pennsylvania Regiment, with
                    invitations, programs, George Gordon Meade Post GAR, 1862-1911; William Thomas
                    Jones letters; record book of relief work for Civil War Veterans and their
                    families; and miscellaneous discharges, letters, and a scrapbook.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>