<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William West Conrad papers <date type="inclusive">1893-1975</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Union League of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William West Conrad papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TULSp.ACC2325</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Union League of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>24 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1893-1975</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William West Conrad (1904-1981) resided at the Union League from 1966 to his
                    death. He was a graduate of William Penn Charter School (1919) and Princeton
                    University (1924). He traveled extensively and was a member of many clubs,
                    including the Wilderness Club and the Adventurers Club.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of correspondence, clippings, memorabilia, and
                    photographs relating to Conrad's activities as explorer, supporter of young
                    members of his extended family and of various music organizations. There are
                    also a number of family photographs and papers. Materials related to Conrad's
                    travels include: travel postcards and maps from all over the world; photographs
                    and slides of Conrad and various sights; and travel brochures and itineraries.
                    Personal and family papers include: school papers and lecture notes from
                    Princeton University; personal correspondence and greeting cards; appointment
                    books and diaries; framed diplomas and certificates; dinner invitations and
                    related programs; bank books and used checkbooks; papers concerning various
                    properties in Florida;family photographs (some framed) and photo albums; and
                    several travel diaries kept by his mother. The collection also includes
                    correspondence and printed materials related to Conrad's involvement with
                    various Philadelphia area and New York City musical organizations, including the
                    Academy of Vocal Arts and the Metropolitan Opera. There are also framed
                    paintings, scrapbooks and loose newspaper clippings, as well as newspapers
                    related to significant events; newsletters and magazines related to Conrad's
                    interests; and various books, mostly related to travel, such as phrase books and
                    dictionaries. The collection contains some personal items and German coins and
                    Italian currency (circa 1947).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences: William West Conrad journals.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>