<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edwin B. Bronner papers regarding Friends World Committee for
                        Consultation <date type="inclusive">1967-1982</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Haverford College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edwin B. Bronner papers regarding Friends World Committee
                    for Consultation</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">HCSp.ACC1465</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Haverford College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1982</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Friends World Committee for Consultation (FWCC) is a section of the
                    international Quaker organization which seeks to strengthen spiritual life of
                    the Society of Friends and review its involvement in world affairs. Edwin
                    Bronner (1920-2005) served as chair of Friends World Committee, American
                    Section, from 1967-1971 and chair of Friends World Committee for Consultation
                    from 1974-79. He was also Librarian of Haverford College and Curator of the
                    Haverford Quaker Collection.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of correspondence, minutes, memos, and reports on the
                    activities of committees of the Friends World Committee for Consultation. Topics
                    include: hiring of Association and General Secretaries; planning for the 14th
                    Triennial meeting of the FWCC; the Mission for Service in Guatemala; information
                    on the One Percent More Program; and activities in India, South Africa, and
                    Korea.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Friends World Committee for Consultation. American
                    Section.</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Haverford College:
                    Edwin B. Bronner papers and Blanche Shaffer papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>