<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rhoads family papers <date type="inclusive">1826-1963</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1826-1930</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Haverford College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rhoads family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">HCSp.ACC1475</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Haverford College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1826-1963</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1826-1930</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Samuel Rhoads (1806-1868) was a publisher and editor of the Friends Review
                    (1853-1867). His wife was Anne Gibbons. Their son, Edward Rhoads (1841-1871),
                    was an 1859 graduate of Haverford College and received his M.D. from the
                    University of Pennsylvania in 1863. He worked at Philadelphia Hospital. He was a
                    conscientious objector during the Civil War. One of their other sons was William
                    Gibbons Rhoads (1838-1880), who attended Haverford from 1854 to 1858. He was a
                    machinist and plumber in Philadelphia. He was a Manager of Haverford College
                    from 1871 to 1880. His wife was Sarah Wistar. Their son, Samuel Rhoads, Jr. (b.
                    1878), received his bachelor's degree from Haverford in 1898 and his M.D. from
                    the University of Pennsylvania in 1901. He worked as a physician in
                    Philadelphia. Their daughter was Lydia W. Rhoads.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Rhoads family papers. Materials include: correspondence
                    from Samuel Rhoads to his parents and friends while in England in 1834; letters
                    between Samuel Rhoads and Anne Gibbons; letters to Anne Gibbons Rhoads; letters
                    to Samuel Rhoads from friends concerning the Friends Review and issues related
                    to meetings; letters from Edward Rhoads to his parents from his 1865-1866 trip
                    to Europe and letters to him from family and friends; letters to Lydia W. Rhoads
                    during her 1907 trip to England; correspondence between Sophia R. Wing and Jane
                    Gibbons and letters to Sophia from Asa Wing. The collection also contains
                    photographs, news clippings, copies of the Friends Review (including obituaries
                    of Anne G. Rhoads, William G. Rhoads, and Jane Rhoads), diaries, receipts, a
                    dues list of the Free Produce Association of Friends of Philadelphia Yearly
                    Meeting, an account book belonging to Ethel Rhoads Potts, deeds and estate
                    papers of Samuel Rhoads, and school compositions of William G. and Edward
                    Rhoads.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Free Produce Association of
                    Friends.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Yearly Meeting of the Religious Society
                    of Friends.</corpname>
                <famname encodinganalog="600">Pusey family.</famname>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Rhoads, Anne Gibbons.</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Rhoads, Edward, 1841-1870.</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Rhoads, S. (Samuel)</persname>
                <famname encodinganalog="600">Rhodes family.</famname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Quakers--Correspondence.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Society of Friends--Periodicals.</subject>
                <geogname encodinganalog="651">Europe--Description and travel.</geogname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Cabinet photographs</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Family papers</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photograph albums</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>