<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Stephen G. Cary papers <date type="inclusive">1928-2001</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960s-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Haverford College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Stephen G. Cary papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">HCSp.ACC849</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Haverford College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>9.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1928-2001</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960s-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Stephen G. Cary (1915-2002) graduated from Germantown Friends School in 1933. He
                    received a bachelor's degree in economics with a minor in chemistry from
                    Haverford in 1937 and a master's in international administration from Columbia
                    University in 1943. He was a conscientious objector during World War II and
                    served in the Civilian Public Service from 1942-1946. Between 1946 and 1969,
                    Cary was an integral part of the American Friends Service Committee (AFSC). With
                    Willis Weatherford, he served as chief of American Quaker Relief Operations in
                    Europe from 1946-1948, overseeing work in 10 countries dealing with the
                    aftermath of World War II. Cary was chairman of the AFSC from 1979-1991. Cary
                    began his service to Haverford College as a member of the Board of Managers from
                    1955-1969. In 1969 he joined the staff as vice president of development, and
                    became vice president of finance and development in 1974. He was named acting
                    president of Haverford from 1977-1978. He served as senior vice president of the
                    College from 1979-81 and was clerk of Haverford's faculty meetings during these
                    three years.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the professional and personal papers of Stephen G. Cary.
                    Materials include: correspondence, memos, and reports on American Friends
                    Service Committee's activities and programs; AFSC pamphlets and brochures;
                    minutes, grant applications, and correspondence related to the Clarence and
                    Lilly Pickett Endowment for Quaker Leadership; subject files on such topics as
                    civil rights, the Germantown Friends School, and the Friends Association for
                    Higher Education; and notebooks and appointment books. Materials related to
                    Cary's association with Haverford include: correspondence; drafts of speeches;
                    minutes of various committees; records related to the "Honor Code"; and
                    clippings on Cary's tenure as acting president. The collection also includes a
                    small batch of letters from Cary to his father, C. Reed Cary, and letters to and
                    from his grandchildren.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">American Friends Service Committee.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Haverford College.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Quakers--Pennsylvania.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Speeches</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 6815</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Peace Collection,
                    Swarthmore College: Civilian Public Service personal papers and collected
                    materials.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>