<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Waring family papers <date type="inclusive">1798-1975</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1860s-1930s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Haverford College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Waring family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">HCSp.ACC807</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Haverford College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1798-1975</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1860s-1930s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Waring family arrived in the United States in 1775. The first generation of
                    Warings to settle in Cecil County, Maryland, included Thomas (1755-1842) and
                    William (d. 1793). The Warings were founding members of the Colora, Maryland,
                    Meeting. Thomas Waring's children included William Waring (1808-1884). William
                    Waring had four sons: Thomas, Wilson (d. 1917), David, and William (1849-1934).
                    The brothers Thomas and Wilson Waring organized the The Waring Fertilizer and
                    Bone Mill Company in 1869 to bring "scientific agriculture" to Cecil County.
                    Thomas Waring (the younger) was also a Superintendent of Cooper Hospital and the
                    founder of the Waring Manufacturing Company and Waring Ink and Index. His
                    children included Bernard Gilpin Waring (b. 1876).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of family papers of the Waring family, primarily of Thomas
                    Waring (the younger) and Bernard G. Waring. Materials related to Thomas and
                    William Waring (the elder generation) include legal documents, such as deeds,
                    mortgages, and indentures. Materials related to Thomas Waring (the younger)
                    include correspondence with family, especially his brother William; personal
                    financial records, such as an expense book, check registers, bills, and
                    receipts; financial records related to the Waring Manufacturing Company (1880s
                    to early 1900s), such as correspondence, stock certificates, proxies, and
                    agreements; records related to the Waring Ink and Index company, including a
                    patent application, correspondence, bills, and receipts. Bernard Waring's papers
                    consist of correspondence with family and friends from the 1920s to the 1930s.
                    Also included in the collection are account books for a grocery business (1863
                    to 1864), family photographs, and ephemera.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Cooper Hospital (Camden, N.J.)</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Business records</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Family papers</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Financial records</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Patents</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 5716</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>