<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>A. Cypen Lubitsh photograph collection <date type="inclusive">1940-1980</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1940-1969</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">A. Cypen Lubitsh photograph collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC171</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1940-1980</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1940-1969</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Aron Cypen "Cy" Lubitsh was born in the Soviet Union, immigrated to Canada and
                    subsequently immigrated to the United States in 1937. Lubitsh worked as a
                    commercial artist and photographer in New York City. He earned a Master's in art
                    at Columbia University. He worked and studied under the Russian-born sculptor
                    Alexander Archipenko. In 1943 Lubitsh was drafted into the Army, and was
                    assigned to the 166th Signal Photographic Company, Camp Crowder, Missouri. His
                    unit was sent to France in 1944, landing at Normandy while the D-Day invasion
                    was still underway. The unit was assigned to Third Army throughout the campaigns
                    in France and Germany. Lubitsh received the Bronze Star, and was honorably
                    discharged in the fall of 1945. In 1964, Lubitsh's photos of the war were
                    exhibited at the Delaware Art Center.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of over 1,000 personal and professional photo negatives and
                    photographs from the 1940s to 1960s from the studio of A. Cypen Lubitsh, Bronx,
                    New York, and later Wilmington, Delaware. Subjects include: portraits of
                    children, theatrical and dance portraits, weddings, marina and waterfront
                    scenes, racetracks, airplanes, animals and rural scenes, beach scenes, and
                    travel photography from Europe to Arizona to Gloucester, Massachusetts. The
                    collection also includes images of still lifes, and photographs of Lubitsh's own
                    artwork in paintings and sculpture.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: William H. Duncan</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 10/29/2004</p>
                <p>Accession number: 05-53</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Military History
                    Institute at Carlisle Barracks: A. Cypen Lubitsh military photos</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>