<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Albert S. Matlack collection <date type="inclusive">1958-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Albert S. Matlack collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC118</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1958-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Albert S. Matlack is an adjunct professor of Chemistry at the University of
                    Delaware and was for many years a research chemist at Hercules Inc. Matlack is a
                    passionate conservationist and an advocate of "green chemistry," which aims to
                    reduce the use of toxic chemicals, to produce less waste, and to use less energy
                    in industry. He is the author of "Introduction to Green Chemistry," and he
                    also lectures on this subject in his classes at the University of Delaware. He
                    is the president of the Society of Natural History of Delaware, in which role he
                    leads monthly educational field trips.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Albert S. Matlack. Materials in the
                    collection include: technical reports, newsletters, notes, and programs related
                    to environmental and conservation issues in Delaware, such as air quality,
                    wetlands, farmland preservation, and native plants. The collection also contains
                    pamphlets, booklets, newsletters, journals, and correspondence related to Tower
                    Hill School, Delaware, Delmarva Power, the Delmarva Ornithological Society, the
                    Experiment in International Living, University of Delaware, the International
                    Meditation Society, and the Jewish Community Center.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Albert S. Matlack</p>
                <p>Accession number: 04-95; 06-111; 06-122; 07-28</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>