<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Archaeological Society of Delaware records <date type="inclusive">1933-2001</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Archaeological Society of Delaware records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC031</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1933-2001</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Archaeological Society of Delaware was founded in 1933 as a professional
                    association for local archaeologists. Over its history, the Society has
                    excavated historic and prehistoric sites, lobbied for Delaware legislation to
                    protect local sites and to hire a State Archaeologist, and raised awareness of
                    the science among the population of the state. The Society publishes the
                    Bulletin of the Archaeological Society of Delaware, Inksherds (the Society's
                    newsletter), and various monographs and papers.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of the Archeological Society of Delaware.
                    Materials include: correspondence; minutes of general meetings and of the Board
                    of Directors; membership records and directories; financial records, copies of
                    the Bulletin of the Archeological Society of Delaware and Inksherds (1933-1996);
                    and annual reports of the Eastern States Archaeological Federation which contain
                    annual reports of the Society. The collection includes the correspondence of Dr.
                    Leon De Valinger, Archibald Crozier, and Herbert Pratt, who served as
                    secretaries of the society, as well as newspaper publicity about the society and
                    its members compiled mostly by Arthur G. Volkman.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of or purchase from Archaeological Society of Delaware</p>
                <p>Accession number: 01-76; 01-69; 99-69</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <otherfindaid>
                <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" xpointer="https://library.udel.edu/special/findaids/view?docId=ead/mss0578.xml">https://library.udel.edu/special/findaids/view?docId=ead/mss0578.xml</extref>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Delaware: Eastern States Archaeological Federation collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>