<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Armistead W. Browning, Jr. papers <date type="inclusive">1960-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Armistead W. Browning, Jr. papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1033</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>31.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Born in 1938, Armistead Willis Browning, Jr., was a landscape architect,
                    environmentalist, and teacher who dedicated his life to environmental
                    preservation and education, and to his career as a landscape designer. Mr.
                    Browning was the founder of Turtle Creek Designs, a landscape design consulting
                    firm in Pocopson, Pennsylvania. The firm did residential work and large-scale
                    environmental studies. Browning worked extensively with the Brandywine
                    Conservancy in Chadds Ford and Pocopson Township, producing landmark studies of
                    the scenic, historical, and natural features of the Brandywine Valley Region.
                    From 1977 until his death in 1987, Browning taught courses in landscape design
                    and native plant horticulture at the University of Delaware. His weekly column,
                    "Notes from Turtle Creek," appeared in The Kennett Paper. He was also an
                    accomplished and prolific photographer of landscape and the natural world.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Armistead W. Browning, Jr., papers consist of material dating from 1960-1987.
                    The papers contain lecture notes on landscape architecture and design, Japanese
                    gardens, native plants and meadows, ecological and environmental topics;
                    material relating to his work with the Brandywine Valley Association and Turtle
                    Creek; notebooks and field books; and copies of his newspaper column, "Notes
                    from Turtle Creek." Also included are approximately 200 plans and drawings for
                    many of his landscaping assignments, and approximately 9,700 slides of gardens,
                    flora, and landscapes.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 91-40; 91-38</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" xpointer="https://library.udel.edu/special/findaids/view?docId=ead/mss0635.xml">https://library.udel.edu/special/findaids/view?docId=ead/mss0635.xml</extref>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>