<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Bird &amp; Bull Press records <date type="inclusive">1846-2006</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1952-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Bird &amp; Bull Press records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1265</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>18.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1846-2006</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1952-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Bird &amp; Bull Press was founded by printer and papermaker Henry Morris in
                    1958 in Newtown, Pennsylvania. Since that time, Morris has produced broadsides,
                    books, and other printed materials that are an important part of the
                    contemporary American private press scene and significant documents in the art,
                    craft, and history of hand papermaking. Morris first made paper as a commercial
                    venture in 1958 for Cheney Pulp and Paper Company, later for his own books, and
                    for friends.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Bird &amp; Bull Press records are a large collection of material dating from
                    1846, with the bulk of the material dating from the mid-1950s to 2006. The
                    collection consists of a variety of materials relating to writing, printing,
                    publication, and other topics. Much of the collection is arranged by title or
                    project, with manuscripts, typescripts, layouts, galleys, and correspondence
                    grouped together. The range of materials to be found in the collection is
                    extensive; it includes typescripts, drawings, manuscripts, illustrations,
                    typographic samples, production files, text samples, prospectuses, metal
                    engravings, wood cuts, ink prints, paper matrix, printer's apron (autographed),
                    proofs, embossing samples, paper samples, layout materials, dummies, page
                    proofs, watermarks, wood blocks, paste papers, tear sheets, books, catalogs,
                    magazines, articles, programs, certificates, orders, broadsides, signed prints,
                    contracts, telegrams, trophies, woven wall hangings, paper weights, visitor
                    badges, correspondence (personal and business), maps, invitations, inscribed
                    shorts, financial papers, coins, greeting cards, medals, business cards, bills,
                    and a Bird and Bull paper mold.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: various</p>
                <p>Year acquired: various</p>
                <p>Accession number: various</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/birdbull.htm">http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/birdbull.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>