<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Bruce Bredin papers <date type="inclusive">1958-1998</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Bruce Bredin papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1858</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1958-1998</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>J. Bruce Bredin was born in Wilmington, Delaware. Bredin attended the University
                    of Delaware and the College of William and Mary, as well as the Wharton School
                    of the University of Pennsylvania. In 1957 Bredin joined the University of
                    Delaware's Board of Trustees and served as its chairman from 1982-1988. During
                    his tenure on the board, he chaired the Executive Committee, the Honorary
                    Degrees and Awards Committee and the Art and Humanities Committee and served on
                    the committees on Grounds and Buildings, Student Personnel Services and Welfare,
                    Education and Training, Nominating and Physical Education, Athletics and
                    Recreation. In 1991 Bredin was awarded an honorary doctor of humane letters
                    degree from the University of Delaware.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the personal and professional papers of Bruce Bredin,
                    including materials related to the Bredin Foundation, Unidel Foundation, and the
                    Winterthur Board of Trustees. Materials include: business and personal
                    correspondence; bylaws, and articles of incorporation of the Bredin Foundation;
                    minutes and financial statements of the Bredin Foundation (1958-1993); and files
                    on a variety of subjects including the University of Delaware, William and Mary
                    College, the Historical Society of Delaware, and the Bredins' travel and other
                    interests.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>