<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Carol Hoffecker papers <date type="inclusive">1982-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Carol Hoffecker papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC101</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Carol E. Hoffecker is a professor of history at the University of Delaware,
                    specializing in the history of Delaware. She received her bachelor's degree from
                    the University, writing her senior thesis on Delaware during the War of 1812 and
                    the siege of Lewes. She received her master's from Radcliffe College and her
                    doctorate from Harvard in 1967. She launched her teaching career at Sweet Briar
                    College in 1963 and later taught at Northeastern University. She returned to
                    Delaware in 1968 as a junior resident scholar at the Hagley Museum and Library,
                    where she began work on a history of Delaware. She came back to the University
                    in 1970, when she became coordinator of the Hagley Graduate Program and taught
                    courses on Delaware history and urban history. In 1973, she became a full-time
                    faculty member. She is the author of Honest John Williams and Books, Bricks, and
                    Bibliophiles: The University of Delaware Library.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Carol Hoffecker papers consist of research materials related to her book,
                    Honest John Williams. Materials include research notes, newspaper clippings, and
                    copies of articles on Senator John J. Williams. The collection also includes
                    photographs of the University of Delaware and research materials for Hoffecker's
                    volume Books, Bricks, and Bibliophiles: The University of Delaware Library.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Carol Hoffecker</p>
                <p>Year acquired: various</p>
                <p>Accession number: 03-74; 03-39; 03-40; 03-41; 03-39</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Delaware: University of Delaware Press collection related to the Cultural
                    Studies of Delaware and the Eastern Shore series.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>