<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Conard-Pyle Company records <date type="inclusive">1891-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Conard-Pyle Company records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC005</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>138 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1891-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Located in West Grove, Pennsylvania, the Conard-Pyle Company was originally
                    organized in 1897 by Alfred S. Conard and A. Morris Jones as a mail-order
                    nursery and seed business specializing in own-root roses grown from cuttings and
                    sold while still small. Robert Pyle joined the company in 1898 and purchased
                    control in it after Conard's death in 1907. Pyle rapidly developed the business
                    with the popular sale of two-year-old field-grown plants on grafted roots, which
                    brought higher prices and yielded plants that would bloom in the first year of
                    purchase. Pyle became an internationally known nurseryman and authority on
                    roses, serving in leadership positions on the American Rose Society, the
                    National Association of Plant Patent Owners, the American Association of
                    Botanical Gardens and Arboretums, the American Horticultural Society, and other
                    organizations. The most famous rose introduced by Pyle is the Peace rose,
                    patented in 1943 from the work of the French hybridizer Francis Meilland. Nearly
                    every new rose today is descended from the Peace rose.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Conard-Pyle Company Archives consist of records from this prominent West
                    Grove, Pennsylvania, rose nursery that span the dates 1891-2000. The extensive
                    collection includes nursery catalogs and brochures, publications, plant patents
                    and records of the license department, annual reports, correspondence and
                    memoranda, photographs, and memorabilia. In addition to documenting the products
                    and business of Conard-Pyle, the collection provides information about the
                    history of the rose, international horticultural research, professional
                    organizations, flower shows, and all aspects of the nursery trade.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 00-09</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" xpointer="https://library.udel.edu/special/findaids/view?docId=ead/mss0634.xml">https://library.udel.edu/special/findaids/view?docId=ead/mss0634.xml</extref>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>