<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Cycling Frog Press records <date type="inclusive">1962-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Cycling Frog Press records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC116</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1962-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Sam Antupit founded The Cycling Frog Press in 1960 in his basement in Pound
                    Ridge, New York. He regularly produced booklets, announcements and other small
                    items for friends and family. In 1994 he received an NEA grant that allowed him
                    to travel the country recording various Native American storytellers then
                    printing their tales in limited editions through Cycling Frog Press. For more
                    than 40 years, Sam was a member of the Westchester Chappel, contributing a page
                    to the yearly letterpress calendar produced by this collective of hobbyist
                    printers.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers related to the Cycling Frog Press founded by Sam
                    Antupit. Materials in the collection include: proofs and samples of work;
                    broadsides, books, and keepsakes from various private presses and chappels; type
                    specimen booklets and sheets; materials related to Bob Jones and the Glad Hand
                    Press, including a wood printing block cut by John DePol; and photographs. The
                    collection also includes materials related to a book project on Native American
                    tales which was funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Antupit</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 8/12/2004</p>
                <p>Accession number: 04-102</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>