<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>David Hudson papers <date type="inclusive">1906-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">David Hudson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC240</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1906-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>David Hudson (1917-2003) was Poet Laureate of Delaware from 1956 to 1960 and from
                    1975 to 1978. He began writing poetry in the 1930s and found a forum for
                    presenting it through the Wilmington Music and Poetry Society. In the late
                    1940s, Hudson produced a weekly half hour program of local poetry on radio
                    station WILM. Hudson published a number of poetry books with works by himself
                    and others under the imprint of the Wilmington Poetry Society and Delaware
                    Writers, Inc. A native of Wilmington, Hudson was a passionate advocate for the
                    city, an was active in neighborhood preservation and beautification projects. He
                    was a leader in the Baynard Boulevard Neighborhood Association in the city's old
                    Ninth Ward. Hudson was vocal about expressing his opinions before Wilmington
                    City Council, doing so with such regularity that he was named the "honorary
                    14th member" by the group.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of the poet David Hudson. Materials include:
                    correspondence, postcards, photographs, photocopies of articles and manuscripts,
                    typescripts, artwork, certificates, notes, and volumes of poetry written by
                    David Hudson, as well as printed programs and booklets which include his poetry
                    along with the work of other Delaware poets. The collection also includes papers
                    related to Hudson's involvement in local civic and cultural activities such as
                    the Baynard Boulevard Neighborhood Association, the Wilmington City Council, the
                    Delaware Poetry Center, the Wilmington Poetry Society, and Delaware Writers
                    Inc.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: David Azartouz</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 2/23/2007; 3/1/2007; 5/19/2003</p>
                <p>Accession number: 07-16; 07-56; 03-61</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>