<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Delaware River Port Authority correspondence regarding naming of
                        the Walt Whitman Bridge <date type="inclusive">1954-1956</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript
                        Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Delaware River Port Authority correspondence regarding
                    naming of the Walt Whitman Bridge</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoPSp.ACC712</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1954-1956</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Walt Whitman Bridge is a suspension bridge spanning the Delaware River from
                    Philadelphia to Gloucester City, New Jersey. The Walt Whitman Bridge is one of
                    the larger bridges on the east coast of the United States. Construction on the
                    bridge began in 1953, and it opened to traffic on May 16, 1957. The name was
                    bestowed on July 20, 1955. The naming of the bridge itself was a subject of
                    controversy. While the span was still under construction, the Catholic Diocese
                    of Camden and local officials in South Jersey led a letter-writing campaign
                    against the naming of the bridge after Whitman because of his homosexuality.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of letters and postcards sent to the Delaware River Port
                    Authority (DRPA) regarding the naming of the Walt Whitman Bridge. The collection
                    also includes minutes and summary reports of the special committee designated
                    DRPA to consider names for the bridge. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 229</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>