<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Dorothy Miller papers <date type="inclusive">1963-2007</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Dorothy Miller papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC190</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.58 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1963-2007</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The contributions of Dorothy P. Miller (1931-) as an open space and conservation
                    activist began over forty years ago with her interest in birds and a desire to
                    preserve their natural habitats. Dorothy Miller acted as a leader in the fight
                    to preserve the White Clay Creek from damming in the 1960s, which led to the
                    creation of the bi-state preserve that is now White Clay Creek State Park in
                    both Delaware and Pennsylvania. She has helped many public and private agencies
                    see the value of land preservation in the State of Delaware, as well as in
                    Pennsylvania and Maryland. After the initial acquisition of 500 acres of
                    parkland in Delaware, then known as Carpenter State Park, she remained active in
                    lobbying for the purchase of additional lands along and in the area of the White
                    Clay Creek, which now covers over 3,800 acres. In addition to her work at White
                    Clay Creek, Dorothy Miller, with the support of the many groups to which she
                    belongs, has also assisted and lobbied for the creation and preservation of many
                    other areas and parks, including Middle Run, Coverdale, and the seven acre tract
                    of land that was designated as Dorothy P. Miller Park by the City of Newark in
                    2006.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Dorothy P. Miller documenting Miller's
                    activities related to environmental and local development issues. Materials
                    include: correspondence; published reports; drafts of legislation; maps and
                    plans; newspaper clippings; and programs. Organizations and issues represented
                    in the collection include the Coalition for Natural Stream Valleys, Inc.; the
                    Sierra Club; White Clay Creek State Park and the proposed White Clay Creek Dam;
                    Fox Den Road Bridge; Cool Run Drainage; I-95 bridges; and the Deerfield Country
                    Club.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Dorothy Miller</p>
                <p>Accession number: 06-57; 06-58; 06-77; 06-116; 07-74</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>