<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Home for Friendless and Destitute Children records <date type="inclusive">1863-2000</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1863-1963</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Home for Friendless and Destitute Children
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1859</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1863-2000</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1863-1963</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Home for Friendless and Destitute Children was founded in November 1863 as a
                    charitable organization for orphans and children whose families were unable to
                    support them, usually dependents of soldiers serving in the Civil War. The Home
                    was established by prominent citizens of Wilmington, Delaware, and the
                    surrounding area who set up various boards to regulate and supervise the Home's
                    dormitories and activities. In 1938 the name of the Home was changed to
                    Children's Home, Inc., under which it still operates.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the records of the Board of Managers of the Home for
                    Friendless and Destitute Children. Materials include: minutes of the Household,
                    Finance, Admissions and Dismission, and Executive committees and the Board of
                    Trustees; summaries of minutes; correspondence; financial reports; director's
                    reports; and reports on child welfare. The collection also contains notes by
                    Mary Morris, who was working on a history of the Home.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>