<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>J. Howard Woolmer - John Malcolm Brinnin correspondence <date type="inclusive">1975-1998</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">J. Howard Woolmer - John Malcolm Brinnin
                    correspondence</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC236</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1998</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>J. Howard Woolmer was born in Montreal in 1929. He moved to New York City in
                    1958, where he began a career as a professional bookseller in the early 1960's.
                    In addition to working at his business J. Howard Woolmer has compiled a number
                    of published bibliographies and collections of note, including A Checklist of
                    the Hogarth Press 1917-1946, and a catalogue as well as a bibliography of
                    Malcolm Lowry's writings. In recent years Mr. Woolmer has built collections
                    relating to American poets, Irish poets, American Jewish writers and Irish
                    theater for the Firestone Library at Princeton University. John Malcolm Brinnin,
                    American poet and literary critic, was born in Halifax Nova Scotia in 1929.
                    Brinnin went to the University of Michigan for his undergraduate studies where
                    he won three Hopwood Awards in 1938, 1939 and 1940. Graduating from Michigan in
                    1942, Brinnin went to Harvard University for graduate work. From 1949-1956,
                    Brinnin was Director of the Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Association
                    Poetry Center (the 92nd Street Y) . While there, he raised the 92nd Street Y to
                    national attention as a focal point of poetry in the United States. Brinnin, for
                    example, was the first person to bring Dylan Thomas to the United States.
                    Brinnin's Dylan Thomas in America (1955) describes much of his attempt to
                    befriend help the troubled Welsh poet. In addition to his work on Thomas,
                    Brinnin published six volumes of his own poetry. Brinnin also wrote scholarly
                    works on T.S. Eliot, Gertrude Stein, Truman Capote, and William Carlos Williams.
                    Brinnin taught in a number of universities including Vassar, Boston University,
                    the University of Connecticut, and Harvard University.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence between J. Howard Woolmer and poet and
                    educator, John Malcolm Brinnin. Much of the correspondence regards the sale of
                    Brinnin's papers.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: J. Howard Woolmer</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 2/19/2007</p>
                <p>Accession number: 07-14</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>