<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James A. Moore collection <date type="inclusive">1940-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James A. Moore collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1936</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1940-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James A. Moore (d. 1999) was professor emeritus of chemistry and biochemistry at
                    the University of Delaware. During World War II, Moore served as an army private
                    at White Sands, New Mexico, with a group of expatriate German rocketeers, led by
                    Werner von Braun. After the war, Moore earned his doctoral degree at
                    Pennsylvania State University and worked for six years as a chemist for Parke
                    Davis in Detroit before joining the University’s Department of Chemistry in
                    1955. Moore earned international recognition for his work as an organic chemist
                    specializing in novel heterocyclic systems, and was editor of the Journal of
                    Organic Chemistry for 25 years. He was a Gordon Conference section chairman for
                    many years and coauthor of a popular textbook in organic chemistry. He was
                    admired as a teacher and as a mentor and adviser to Ph.D. candidates and
                    postdoctoral associates. He retired from the University in 1988.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of notebooks, printed volumes, notes and other records
                    of James A. Moore. There are eight notebooks, the topics of which include
                    heterocyclic studies, 1958-1961; bromoketones, 1947-1948; cheiranthus cheiri
                    seeds, 1952-1958; the chemistry of steroidal sapogenins, 1950; excerpts from
                    research literature on psychotropic mushrooms and LSD, 1950s; and notes kept by
                    Rita Hetzell on chemistry experiments, 1983. There are two published volumes in
                    the collection: John R. Dyer's Applications of Absorption Spectroscopy of
                    Organic Compounds, 1965; and Ralph Shriner and Reynold Fuson's The Systematic
                    Identification of Organic Compounds, 1940. The collection also includes
                    correspondence with Frederick Uhle, 1950-1964; correspondence related to the
                    pennogenin problem, 1956-1963; annual evaluations and peer reviews from the
                    University of Delaware, 1976-1986; a syllabus and notes for a 1989 course on
                    biological evolution; lantern slides for presentations; and measuring tools.
                </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>