<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>J. Howard Woolmer Bloomsbury Workshop and Charleston Farmhouse
                        collection <date type="inclusive">1982-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">J. Howard Woolmer Bloomsbury Workshop and Charleston
                    Farmhouse collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC225</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>J. Howard Woolmer was born in Montreal in 1929. He moved to New York City in
                    1958, where he began a career as a professional bookseller in the early 1960s.
                    In addition to working at his business, J. Howard Woolmer has compiled a number
                    of published bibliographies and collections of note, including A Checklist of
                    the Hogarth Press 1917-1946, and a catalogue as well as a bibliography of
                    Malcolm Lowry's writings. In recent years Mr. Woolmer has built collections
                    relating to American poets, Irish poets, American Jewish writers and Irish
                    theater for the Firestone Library at Princeton University. The Bloomsbury
                    Workshop is the international specialist for work by the Bloomsbury Group. The
                    Charleston Trust is a charity set up in 1980 to restore and maintain the home of
                    the Bloomsbury Group for the benefit of the public.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials related to the Bloomsbury Workshop and the
                    Charleston Farmhouse Trust gathered by J. Howard Woolmer. Materials include:
                    programs, brochures, flyers, and correspondence.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: J. Howard Woolmer</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 2/19/2007</p>
                <p>Accession number: 07-13</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>