<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Caldwell papers supplement <date type="inclusive">1949-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Caldwell papers supplement</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC102</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1949-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Novelist and playwright Joseph K. Caldwell was born on October 2, 1928, in
                    Milwaukee, Wisconsin. His education included studies at Marquette University,
                    Columbia University, and three years in the graduate program of the School of
                    Drama at Yale University. Caldwell's plays have been produced off-Broadway, as
                    well as being transformed into television scripts. New York productions of his
                    plays include Cockeyed Kite at the Actors' Playhouse, The Downtown Holy Lady at
                    the Greenwich Mews Theatre, and Jack Fallon, Fare Thee Well by the Joseph
                    Jefferson Theatre Company. The School of Drama at Yale University produced two
                    of his plays, namely, The Bridge and Clay for the Statues of Saints. Caldwell
                    may be more widely known for his four novels, published between 1978 and 1992.
                    In Such Dark Places (1978), for which Caldwell was awarded an American Academy
                    in Rome Fellowship in Creative Writing in 1979, was his first novel. Following
                    In Such Dark Places, Caldwell wrote Deer at the River (1984), Under the Dog Star
                    (1987), and The Uncle From Rome (1992). Caldwell's most recent novel, Bread for
                    the Baker's Child, was published by Sarabande Books in 2002.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Joseph Caldwell. Materials include:
                    typescripts of The Cockeyed Kite, Bread for the Baker's Child, Mystery of the
                    Body, The Idiot's Tale, The Pig Did It, The Pig Comes to Dinner, and several
                    short stories; autograph pages from Bread for the Baker's Child and Mystery of
                    the Body; articles, and plays; and a producer's copy of The Cockeyed Kite.
                    Correspondence includes letters to Caldwell from friends, family, colleagues,
                    and publishers, as well as a few letters from Caldwell to others. The
                    correspondence includes letters from Yaddo and the MacDowell colony. Other
                    materials in the collection include: drafts of works by other writers, including
                    Andrew Kappel, Jess Grett, and Allan Gurganus; photographs; awards; programs,
                    calendars and appointment books; contracts and documents related to copyright;
                    magazines in which Caldwell's writings appear; records related to writing
                    courses taught by Caldwell; reviews; posters; sheet music; and Caldwell's
                    will.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Joseph Caldwell</p>
                <p>Year acquired: various</p>
                <p>Accession number: 03-96; 03-89; 03-90; 03-09; 07-15; 04-103; 06-25</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>