<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>June D. MacArtor papers <date type="inclusive">1966-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">June D. MacArtor papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1263</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>42 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1966-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>June D. MacArtor is a lawyer who has been very active in the area of
                    environmental law. She received her law degree from Villanova University in 1974
                    after raising four children. She headed the Delaware Department of Justice
                    Environmental Group for ten years, after which she became the head of the
                    investigative group at the Division of Consumer Affairs. Later she was Deputy
                    Director of the Division of Air and Waste Management in the Department of
                    Natural Resources and Environmental Control. She retired in 1990. MacArtor
                    serves on the board of directors of the Delaware Nature Society and has also
                    held positions at a number of other conservation, planning, and advisory
                    committees and councils. She has taught courses in environmental law and policy
                    at the University of Delaware and at Widener University.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of June D. MacArtor papers related to Ms. MacArtor's work on
                    environmental issues for the State of Delaware and other citizens' watch groups.
                    The collection includes reports and studies, minutes, handbooks, correspondence,
                    legal forms, programs, notebooks, calendars, and memos.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of June D. MacArtor</p>
                <p>Year acquired: various</p>
                <p>Accession number: various</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/macartor.htm">http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/macartor.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>