<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Major David Lenox papers <date type="inclusive">1782-1832</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Major David Lenox papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC207</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1782-1832</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>David Lenox was the United States Marshall for the Pennsylvania District Court
                    during the Whiskey Rebellion. Lenox also served as the President of the Bank of
                    the United States, and was a businessman and land speculator. His wife was Tacy
                    Lukens.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of David Lenox. Materials include:
                    correspondence relating to Lenox's career subsequent to the Revolution (land
                    speculation, duties in the Whiskey Rebellion, executorship of the estates of
                    John Lukens and Joseph Prowell, and banking); personal business and household
                    receipts; and records related to the settlement of his estate. Included in the
                    collection is Alexander Hamilton's and Richard Peters's letter of November 11,
                    1794, thanking Lenox for his government service, but urging him to the bedside
                    of his sick wife. Also included are letters from Robert and William Pulsford
                    advising Lenox on the financial affairs of the Washington Plantation. These
                    letters contain discussions of the sale of slaves. Other correspondents include
                    Horace Binney, William Bradford, George Fisher, Alexander Graydon, Robert Lenox,
                    Levi Lincoln, various members of the Lukens family, various members of the
                    Prowell family, and Forsyth Smith &amp; Co.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Anna D. Moyerman.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1972</p>
                <p>Accession number: 07-104</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Pennsylvania State
                    Archives: Lukens-Lenox papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>