<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Marion H. Steele papers <date type="inclusive">1916-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Marion H. Steele papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1937</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Marion Harlan Steele (1904-1985) was one of the pioneers of the American home
                    economics movement, which began at the turn of the twentieth century. Ellen H.
                    Richards founded the American Home Economics Association (AHEA) in 1909. Steele
                    championed Richards’ philosophy about family, nutrition, and ecology, but
                    especially devoted her efforts to the International Scholarship Program of AHEA
                    (which became the American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences—AAFCS—in
                    1994). Steele attended the University of Delaware’s Women’s College, graduating
                    in 1928 with a bachelor's degree in English. In 1928 she began working as
                    secretary to Helen W. Atwater, the editor of AHEA's Journal of Home Economics.
                    Atwater also served as Specialist in Home Economics for the States Relations
                    Service of the USDA. After a number of promotions, Marion Steele became the
                    journal's managing editor in 1946. Steele held that position until she retired
                    in 1969.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of papers related to the AHEA, the Marion H. Steele
                    Symposium, and records of Helen W. Atwater. AHEA records include copies of the
                    AHEA Journal of Home Economics (1953, 1959, including 50th anniversary issue);
                    extracts regarding the AHEA International Scholarship Students (1935-1969);
                    copies of the National Magazine of Home Economics Student Clubs (1936-1942); the
                    resume of Marion H. Steele; a booklet from the 14th annual Marion H. Steele
                    Symposium (1999), with biographical information; a history of the AHEA; and
                    photos, largely from the USDA and the US Bureau of Home Economics. The Atwater
                    papers date from 1916 to the mid 1940s and include correspondence, printed
                    bulletins, newspaper clippings, and typescripts of articles. There are also
                    tributes and memorials for Atwater, and for Mildred Horton, the Executive
                    Secretary of the AHEA.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <otherfindaid>
                <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" xpointer="https://library.udel.edu/special/findaids/view?docId=ead/mss0439.xml">https://library.udel.edu/special/findaids/view?docId=ead/mss0439.xml</extref>
            </otherfindaid>

        </archdesc>
    </ead>