<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Mark Harris papers supplement <date type="inclusive">1958-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Mark Harris papers supplement</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC083</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.0 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1958-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Mark Harris was born in Mount Vernon, New York, in 1922. After serving in the
                    Armed Forces during World War II, Harris worked as a journalist in New York
                    City, St. Louis, and Chicago before enrolling at the University of Denver, from
                    which he received a Master's degree in 1951. He obtained a Ph.D. in American
                    Studies from the University of Minnesota in 1956 and went on to teach at several
                    universities, eventually settling at Arizona State, where he was a professor of
                    English and taught in the creative writing program from 1980 to 2001. Harris was
                    best known for a quartet of novels about baseball players: The Southpaw (1953),
                    Bang the Drum Slowly (1956), A Ticket for a Seamstitch (1957), and It Looked
                    Like Forever (1979). In 1956, Bang the Drum Slowly was adapted for an
                    installment of the dramatic television anthology series The United States Steel
                    Hour; the production starred Paul Newman as Wiggen and Albert Salmi as doomed
                    catcher Bruce Pearson. The novel also became a major motion picture in 1973,
                    with a screenplay written by Harris, directed by John D. Hancock and featuring
                    Michael Moriarty as Wiggen and Robert DeNiro as Pearson.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection is a supplement to the Mark Harris papers. Materials include:
                    correspondence, screenplays, typescripts, bills and receipts, books, magazines,
                    articles, and genealogies. The collection also includes records relating to a
                    lawsuit between Harris and Arizona State University over a matter of tenure.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 02-34; 02-15</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/harriss.htm">http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/harriss.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>