<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Meserve Holly collection <date type="inclusive">1947-1989</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Meserve Holly collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC636</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1947-1989</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Kathleen Kellogg Meserve (1906-1999) was an amateur horticulturist from Long
                    Island who produced a series of hardy holly hybrids that have become standard in
                    nurseries and gardens in the United States and Europe. Meserve's interest in
                    holly began shortly after World War II when she and her family moved to a
                    10-acre estate in St. James on Long Island, where she attended a local
                    garden-club lecture about holly. In 1975 the American Horticultural Society
                    honored Meserve for her "outstanding contributions to amateur horticulture,"
                    and six years later she received the Eloise Payne Luquer Medal of the Garden
                    Club of America for her work in hybridizing hollies and greatly extending their
                    temperature range. The profits from the sale of Mrs. Meserve's holly patents
                    helped to maintain her estate, which came to be called Holly-by-Golly. Her
                    plants are sold by commercial growers throughout the world.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials related to Kathleen Meserve's horticultural
                    work and her business Holly-By-Golly. Materials in the collection include:
                    business and personal correspondence, propagation records, financial records,
                    brochures, posters, printed reference material and catalogs, magazines,
                    journals, books, slides and photographs, and seeds.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Longwood Gardens</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 3/20/2003</p>
                <p>Accession number: 2003-30</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Delaware: Conard-Pyle Company records (has information on Holly-By-Golly).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>