<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Oak Knoll Books records <date type="inclusive">1958-2003</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1976-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Oak Knoll Books records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC100</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>13 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1958-2003</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1976-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Oak Knoll Books was founded in 1976 by Robert D. Fleck, and in 1978 Oak Knoll
                    Press was founded as an extension of the business. Today, Oak Knoll Books
                    maintains an inventory of approximately 18,000 titles, and the press has
                    published approximately 950 books. Oak Knoll specializes in books concerning
                    book collecting, book selling, bibliographies, libraries, publishing, private
                    press printing, fine printing, bookbinding, book design, book illustration,
                    calligraphy, graphic arts, marbling, papermaking, printing, typography and type
                    specimens. Oak Knoll is also the exclusive distributor of books published by the
                    American Antiquarian Society, the Bibliographical Society, the Bibliographical
                    Society of the University of Virginia, The John Carter Brown Library, and many
                    others. Oak Knoll Books is located in historic New Castle, Delaware.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The archives of Oak Knoll Books consists of material spanning the dates
                    1930-2003. It includes books, correspondence, shipping logs, paper sample books,
                    prospectuses, purchasing files, advertisements, financial files, speeches, and
                    newsletters and periodicals pertaining to the business of collecting,
                    publishing, and selling books. The collection also includes catalogs and price
                    lists, as well as materials related to Oak Knoll Fest, an annual book festival
                    produced by Oak Knoll Books.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Robert Fleck</p>
                <p>Year acquired: various</p>
                <p>Accession number: 03-56; 02-35; 01-42; 99-3; 98-3; 97-36; 97-19c; 96-18c</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/oakknoll.htm">http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/oakknoll.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>