<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Patriotic Order of the Sons of America Washington Camp No. 554
                        minute book <date type="inclusive">1896-1903</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Patriotic Order of the Sons of America Washington Camp No.
                    554 minute book</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1925</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1896-1903</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Order of the Junior Sons of America was founded in 1847 in Philadelphia,
                    Pennsylvania, by Dr. Reynell Coates (1802-1886). Dr. Coates was a surgeon,
                    scientist, statesman, naturalist, teacher, poet, lecturer and essayist, and
                    wished to found a fraternity for American boys to serve as a "High School of
                    American Patriotism." The organization was open to American boys aged 16 to 21
                    years of age. Upon turning 21, their membership would be transferred to the
                    United Sons of America, the parent organization of the Junior Sons. The first
                    meeting of the Junior Sons of America was conducted on December 10, 1847, on
                    Ridge Road, near Spring Garden Street in Philadelphia. Towards the conclusion of
                    the Civil War, a convention was held by several Brothers of the Junior Sons of
                    America in Norristown, Pennsylvania, to reorganize the Order. It was at this
                    time that the name was changed to the Patriotic Order of the Sons of America
                    (P.O.S. of A.) and the age limit of 21 was discontinued.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of a minute book of weekly meetings of the Patriotic
                    Order of the Sons of America from 1896 to 1903. Many of the entries include
                    brief financial statements.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Delaware: Order of the U.S.A. Pennsylvania Camp No. 1 minute book and Junior
                    Sons of America minute book.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>