<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Custom House records <date type="inclusive">1779-1930</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Custom House records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC212</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>30 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1779-1930</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The United States Customs Service (1789-1927) processed paperwork for the import
                    and export of goods into and out of the country. Customs officials also assessed
                    and collected customs fees and penalties. Past functions of the Customs Service
                    included administration of navigation aids and lighthouses, and functions
                    relating to the protection of seamen, and to revenue cutters. In 1927 the
                    Customs Service became the Bureau of Customs.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of the United States Customs Service of the Port
                    of Philadelphia, illustrating commercial and shipping interests, as well as
                    foreign trade relations, of Colonial America and of the United States. The
                    records include: official Customs House records, liquidation entries,
                    affidavits, foreign invoices, general correspondence, consular authentications,
                    and abstracts of duties. There are also four microfilm reels of documents within
                    the collection, 1790-1869, categorized by topic, such as metalwork, clothing,
                    textiles, ceramics, other craftsmen, artists, and occupations. In addition,
                    there is a set of printouts of the U.S. Customs Service archives.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Barry Moyerman.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1972</p>
                <p>Accession number: 07-109</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>