<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia and Erie Land Company and South Renovo Land Company
                        records <date type="inclusive">1865-1907</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia and Erie Land Company and South Renovo Land
                    Company records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC210</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1865-1907</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Incorporated in 1864, the Philadelphia and Erie Land Company laid out the town of
                    Renovo, Pennsylvania, as the site for the great repair shops of the Philadelphia
                    and Erie Division of the Pennsylvania Railroad. South Renovo, Pennsylvania,
                    across the river from Renovo, was laid out in 1881.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of the Philadelphia and Erie Land Company.
                    Bound volumes include a dividend book (1866-1903), a record of the sale of town
                    plots in Renovo, including sketches of the plots, and a book of unused stock
                    certificates. Other materials include: maps, deeds, bond and warranties, reports
                    and appraisals, mortgages, a record of capital distribution (1870-1903) and
                    business correspondence. Most of the correspondence relates to the sale and
                    development of land in Emporium and Renovo, and is directed to John A. Glenn,
                    Secretary of the Company, and to Joseph F. Reilley, agent. The collection also
                    includes a small number of business papers of the South Renovo Land Company.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Barry Moyerman.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1972</p>
                <p>Accession number: 07-107</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>