<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Planned Parenthood of Delaware records <date type="inclusive">1931-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Planned Parenthood of Delaware records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC029</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1931-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Founded in 1931, Planned Parenthood has changed and expanded its services in
                    response to social, legal, and medical developments over the twentieth century.
                    The early Birth Control League of Delaware was established by a group of
                    socially prominent women to address social and economic hardships of families in
                    Wilmington. It was modeled after Margaret Sanger's American Birth Control
                    League. Their objective was "to make available to every family in Delaware good
                    medical advice and proper supplies in the fields of contraception and fertility;
                    and to educate the general public to the idea of using scientific knowledge to
                    improve the quality of family life." To this end, they counseled patients on
                    contraceptive practices, and the benefits of child spacing for family growth,
                    and provided health care to new mothers and babies with a post-partum clinic and
                    a visiting new mothers program. In 1942, adhering to the nation's wartime focus
                    on family unity, the Birth Control League changed its name to the Delaware
                    League for Planned Parenthood. In the 1950s, the League sponsored lectures for
                    interns, residents, and practical nurses at Delaware Hospital and, with a Clergy
                    Advisory Committee, developed "education for marriage" programs. Marriage
                    lectures were presented to young women at the University of Delaware and
                    Delaware State College. Unwed mothers were not served by the Delaware League
                    until 1961; American married couples were not legally protected in efforts to
                    obtain birth control until 1965; the right purchase contraceptives was extended
                    to unmarried persons in 1972; and in 1973, the U.S. Supreme Court extended a
                    woman's right to privacy to her decision to terminate a pregnancy. In addition
                    to continuing birth control, family planning, and infertility services, the
                    League expanded over time to provide sex education, abortion services, surveys
                    and research, cancer screening, HIV testing, and AIDS counseling. Planned
                    Parenthood of Delaware's outreach has been widely diverse as it has developed
                    special programs for the inner-city poor of Wilmington, rural women in southern
                    Delaware, prisoners, migrant workers, teenagers, college students, clergy, and
                    medical professionals. The League has worked from its earliest days to
                    collaborate with general social service programs, working with social workers
                    and social agencies for referrals, and publicity. Some of its first audiences
                    for public relations efforts were Parent Teacher Association (PTA) assemblies,
                    women's clubs, and groups of Polish and Italian immigrant women in Wilmington.
                    Source: Newsletter of the University of Delaware Library Associates. March 1997,
                    no. 32.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Archives of Planned Parenthood of Delaware consist of material dating from
                    1931-1999. In particular it documents the early history of the organization, its
                    administration, and the variety of services Planned Parenthood has provided in
                    Delaware over the years. The Archives includes Board minutes and reports,
                    bylaws, budgets, clipping files, newsletters, promotional material, anniversary
                    and benefit program files, and photographs. This archives is a valuable source
                    to tell the history of this organization and the community it serves.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 01-53; 96-53c</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/planned.htm">http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/planned.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>