<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert B. Wolf papers <date type="inclusive">1910-1952</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert B. Wolf papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1861</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1952</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert B. Wolf was born in Newark, Delaware, and educated at the University of
                    Delaware. Wolf was a director of the National Bureau of Economic Research, the
                    American Paper and Pulp Association, and the New York Merchants Association, of
                    which he was chairman of its Industrial Relations Committee. Wolf was the
                    manager of the Pulp Division of the Weyerhaeuser Timber Company (retired in
                    1947, after which he did consulting) and a specialist in labor-management
                    relations.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Robert B. Wolf that span the dates
                    1910-1952. Materials include: incoming and outgoing letters to figures in
                    industry, government, and trade unions (both individual unions and federations);
                    typescript and printed addresses on issues related to business and labor; and
                    biographical information on Wolf. Correspondents include Florence Thorne and
                    William Green of the American Federation of Labor. The collection also includes
                    subject files on the war scare, and notable figures of the time, including H.G.
                    Wells, Hitler, Walter Lippmann, and Frances Perkins.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>