<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert Barnes collection of Curtis and James River paper samples
                            <date type="inclusive">1974-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert Barnes collection of Curtis and James River paper
                    samples</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1204</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1974-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert C. Barnes is a retired police officer and a local historian. He is the
                    co-author of Press, Politics &amp; Perseverance: Everett C. Johnson and The
                    Press of Kells. The Curtis Paper Mill (also known as the Nonantum Mill) is a
                    factory located near White Clay Creek in Newark, Delaware. Although a mill has
                    existed on the site since the late eighteenth century, the present structure was
                    built in 1870. The Curtis brothers bought the plant in 1848. Although the plant
                    is usually referred to in Newark as the Curtis Paper Mill, the actual name is
                    Nonantum Mill, referring to an Indian name for the area of Newton,
                    Massachusetts, the Curtis' hometown. The plant had the distinction of
                    manufacturing the paper on which several of the peace treaties ending World War
                    II were signed. The James River Corporation eventually purchased the plant, but
                    closed it in 1997 as they consolidated their operations.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Robert Barnes collection of Curtis and James River paper samples consists of
                    material dating from the 1980s and 1990s. The collection contains paper sample
                    books and albums, promotional posters, envelopes, and brochures. The samples
                    were collected from the Curtis Paper Mill in Newark, Delaware.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 99-32</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/barnes.htm">http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/barnes.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>