<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Roger E. Nathan papers <date type="inclusive">1909-2005</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960s-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Roger E. Nathan papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC293</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1909-2005</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960s-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Roger E. Nathan (d. 2005) of Woodstown, New Jersey, was a significant help to the
                    Delaware, Maryland, Pennsylvania, and New Jersey boundary commissions during the
                    1980s and 1990s when the Delaware Boundary Commission was reestablishing
                    Delaware's boundary monuments and signing new boundary agreements with
                    neighboring states. Roger Nathan visited every monument and provided the
                    commissions with photographic evidence and written reports on the condition of
                    all 179 monuments. He was the author of East of the Mason-Dixon Line, A History
                    of the Delaware Boundaries.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Roger E. Nathan Papers consist of research materials related to the surveying
                    of Delaware boundaries and the Mason-Dixon Line. Included among the papers are
                    newspaper clippings, magazines, photocopies, a 1909 copy of the Report on the
                    Resurvey of the Maryland-Pennsylvania Boundary, maps. note, and a foreword for a
                    History of the Delaware Boundaries. The collection also includes some
                    correspondence between Nathan and members of the State Boundary Commission and
                    meeting minutes of the commission.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Mrs. Barbara Nathan</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 2/19/2007</p>
                <p>Accession number: 07-9</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Delaware Public
                    Archives: Roger E. Nathan’s Delaware Boundary Monument Slide Collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>