<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Ruth J. Snowdon collection of travel slides <date type="inclusive">undated</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Ruth J. Snowdon collection of travel slides</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1135</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>31 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Ruth Anna Johnson Snowdon, was the wife of Charles Leidy Snowdon Jr., and the
                    mother of Elizabeth Snowdon Hoopes. Snowdon traveled extensively during the
                    1960s and 1970s.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Ruth J. Snowdon collection of Travel Slides consists of material dating from
                    the 1960s and 1970s. It is a collection of over 7,000 3-D color slides which
                    depict Mrs. Snowdon's worldwide travels to Egypt, Greece, Israel, Haiti, Ceylon,
                    Japan, Italy, Mexico, Bali, Burma, Cambodia, Ceylon, Denmark, Guatemala, India,
                    Java, Jordan, Korea, Qumran, Portugal, Lebanon, Spain, Singapore, Switzerland,
                    Taiwan, Morocco, Philippines, Sicily, Thailand, Yugoslavia, France, and the
                    United States. Each slide is numbered and labeled as to content. An extensive
                    index to the collection includes subject headings and cross-references. Most of
                    the slides are grouped by country, with some series including subheadings, such
                    as cities or regions within a country. Other series include subject groupings
                    such as plants and trees, gardens, children, agriculture, transportation,
                    religion, architecture, or industry. The collection also includes five hand-held
                    3D slide viewers.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 96-33c</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/snowdon.htm">http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/snowdon.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>