<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>University of Delaware Press collection related to the Cultural
                        Studies of Delaware and the Eastern Shore series <date type="inclusive">1972-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">University of Delaware Press collection related to the
                    Cultural Studies of Delaware and the Eastern Shore series</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC290</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.66 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1972-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The University of Delaware Press was established in the early 1970s and published
                    infrequently until 1975, when it joined the consortium, Associated University
                    Presses. The Press now publishes approximately thirty-five to forty books every
                    year under its own imprint. The Press publishes books in all fields of
                    scholarship, including: literary studies, especially Shakespeare, Renaissance
                    and Early Modern Literature; Eighteenth-Century Studies; French Literature; art
                    history and history; and historical and cultural studies of Delaware and the
                    Eastern Shore.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of publication files, including correspondence, drafts,
                    proofs, and clippings, related to works published as part of the University of
                    Delaware Press - Cultural Studies of Delaware and the Eastern Shore series. The
                    collection includes files for the following titles: Honest John Williams, U. S.
                    Senator and New Sweden in America by Carol Hoffecker; Governing Delaware: Policy
                    Problems by William Boyer; Creek Walking: Growing Up in Delaware in the 1950s by
                    Jacqueline Jones; Hanging the Moon: The Rollins Rise to Riches by Drury Pifer;
                    and Rebel With a Conscience by Russell W. Peterson.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: University of Delaware Press</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 3/5/2007; 2/26/2007; 5/21/2007; 12/19/2006</p>
                <p>Accession number: 07-27; 07-10; 07-64; 06-134</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Delaware: Carol Hoffecker papers and William Boyer papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>