<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>W.D. Snodgrass papers <date type="inclusive">1939-2007</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">W.D. Snodgrass papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1266</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>55.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1939-2007</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Poet W. D. Snodgrass was born William De Witt Snodgrass on January 5, 1926, in
                    Wilkinsburg, Pennsylvania. He attended Geneva College prior to graduating from
                    the University of Iowa with a B.A. in 1949, an M.A. in 1951, and a M.F.A. in
                    1953. He also holds an honorary Doctor of Letters from Allegheny College. W. D.
                    Snodgrass's first book, a collection of poetry titled Heart's Needle (New York:
                    Knopf, 1959) was awarded the 1960 Pulitzer Prize for Poetry. Since that
                    publication Snodgrass has produced over thirty books of poetry, translations,
                    and criticism. In addition to Heart's Needle, the poet's other published
                    collections of poetry include After Experience (1968), the Fuhrer Bunker: A
                    Cycle of Poems in Progress (1977), Remains (1970), and The Death of Cock Robin
                    (1989). In addition to the Pulitzer Prize, the poet has been honored with such
                    awards as the Hudson Review Fellowship (1958), the Longview Award (1959), the
                    Poetry Society of America Special Citation (1960), the Guinness Award (1961),
                    the Ingram Merrill Foundation Award (1968), and the Centennial Medal of Romania
                    (1977). Snodgrass was elected to the National Institute of Arts and Letters in
                    1972, and was made a Fellow of the Academy of American Poets in 1973. Following
                    faculty assignments at Cornell University (1955-1957), University of Rochester
                    (1957-1958), Wayne State University (1959-1967), Syracuse University
                    (1968-1977), and Old Dominion University (1978-1979); W. D. Snodgrass joined the
                    faculty at the University of Delaware in 1979. He currently holds the position
                    of Distinguished Professor of Creative Writing and Contemporary Poetry.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The papers of W.D. Snodgrass represent the entire career of the poet and author,
                    from his elementary school days and early poems at the Writers Workshop to the
                    most recent drafts of his current work. The collection consists of numerous
                    drafts of poetry manuscripts (in autograph, typescript, and electronic format),
                    translations, plays, essays, criticism and other writing, personal and
                    professional correspondence, calendars and travel plans, papers for seminars and
                    classes, publishing proofs, books and journals, interviews, clippings,
                    photographs, artwork, video and audio recordings, and awards. The correspondence
                    includes exchanges with notable authors such as Anne Sexton, Donald Hall, James
                    Merrill, Robert Lowell, John Berryman, Richard Wilbur, Donald Justice, Mona
                    Thurston, Hortense Caslisher, and many others.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Most purchased from W.D. Snodgrass</p>
                <p>Year acquired: various</p>
                <p>Accession number: various</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/snodgras.htm">http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/snodgras.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Delaware: W. D. Snodgrass Correspondence with Daniela Gioseffi (Mss 272), W. D.
                    Snodgrass Letters and Manuscripts to Jerome Mazzaro (Mss 273), and W. D.
                    Snodgrass Collection (Mss 274).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>