<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wanda Blazejewski Larsen papers <date type="inclusive">1940-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wanda Blazejewski Larsen papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC007</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1940-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Wanda Catherine Blazejewski Larsen was extremely active in the Polish-American
                    community in Delaware. She spent three summers studying at Polish universities
                    in Krakow and Lublin to gain knowledge so she could inform the American public
                    about Poland. To this end, she held many lectures and exhibits, and was a member
                    of the Delaware Council of International Visitors and the Americans of Polish
                    Descent Cultural Society. Mrs. Larsen was an active volunteer in Newark,
                    Delaware, and Elkton, Maryland. Her autobiography is titled Dear and Not So Dear
                    Memories.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Wanda Larsen, dating from 1940-1999. Much
                    of the material relates to Larsen's travels to Poland and other destinations.
                    These mainly consist of photographs and slides, but also include maps,
                    brochures, and guidebooks. In addition, the collection includes 16 scrapbooks
                    and photo albums which document her life, including her involvement with the
                    Americans of Polish Descent Cultural Society and her ties with the University of
                    Delaware. The scrapbooks contain photographs, awards, certificates, greeting
                    cards, menus, programs, and magazine articles. The collection also includes
                    drafts of her autobiography, Dear and Not So Dear Memories, and college papers
                    of Larsen and of her husband, Louis.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 00-43; 00-05; 99-80; 96-50; 95-38c ; 94-71</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/larsen.htm">http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/larsen.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>