<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Williams family papers <date type="inclusive">1778-1877</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Williams family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC1865</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1778-1877</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Jonathan Williams (1750-1815) was a merchant and soldier. He was the grandnephew
                    of Benjamin Franklin, and served as the first Superintendent of West Point. He
                    married Marianne Alexander of Edinburgh, Scotland. The couple lived at Mount
                    Pleasant. Their daughter, Christine, married Thomas Biddle. Jonathan and
                    Marianne Williams's son, Henry Jonathan (1791-1879), married Julia Rush
                    (1792-1860), the daughter of Dr. Benjamin Rush. The Williams' daughter,
                    Christine, married Thomas Biddle. Their son was Alexander Biddle.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of personal and business papers of the Williams family.
                    Jonathan Williams papers (1778-1811) consist of personal and business
                    correspondence, including McFarlan &amp; Reilly's 1811 "Estimate of a Coachee
                    for Col. Williams." Correspondents include Robert Alexander, William Alexander,
                    and John Wheelock. Marianne Williams papers consist of personal letters dating
                    from 1785 to 1813. Julia Rush Williams papers include her personal
                    correspondence to her husband, and a commonplace book of religious extracts. The
                    bulk of the collection consists of the papers of Henry Jonathan Williams, dating
                    from 1815 to 1875. These include Williams's professional correspondence:
                    documents related to the estates of Miss Bothia Alexander, Miss Elizabeth Stott,
                    and Mrs. Maria Nixon; papers (taxes, rents, improvements) as agent and part
                    owner of the Morrisville Estate; accounts of Jonathan Williams Biddle, also an
                    agent of the Morrisville Estate; estate papers for members of the of the Rush
                    family, including Dr. James Rush and Mrs. P.A. Rush; printed court transcripts,
                    indentures, and deeds; articles of agreement; bills and receipts; household
                    account books; and verses written to Williams by George Wilson. Williams's
                    correspondents include: Horace Binney, John C. Bullitt, T. P. Carpenter,
                    Frederick Graff, Hyman Gratz, Henry Harrison, Jared R. Ingersoll, William
                    Jeffrey, Joseph S. Lewis, D. H. Nevins, Mrs. Maria Nixon, Ralph Peters, Richard
                    Peters, John M. Read, George Sharswood, and Francis Gurney Smith. There is also
                    one receipt book related to the Fame Insurance Company and an inventory of stock
                    for the Crescent Factory.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of the Moyerman family.</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Library Company of
                    Philadelphia: Library Company of Philadelphia financial and legal records. (Rush
                    estate papers and related legal papers.); University of Delaware: Philadelphia
                    insurance companies collection (Fame Insurance Company receipt book); Crescent
                    Factory (two daybooks). </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>