<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William Boyer papers <date type="inclusive">1960-2000</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1990s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William Boyer papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC186</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-2000</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1990s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Boyer is Charles Polk Messick Professor Emeritus of Public Administration
                    and former Chair of the Department of Political Science at the University of
                    Delaware. He is the author of Governing Delaware and has written extensively
                    about public policy issues in Delaware, the United States, and abroad. A
                    graduate of the College of Wooster, Boyer received his master's and doctoral
                    degrees from the University of Wisconsin in Madison, after which he served as an
                    assistant to the governor of Wisconsin and in other government positions. At the
                    University of Delaware, he was co-founder of the master of public administration
                    degree program and helped establish study abroad programs in Geneva and Costa
                    Rica.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of William Boyer. The bulk of the collection
                    consists of files Boyer compiled in the process of writing a book on the state
                    of Delaware. The files cover Delaware's politics and government, health,
                    education, housing, economics, environment, crime, and demographics. Materials
                    include printed technical and research reports and statistical summaries;
                    newspaper and magazine articles; and academic theses. The collection also
                    includes audio tapes from the 1960s of Boyer speaking on international and
                    domestic political issues.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of William Boyer</p>
                <p>Accession number: 06-4</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Delaware: University of Delaware Press collection related to the Cultural
                    Studies of Delaware and the Eastern Shore series.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>