<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William Innes Homer papers <date type="inclusive">1887-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>University of Delaware</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William Innes Homer papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">UoDSp.ACC115</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">University of Delaware<address>
                        <addressline>Special Collections Department</addressline>
                        <addressline>Morris Library, 181 South College Avenue</addressline>
                        <addressline>Newark, DE 19717-5267</addressline>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>25.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1887-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Art historian William Innes Homer is H. Rodney Sharp Professor Emeritus of Art
                    History at the University of Delaware. His research includes work on American
                    painters Albert Pinkham Ryder and Thomas Eakins, and Photo Secessionists Alfred
                    Stieglitz, Gertrude Käsebier, Clarence White, and others.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of William Innes Homer, which document Homer’s
                    research on art, design and photography in the early decades of the twentieth
                    century. Materials in the collection include correspondence, research notes,
                    slides, programs, and a copy of Homer’s Portrait of My Life: a Work in Progress.
                    Artists and movements represented include Clarence S. White, Gertrude Käsebier,
                    Alfred Stieglitz and the Photo Secessionists, Albert Pinkham Ryder, John Sloan,
                    Chagall, Dufy, Leger, and Beaux Arts architects. Notable items in the collection
                    include: a 1914 publisher's prospectus from Galerie Vollard for work by Paul
                    Cezanne; a 1913 prospectus for the Albert and Charles Boni magazine The Glebe; a
                    brochure, with commentary by Gertrude Traubel, for a 1919 painting and sculpture
                    exhibition at the Macdowell Club in New York; and a small collection of books
                    and periodicals related to the history and technology of photography.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of William Innes Homer.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 04-04; 04-119; 05-46; 06-103; 02-38; 01-49; 00-20; 99-55;
                    04-63; 04-69; 04-13</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/homer.htm">http://www.lib.udel.edu/ud/spec/findaids/homer.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>