<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Anne Hampton Brewster papers <date type="inclusive">1777-1892</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Anne Hampton Brewster papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1517</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1777-1892</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Correspondence, diaries, commonplace books, notes and article drafts and
                    clippings of Anne Hampton Brewster, novelist, journalist, and foreign
                    correspondent. She lived in Rome beginning in 1868 and wrote articles about
                    Italian art, architecture, archaeology, political events, and social gossip,
                    until about 1888. Much of the collection consists of her notes and drafts for
                    these articles, which appeared in such American newspapers as the Philadelphia
                    Evening Bulletin, the Boston Advertiser, and the New York World. Other materials
                    concern her story and novel drafts--she wrote St. Martin's Summer, Compensation,
                    and several short stories for magazines such as Blackwood's. Her correspondents,
                    whose letters are primarily of a personal nature, include Thomas Buchanan Read
                    (painter, poet), Amelia B. Edwards, author, archaeologist, Grace Greenwood
                    (pseudonym for Sara Hane Clarke Lippincot), and Benjamin Harris Brewster, her
                    brother, a lawyer and attorney general of the United States from 1881-1885. Her
                    detailed diaries run from 1845 to 1892. The papers also include an autograph
                    collection with documents signed by Abraham Lincoln, W. T. Sherman, James
                    Madison, and others.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>