<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Bank of the United States minute book <date type="inclusive">1841-1842</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Bank of the United States minute book</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1221</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.06 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1841-1842</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Second Bank of the United States was located in Philadelphia and chartered in
                    1816, five years after the expiration of the First Bank of the United States. It
                    was founded during the administration of President James Madison in an attempt
                    to stabilize the currency. The Bank served as the repository for Federal funds
                    until 1836, when its charter expired after President Andrew Jackson refused to
                    recharter it due to a dispute with the Bank's president, Nicholas Biddle. The
                    Bank then operated as a private institution until it went defunct in 1841.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This volume contains the rough minutes from June 1841 to January 1842 of the
                    Trustees for Circulation and Deposits of the Bank of the United States. The
                    entries are nearly daily, and discuss receipt of correspondence, appointment of
                    agents, recovery of debts, and investments held by the bank. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 9989.F</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Bank of the United States of Pennsylvania papers (1390A/B/C).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>