<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charles A. Poulson Philadelphia scrapbooks <date type="inclusive">1822-1865</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charles A. Poulson Philadelphia scrapbooks</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1744</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1822-1865</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles Augustus Poulson Jr., grandson of Library Company of Philadelphia
                    librarian Zachariah Poulson, was a publisher, antiquarian, and amateur
                    historian. He compiled several series of scrapbooks of Philadelphia history,
                    which were bequeathed to the Library Company following his death in 1866. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of scrapbooks predominately containing newspaper clippings,
                    many dated between 1850 and 1860, describing the history, society, built
                    environment, and political climate of Philadelphia. Other subject matter
                    includes local anecdotes, price lists, mortality charts, tax lists, and year
                    chronologies. Also contains periodical illustrations, advertisements, and prints
                    showing businesses, churches, benevolent institutions, public and municipal
                    buildings, household furnishings and implements, and social satires, several
                    with an Afro-Americana or fashion content. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Dickinson College:
                    Poulson, Charles Augustus, Sr. (1789-1866) Family papers, MC 2006.02</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>