<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>C.S. Rafinesque daybook <date type="inclusive">1832-1834</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">C.S. Rafinesque daybook</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1683</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1832-1834</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Constantine Samuel Rafinesque, naturalist and ichthyologist, made the United
                    States his home in 1815, and became one of the outstanding American natural
                    scientists. He numbered among his friends the scientific elite of his day, a
                    circle which included Zaccheus Collins, the great Quaker naturalist, with whom
                    Rafinesque entered into a law suit in 1832. In 1818, Rafinesque became a
                    professor of botany, natural history, and modern languages at Transylvania
                    College, Lexington, KY. Here he continued the extensive field trips which
                    carried him over a large portion of the eastern and trans-Appalachian states.
                    From 1826 to his death, Rafinesque lived in Philadelphia where he devoted much
                    time to writing and publishing. Although most of his literary efforts were of a
                    scientific nature, he wrote also on banking, economy, and the Bible, and
                    published a great amount of periodical material and some verse. Rafinesque was a
                    man of imagination and great ability, but for all this, like so many pioneers in
                    the field of learning, he died inconspicuously and unrewarded.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The daybook of Rafinesque, kept for the years 1832-1834, might more accurately be
                    called an account book. It is a daily record of expenses and business
                    transactions which cast brief but considerable light on the activities of the
                    author during this period. The volume opens with a statement of Rafinesque's
                    properties as of January first, 1832. This statement includes entries of claims
                    and debts, medicines in the hands of agents, books sent abroad for sale, and an
                    evaluation of his library, manuscripts, maps and engravings, herbarium, shells
                    and fossils, drugs and minerals. Accounts with the United States Bank, expenses
                    for paper, specimens, publications, notes on the sales of Pulmel (his remedy for
                    consumption), an account of his books sold at auction in 1834, entries of
                    expenses for rent, clothing, furniture, and milk are all to be found. Notations
                    on his suit against Zaccheus Collins and the expenses incurred in the course of
                    it are also itemized.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>