<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Deborah Norris Logan papers <date type="inclusive">1808-1839</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Deborah Norris Logan papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC375</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.125 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1808-1839</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Deborah Norris Logan (1761-1839) was an eminent Philadelphian. She was the
                    daughter of Charles and Mary Parker Norris and the granddaughter of Isaac
                    Norris. In 1781, she married Dr. George Logan, a physician, farmer, and
                    statesman. In 1814, Deborah Norris Logan started work copying and annotating the
                    Penn-Logan Correspondence. She also wrote a memoir of her husband's life, which
                    was published by the Historical Society of Pennsylvania well after Logan's
                    death. In addition to these works, and her diaries, she continued to write
                    articles and poetry into her seventies. Deborah Norris Logan was a Quaker
                    throughout her life. Her husband, Dr. George Logan, was a Quaker until disowned
                    in 1791.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a miscellaneous collection of items belonging to Deborah Norris Logan.
                    Materials include a commonplace book/diary, largely concerned with family
                    history and genealogy; loose diary entries from November-December, 1838; a
                    manuscript copy of her obituary for The Friend; a fragment of a biographical
                    sketch of George Logan; and a manuscript copy of Memoir of Dr. George Logan.
                </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 14720.Q, 14721.Q, 107122.O, 107124.O, 14722.Q</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Deborah Norris Logan diaries (0380).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>