<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Elizabeth Graeme Fergusson papers <date type="inclusive">1752-1799</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Elizabeth Graeme Fergusson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1574</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1752-1799</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Six volumes of poems, translations, interpretations, letters, etc. of Elizabeth
                    Graeme Fergusson of Philadelphia. "Fergusson (1737-1801) was an important
                    literary figure whose work was largely obscured by the fact that she was a woman
                    writing in the 18th century" (Phila. Inquirer, 3/26/85). "Telemachus," a
                    poetic translation of Fenelon's "Telemaque," completed in 1769, with
                    "translator's notes" added in subsequent years, by Elizabeth Graeme Fergusson,
                    Philadelphia litterateur. Poetic interpretation of the Book of Psalms, with
                    Graeme's notations and introductory letter addressed to the Rev. Richard Peters.
                    Poetry, prose, letters, memoranda, covering a wide range of political, social,
                    moral, religious, and economic subjects composed or extracted by Ferguson.
                    Although the material dates from 1768, apparently it was recorded from 1790 to
                    1795, and it is often signed "Laura." The work, which Mrs. Fergusson referred
                    to as her "Poemata Juvenilia," was written between 1752 and 1772. Nearly all
                    her poems are signed "Laura," her most common pseudonym. In the volume she
                    also copied poems to her from others, including Benjamin Franklin's son William,
                    to whom she was engaged from 1752 until 1762 when he married Miss Elizabeth
                    Downes in London. She traveled to Europe to restore her spirits, and dazzled the
                    social and intellectual circles there. Upon her return in 1766 she established
                    at Graeme Park a celebrated literary salon. Her friendships with Philadelphia's
                    best and brightest in the world of letters--Francis Hopkinson, Provost William
                    Smith (first President of the University of Pennsylvania), Jacob Duche, and
                    others--are chronicled in "Poemata Juvenilia." The volume ends shortly before
                    her ill-fated marriage to Henry Hugh Fergusson in 1772. Most volumes are indexed
                    by Fergusson.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Purchased; By exchange with the Osborn Collection at Yale; Gift of
                    Mrs. Howard Aley</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1962; 1978; 1985</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>