<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Henry Drinker Biddle scrapbook <date type="inclusive">1772-1897</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Henry Drinker Biddle scrapbook</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1220</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1772-1897</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henry Drinker Biddle (1831-1898) was the son of Sally Drinker and James Canby
                    Biddle. His great-grandmother was Elizabeth Drinker (1734-1807). In 1889, Henry
                    Drinker Biddle published Extracts From the Journal of Elizabeth Drinker, from
                    1759 to 1807. Biddle also compiled a genealogy of his family titled The Drinker
                    Family in America (1893).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a scrapbook of miscellaneous family papers assembled by Henry Drinker
                    Biddle. Materials include: correspondence to the publishing firm of Key and
                    Biddle; portraits of family members; newspaper clippings; transcriptions of
                    marriage certificates, indentures, and wills; letters, some copied, from various
                    family members, including some written by Biddle as a child; a chart of the
                    Upper Lakes (Michigan) drawn by Biddle; a blueprint of a chain block patented by
                    S.M. Vauclain; and several Confederate bond certificates.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 9980.F</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Drinker family papers and other family papers collections with
                    Biddle and Drinker family connections.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>