<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James Barton Longacre papers <date type="inclusive">1806-1869</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1830-1869</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James Barton Longacre papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1632</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1806-1869</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1830-1869</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Papers of James Barton Longacre, line and stipple engraver of Philadelphia, and
                    chief engraver of the U.S. Mint, 1844-1869. Correspondence concerning his work
                    on "The National Portrait Gallery of Distinguished Americans," discussing
                    portraits, engravings, and biographical sketches, and financial matters; and
                    letters revealing his responsibilities as Chief Engraver. Topics include coin
                    design, mottos and inscriptions, composition, and production. Special
                    correspondence files consider the use of aluminum in U.S. specie, execution of
                    Chilean coinage, Longacre's salary and the Ingraham medal, and use of a
                    "reducing machine" in making currency. A significant amount of correspondence
                    with Richard Sears McCulloh, James Ross Snowden, and others reflects conflicts
                    between the Chief Engraver and the Chief Coiner, Franklin Peale, especially in
                    connection with Peale's manufacturing of medals. Letter book, 1830-37, of
                    Longacre's business matters, and his fragmented memorandum books and diaries,
                    1821-1867. Some family letters. Miscellaneous school books, 1806-07, account
                    books, 1829-30, subscription book, 1830 for his engraved portrait of Bushrod
                    Washington, notes on the Longacre family, and some printed material, concerning
                    "The National Portrait Gallery," the Mint, and estate papers. Separated from
                    the collection are a number of engravings, sketches, watercolors, etc. to the
                    prints department.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Purchased</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1948</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>