<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Jeremiah Cullen collection <date type="inclusive">1900-1930</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Jeremiah Cullen collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1549</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1900-1930</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Jeremiah Cullen was a Philadelphia bookseller from 1877 until he died, sometime
                    in the 1930s. He opened his own store, called Cullen's Bookstore, in 1906, and
                    sold both rare and new books. It was located at 9th and Walnut.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes advertisements and brochures for Cullen's Bookstore and
                    other booksellers, poetry by Joseph Jackson, a small amount of correspondence,
                    and business cards and other ephemera. Two of the letters are from Harry
                    Houdini. There is also one volume of photographs, newspaper clippings, and
                    advertisements, with captions written by Cullen, which chronicles his business
                    and some of his customers. The volume used for the scrapbook is a history book.
                    There are a few notes written by his son John.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of William H. Allen, Inc.</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>