<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Dickinson papers <date type="inclusive">1676-1885</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1759-1807</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Dickinson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1553</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>9 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1676-1885</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1759-1807</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Correspondence, documents, business records, essays, notes, and newspaper
                    clippings of John Dickinson, lawyer and statesman. The collection consists
                    almost entirely of papers collected by Dickinson in relation to his political
                    and business activities, but there are some miscellaneous papers of Sally Norris
                    Dickinson, his daughter. Although the correspondence deals predominantly with
                    Dickinson's activities in the public, governmental sphere, a significant portion
                    concerns his private affairs, especially land and business activities.
                    Correspondents include various statesmen and Revolutionary leaders among whom
                    are Samuel Chase, Dickinson's brother Philemon Dickinson, litterateur Elizabeth
                    Graeme Ferguson, poet and political satirist Hannah Griffitts, army surgeon John
                    Jones, Arthur Lee, Charles Lee, Richard Henry Lee, William Lee, the first
                    president of Dickinson College Charles Nisbet, George Read, Caesar Rodney,
                    Charles Thomson, army surgeon James Tilton. There are one or two letters each
                    from Samuel Adams, Robert Morris, Benjamin Rush, and George Washington.
                    Interesting letters appear from several of his overseers and tenants including
                    Daniel Walker, a free black tenant farmer. Documents from the Revolutionary War
                    period, 1776-1883 (100 items) relate chiefly to Dickinson's service as an
                    officer in the Pennsylvania militia. They include furlough recommendations,
                    hospital reports, notes on military movements, militia returns, and information
                    on soldiers' provisions, including ammunition. Government documents (150 items)
                    extend from the early Revolutionary period and Dickinson's involvement in the
                    Stamp Act Congress to his participation in the 1787 Constitutional Convention.
                    Included are Dickinson's notes on the first Continental Congress, papers
                    concerning early national land policies, foreign policy, taxation proposals, and
                    the New Jersey and Virginia Plans. There are drafts of Dickinson's and Patrick
                    Henry's petitions to the King, 1774, a John Jay draft of the Olive Branch
                    Petition, drafts of Dickinson speeches at the Constitutional Convention, and
                    copies of the Fabius letters which Dickinson wrote in support of the
                    Constitution. Pennsylvania government documents, 1764-1784, (150 items) include
                    financial accounts, drafts of Dickinson speeches prepared while he was president
                    of the Supreme Executive Council of Pennsylvania, bills, materials on the Aaron
                    Doane case, court-martial records, materials on the Wyoming controversy and
                    miscellaneous Dickinson notes on government affairs. Delaware government
                    documents, 1772-1789, (75 items) include papers on the Delaware River land
                    dispute, 1772; suggestions for reform of the court system, submitted by Justice
                    William Killen, 1781; militia returns, 1782; budget figures, and various bill
                    drafts and notes. The collection includes Dickinson's land and business records,
                    1733-1854 (500 items). Leases, agreements, memoranda, bills, receipts, etc.,
                    center around the management of his real estate holdings, primarily in Delaware;
                    house construction, relations with tenants, property sales, farming techniques,
                    production figures. There is material relating to Dickinson's law practice which
                    include information on cases argued before the High Court of Errors in
                    Pennsylvania. Drafts of Dickinson's will, with codicils, are also present.
                    Miscellaneous notes and essays include a commonplace book, n.d., essays
                    ("Reflections on the Flag of Truce in America," "Opinion on the 40 Pr Poll
                    Act in Maryland"), a comment on Pennsylvania land law, and a speech written on
                    the founding of Dickinson College. Chronological arrangement, with series as
                    described. Formerly calendared by John H. Powell, but since rearranged.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Robert Restalrig Logan.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1943-1949</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>