<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Capnerhurst Hall journal <date type="inclusive">1777-1779</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Capnerhurst Hall journal</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1740</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.083 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1777-1779</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Capnerhurst Hall was the nephew of John Hall. Hall adopted the boy and paid
                    for his education in England, in return for which he took Hall's name and
                    dropped his original surname. He worked for Boulton and Fothergill near
                    Birmingham as a sort of trouble shooter for the steam engines the firm licensed,
                    installed, and repaired. He emigrated to the United States in 1783 (before his
                    uncle) and set up a foundry at Mount Hope, New Jersey.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a journal of John Capnerhurst Hall kept between 1777 and 1779. The volume
                    includes notes on his mechanical work, drawings of equipment, and chemical
                    tables and mathematical formulae, as well as descriptions of conversations,
                    excursions, and other events. The journal includes an index to entries.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Library Company of
                    Philadelphia: John Hall diaries. </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>