<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Hall diaries <date type="inclusive">1785-1812</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Hall diaries</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC855</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1785-1812</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Hall (1736-1820) was an English mechanic and inventor. He was a close
                    associate of the pioneers of steam power, Boulton and Watt. He came to America
                    in 1785. He attended the Assembly Debates, and was present when Benjamin
                    Franklin was elected president of Pennsylvania. He helped Thomas Paine build a
                    model for a bridge over the Schuylkill River (a project that never came to
                    completion). Hall later settled in Flemington, New Jersey, where he farmed and
                    kept a store and tavern. He was a founder of the Flemington Library Company. He
                    made frequent trips to New York City, Baltimore, and Alexandria, as well as a
                    voyage to England in 1791.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of 62 journals kept by John Hall between 1785 and 1812. The
                    journals begin with a description of Hall's voyage across the Atlantic, and
                    continue on to describe in detail his daily activities, travels, and
                    business.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 70115.D, 70116.D</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Library Company of
                    Philadelphia: John Capnerhurst Hall journal.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>