<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Lea family papers <date type="inclusive">1803-1968</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1803-1900</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Lea family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1248</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1803-1968</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1803-1900</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Isaac Lea (1792-1886) was an American conchologist, geologist, and business man,
                    born at Wilmington, Delaware. In 1821, Isaac Lea married Frances Anne Carey
                    (1799-1873), the daughter of Mathew Carey. He entered his father-in-law's
                    publishing firm, and soon became Carey's partner. Henry Charles Lea (1825-1909),
                    Isaac Lea's son, worked for the firm until 1880, when he retired to focus on his
                    scholarly studies. He published numerous articles on various scientific matters
                    from medicine to marine biology, but is best known for his work on medieval
                    history. Isaac Lea's other son, Mathew Carey Lea (1823-1897), undertook a career
                    in law, but abandoned it after several years to pursue a second career in
                    chemistry. His particular interest was in photographic chemistry, and he was
                    influential in laying the foundations for the science of photography.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of volumes and documents related to the Lea family.
                    Materials include: a Lea family commonplace book consisting of prose and verse,
                    some in Latin, with copies of notices and extracts from "Journal of the House
                    of Commons" (1641); Eliza Lea album of verse (some in French) with watercolors,
                    and several papercuts. Includes inscriptions by Robert Owen and the Marquis de
                    Lafayette, dated 1826-1827; Anna C. Jaudon commonplace book, 1845-1848; several
                    scrapbooks on the Lea family, containing correspondence (Henry Charles Lea,
                    Isaac Lea, Mathew Carey, Frances Ann [Fanny] Lea, Maria Carey, Lizzie Lea, J.
                    Henry Lea, and Anna C. Jaudon), typed copy of a travel journal of Thomas Gibson
                    Lea, family trees, obituaries, biographical sketches, travel writings, and
                    pamphlets; Isaac Lea membership certificates and diplomas in various scientific
                    and historical societies and institutions. 1815-1877; Isaac Lea European travel
                    diaries, 1852-53; documents related to the printing business of Mathew Carey,
                    including insurance survey, business correspondence, and book lists; and stamps,
                    medals, and pamphlets.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: no number, 13897.Q, unaccessioned, 104851.D</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Eliza Lea commonplace book (Am .8223).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>