<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Library Company of Philadelphia accession books <date type="inclusive">1891-1965</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Library Company of Philadelphia accession books</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1776</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1891-1965</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Library Company of Philadelphia is an independent research library
                    concentrating on American society and culture from the 17th through 19th
                    centuries. It was founded in 1731 by Benjamin Franklin as a subscription library
                    supported by its shareholders, as it is to this day. Free and open to the
                    public, the Library Company houses an extensive non-circulating collection of
                    rare books, manuscripts, broadsides, ephemera, and works of art. The Loganian
                    Library, created in 1754 as a trust for the public, was transferred to the
                    Library Company in 1792. The nucleus of the Loganian Library was the personal
                    library of James Logan, which at the time of his death in 1751 was one of the
                    three largest private libraries in the colonies, and the strongest in scientific
                    books. The Ridgway branch opened in 1878, and was located at Broad and Christian
                    streets. It was named after Phoebe Ann Ridgway Rush, wife of James Rush. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of 32 accession books for the Ridgway branch of the
                    Library Company and 5 accession books for the Loganian Library. The Ridgway
                    accession books are duplicates of the original set of accession books maintained
                    at the Library. Entries in the accession books include accession number, title,
                    author, classification, city and date of publication, and occasional remarks.
                    Accessions are arranged by the size of volume and then by accession number.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>