<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Library Company of Philadelphia miscellaneous records <date type="inclusive">1901-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Library Company of Philadelphia miscellaneous
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1778</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1901-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Library Company of Philadelphia is an independent research library
                    concentrating on American society and culture from the 17th through 19th
                    centuries. It was founded in 1731 by Benjamin Franklin as a subscription library
                    supported by its shareholders, as it is to this day. Free and open to the
                    public, the Library Company houses an extensive non-circulating collection of
                    rare books, manuscripts, broadsides, ephemera, and works of art. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of miscellaneous materials related to the Library Company of
                    Philadelphia. Materials include: awards and citations, including House of
                    Representatives Citation from 1981, proclamation of James Logan Day (Oct 20th,
                    1974), and a membership certificate from the Huguenot Society of London (1901);
                    broadside reproductions; scrapbooks compiled by Herbert Harley on: Button
                    Gwinnett, Henry Hudson, and Governor Johann Printz; several first day issues of
                    stamps; 1988 Library Company Christmas party photos; a Library Company cookbook;
                    non-Library Company posters and oversize reproductions, including maps of
                    Philadelphia and a calligraphic list of contributors to the Edwin Wolf Fund;
                    humorous broadside "A Quart of Millennium"; Ben Wolf poem, 1988; gifts
                    presented to John Van Horne on his 1986 visit to Italy; magazines and books
                    containing references to Library Company materials, including Antiques Magazine,
                    American Heritage, and National Geographic; books edited by Library Company
                    staff; and Library Company seals. The collection also includes photographs, a
                    silhouette, and a cartoon of Edwin Wolf. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>