<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Library Company of Philadelphia Annual Reports, Bulletins, and
                        Occasional Miscellanies <date type="inclusive">1841-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Library Company of Philadelphia Annual Reports, Bulletins,
                    and Occasional Miscellanies</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1781</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1841-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Library Company of Philadelphia is an independent research library
                    concentrating on American society and culture from the 17th through 19th
                    centuries. It was founded in 1731 by Benjamin Franklin as a subscription library
                    supported by its shareholders, as it is to this day. Free and open to the
                    public, the Library Company houses an extensive non-circulating collection of
                    rare books, manuscripts, broadsides, ephemera, and works of art. The Library
                    Company's Annual Report includes president's, director's, and treasurer's
                    reports, and descriptions of notable acquisitions, gifts, and donations. The
                    Bulletin consists of a list of books recently acquired by the Library Company,
                    arranged by topic. The Bulletin also contains the rules of the Library Company.
                    The Occasional Miscellany is a newsletter that provides information about
                    endowments and funding, acquisition highlights, work being done in conservation
                    lab, and other topics. Librarian's Reports are typed reports of library usage
                    and acquisitions.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the Library Company's Annual Reports, Bulletins and
                    Occasional Miscellanies. The Annual Reports date from 1879, 1903-1934 (some
                    years missing), 1935-1942, 1947-1949, and 1951-2005. Additionally there are two
                    reels of microfilm of annual reports from 1874 to 1987 (some issues missing).
                    Bulletins date from 1841-1938, 1940-1841, 1945, 1958, 1966-1968. There are
                    copies of the Occasional Miscellany from 1977-2005. The collection also includes
                    Librarian's reports, 1953-1983. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>