<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Library Company of Philadelphia conservation records <date type="inclusive">1966-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Library Company of Philadelphia conservation
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1787</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1966-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Library Company of Philadelphia is an independent research library
                    concentrating on American society and culture from the 17th through 19th
                    centuries. It was founded in 1731 by Benjamin Franklin as a subscription library
                    supported by its shareholders, as it is to this day. Free and open to the
                    public, the Library Company houses an extensive non-circulating collection of
                    rare books, manuscripts, broadsides, ephemera, and works of art. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of documents related to several conservation projects,
                    including the 1992-1993 restoration of the Lazzarini statue of Benjamin Franklin
                    and assessment of paintings owned by the Library Company performed between 1988
                    and 1991. Materials related to the restoration of the Franklin statue include an
                    examination report and treatment recommendations, slides, photographs, and
                    negatives of the project, and samples of marble from the statue. The collection
                    also includes a small batch of materials related to the sale of paintings,
                    furniture, and objects.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>