<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Library Company of Philadelphia histories <date type="inclusive">1835-1995</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Library Company of Philadelphia histories</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1784</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1835-1995</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Library Company of Philadelphia is an independent research library
                    concentrating on American society and culture from the 17th through 19th
                    centuries. It was founded in 1731 by Benjamin Franklin as a subscription library
                    supported by its shareholders, as it is to this day. Free and open to the
                    public, the Library Company houses an extensive non-circulating collection of
                    rare books, manuscripts, broadsides, ephemera, and works of art. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials documenting the history of the Library Company
                    of Philadelphia. Items include: a typescript copy of Dorothy F. Grimm's doctoral
                    dissertation "A History of the Library Company of Philadelphia, 1731-1835"
                    (University of Pennsylvania, 1955); several printed histories (1835-1995) by
                    various authors, including George M. Abbot, Austin K. Gray, and Edwin Wolf and a
                    1867 manuscript history by John Meredith Read; scrapbook (1936-1971) of
                    newspaper clippings, photographs, magazine articles, correspondence, exhibition
                    signs and announcements; scrapbook (1920s) containing correspondence,
                    photographs of Library Company buildings, paintings and furniture; two
                    scrapbooks of newspaper clippings (1850s-1930 and 1933-1939), which include
                    certificates from other institutions, event announcements, and maps.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>