<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Mathew Carey record of books loaned <date type="inclusive">1825-1838</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Mathew Carey record of books loaned</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC359</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1825-1838</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Mathew Carey (1760-1839) was an important Philadelphia publisher and bookseller.
                    He was born in Dublin, Ireland, and settled in Philadelphia in 1784. He founded
                    the Pennsylvania Herald in 1785, and the Columbian Magazine in 1786. In the
                    1790s Carey went on to develop a successful publishing house, which printed the
                    works of Thomas Jefferson, Parson Weems, Sir Walter Scott, and James Fenimore
                    Cooper, as well as the first quarto Bible of American manufacture, in both the
                    Douay version and the Authorized version.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a book Carey kept to track the books and pamphlets he lent out. Each
                    entry lists the date, the title of the book or pamphlet, and the name of the
                    borrower. Names appear to have been crossed out as books were returned. It
                    covers the period 1825 to 1838. Borrowers include John Naegle, Joseph
                    Abercrombie, James Robertson, Girard Ralston, H.D. Gilpin, Clement Biddle,
                    William Darlington, and William B. Reed.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 13612.Q</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Library Company of
                    Philadelphia: Mathew Carey papers and other Carey collections.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>