<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Mathew Carey clippings <date type="inclusive">1790-1833</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Mathew Carey clippings</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1198</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>44.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1790-1833</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Mathew Carey (1760-1839) was an important Philadelphia publisher and bookseller.
                    He was born in Dublin, Ireland, and settled in Philadelphia in 1784. He founded
                    the Pennsylvania Herald in 1785, and the Columbian Magazine in 1786. In the
                    1790s Carey went on to develop a successful publishing house, which printed the
                    works of Thomas Jefferson, Parson Weems, Sir Walter Scott, and James Fenimore
                    Cooper, as well as the first quarto Bible of American manufacture, in both the
                    Douay version and the Authorized version.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of 169 volumes of newspaper clippings compiled by Mathew
                    Carey. The clippings are drawn from various sources, but nearly all are
                    unattributed, and many are undated. Most volumes are miscellanies, but some are
                    devoted to a single subject. Subjects include: law, internal improvements,
                    politics, manufactures, sedition, medicine, education, and poetry. Many of the
                    volumes are selectively indexed. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 9841.O, 9842.O, 9843.O, 9844.O, 9845.O, 9850.O</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Library Company of
                    Philadelphia: various Mathew Carey papers and collections.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>