<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>McAllister family papers <date type="inclusive">1683-1881</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">McAllister family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1638</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>45 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1683-1881</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection was begun by John McAllister Jr., 1786-1877, and continued by son
                    John A. McAllister, b. 1822. The McAllisters were well known Philadelphia
                    opticians and manufacturers of scientific instruments. The collection consists
                    of approximately 15,000 items of a miscellaneous nature (1683-1881). There are
                    many letters from John F. Watson, Benson J. Lossing, George Bancroft, Henry B.
                    Dawson, William J. Buck, Francis Lieber, Samuel Austin Allibone, George Henry
                    Preble, and Brantz Mayer. There is a considerable amount of business materials
                    from the firms of Watson &amp; Paul, Binney and Ronaldson, Charles Bird &amp;
                    Co., and others. In addition, there are about 500 items relating to the Civil
                    War which have been segregated from the rest of the collection. One third of
                    this Civil War material consists of letters concerning optical instruments,
                    photographs, war relics, and autographs. Other records concern surgeon James
                    McClelland, orders of the day, general orders, discharges, etc. There are also
                    letters from General Sherman, Pellow Rosecrans, and others, concerning
                    appointments, dispositions of forces, and location of the guards and sharp
                    shooters. There is also one volume in the collection, which is a "Principles of
                    Perspective" possibly from 1839 with illustrations. The oversized box contains
                    pages entitled "Extracts from the Customs House books of Exports of Merchandise
                    from Philadelphia and other areas of Pennsylvania," 1759-1763.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>