<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Pierre Eugène Du Simitière collection <date type="inclusive">1492-1783</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Pierre Eugène Du Simitière collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1562</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1492-1783</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is the manuscript section of that portion of Du Simitiere's collection
                    purchased at auction March 10, 1785. The books and pamphlets bought at the same
                    auction have been dispersed through the Library Company's collections. These
                    manuscripts were gathered or copied by Du Simitiere during his travels in the
                    West Indies, Boston, New York, and during the years he lived in Philadelphia,
                    where he was a member of and one of the curators of the APS. After purchase by
                    the LCP, the manuscripts were bound together and they remain in that order
                    today. Those volumes were described by the Historical Records Survey of the WPA
                    in "Descriptive Catalogue of the Du Simitiere Papers in the Library Company of
                    Philadelphia" (1940), from which the following descriptions have been
                    abstracted. Papers relating to Natural History written between 1763-1773 in Du
                    Simitiere's hand: catalogues, descriptions, and bibliographical references to
                    plants, animals, and some archaeological specimens in North and South America,
                    but particularly Santo Domingo. [In French.] Papers relating to New York consist
                    of copies made by Du Simitiere of documents concerning Leisler's Rebellion and
                    the subsequent controversy over Lord Bellomont's administration, 1689-1712.
                    There are also some copies of early New Netherland records, and a list of coach
                    owners in New York, 1770. [In Dutch and English.] Leisler papers published in
                    Collections of The New York Historical Society. Papers relating to Pennsylvania,
                    the Carolinas, etc. contains 38 manuscripts, probably written 1753-1778,
                    concerning Indian life and history, and travel, including a copy of Lewis Evans'
                    description of Pennsylvania, 1753 and George Croghan's Ohio journal, 1749 [In
                    2001 LCP alerted survey staff that this journal, along with two other documents
                    -- Statement of John Patten, and "A Brief Account of Pennsylvania, in a letter
                    to Richard Peters, Esqr…" is missing]. Indian Treaties, 1721-1756: originals
                    and contemporary copies in several hands of minutes of councils held in
                    Philadelphia, New York, and elsewhere between the English and the Six Nations,
                    together with relevant correspondence from Conrad Weiser, William Shirley, James
                    DeLancey, Robert Hunter Morris and others. Original letters, 1660-1781. A
                    miscellaneous volume which includes some material not collected by DuSimitiere:
                    2 letters from Pope Alexander VIII to King James II, 1689, 6 letters of Tobias
                    Smolett, 1761-1770, and others once part of the Henry Cox gift. The remainder of
                    the volume appears to have been gathered by Du Simitiere: letters of colonial
                    committees of correspondence, and documents relating to the revolt of the
                    Pennsylvania line, 1781. Papers relating to the West Indies. Notes and sketches
                    done by Du Simitiere including a description, in French, of Java and of Batavia,
                    with map; descriptions of Jamaica, St. Eustatius, Cuba, Santo Domingo;
                    compilations of Creole dialects; and three watercolors of Kingston, c. 1760.
                    Original journals and extracts. Miscellaneous compendium of travel journals:
                    Susquehanna (1769) and Ottowa (1775); notes and accounts of the Sullivan
                    expedition, 1779; extracts from travel accounts of Captain Cook in the Pacific
                    and Thurberg's account of Japan; and Du Simitiere's copies of verses by John
                    Moylem. Includes several wash drawings of Indian dwellings and writings. Papers
                    relating to New England, New York, etc. Materials gathered and copied by Du
                    Simitiere for a history of New York, with some notes on Pennsylvania, New Jersey
                    and New England. Papers relating to Pennsylvania and New England. Additional
                    materials gathered or copied Du Simitiere relating to Pennsylvania and other
                    parts of British North America. Of special interest are the several
                    bibliographies of the books available to Du Simitiere. Scraps (3 boxes) of
                    highly miscellaneous materials, about one-third of which were copied by Du
                    Simitiere from other sources. Drawings, journals, poems, and particularly,
                    vocabularies and notes on North American Indians.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Purchased by Library Company of Philadelphia.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1785</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>