<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Powel family papers <date type="inclusive">1685-1884</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1726-1843</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Powel family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1676</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1685-1884</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1726-1843</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The volumes of accounts, letters, memoranda, and other records concern the
                    personal professional business interests of four Powel family members of
                    Philadelphia. The first represented here is Samuel Powel, colonial merchant, who
                    apparently conducted his business in London from 1726 to 1727 and then continued
                    in Philadelphia, trading with England and the West Indies, until his death. His
                    merchant's account books, 1726-1747, include: day books (7 v.), journals (5 v.),
                    ledgers (4 v., broken series), bills of lading (2 v.), and ship invoice book.
                    His son Samuel Powel was elected mayor of Philadelphia in 1775, his tenure ended
                    by the Revolution, and he was reelected in 1789. His personal financial accounts
                    consist of ledger, 1760-1793; receipt books, 1771-1792 (9 v., broken series);
                    miscellaneous account and memorandum book, 1786-1796. Elizabeth Willing Powel,
                    Mayor Powel's wife, inherited his substantial estate including "Powelton" and
                    other Philadelphia real estate. Her account books, 1793-1821 (6 v.), relate
                    principally to finances concerning her property; there are also check stubs,
                    1793-1803. Elizabeth and Samuel Powel had no heirs, and therefore Mrs. Powel
                    adopted her nephew John Powel Hare who subsequently changed his name to John
                    Hare Powel. Powel joined the counting house of Willing and Francis, 1803-1807,
                    acting as supercargo on a voyage to Calcutta in 1806. He was secretary to the
                    U.S. legation in London, 1809-1811, a colonel in the War of 1812, and
                    Pennsylvania state senator, 1827-1830. He acted as agent in managing the
                    property of the Elizabeth Powel estate, William Bingham estate, and Alexander
                    Baring's Hope and Company lands in northern Pennsylvania. For most of his life,
                    Powel's major occupation was as an agriculturist with particular interest in the
                    improvement of livestock. The John Hare Powel papers include: letter book, 1806,
                    on business conducted while in Calcutta; letter books, 1824-1853 (bulk,
                    1824-1843) (5 v.), relating primarily to husbandry, but also concerning his land
                    management activities on behalf of Baring and others, his interest in
                    Pennsylvania Railroad construction, and the construction of his house at 13th
                    and Locust; accounts and memoranda on Hope and Co. lands, 1824-1842 (2 v.);
                    personal receipt book, 1825-1830; cattle record book, 1825-1829, including
                    copies of letters from Jonathan Whitaker and George Coates; ledger of Elizabeth
                    Powel estate rents, 1830-1836 (bulk 1830-1833); William Bingham shipping account
                    book from Martinique, 176-1778; William Bingham estate account books, 1813-1830
                    (7 v.) with memoranda and letters concerning Philadelphia property; receipt
                    book, 1868-1884, of payments made from the John Hare Powel estate to Julia
                    deVeaux Foulke and Ida Powel Morrell (later Johnson). There are some additional
                    loose miscellaneous papers.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Mr. And Mrs. Harford Powel.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1937</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>