<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Read family papers <date type="inclusive">1736-1896</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1792-1896</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Read family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1684</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>86 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1736-1896</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1792-1896</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Papers of a family prominent in politics covering three generations. The papers,
                    1792-1854, of John Read, a lawyer of Philadelphia, President of the Philadelphia
                    Bank, 1819-1841, (about 5,000 items, unarranged) include incoming
                    correspondence, legal papers, and miscellaneous items. There are a large number
                    of papers pertaining to his legal practice; some records of the Philadelphia
                    Bank, especially suits in which the bank was involved; family correspondence,
                    including letters, 1804-1807, from his brother, William Read, a merchant of
                    Philadelphia, regarding the China trade; a letter book, 1850-1854 (1 volume);
                    bills and receipts, 1792-1845; a receipt book, 1800-1822; account books,
                    1835-1854 (3 volumes); financial and legal memoranda (9 volumes); and a
                    scrapbook. The papers, 1815-1874, of John Meredith Read [I], the son of John
                    Read (about 4,000 items, arranged chronologically) include incoming
                    correspondence, legal, and miscellaneous papers relating especially to
                    Pennsylvania and national politics. Read was a prominent figure in the
                    Democratic Party and, after 1854, the Republican Party. The papers pertain to
                    his term as Attorney General for eastern Pennsylvania, 1837-1841, and Attorney
                    General for Pennsylvania, 1846; his unsuccessful nomination to the U. S. Supreme
                    Court, 1845-1846; his candidacy for the presidency, 1860; and his tenure on the
                    Pennsylvania Supreme Court, 1858-1873. Political correspondents include James
                    Buchanan, Henry D. Gilpin, Henry A. P. Muhlenberg, Andrew G. Curtin, and Senator
                    Henry Wilson (MA). His papers also contain more than 200 detailed Civil War
                    letters, 1862-1864, by Charles H. T. Collis, an Union officer, written from the
                    principal theaters of war; family correspondence; Read and related family
                    letters (2 volumes); letter books, 1846-1852, 1855, 1857-1858 (2 volumes);
                    account books, 1837-1838, 1840-1841, 1855 (3 volumes); and miscellaneous
                    financial records. The papers, 1859-1896, of John Meredith Read [II], the son of
                    John Meredith Read [I], diplomat, and social lion in European capitals, make up
                    the largest part of the collection. They consist of 77 large folio-size albums
                    of correspondence and miscellaneous papers, about 4,500 unbound items,
                    letterpress books, scrapbooks, and miscellaneous volumes. Incoming and outgoing
                    correspondence relates to legal, political, diplomatic, family, and personal
                    affairs. Read's activities represented in the collection include: the
                    organization of the Wide Awake Clubs and other Republican political efforts in
                    New York state in 1860; letterpress files, Jan.-Aug. 1861 (2 volumes) of
                    official correspondence as adjutant general in New York; letterpress file,
                    1868-1873 (12 volumes), as consul general at Paris, including his service as
                    Prussian Consul in France during the Franco-Prussian War; letterpress file, 1874
                    (2 volumes), as U. S. minister to Greece, a position he held from 1873 to 1878;
                    and a letterpress file, 1879-1896, while living as an expatriate in Paris. There
                    are also about 100 letters, 1877-1896, from King George I of Greece; notebooks,
                    1879-1896 (15 volumes) of research materials collected for his "Historic
                    Studies of Vaud. . ." (1897); and a small autograph collection which includes
                    64 letters, 1736-1776, by Voltaire, 43 of which are to Charles Mancel de
                    Vegobre. Miscellaneous items include numerous memorandum books; and scrapbooks
                    (33 volumes) on Read's wide ranging social and research interests. The
                    scrapbooks are largely filled with memorabilia, but they include a volume of
                    correspondence regarding the 5,726 Robert Morris letters, 1781-1784, that Read
                    at one time owned; and a volume of correspondence with Samuel Sartain, engraver,
                    and the Broadbent Brothers, photographers, of Philadelphia. Read's efforts to
                    trace the American and British branches of the Read and related families are
                    documented by 36 volumes of correspondence and records, two of which are devoted
                    to Thomas, a navy officer during the American Revolution. Related families
                    represented include Cadwalader, Howell, Marshall, Meredith, Pumpelly, Ross, and
                    Waterman. In addition, there are some Cadwalader and Meredith papers, including
                    correspondence, a few Samuel Meredith letters and record books (5 volumes)
                    1777-1801, and Thomas Meredith account books, 1792-1819 (2 volumes).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Bequest of Marguerite de Carron Read.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1940</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>