<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rittenhouse family papers and William Rittenhouse indenture <date type="inclusive">1690-1988</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1690-1899</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rittenhouse family papers and William Rittenhouse
                    indenture</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1262</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1690-1988</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1690-1899</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Rittenhouse family were paper-makers in Germany and Holland. In 1687 or 1688,
                    William Rittenhouse (1644-1708) (originally called Wilhelm Rittinghausen), his
                    sons Claus (1666-1734) and Garret (1674-1742), and his daughter Elizabeth (b.
                    ca. 1670) emigrated to the United States. By 1689 they were established in the
                    Philadelphia area. In 1690, William Rittenhouse, together with William Bradford,
                    the printer, and two other investors, Robert Turner and Thomas Treese, opened
                    the first American paper mill, on Wissahickon Creek in Roxborough, Pennsylvania.
                    The descendants of William Rittenhouse, including his son Claus, his grandson
                    William 2nd, his great grandson Jacob and another relative, possibly also a
                    great-grandson, Nicholas Rittenhouse, continued to operate the mill until the
                    mid 19th century. William's great-grandson, David Rittenhouse (1732-1796), was a
                    mathematician and astronomer and, during the Revolution, he was in charge of the
                    Safety Committee in Philadelphia, which was responsible for recruitment.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of the Rittenhouse family. Documents related to
                    William Rittenhouse and his sons Claus and Jacob include indentures, receipts,
                    and correspondence. Of note is the 1706 indenture for the property on which the
                    Rittenhouse paper mill was built, a plan for the new mill (undated), and the
                    last will and testament of Claus Rittenhouse. The collection also includes
                    correspondence between Nicholas Rittenhouse and his son Josiah, and invitations
                    and certificates related to various Civil War memorials belonging to Nicholas
                    Martin Rittenhouse.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: unaccessioned</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: American
                    Philosophical Society: Rittenhouse family papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>