<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rush family papers <date type="inclusive">1748-1876</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rush family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1696</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>40 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1748-1876</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Benjamin Rush began his lengthy career as a Philadelphia physician by studying at
                    the College of Philadelphia, then the University of Edinburgh. He returned home
                    in 1769 to teach and practice, and to promote his system of medicine wherein all
                    diseases were the result of spasms of the blood vessels. Rush worked tirelessly
                    during the Yellow Fever epidemics which swept the city in the 1790s, and he
                    devoted much study to finding its causes. Rush was an early proponent of
                    scientific and humane treatment for the insane. His popularity as a teacher
                    caused his reputation to spread, especially in the South and West, although his
                    blood-letting treatment was so controversial that his practice could not support
                    his large family. He therefore sought and received appointment as Treasurer of
                    the U. S. Mint, a position he held from 1797 to his death. Rush's active
                    involvement in politics was brief: he served only long enough on the Continental
                    Congress to sign the Declaration of Independence, and campaigned in favor of the
                    U. S. Constitution in 1787 and the PA state constitution in 1789. Rush was
                    particularly interested in social reform movements, for which he wrote numerous
                    articles and acted as sponsor. He condemned capital punishment and advocated
                    prison reform; he supported a system of schooling to be partially financed by
                    public funds, the education of women, and teaching subjects with practical
                    applications. Rush was a founding trustee of Dickinson College and president of
                    the Pennsylvania Society for Promoting the Abolition of Slavery. He was a
                    proselytizer for temperance. James Rush, following in the footsteps of his
                    father, was educated as a doctor, but practiced and taught only occasionally.
                    Having married Phoebe Anne Ridgway, heiress to a large Philadelphia fortune, he
                    followed primarily literary and scientific pursuits. The only work to receive
                    any public recognition was his first, "The Philosophy of the Human Voice,"
                    published in 1827. By the time of his death, Rush was considered a penurious,
                    reclusive, eccentric grouch.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Rush Papers consist primarily of incoming correspondence and medical papers
                    of Benjamin Rush and his son James Rush. BENJAMIN RUSH SECTION, (1762-1828). The
                    largest portion of the Benjamin Rush section consists of incoming correspondence
                    [2,700 items in 26 volumes, alphabetically arranged] from doctors, patients, and
                    students concerning medicine, giving case histories, and requesting advice on
                    treatment. Rush's response is sometimes noted on the letter. Among the
                    correspondents in this series are: Ashton Alexander, James M. Anderson, Jr.,
                    Edward Fisher, Nathaniel Potter, Benjamin Vaughan, John Vaughan. Some of the
                    letters have been separated into special groups and are of a more personal
                    nature, relating to private affairs and interests of Rush and his
                    correspondents, and reform activities, as well as medicine. The major
                    correspondents here are: Jeremy Belknap, Edward and Charles Dilly, Elizabeth
                    Graeme Ferguson, James E. B. Finley, Thomas Hall, David Hosack, John Coakly
                    Lettsom, Edward Miller, David Ramsay, Jacob Rush, James Rush reporting on his
                    studies in Edinburgh (this is in a different series altogether), Richard Rush,
                    Granville Sharp, and Noah Webster. There are some of the Rush's own letter
                    drafts. Subject groupings are: Dickinson College, consisting of Rush's
                    correspondence with John Montgomery, Charles Nisbet, John Armstrong and others
                    relating to the establishment and administration of the college; Northumberland
                    County land papers containing Rush's letters to William Plunkett; Yellow Fever
                    correspondence with letters from patients and reports from other doctors on the
                    onset, progress, and cure of outbreaks outside of Philadelphia; letters and
                    papers relating to Rush's disputes with Elias Boudinot and others. Many of
                    Benjamin Rush's drafts for his medical lectures are here including courses in
                    the practice of medicine, physiology, pathology, and fevers [8 boxes]. There are
                    also drafts of "Lectures on Natural Philosophy, Chemistry, and Medicine for the
                    Young Ladies Academy." Several of Rush's medical commonplace books are among
                    the papers, with a special series of diaries kept as a record of epidemic
                    diseases, 1779-1813 [5 volumes]. In addition to medical subjects, there are
                    personal memoranda books of letters and reminiscences among which are notes on
                    the Continental Congress and volume 9 of Rush's autobiography. (The other
                    volumes are at the American Philosophical Society). Dr. Rush's professional
                    account books, 1769-1815, consist of daybooks [9 volumes], journals [9 volumes],
                    and ledgers [5 volumes]. There are personal receipt books, 1794-1802, 1807-1828
                    [3 volumes], continued by Julia Rush after Benjamin's death. Miscellaneous
                    papers are comprised of notes on Dr. William Cullen's lectures while Rush was
                    attending the University of Edinburgh, 1766-1768, dissertations by some of
                    Rush's students and other third party essays and notes, mostly concerning
                    medical matters. JAMES RUSH SECTION, 1802-1869 The incoming correspondence [900
                    items in 6 volumes, alphabetically arranged] of James Rush is a miscellany of
                    letters from friends, orators and elocutionists, patients, and beggars. In a
                    separate series are letters from Benjamin and Julia Rush to their son while he
                    attended Princeton. A small selection of James Rush's own letters are found in a
                    volume of first copies of letters, 1835-1843. There are some scattered diaries:
                    1809, while studying in Scotland; 1838-1844; 1845-1847, while traveling in
                    Europe. Rush's commonplace books [20 volumes] contain notes on medicine,
                    literature, doodles, and memos for construction of his Chestnut St. house. There
                    are notes, drafts, and printer's copies for James Rush's published works: "The
                    Philosophy of the Human Voice," 1827; "Hamlet, A Prelude in Five Acts," 1834;
                    "Brief Outline of an Analysis of the Human Intellect," 1865; "Rhymes and
                    Contrast on Wisdom and Folly," 1869; and drafts and notes for an unpublished
                    study "Hints for a New System of Medicine," 1835-1843. Additional material in
                    this section are grocery accounts, 1859-1867; invitations; and visiting cards.
                    RUSH FAMILY MISCELLANEOUS, 1811-1876 [5 volumes]. Cassie Murray Rush diary,
                    1876, with description of visits to the Centennial. [Provenance unknown]. Phoebe
                    Anne Rush music book, presented to her in 1820 by Frank Johnson, a black
                    Philadelphia musician. Richard Rush letter book, 1811, as Attorney General of
                    Pennsylvania. [Provenance unknown]. Richard Rush "Memoranda of a Residence at
                    the Court of London" from November, 1817 to January, 1819, written in 1833,
                    containing recollections of official and personal activities of Rush's first
                    year as U. S. minister to Great Britain. [Purchased, 1963]. William Rush,
                    "Examinations on Materia Medica," 1832, given by him as lecturer on materia
                    medica and therapeutics at the Philadelphia School of Medicine.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Bequest of James Rush (except otherwise noted in abstract)</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1869</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>