<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>S.W. Swayne scrapbooks <date type="inclusive">1875-1892</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">S.W. Swayne scrapbooks</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC772</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1875-1892</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Swaynes were a Quaker family who lived in London Grove and Kennett,
                    Pennsylvania. Evan Thomas Swayne (1824-1929) was the son of Benjamin and Sarah
                    Swayne. He was married to Sarah Wayne Pusey, daughter of Jacob and Hannah
                    (Mendenhall) Pusey of Wilmington, Delaware. The couple had four children:
                    Edward, Laura Pusey, Anna Belle, and Charles Sumner. Evan T. Swayne was a school
                    teacher in Octoraro, Birmingham, and London Grove. The family moved to Kennett
                    in 1865, where Swayne took charge of a girl's boarding school, the Eaton
                    Institute. After the school had been discontinued, the family continued to live
                    in Kennett, and he was Clerk of Western Quarterly Meeting, Assistant Clerk of
                    Philadelphia Yearly Meeting, and President of the Board of Managers of Martin
                    Academy.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of scrapbooks of newspaper clippings kept by S. W. Swayne
                    [possibly Sarah W. Swayne]. Many of the clippings are obituaries of prominent
                    Americans, poets, and family members. Subjects include John Greenleaf Whittier,
                    Alfred Lord Tennyson, and Bayard Taylor. Other topics include travel and
                    Lincoln's assassination. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 3318.F, 3319.F</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Swarthmore, Friends
                    Historical Library: Norman Walton Swayne Family Papers, 1733-1987</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>