<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sarah Biddle Cabeen papers <date type="inclusive">1827-1919</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sarah Biddle Cabeen papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1526</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1827-1919</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Sarah Biddle Cabeen's family and research papers concern primarily her father,
                    Thomas Biddle, diplomat, of Philadelphia. The typescript of "A Diplomat in the
                    Tropics" by Sara and Francis von A. Cabeen, based on detailed transcriptions of
                    Biddle's largely personal incoming correspondence, covers the period 1855-59
                    while Biddle was in the West Indies, Calcutta, and Singapore. There is, however,
                    little description of Biddle's surroundings. Some of the original manuscripts
                    for this correspondence are also in the papers, along with some official
                    dispatches as Minister Resident of the U.S. to El Salvador, 1871-73, including
                    reports on the new Republic under President Don Santiago Gonzalez and on the
                    1873 earthquake. There are also typescript notes, extracts, reminiscences of
                    Singapore in min-nineteenth century, and a typescript of "The Sister, or a
                    Romance of the United Brethren," 1908 by Sarah Cabeen.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Library Company of
                    Philadelphia: Thomas Biddle collection</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>