<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Stevens-Cogdell-Sanders-Venning collection <date type="inclusive">1734-1955</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Stevens-Cogdell-Sanders-Venning collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1259</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1734-1955</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Stevens was a Charleston, South Carolina, businessman. His daughter, Mary
                    Ann Elizabeth Stevens, married George Cogdell. Their son was Richard Walpole
                    Cogdell (1787-1866). He had several children by his African-American mistress,
                    Sarah Sanders (d. 1850). In the 1850s, Cogdell arranged for the Sanderses to
                    move to Philadelphia. One of Richard and Sarah's daughters was Julia Sanders,
                    who married Edward Y. Venning. Their daughter was Miranda Cogdell Venning
                    (1862-1900), the first African-American graduate of Philadelphia's Girls’ Normal
                    School (1882) and principal of the Joseph E. Hill School.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a miscellaneous collection of papers related to the Cogdell, Venning,
                    Sanders, and Stevens families. Stevens family materials include two letter books
                    (1768-1772) dealing largely with business matters in the West Indies and
                    England, and a commonplace book of Mary Ann Elizabeth Stevens. The Cogdell
                    family materials include estate papers, deeds, indentures, and wills; and
                    correspondence, receipt books, and scrapbooks of R.W. Cogdell. Venning family
                    materials include a family bible, baptismal certificates, and genealogical
                    material; Declaration of Substitute for Edward Y. Venning (1863); and a book of
                    quotes presented to Miranda Venning by William Carl Bolivar. Other families
                    represented in the collection are the Holdens, Chews, Bowies, and Capps. The
                    collection also includes wedding invitations and funeral announcements,
                    scrapbooks, programs, church bulletins, broadsides, and newspaper clippings,
                    including some of W. Carl Bolivar's column "Pencil Pusher Points," which was
                    published in the Philadelphia Tribune.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: unaccessioned</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Library Company of
                    Philadelphia: Photograph Album Collection, Stevens, Cogdell, Sanders, and
                    Venning families, two albums.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>