<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas Leiper account books <date type="inclusive">1771-1947</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas Leiper account books</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1739</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1771-1947</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas Leiper (1745-1825) was born in Scotland and immigrated to Maryland in
                    1763. In 1765, he moved to Philadelphia and began a tobacco storage and export
                    business. In 1780, he purchased several quarries. He amassed a large fortune,
                    and contributed to improvements in Philadelphia, and in Delaware County, where
                    he made his home. He was one of the founders of the first troop of city light
                    horse, and served with them as Lieutenant during the Revolution in the battles
                    of Trenton, Brandywine, and Germantown. He was a staunch democrat and
                    participated in town meetings, and was a member, and eventually, president of
                    the city council. He was also the director of the Banks of Philadelphia and the
                    United States, and constructed the first permanent tramway in America.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of business volumes of Thomas Leiper and his descendants.
                    These volumes record the activities of Thomas Leiper &amp; Sons, Tobacconists,
                    several quarries, a lumber yard and stable, and the Caldwell and Crosby estates.
                    The volumes also record Leiper’s purchase and sale of real estate. Volumes
                    include: ledgers, account books, daybooks, letterbooks, order books, cash books,
                    wage books, and receipt books.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: On deposit from the Friends of the Thomas Leiper House</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>