<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas Richardson American Bank Note Company scrapbook <date type="inclusive">1865-1865</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas Richardson American Bank Note Company
                    scrapbook</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1745</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1865-1865</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American Bank Note Company was co-founded in 1810 by Robert Scot, who had
                    been appointed by Thomas Jefferson to be the first chief engraver for the United
                    States Mint in 1793. Originally known as Murray, Draper, Fairham &amp; Company
                    (after Scot's three partners), it merged in 1858 with six other engraving
                    companies to form the American Bank Note Company. In addition to producing
                    millions of U.S. Government bank notes annually, as well as postage stamps and
                    public and private securities certificates, the company also printed currencies,
                    bonds and stamps for various foreign countries including Argentina, Colombia,
                    Brazil, Ecuador, Italy, Peru and Uruguay. It remains a major international
                    producer today.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a scrapbook collection of etchings, many of which carry the imprint of
                    the American Bank Note Company. The engravings include portraits of prominent
                    Americans, vignettes, and book illustrations. The volume also includes an
                    engraving of the American Bank Note Company's building in New York. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>