<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William Helfand comic valentines collection <date type="inclusive">undated</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1840s-1880s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Library Company of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William Helfand comic valentines collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">LCoSp.ACC1252</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Library Company of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1840s-1880s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William H. Helfand is a consultant to the National Library of Medicine, the
                    Philadelphia Museum of Art and other institutions in areas relating to art and
                    medicine, and a member of the Board of Trustees of the Library Company of
                    Philadelphia. He has degrees in Chemical Engineering (University of
                    Pennsylvania, 1948), Pharmacy (Philadelphia College of Pharmacy and Science,
                    1952). Before his retirement in 1987, he had worked for more than 33 years as an
                    executive with Merck and Co., the multinational pharmaceutical company. He is a
                    noted collector of ephemera, much of it related to medicine and pharmaceuticals.
                    Exhibitions of portions of his collection have been held at the Philadelphia
                    Museum of Art and the National Library of Medicine, among other institutions.
                    Helfand is the author of several books and a number of articles on the history
                    of pharmacy and medicine and on printed ephemera related to these fields.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of 19th century comic valentines, which lampoon men and
                    women for aspects of their work and gender roles. Most of them are American, but
                    there are a few from England as well. Several have an extra sheet of blank paper
                    for writing a message. Several have no verses.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: not accessioned</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: LCP: McAllister
                    collection of comic valentines.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>