<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Southeastern Pennsylvania Synod archives <date type="inclusive">1930-1978</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Lutheran Theological Seminary at Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Southeastern Pennsylvania Synod archives</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TLTSp.ACC2353</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Lutheran Theological Seminary at Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>105 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1930-1978</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Southeastern Pennsylvania Synod of the Evangelical Lutheran Church in America
                    is a collaborative partnership of congregations, institutions, rostered leaders
                    and lay leaders on the territory of Southeastern Pennsylvania. According to its
                    mission statement, the Mission of the Southeastern Pennsylvania Synod "is to
                    oversee the life and ministry of this church in this territory so that: the
                    Gospel of Jesus Christ is proclaimed; the witness of congregations is
                    strengthened; people receive healing, justice and mercy; and the unity that our
                    Lord gives is realized."</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Types of materials: minutes, correspondence, reports, publications, printing cuts
                    (the old metal designs), audio tapes dating in general from the 1930-1978 era,
                    with most in the 1950-1968 period. There are a few published volumes of minutes
                    dating from the 18th and 19th centuries. The majority of the collection is
                    paper. Some portions of the collection will be easier to work through as they
                    are sorted by topics as they appeared in a file (although some of this material
                    is not always in order). Other boxes are much more disorganized and someone will
                    need to figure out how to organize them better, although the contents per box
                    generally relate to the same topic. Types of sub-collections: Bishop's general
                    files 1930-1978 (21 boxes); Committee on Social Ministry 1957-1969 (1 box);
                    Synod Office general files 1953-1974 (4 boxes); Board of Home Missions 1950-1969
                    (3 boxes); SEPA Synod, LCA general files 1955-1978 (17 boxes); SEPA Synod, LCA
                    President's files 1953-1972 (6 boxes); SEPA Synod, LCA minutes, correspondence,
                    financial files 1958-1969 (2 boxes). [Please note--some of the boxes have been
                    separated into two Hollinger record boxes; I just counted the first box whose
                    inventory I photocopied, so these figures are approximate. Most of the "B"
                    boxes are not completely full--more like half full.]</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>