<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Academy of Dermatology records <date type="inclusive">1936-1980</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960s-1970s </date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Academy of Dermatology records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC2279</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.9 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1980</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960s-1970s </unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American Academy of Dermatology, a society of American dermatologists, was
                    founded in 1938. The organization's original name, the American Academy of
                    Dermatology and Syphilology, was changed to its current form in 1961 when the
                    Academy incorporated. The Academy's mission has been and still is educational,
                    although the organization also offers placement services to its members and
                    maintains statistics regarding its membership and the specialty in general. The
                    organization holds an annual meeting. In 1979, the Academy began publication of
                    the medical periodical Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology, which
                    remains in publication.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the American Academy of Dermatology. Materials
                    include: correspondence, minutes, agendas, and reports of the board of
                    directors, the council of the National Program for Dermatology, and from various
                    AAD task forces; correspondence of successive incumbents of the offices of
                    Secretary-Treasurer, Historian, and Director of National Program for
                    Dermatology; biographies and obituaries of members; and histories of the
                    organization. The collection also includes information on the 1975
                    reorganization of the Academy and 40th anniversary issues of the Bulletin of the
                    AAD. AAD officers represented in the collection include John M. Knox, Richard C.
                    Gibb, Robert D. Hamilton, Peyton Weary, and Lawrence C. Parish. The section of
                    Gibb papers includes editorial files from his tenure as editor of the
                    International Journal of Dermatology. Other items in the collection are: framed
                    and unframed photographs of dermatologists; a notebook of photographs of culture
                    studies from the collection of Sabouraud; photographs of patients with
                    dermatologic conditions by Henry W. Stelwagon; illustrations and descriptions
                    from a text on skin conditions; and a small number of reprints, illustrations,
                    and clippings on dermatology and dermatologists (1930s-1970s).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia: American Academy of Dermatology collection of biographical
                    records regarding dermatologists (MSS 3/0023-01) and Lawrence Parish papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>