<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Anderson P. Jones papers <date type="inclusive">1875-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Anderson P. Jones papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC657</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>13.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1875-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Notley Jones (1809-1887), began practice in Hebron, West Virginia, in
                    1840. His son, Anderson Porter Jones (1852-1933), was a physician in Hebron and
                    Pennsboro, West Virginia. A. P. Jones studied medicine at the College of
                    Physicians and Surgeons in Baltimore, Maryland, and at St. Louis Physicians and
                    Surgeons School. He did not graduate from either school, but joined his father,
                    William Notley Jones, in his practice in Hebron in 1897. In the early 1900s, A.
                    P. Jones moved his practice to Pennsboro. A. P. Jones had two children: Oda
                    (1880-1954) and Latimer (1884-1956). Latimer studied at the College of
                    Physicians and Surgeons in Baltimore and worked with his father in the practice
                    in Hebron. Latimer's son, James P. Jones (1810-1974), received his M.D. from the
                    University of Maryland Medical School in 1937, and joined the family practice in
                    1938.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of medical and family papers of three generations of the
                    Jones family (Anderson P. Jones, Latimer P. Jones, and James P. Jones).
                    Materials include: daybooks (1896-1952); physician's logbooks (1938-1968);
                    account and billing ledgers; file cards for patients; bills and receipts for
                    medical supplies and pharmaceuticals; prescription registers; delivery records
                    (1941-1944); pharmaceutical and medical supply catalogs, circulars, price lists,
                    and advertisements; and several printed works on anatomy, first aid, and
                    childbirth. Other materials include lecture notes from medical courses, 1879 and
                    1936; correspondence from James P. Jones to Elizabeth (his wife), 1937-1938;
                    other family letters, including letters from William Notley Jones to A. P Jones;
                    and several photographs of family members, homes, and medical offices. The
                    collection also includes a series of vinyl recordings on cardiac
                    auscultation.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2005-003</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>