<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Arthur Vincent Meigs papers <date type="inclusive">1874-1911</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Arthur Vincent Meigs papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC606</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1874-1911</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Arthur Vincent Meigs (1850-1912) was the son and grandson of the physicians, J.
                    Forsyth Meigs and Charles D. Meigs. After studying at the University of
                    Pennsylvania for two years, he entered its medical school, receiving the M.D.
                    degree in 1871. He spent the next two years in Vienna. Upon his return to
                    Philadelphia, he established a medical practice which he continued until his
                    death. He was attending physician at the Children’s Hospital, Pennsylvania
                    Hospital, and the Sheltering Arms (a home for foundlings) and consulting
                    physician at the Eastern State Penitentiary and the Pennsylvania Institute for
                    the Instruction of the Blind. He was a fellow of the College of Physicians and
                    its president from 1904 to 1907. He was president of the Philadelphia
                    Pathological Society, a trustee of the University of Pennsylvania and of the
                    Wistar Institute, and a member of the American Philosophical Society. His
                    scientific work on the comparative chemistry of the milk of humans and cows was
                    begun in the 1880s, when he published a treatise, Milk Analysis and Infant
                    Feeding, and was continued until about 1908, when he worked in the Hare
                    Laboratory of the University of Pennsylvania.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Arthur Vincent Meigs, including
                    correspondence, case notes and articles, and reprints. Correspondence related to
                    the College of Physicians includes letters about the move of the College to the
                    building on 22nd Street, an ethics charge brought against W.W. Keen, and other
                    topics. Correspondents in this section include W.W. Keen, S. Weir Mitchell,
                    William Osler, and Alfred Stengel. Correspondence related to the University of
                    Pennsylvania relates to hospital policies for patient care and accommodations,
                    specific cases, and various other medical and administrative issues.
                    Correspondents in this section include William Pepper, James Tyson, Richard
                    Wood, and John Herr Musser. There is also correspondence relating to Penn
                    Hospital and Sheltering Arms and Meigs' own medical practice. The collection
                    also includes notes for articles and addresses, case notes, recipes for
                    prescriptions, reprints of articles by Meigs and others, and a daybook listing
                    patients seen by Dr. Meigs in 1880 (incomplete for year). </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2000-005</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>