<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Babies’ Hospital of Philadelphia records <date type="inclusive">1911-1960</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Babies’ Hospital of Philadelphia records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC502</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1911-1960</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Babies' Hospital of Philadelphia was opened at the Country Branch of
                    Children's Hospital in Wynnefield, Pennsylvania on July 11, 1911, and was
                    incorporated in November 1911 with Charles A. Fife serving as its first
                    president. The following year, the hospital secured the use of the Presbyterian
                    Hospital's convalescent home in Devon for recovered babies who required
                    additional care. In 1913, the Babies' Hospital opened a clinic, dispensary, and
                    milk station on 729 Lombard Street in the city of Philadelphia. The clinic
                    provided numerous services, including instruction courses for expectant mothers.
                    The following year, another dispensary was opened at 609 Addison Street. By
                    1918, this dispensary had moved to larger quarters on Ninth and Pine Streets. In
                    1915, a permanent home for the country hospital was established in Llanerch,
                    Pennsylvania. 1920 marked the opening of the Ethel Burnham Worcester Memorial
                    Cottage, a "seashore branch" of the hospital located in Beach Haven, New
                    Jersey. The main concern of the Babies' Hospital was its social services, which
                    emphasized preventive medicine, good nutrition and hygiene, and the proper care
                    of babies in the home. To house its growing facilities, the hospital built a six
                    story Health Center Building at 7th and Delancey Streets, which was dedicated in
                    May 1921. In 1948, the funds and resources of Babies' Hospital of Philadelphia
                    and the Philadelphia Child Health Society were merged into the Fife Hamill
                    Memorial Health Center for Southeast Philadelphia. The new organization was
                    housed in the Health Center Building formerly occupied by the Babies' Hospital.
                    When the Fife Hamill Memorial Health Center closed in 1960, the Corporation of
                    Babies' Hospital was merged with St. Christopher's Hospital for Children.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains miscellaneous records of the Babies' Hospital of
                    Philadelphia. Printed materials include annual reports (1911-1930); Babies'
                    Hospital and Babies' News (1915-1921); benefit matinee programs (1915-1921); and
                    miscellaneous printed material. Corporate records include a ledger for the
                    Charles A. Fife Memorial Fund kept by the Women's Committee (1929-1937); and
                    minutes of the Medical Administration Committee (1940-1948). There are also
                    papers of H. Lea Hudson, 1932-1960; by-laws, histories, and list of officers of
                    Babies' Hospital of Philadelphia; and correspondence and historical material
                    related to the Fife-Hamill Memorial Health Center for Southeast Philadelphia.
                    There are also photographs and film of the Babies' Hospital dated 1941-1942.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1991-024-02</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia: Babies Hospital of Philadelphia (MSS 6/0006-01).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>