<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>C. Everett Koop M.D. collection <date type="inclusive">1968-1999</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1980-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">C. Everett Koop M.D. collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC2291</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1968-1999</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1980-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles Everett Koop (b. 1916) graduated from Dartmouth College in 1937 and
                    received his M.D. from Cornell Medical College in 1941. After serving an
                    internship at the Pennsylvania Hospital, he pursued postgraduate training at the
                    University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine, Boston Children's Hospital and
                    the Graduate School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, from which he
                    received the degree of Doctor of Science (Medicine) in 1947. Koop was named
                    Professor of Pediatric Surgery, School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania
                    in 1959 and Professor of Pediatrics in 1971. Koop was appointed Deputy Assistant
                    Secretary for Health, U.S. Public Health Service (PHS) in February 1981, and
                    sworn in as Surgeon General on November 17, 1981. He was appointed Director of
                    the Office of International Health in May 1982. Dr. Koop is a member of the
                    American Surgical Association, the Society of University Surgeons, the American
                    Pediatric Surgical Association, and other professional societies. He is a Fellow
                    of the American College of Surgeons and the American Academy of Pediatrics. He
                    also holds membership in many international organizations. He is the author of
                    more than 200 articles and books on the practice of medicine.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of memorabilia related to C. Everett Koop. The collection
                    includes loose, framed, and mounted certificates, citations, and awards;
                    photographs; magazines and magazine covers featuring stories about or interviews
                    of Koop; posters and placards related to health issues; political cartoons;
                    letters regarding the awarding of honors; and a series of Time-Life videos on
                    health. The collection also includes a copy of Koop and a small amount of
                    publicity material for the book. The certificates and awards are from a wide
                    variety of medical and educational organizations and institutions, from the
                    United States and abroad.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: National Institute of
                    Health/National Library of Medicine: C. Everett Koop papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>