<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Chevalier Jackson collection of photographs and etchings <date type="inclusive">1923-1957</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Chevalier Jackson collection of photographs and
                    etchings</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC496</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1923-1957</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Chevalier Jackson (1865-1958) was a laryngologist. Jackson attended the Western
                    University of Pennsylvania (now the University of Pittsburgh) from 1879 to 1883,
                    and received his MD from Jefferson Medical College. He also studied laryngology
                    with the British specialist Sir Morell McKenzie. In the course of his career
                    Jackson introduced many improved techniques for bronchoscopy, oesophagoscopy and
                    gastroscopy. and was successful in removing dangerous foreign bodies with the
                    medical instruments and techniques he designed. During the 1920s, Jackson began
                    a crusade to spread knowledge of preventive measures in order to protect
                    children from inhaling foreign objects. His work led to the passage of the
                    Federal Caustic Poison Act of 1927. He was also the author of four monographs,
                    twelve textbooks, and over 400 medical articles. Jackson was a professor at six
                    different schools, including the University of Pittsburgh, Jefferson Medical
                    College, Women's Medical College (now Drexel University College of Medicine) and
                    Temple University.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of photographs of Chevalier Jackson and prints of his
                    etchings. There are a series of framed photographs of students enrolled in the
                    course in brochoscopy Jackson taught at the University of Pennsylvania, and
                    several photographs of Jackson inscribed to George Pilling. The etchings include
                    images of Old Blockley, Pennsylvania Hospital, Women's Medical College, and
                    Sunrise Mills in Schwenksville, Pennsylvania.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1990-108, 1990-109, 1990-110, 1990-111, and 1990-112</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>