<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia records <date type="inclusive">1855-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC2281</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>102 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1855-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia was founded in 1855. The first location
                    of the original Children's Hospital was a small building on Blight Street (now
                    Watts St). The hospital consisted of 12 beds and a dispensary. That year they
                    recorded 67 inpatient admissions and 306 outpatient visits. Children’s Hospital
                    was relocated to 22nd Street between Locust and Walnut Sts after the American
                    Civil War. This hospital consisted of 35 beds and a dispensary. Construction
                    adjacent to the 2nd hospital was begun in 1913 and the first unit was opened in
                    1916 extending toward 18th and Bainbridge Sts. In 1919 the hospital became
                    affiliated with the University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine. The
                    affiliation became steadily closer over the next 17 years, with the Children's
                    Hospital becoming identical to the pediatric department of the school of
                    medicine, with most of the attending physicians appointed jointly to both
                    institutions. Construction of the new hospital at a new site on the west side of
                    the Schuylkill River at 34th Street and Civic Center Boulevard, adjacent to the
                    campus of the University of Pennsylvania, was begun in 1969 and the first
                    building was opened in 1974. This present Children's Hospital complex occupies
                    part of the site of the old Philadelphia General Hospital and Blockley
                    Almshouse. CHOP has over 430 beds, 40 percent of which are allocated to
                    neonatal, cardiac, and pediatric intensive care. Each year the hospital admits
                    more than 15,000 children and more than 600,000 are seen in the emergency and
                    outpatient departments.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes administrative records, historical items, and
                    audiovisual, visual and printed materials relating to the Children's Hospital of
                    Philadelphia. In addition to records of committees, departments, workshops,
                    symposia, and fundraising events, there is information on strategic planning
                    efforts and building projects. The collection contains substantial documentation
                    of public relations and advertising efforts, and includes: correspondence; press
                    kits; fact sheets; news releases; newspaper clippings; reports and memoranda;
                    and copies of brochures. The collection contains some audiovisual materials, as
                    well as numerous photographs and negatives, some of which have been scanned.
                    Printed CHOP materials include Annual Reports (1856-2003), Pediatric Pioneering,
                    CHOP Notes, Children's Times, Children's View, and other periodicals. There is a
                    set of biographical files on physicians, officers, board members and staff
                    including consisting of audiocassettes and transcripts of interviews, CVs,
                    biographical sketches, clippings, and other materials. The collection includes
                    some patient records (1876-1920) and slides of patients. There are a number of
                    artifacts and framed awards in the collection.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Children--Hospitals.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Hospital Administration.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Hospitals--Pennsylvania.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Hospitals--Public relations.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Annual reports</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Interviews</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Medical records</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Negatives (Photographic)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Press kits.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Publications.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Slides (Photographs)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Video recordings</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia: Children's Seashore House records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>