<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Children’s Seashore House records <date type="inclusive">1874-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Children’s Seashore House records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC2280</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>14.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1874-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Children's Seashore House was founded in 1872 near Atlantic City, New Jersey, as
                    a place for children to receive rehabilitation treatment. Funded by donations
                    from wealthy Philadelphians, Children’s Seashore House accepted its first 55
                    young patients in the summer of 1873. Years ahead of its time, the hospital was
                    the first pediatric rehabilitation hospital in the nation. In 1990 the hospital
                    moved to its current location next to CHOP and in 1998 it was acquired by CHOP.
                    As of 1998, the hospital had 45 beds. It currently offers provides inpatient and
                    outpatient care for children with developmental disabilities and chronic
                    illnesses.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records, printed matter, images and artifacts from the
                    Children's Seashore House. Administrative records of the Seashore House include:
                    patient registers (1874-1982, with some gaps); visitor registers (1909-1968,
                    also with gaps); bound volumes of annual reports; charter and by-laws; strategic
                    planning documents; brochures and postcards; newsletters; and a small amount of
                    correspondence related to patients. Photographic materials include prints,
                    slides, negatives, and contact sheets showing patients, staff, buildings, and
                    events and ceremonies. The collection also includes plaques, awards, citations,
                    architectural plans, clippings about the hospital, and the official seal of
                    Seashore House.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia: Children's Hospital of Philadelphia (CHOP) records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>