<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>College of Physicians of Philadelphia Office of the Executive
                        Director records <date type="inclusive">1953-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">College of Physicians of Philadelphia Office of the
                    Executive Director records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC504</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>64 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The College of Physicians of Philadelphia, founded in 1787, is the oldest
                    professional medical organization in the country. The College is home to the
                    Mütter Museum and the Historical Medical Library. Through its program of
                    lectures, workshops, and conferences, as well as through the C. Everett Koop
                    Community Education Center and PhillyHealthInfo.org, an online health
                    information resource, the College provides a place for both medical
                    professionals and the general public to learn about medicine as both a science
                    and as an art. Past Executive Directors of the College include Marc Micozzi and
                    John O'Donnell.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records from the Office of the Executive Director. The
                    materials in the collection date from 1953 to 2003 and include records of John
                    M. O'Donnell, William F. Chaveas, and Marc Micozzi. Materials include
                    correspondence and memoranda; minutes and agendas for meetings of the Council
                    and of various College committees; subject files; appointment books; financial
                    records; development and strategic planning files; information on Fellows,
                    including statistical reports; fellowship ballots and proxies; files on College
                    programs, lectures, and events, including programs, announcements, and
                    photographs of speakers; records related to facilities and maintenance matters
                    and building renovations; files on and external projects and medical
                    organizations, such as the History of Nursing in Philadelphia project,
                    Philadelphia Health Management Corporation, the Health Sciences Library
                    Consortium, the Association of American Medical Colleges, the National Library
                    of Medicine, and the Royal Society of Medicine.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Financial records</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1991-048; 1991-091; 1992-109; 1993-019; 1993-040; 1993-043;
                    1993-048; 1993-057; 1994-030; 1995-056; 1996-002; 1996-016; 1997-007; 1989-27;
                    1989-46; 1989-82; 1990-002; 1991-121; 1992-045; 1990-103; </p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>