<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>College of Physicians of Philadelphia Office of the President
                        records <date type="inclusive">1948-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">College of Physicians of Philadelphia Office of the
                    President records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC481</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1948-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The College of Physicians of Philadelphia, founded in 1787, is the oldest
                    professional medical organization in the country. The College is home to the
                    Mütter Museum and the Historical Medical Library. Through its program of
                    lectures, workshops, and conferences, as well as through the C. Everett Koop
                    Community Education Center and PhillyHealthInfo.org, an online health
                    information resource, the College provides a place for both medical
                    professionals and the general public to learn about medicine as both a science
                    and as an art. The President of the College of Physicians calls and presides at
                    meetings, appoints committees, serves as an ex-officio member of all committees,
                    and submits a yearly report of the College's activities to the Countil. The
                    President serves a two-year term.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials from the Office of the President of the College
                    of Physicians of Philadelphia. The collection includes files from J.P. Hubbard,
                    Katherine Sturgis, R.S. Pressman, Arthur Asbury, and Thomas Langfitt. Records
                    relate to annual meetings, Practice-related Educational Programs (PREP)
                    formation and development, Continuing Medical Education programs, the Building
                    Fund, the Wood Institute, the Ghana Medical College project, development, and
                    strategic planning. Materials include: correspondence, meeting minutes and
                    agendas, memoranda, grant proposals, reports, and speeches. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1989-082; 2007-009; 2008-002</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>