<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>College of Physicians of Philadelphia Library records <date type="inclusive">1882-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">College of Physicians of Philadelphia Library
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC484</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>236 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1882-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Established in 1788, the Library of the College of Physicians of Philadelphia was
                    Philadelphia’s central medical library for over 150 years, serving its medical
                    schools, hospitals, physicians and other health professionals. Today, it is an
                    independent research library devoted to the history of medicine and serves
                    hundreds of scholars, health professionals, students and popular writers each
                    year. In addition to its rare books and nineteenth- and twentieth-century
                    collections, the College Library is notable for its manuscripts and archives.
                    Within this collection are the College’s own archives, the archives of other
                    Philadelphia medical institutions, and letters, case books, and student
                    notebooks that document the personal life and professional practice of doctors
                    in the Philadelphia region and around the world. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection documents both the Public Services and Historical Collections
                    functions of the Library of the College of Physicians of Philadelphia. The
                    collection ranges in date from the late nineteenth to the twenty-first century
                    and includes papers of several Librarians, Curators of Historical Collections,
                    and other Library staff members, including Thomas A. Horrocks, Marjorie Smink,
                    Christine Ruggere, Anthony A. Aguirre, Ellen Gatrell, Charles Greifenstein,
                    Andrea Kenyon, and Sofie Sereda. Programs and College Sections documented in the
                    collection include: PhillyHealthInfo.org, Consumer Health Information Network
                    (CHINET), Community Health Information Center (CHIC), Medical Documentation
                    Service (MDS), Mid-Eastern Regional Medical Library Service (MERMLS), the
                    Strategic Core Planning Group, the Samuel Lewis Circle, and the Sections on Arts
                    and Medicine and Public Health. Outside professional organizations and consortia
                    documented in the collection include the Philadelphia Area Consortium of Special
                    Collections Libraries (PACSCL), the Delaware Valley Archivists Group (DVAG), the
                    Mid-Atlantic Regional Archives Conference (MARAC), the American Osler Society,
                    and the Health Sciences Library Consortium, This collection includes extensive
                    documentation of the administration of the College Library, including records of
                    librarians and curators of historical collections and records of the Mid-Eastern
                    Regional Medical Library Service (MERMLS). Administrative files date from 1882
                    to 2000, and include: correspondence, meeting minutes and agendas, newsletters,
                    financial records, budgets and planning documents, personnel records,
                    correspondence, grant proposals and reports, subject and research files, and
                    exhibit files. Also included among the administrative files are clippings and
                    publicity information, conservation assessments, records of loans to other
                    institutions, personnel files of MDS staff (1959-1989), records related to the
                    Strategic Planning Core Group, records related to the Samuel Lewis Circle, floor
                    plans of the library’s reading room and stacks, interlibrary loan reports,
                    letterpress volumes of correspondence (1882-1932), binder’s books (1882-1895 and
                    1920-1935), lists of information resources on consumer health and public health,
                    audiocassettes of lectures and programs. MERMLS records date from 1962 to 1983
                    and include: director’s files, publications, workshop materials, grant
                    applications, annual reports, correspondence, and questionnaires. The collection
                    also includes detailed documentation of library usage and holdings. These
                    materials include circulation and call slips, circulation statistics, OCLC
                    statistics, correspondence about reference requests, photo requests, document
                    delivery statistics, online searches, patron surveys, acquisitions, records of
                    gifts, information on duplicate books, a 1930 inventory of archives in the
                    vault, lists of materials in offsite storage, inventories of the Radbill book
                    collection, an inventory of incunabula, library policies and procedures, MDS
                    data input forms, and appointment books from Public Services, 2003-2005.
                    Documentation of specific programs involving the Library’s Public Services
                    division include records of CHINET: budgets, minutes, information packets,
                    correspondence, and reports, 1983-1985; records of Philly Health Info such as
                    correspondence, reports, statistics, surveys, evaluations, printed materials,
                    training manuals, and banners, 2002-2005; and records of CHIC: catalogs of
                    journal held by CPP, reference correspondence, usage statistics, and reports.
                    Documentation of publication projects involving the Library include: catalog
                    entries for the manuscript guide, 1953-1982; proofs of the Portrait Catalog;
                    articles and notes related to Fugitive Leaves; and printed brochures and
                    catalogues.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1989-21; 1989-22; 1989-23; 1989-33; 1989-55; 1989-68; 1989-121;
                    1989-114; 1990-013; 1990-069; 1992-085; 1992-095; 1992-107; 1996-035; 1997-005;
                    1997-023; 1997-025; 1997-026; 1997-027-01; 1997-027-02; 1997-032; 1998-012;
                    1999-002; 2002-010; 2003-006; 1989-56; 1989-77; 1989-117</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>