<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Frank Hartman papers <date type="inclusive">1904-1977</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Frank Hartman papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC580</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1904-1977</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Frank Hartman (1893-1986), was a radium specialist and consultant, and owner of
                    Radium Services, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1919-1956. He started selling
                    radium products after World War I. In 1934 he became a sales agent for radium
                    from the Eldorado Mining and Refining Company of Canada, which along with the
                    Atomic Energy Commission after World War II, supplied him with radium and
                    various isotopes. By the late 1930s, Hartman was acutely aware of the dangers of
                    radium and took it upon himself to locate and recover pieces lost by area
                    hospitals and industry until his retirements in 1956.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Frank Hartman. Materials include:
                    correspondence with academic institutions, officials of government and cancer
                    societies, and Philadelphia radiologists, relating to Hartman's services;
                    reports, catalogs, and price lists, including US Atomic Energy publications
                    (1918-1960s) of radium products; photographs; a diary of radium retrieval
                    efforts (1930s-1956); clippings regarding radium in Philadelphia area
                    (1930s-1960s); reprints, flyers in German and English for radiation therapies
                    (1920s-1930s); books on radium and radioactivity (1904-1968); photographs of
                    Marie Curie, Frank Hartman, and Hartman Laboratories; and other papers relating
                    to Hartman's life and career. The collection also includes: 117 glass lantern
                    slides related to radium, radioactivity, and the Curies; framed photos and
                    illustrations of radiation theory and phenomena; a binder of photos made from
                    glass slides and box of other photos; publications relating to the radiation
                    industry, including Vols. 14 and 17 of Atomic Energy of Canada, Ltd. Published
                    Papers; and 2 cassettes (and CDs) of 1971 and 1976 interviews with Hartman.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Holy Family College.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1997</p>
                <p>Accession number: 1997-012</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>