<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Howard Childs Carpenter slide collection <date type="inclusive">undated</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Howard Childs Carpenter slide collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC2307</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Howard Childs Carpenter (1878-1955) received his M.D. from the University of
                    Pennsylvania Medical School in 1900. In 1914 Carpenter founded the Department
                    for the Prevention of Disease at the Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia. He was
                    appointed Professor of Pediatrics, Graduate School of Medicine, University of
                    Pennsylvania in 1929. He was a member of the Philadelphia Pediatric Society, the
                    Philadelphia County Medical Society, The American Pediatrics Society, and many
                    other societies and associations. Carpenter was elected a fellow of College of
                    Physicians in 1925.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains approximately 250 glass lantern slides, measuring 3.25 x
                    4". Most of the slide are in black and white. The diverse images relate to
                    child healthcare, nutrition, and disease prevention. Subjects include: the
                    activities of the Department of Prevention of Disease; foreign children; infant
                    care; sanitary kitchens and farms; portraits of physicians; cartoons; and graphs
                    and diagrams. These slides probably accompanied lectures given by Carpenter to
                    community groups, mothers attending clinics at the Department for Prevention of
                    Diseases, and students attending the Pennsylvania School of Social and Health
                    Work.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Samuel Radbill?</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>