<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John M. Keating correpondence <date type="inclusive">1888-1893</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1891-1893</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John M. Keating correpondence</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC621</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1888-1893</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1891-1893</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John M. Keating (1852-1893) was Professor of Obstetrics in the Jefferson Medical
                    College. He graduated with a medical degree from the University of Pennsylvania
                    in 1873. He was Physician to Blockley Hospital and Lecturer on the Diseases of
                    Children in the University of Pennsylvania. Keating was the editor of Cyclopedia
                    of Diseases of Children, and contributed to a number of other volumes on
                    obstetrics pediatrics. He was the editor of Archives of Pediatrics, the
                    International Clinics, and the Climatologist, and was president of the American
                    Medical Association Section on Diseases of Children.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence of John M. Keating, from 1891 and 1893.
                    Most of the letters concern medical publishing and Keating's role as editor and
                    as reviewer. Other topics include the Pan-American Medical Congress of 1893.
                    Correspondents include William Osler, Charles Penrose, Judson Daland, J.M. Da
                    Costa, W.B. Saunders, Charles Lea, and John Wanamaker.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2002-02</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>