<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Katharine R. Sturgis papers <date type="inclusive">1948-1976</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Katharine R. Sturgis papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC2284</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1948-1976</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Katharine Rosenbaum Guest Boucot Sturgis was born in Philadelphia in 1903. She
                    received her undergraduate degree from Penn State University and entered Woman's
                    Medical College of Pennsylvania in 1935. She was forced to leave school when she
                    contracted tuberculosis, but she later resumed her studies and earned her
                    medical degree in 1940. After her internship at the Woman's Medical College
                    Hospital and a residency at Herman Kiefer Hospital in Detroit, Sturgis returned
                    to Philadelphia to teach at the Woman's Medical College. Throughout her career
                    she conducted research in the early detection of lung cancer and tuberculosis,
                    and later in life, she waged a vigorous campaign to inform the public of the
                    hazards of smoking. Sturgis became a Fellow of the College of Physicians of
                    Philadelphia in 1951 and was elected its first woman president in 1972. She was
                    forced to retire one year later due to health problems. During her distinguished
                    career, Sturgis also served as the first woman president of the Philadelphia
                    County Medical Society and president of the American College of Preventive
                    Medicine. Katharine R. Sturgis died 1987.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Katherine R. Sturgis. Materials include:
                    professional correspondence with individual colleagues and related to
                    involvement with various groups and institutions., and to activities as
                    President of the College of Physicians. Additional materials include: medical
                    papers (typescripts and reprints) by Sturgis, many related to lung cancer; notes
                    and text for speeches and addresses given by Sturgis; correspondence, notes, and
                    other information related to involvement with the Medical Advisory Board of
                    Girard College; correspondence, minutes, and agendas from the Philadelphia
                    County Medical Society; notebooks containing notes and sketches from patient
                    visits; memos related to work as a tuberculosis consultant for the City of
                    Philadelphia; annual reports from the Department of Preventative Medicine,
                    Women's Medical College of Pennsylvania (1954-1965); and pencil drawings of an
                    eye operation by H.C. Eggers. The collection also includes: a small number of
                    family photographs and several framed items; clippings about Sturgis's career;
                    diplomas and certificates of Samuel B. Sturgis; and a manuscript copy of
                    Sturgis's autobiography The Kath with Nine Lives.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia: Office of the President, general correspondence files of
                    Kathereine Sturgis (CPP 2/0002-02) and Office of the President, Presidential
                    papers of Katharine R. Sturgis (CPP 2/0002-01).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>