<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Mutter Museum records <date type="inclusive">1887-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Mutter Museum records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC506</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>28.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1887-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1849, Dr. Isaac Parrish suggested that the College of Physicians of
                    Philadelphia start a museum of pathological anatomy to preserve valuable
                    material that might otherwise be lost to science. In 1858, Thomas Dent Mütter,
                    retired Professor of Surgery at Jefferson Medical College, presented his
                    personal collection of unique anatomic and pathological materials to The College
                    of Physicians of Philadelphia. The collection now boasts over 20,000 objects.
                    These include fluid-preserved anatomical and pathological specimens; skeletal
                    and dried specimens, medical instruments and apparati; anatomical and
                    pathological models in plaster, wax, papier-mâché, and plastic; memorabilia of
                    famous scientists and physicians; medical illustrations, photographs, prints,
                    and portraits. In addition, the Museum offers changing exhibits on a variety of
                    medical and historical topics.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Mütter Museum. Records include: budget
                    records (2000-2006); files related to the Lewis and Clark and Say Ahh! Exhibits;
                    files related to the Museum's calendar, activity and accession record books
                    (1937-1970), museum guest and visitor registers (1887-1985); catalog of the
                    museum (1947-1949); catalog of medals; scrapbooks (1930s and 1950s-1960s);
                    Museum statistics; photo requests (1999-2004); group tour schedules and
                    evaluations; and a typescript of a history of the Museum, ca. 1968-1978. Also in
                    the collection are records of the Museum Council of Philadelphia and the
                    Delaware Valley. Records include minutes and correspondence, and some
                    photographs of objects in member institutions (1978-1989).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1991-119-16/17/18, 2007-005, 2007-006</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>