<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Palmer Futcher papers <date type="inclusive">1939-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Palmer Futcher papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC495</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>14 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1939-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Palmer Howard Futcher (1910-2004) graduated from Harvard College and in 1936
                    earned a medical degree from Johns Hopkins University. After his residency there
                    he joined a research team at the Rockefeller Institute, resigning soon after
                    Pearl Harbor to join the Navy in 1942. At Pensacola he studied survival at sea,
                    and met and married Mary Viola Rightor. After discharge from the Navy in 1946,
                    he taught medicine at Washington University and became certified in internal
                    medicine in 1947, before returning to Johns Hopkins in 1948. For 19 years he was
                    variously director of the outpatient service, director of the university's
                    student health service, and an assistant dean. In 1967 Futcher moved to
                    Philadelphia to become the Executive Secretary of the American Board of Internal
                    Medicine (ABIM). Following retirement from ABIM in 1975 he attended at a
                    University of Pennsylvania diabetes clinic, and volunteered successfully for
                    recertification in internal medicine in 1977. An active member of both the World
                    Federalist Association and Physicians for Social Responsibility, he advocated
                    world peace through law and negotiation. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Palmer Futcher papers contain files concerning the College of Physicians of
                    Philadelphia Library Committee (1975-1984), including correspondence, memoranda,
                    reports, and printed material (7 folders). Additional College of Physicians of
                    Philadelphia materials include: memoranda, correspondence, and reports related
                    to the Section of Medical History and the Wood Institute Advisory Committee (up
                    to 1994). There are files from Futcher's time as assistant dean at Johns
                    Hopkins, and some files from his time as Executive Secretary of the American
                    Board of Internal Medicine. A portion of the collection is made of subject files
                    (1939-1980s) on medical topics including diseases, disciplines, health care
                    systems, and medical education, and non-medical topics such as economics,
                    education, and philosophy. The subject files contain such formats as magazine
                    and newspaper clippings, reprints of scientific articles, reports, medical case
                    files, photographs, transparencies, bibliographies, newsletters, memoranda and
                    correspondence. There are drafts of articles and presentations by Futcher as
                    well.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Palmer Futcher.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1990, 1994</p>
                <p>Accession number: 1990-092-01 and 1990-091-01</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia: Committee on By-laws and Ordinances, records of the Chairman
                    (CPP 10/0010-01).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>