<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia General Hospital records and microfilm <date type="inclusive">1844-1941</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia General Hospital records and
                    microfilm</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC2292</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1844-1941</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Until its closing, Philadelphia General Hospital (PGH) was the oldest institution
                    in the United States in continuous service providing hospitalized care.
                    Established in 1729, the Hospital had a long history dedicated to the care of
                    the medically indigent of the city. In 1834, the institution moved from Center
                    City to Blockley Township in West Philadelphia to the area that is now between
                    34th Street and University Avenue. At that time, it was renamed the Philadelphia
                    Almshouse and Hospital and became affectionately known as "Old Blockley". In
                    1903, the Hospital was officially separated from the Almshouse. The Hospital was
                    officially named the Philadelphia General Hospital in 1919 and its supervision,
                    as well as that of the Philadelphia Hospital for the Insane ("Byberry") and
                    the Municipal Hospital for Contagious Diseases, were placed within the newly
                    created Bureau of Hospitals in the Department of Public Health. Under contracts
                    signed in 1959, medical care at Philadelphia General Hospital became the
                    responsibility of the medical schools of Temple University and the University of
                    Pennsylvania who then subcontracted some of their work to Jefferson Medical
                    College, Women's Medical College and Hahnemann Medical School. By the early
                    1970s, Philadelphia General Hospital no longer met modern standards for a
                    hospital. Because of the extensive renovation necessary to meet the requirements
                    of new fire and other life safety codes, the decision was made to close
                    Philadelphia General Hospital in 1977.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Philadelphia General Hospital. Materials
                    include: registers of resident physicians (1884-1913); registers of attending
                    physicians, surgical chiefs, and neurological chiefs; clinical laboratory
                    reports (1905-1921); daily record of ambulance calls (1933-1941); and an
                    appointment book from the Men's Nervous Department (1903-1915). The collection
                    also contains 10 rolls each of positive and negative microfilm of the
                    Philadelphia Almshouse records (held by the City Archives).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>