<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Area Consortium of Special Collections Libraries
                        records <date type="inclusive">1988-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Area Consortium of Special Collections
                    Libraries records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC2290</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1988-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1985, 16 institutions came together to create Philadelphia Area Consortium of
                    Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) as an informal cooperative group with a
                    shared agenda ranging from access to public programs and development. PACSCL has
                    grown in size to over 30 libraries and evolved into a formal organization.
                    PACSCL is governed by a Board of Directors consisting of one representative from
                    each member library. An Executive Committee, consisting of six elected members
                    (four officers and two at-large members), the immediate past chair, and the
                    chairs of standing and ad hoc committees, oversees programs and planning.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Philadelphia Area Consortium of Special
                    Collections Libraries (PACSCL). Materials include project and budget reports for
                    NHPRC and Pew Charitable Trust grant projects; minutes of meetings of PACSCL and
                    of the group's executive committee; correspondence related to membership and
                    special projects; files on legal, insurance, and tax status of PACSCL; and files
                    on programs and events. The records appear to be the files of Carol Spawn and
                    Thomas Horrocks.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>