<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia County Medical Society Committee on Maternal Welfare
                        Maternal Mortality Study records <date type="inclusive">1934-1970</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia County Medical Society Committee on Maternal
                    Welfare Maternal Mortality Study records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC531</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1934-1970</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Committee on Maternal Welfare was established in 1930 by George P. Muller,
                    President of the Philadelphia County Medical Society. Muller created the
                    committee after he became aware of the results of a survey conducted by Dr.
                    Haven Emerson; the survey revealed that although Philadelphia had a falling
                    birth rate, the maternal mortality rate had remained the same over a period of
                    ten years. In order to study this problem, President Muller appointed a
                    committee, chaired by Philip F. Williams, to conduct additional research on
                    maternal death in Philadelphia. In 1934, after a three year survey of 717
                    maternal deaths, the Committee on Maternal Welfare produced a report of its
                    findings. The impact of this report was so great that the committee became a
                    permanent division of the Philadelphia County Medical Society and began holding
                    monthly meetings. In subsequent years, the Committee on Maternal Welfare
                    continued its surveys and began to implement programs designed to reduce the
                    maternal death rate. Its work had a profound impact on the community; as a
                    result of the committee's on going research and innovative programs,
                    Philadelphia's maternal death rate dropped from 6.8 per thousand births in 1931
                    to .9 per thousand births in 1949. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Philadelphia County Medical Society Committee on Maternal
                    Welfare Maternal Mortality Study records. The collection includes five volumes
                    of statistics on maternal mortality in Philadelphia, 1934-1960, compiled by the
                    Committee on Maternal Welfare. The monthly summaries list the hospital, cause,
                    preventability and notes about other related factors. Most of the volumes
                    include yearly summaries as well. The collection also includes a small amount of
                    material from the Philadelphia County Medical Society committees on Maternal
                    Welfare and Maternal and Perinatal Studies (1955-1970). Items include:
                    correspondence with committee members; lists of committee members; guidelines
                    for maternity departments from the Philadelphia Country Medical Society and the
                    Philadelphia Department of Health; and reports of maternal and fetal deaths.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1994-039 and 1996-010</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia: Philadelphia County Medical Society. Committee on Maternal
                    Welfare Maternal Mortality Study records (MSS 03/0013-01).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>