<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert H. Ivy papers <date type="inclusive">1904-1974</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert H. Ivy papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC489</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1904-1974</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert H. Ivy (1881-1974) was an internationally known plastic surgeon and
                    authority on lip and cleft palate deformity. Ivy immigrated to the United States
                    from England in 1899. He graduated from the University of Pennsylvania Dental
                    School in 1902 and its School of Medicine in 1907. Ivy was a professor of
                    plastic surgery and maxillofacial surgery at the University of Pennsylvania (he
                    held appointments in both the Medical and Dental Schools), and a Fellow of the
                    American College of Surgeons and of the College of Physicians.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection includes certificates from various professional organizations,
                    including the American College of Surgeons, the American Board of Plastic
                    Surgeons, the Association of Military Plastic Surgeons, and the American
                    Association for the Advancement of Science; honorary diplomas, plaques, a
                    trophy, and licenses; and military certificates, including Ivy's appointments to
                    the ranks of Lieutenant Colonel (1919) and Colonel (1924 and 1939) and a 1945
                    certificate recognizing his service as a consultant to the Secretary of War.
                    Other items include a notebook titled "Notes on clinical laboratory
                    examinations," 1912; addresses and recollections by Ivy; numerous photos and
                    slides of Ivy, meetings and reunions, golfing, and fishing and photos,
                    negatives, and slides of a visit to North China and Korea, 1904-1905;
                    correspondence related to the Graduate Hospital's role in the University of
                    Pennsylvania's medical program (1969-1970); correspondence, announcements, and
                    schedules from the College of Physicians, largely from the early 1970s; and
                    correspondence for Ivy's "Personal Recollections of Holders of the John Rhea
                    Barton Professorship of Surgery in the School of Medicine of the University of
                    Pennsylvania".</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Transferred from Mutter Museum</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1989</p>
                <p>Accession number: 1989-84</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>