<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert S. Pressman papers <date type="inclusive">1933-1982</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert S. Pressman papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC2272</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>9.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1933-1982</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert S. Pressman (1911-1995) graduated from the Temple University School of
                    Medicine in 1946 and received an M.M.S. degree in Internal Medicine from the
                    University of Pennsylvania. Pressman served as an Associate Professor of
                    Medicine at Temple University and as head of the infectious diseases section at
                    the Albert Einstein Medical Center. He was a president of the Philadelphia
                    County Medical Society and of the Pennsylvania Society of Internal Medicine
                    (1968-1969). He also served as president of the medical staff at Albert Einstein
                    Medical Center. Pressman was elected a fellow of the College of Physicians in
                    1955. He served as president of the College of Physicians from 1984 to 1986. He
                    also served on several College committees, including the Committees on Audit,
                    Fellowship, Finance, Major Gifts, and Nominations, and he was also an S. Weir
                    Mitchell Associate and an active supporter of the New Century Fund.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Robert S. Pressman. Materials include:
                    records of Pressman's term as President of the College of Physicians including
                    correspondence, minutes and reports, and financial information; correspondence,
                    minutes and reports, memoranda, policy statements, and annual reports, from the
                    Philadelphia County Medical Society, the Pennsylvania Medical Society, and the
                    Albert Einstein Medical Center; lecture notes from Pressman's medical studies at
                    Temple University; product catalogs for medical equipment and supplies; bills
                    and receipts; articles, reprints and journals; notes on research studies; grant
                    proposals; correspondence with colleagues, editors, and patients.; and awards,
                    certificates, and diplomas. The collection also includes a small amount of
                    materials related to Pressman and his wife's military service, including patient
                    records; family papers including a Pressman family history, school records of
                    Alice Pressman, and photographs several diaries; and also medical textbooks.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia. Committee on By-Laws and Ordinances records of the Chairman
                    (CPP 10/0010-01) and College of Physicians of Philadelphia. Office of the
                    President records concerning the search committee (CPP 2/0009-01).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>