<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert A. Groff papers <date type="inclusive">1908-1977</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1936-1975</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert A. Groff papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC483</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>23 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1908-1977</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1936-1975</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert Armand Groff (1903-1975) earned his bachelor's degree in 1925, and M.D. in
                    1928, from the University of Pennsylvania. Groff served on the faculties of
                    Jefferson Medical College, Graduate Hospital, Presbyterian Hospital and the
                    University of Pennsylvania. During World War II, Groff served in the 20th
                    General Hospital in northeast India. He served as Chairman of Neurosurgery at
                    the University of Pennsylvania from 1957-1968. Groff was the author of many
                    scientific articles as well as the publication Manual of Diagnosis and
                    Management of Peripheral Nerve Injuries. Groff was a Fellow of the College of
                    Physicians of Philadelphia from 1941-1975.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Robert A. Groff. The materials in the
                    collection are located both onsite at the College of Physicians of Philadelphia,
                    and in offsite storage. The onsite collection includes: indices for offsite
                    files; awards, plaques, medals, and memorabilia; portraits and family snapshots;
                    surgical records of Groff and several other neurosurgeons from 1934-1949; some
                    biographical information; a few manuscripts; a folder of news clippings; and
                    papers from Groff's Army service in World War II, including data collected on
                    nerve injuries. The collection contains case logs from 1938-1943 and 1949-1951,
                    and case records from 1946-1951. Along with the collection is a box of patient
                    records from the 1930s-1940s, and a box of billing records (1977) from the
                    Graduate Hospital, which do not appear to be closely related to Groff. The
                    portion of the collection held offsite contains 120 feet of primarily patient
                    records and other miscellaneous, uncatalogued material.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Mary A. Groff. Gift of UPenn Hospital Department of
                    Neurosurgery.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1982, 1987, 1989</p>
                <p>Accession number: 1989-19, 1991-116</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, University Archives and Records Center: U.S. Army 20th General
                    Hospital records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>