<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Board of Scientific
                        Directors reports and minutes <date type="inclusive">1931</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Board of
                    Scientific Directors reports and minutes</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC581</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1931</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research was founded by John D.
                    Rockefeller, and incorporated in 1901. It was the first institution in the
                    United States devoted solely to biomedical research. In 1955, Rockefeller
                    expanded its mission to include education, admitting its first class of graduate
                    students. It granted its first doctoral degrees in 1959. In 1965, The
                    Rockefeller Institute became The Rockefeller University, broadening its research
                    mandate further. In the early 1960s, new faculty with expertise in physics and
                    mathematics came to Rockefeller. In 1972, the University began its collaboration
                    with Cornell University to offer graduate students an M.D.-Ph.D. program. Later,
                    the Sloan-Kettering Institute became a partner in the program. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of two volumes of Rockefeller Institute for Medical
                    Research Board of Scientific Directors reports from 1931. The reports summarize
                    the work of the various divisions of the institute, including the Departments of
                    the Hospital, Animal Pathology, Experimental Surgery, Chemistry, Chemical
                    Pharmacology, and others. The collection also includes minutes of the Board of
                    Scientific Directors, January and April, 1931. Most of the business recorded in
                    the minutes relates to appointments of staff and to financial matters.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1997-017</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>