<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Samuel X. Radbill papers <date type="inclusive">1751-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Samuel X. Radbill papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC507</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>53.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1751-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Samuel X Radbill, Philadelphia pediatrician and medical historian, was born in
                    1901. Radbill received his M.D. from the University of Pennsylvania in 1924. In
                    1925, he became a Resident at Children's Hospital of Philadelphia. In 1926,
                    Radbill opened his private practice. He began to specialize in pediatrics in
                    1938 and joined the pediatrics staff at Philadelphia General Hospital. During
                    the early 1930s, Radbill helped organize and run three free local pediatric
                    clinics in Philadelphia. During World War II, he served as an examiner for the
                    local draft board, then enlisted in 1942. He served as Chief of the Communicable
                    Disease Section at Ashburn General Hospital in McKinney, Tex., and Chief of
                    Medical Service and Venereal Disease Control Officer at Fort Crockett,
                    Galveston, Tex. Radbill was elected to fellowship in the College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia in 1943. He died in 1987.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Samuel X. Radbill. Major topics within the
                    collection include medicine in folklore, the history of pediatrics, pediatrics
                    in art, Jewish physicians, children's hospitals, medical history of Philadelphia
                    and the history of Children's Hospital of Philadelphia. Materials include:
                    pamphlets and reprints; manuscripts and typescripts of articles; research and
                    bibliographic notes; prints and engravings; photographs; postcards; clippings
                    from magazines and newspapers; museum and auction catalogs; a small amount of
                    correspondence; minutes of the Library Committee and the Wood Institute Advisory
                    Committee of the College of Physicians, 1949-1987; and manuscripts and printed
                    volumes. Among the images and illustrations are many portraits of physicians.
                    Bound manuscripts include lecture notes from Dr. Chapman's courses, 1817; and a
                    three-volume text book on medicine in Latin, 1751. Reprints are in English,
                    French, German, Italian, Hebrew; several books are in Latin.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">College of Physicians of Philadelphia.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">History of Medicine.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Medicine--Pictorial works.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Medicine--Study and teaching.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Broadsides</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Cartoons (Humorous images)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Catalogs</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ephemera</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Exhibition catalogs</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Pamphlets</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photograph albums</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Portraits</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Postcards</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Prints (Visual works)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reprints</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Research notes</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1991-166</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia: Samuel X. Radbill papers (MSS 2/0037-01).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>