<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Samuel M. Beale papers <date type="inclusive">1927-1965</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Samuel M. Beale papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC497</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1927-1965</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Samuel Marsden Beale, Jr. (1876-1965) practiced medicine for 60 years on Cape
                    Cod. Beale received his bachelor's degree from Brown University and his M.D.
                    from Jefferson Medical College in Philadelphia in 1902. In 1919 Beale became a
                    member of the original staff of the Cape Cod Hospital in Hyannis and a trustee
                    of the Barnstable County Hospital at Pocasset. His clinical interests included
                    metabolic diseases and cancer. Beale published multiple articles on insulin and
                    cancer. In 1933 he became a member of a correspondence club organized by De
                    Forest Clinton Jarvis, who later published the best-selling Folk Medicine
                    (1958); after the group ended, Beale sent out a series of communication letters
                    on health matters titled "Letters to My People."</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Dr. Beale's patient records, 1927-1965, in rough
                    alphabetical order by patient name. These files include patient medical
                    histories, correspondence with patients and other physicians, test results,
                    photographs, and x-rays. The collection also includes several reprints by Beale,
                    a copy of The Doctor Beale Book, and photographic illustrations for an article
                    by Beale. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Elizabeth S. Beale</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1990, 1996</p>
                <p>Accession number: 1990-136 and 1996-035</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>