<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Teratology Society records <date type="inclusive">1964-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Teratology Society records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC634</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Teratology Society was founded by Drs. F. Clarke Fraser, Josef Warkany and
                    James G. Wilson in 1960 with the first annual meeting in 1961. The purpose of
                    the society was to foster exchange of information relating to congenital (birth)
                    defects including their nature, cause, mechanism and prevention. Members are
                    drawn from a wide range of scientific fields including pediatrics, anatomy,
                    epidemiology, pharmacology and industrial toxicology, developmental biology,
                    obstetrics, pathology, genetics and dentistry. The Society through its officers
                    and council members plans the annual meetings and carries out the business
                    related to the interests of its members. A number of committees aid the society
                    in such areas as elections, education, publications, student affairs,
                    legislative affairs and other mostly ad hoc groups. Symposia and refresher
                    courses are included in the annual meeting. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Teratology Society. Materials include
                    photographs, slides, and postcards from meetings; meeting agendas and programs;
                    council notebooks from 1992 to 1994, which include minutes and committee
                    reports; information on the history of the Society, including reprints of
                    articles from the journal Teratology; items used in an exhibit at the 2003
                    meeting; an article entitled "Historical Reflections."; a supplement from the
                    third teratology workshop, 1966; and an administrative report from the 1964
                    workshop.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2003-007 and 2003-015</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of
                    Physicians: Teratology Society records (MSS 3/0015-01).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>