<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Waldo E. Nelson papers <date type="inclusive">1924-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Waldo E. Nelson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC593</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1924-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Waldo Emerson Nelson (1898-1997) was born in McClure, Ohio, and obtained his
                    medical degree from the University of Cincinnati in 1926. He was an intern at
                    Cincinnati General Hospital, and went on to completed his residency at
                    Cincinnati Children's Hospital in 1929. Nelson subsequently joined the
                    Cincinnati Children's Hospital's medical staff. In 1940, he moved to
                    Philadelphia where he served as the chairman of the department of pediatrics at
                    Temple University and the medical director of St. Christopher's Hospital. Nelson
                    was the author of the Nelson Textbook of Pediatrics and was the editor of The
                    Journal of Pediatrics from 1959 through 1978.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Waldo Emerson Nelson papers contain a variety of materials relating to
                    Emerson's professional career. The collection includes an oral history taken by
                    the American Academy of Pediatrics. There are transcripts of speeches from the
                    1940s to the mid-1960s, as well as post-retirement visits and speeches. Topics
                    covered in the speeches include pediatrics, fluid therapy, cerebral palsy and
                    infectious diseases. Some film and glass slides that accompanied his talks are
                    present. The collection also includes material relating to his Nelson Textbook
                    of Pediatrics, such as correspondence with editors, clippings of notices,
                    reviews of the textbook and a history of the textbook by Nelson. Correspondence
                    relating to the Journal of Pediatrics, and files regarding his work at Temple
                    and St. Christopher's hospitals are present. Other types of materials include
                    awards; research on diabetes such as charts, photographs of patients, and
                    research findings; a small amount of research on tuberculosis and low birth
                    weight; reprints; and medical school notes.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Jane Nelson Beatty</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1998</p>
                <p>Accession number: 1998-008</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>