<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William N. Bradley papers <date type="inclusive">1894-1962</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>College of Physicians of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William N. Bradley papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CoPSp.ACC505</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">College of Physicians of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1894-1962</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Nathaniel Bradley (1871-1962) was a Philadelphia pediatrician. He
                    graduated from the Philadelphia College of Pharmacy in 1892, and received an
                    M.D. from the University of Pennsylvania in 1894. Bradley taught Histology (from
                    1894-1896) and pediatrics (from 1910-1912) at Jefferson Medical College. In
                    1896, he became the chief of the Children's Clinic at the South Eastern
                    Dispensary. In 1909, Bradley was appointed Medical Director of the Starr Center
                    Association. He also worked as assistant physician in the outpatient departments
                    at Pennsylvania Hospital and Philadelphia Orthopaedic Hospital (1909-1911). He
                    served as Pediatrist at Children's Hospital of Philadelphia from 1912 to 1915.
                    From 1915 to 1929, Bradley had charge of the pediatric department at Howard
                    Hospital. He also was instrumental in the establishment of Babies' Hospital of
                    Philadelphia in 1911. From 1912-1926 he taught pediatrics at the School of
                    Medicine of the University of Pennsylvania, and from 1917 to 1946, he worked on
                    the pediatric staff at Philadelphia General Hospital. Bradley also taught at the
                    Graduate School of Medicine of the University of Pennsylvania (1921 to 1946). He
                    served as consulting pediatrist to the Municipal Hospital for Contagious
                    Diseases (1936-1946) and Wills Eye Hospital (1932-1945). Bradley retired from
                    active practice in 1955.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of 17 scrapbooks (some disbound) containing
                    correspondence and reports, 1907-1962. Materials include: correspondence with
                    colleagues about referrals and consultations; letters related to meetings of the
                    Philadelphia Pediatric Society and other professional societies; invitations and
                    programs from meetings; letters regarding papers submitted to [MSSP] section of
                    Pediatrics; acknowledgments of reprints; letters of appointment; and letters of
                    recommendation. Also included are one folder of reprints; correspondence and
                    research material (clippings, notes, reprints) for "Philadelphia physicians in
                    art," 1945-1961, and a scrapbook of portraits of notable physicians
                    (photographs, engravings, clippings); and loose photographs and cabinet cards
                    with portraits of physicians, along with invitations and programs.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of William N. Bradley, Mrs. Burlingame Harvey, and Mrs. Carl
                    Anderson. 1991-064 was transferred by the Mutter Museum in 1991.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1961, 1984</p>
                <p>Accession number: 1991-064 and 1993-045</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia: William N. Bradley radio broadcasts, addresses, and other
                    writings (MSS 2/0008-01).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>