<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Agnes Michels papers <date type="inclusive">1916-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Agnes Michels papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1352</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Agnes Kirsopp Lake Michels (1909-1993) was a leading twentieth century scholar of
                    Roman religion and daily life and a daughter of the Biblical scholar Kirsopp
                    Lake (1872-1946). Michels earned her bachelor's, master's, and doctoral degrees
                    in Latin from Bryn Mawr College, where she was also a member of the faculty from
                    1934 until 1975. After her retirement she frequently taught courses at Duke
                    University as well as at the University of North Carolina. Michels Calendar of
                    the Roman Republic is still consulted by scholars as a work of authority.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the professional and personal papers of Agnes
                    Michels. Materials include: research notes; drafts and manuscripts of books and
                    other publications; correspondence and minutes from the American Philological
                    Association; minutes from Bryn Mawr's Admissions and Curriculum Committees;
                    teaching and lecture notes for courses in the history of religion and Latin;
                    correspondence with students, colleagues, and family; and offprints. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>