<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Andrew Henry Woods papers <date type="inclusive">1885-1956</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Andrew Henry Woods papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1447</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1885-1956</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Andrew Henry Woods (1872-1956) was a physician and psychiatrist. In 1899 he went
                    to China to help found the medical department of Canton Christian College (later
                    Lingnan University). His wife was Fanny Soutter Sinclair who graduated from Bryn
                    Mawr College in 1901. They were married in 1902. Woods was the first head of the
                    Department of Neurology at Peking Union Medical College and at the Iowa State
                    Psychopathic Hospital and Department of Psychiatry at University of Iowa.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the papers of Andrew Henry Woods and his family.
                    Materials include: diaries and journals (1885-1956); correspondence; photo
                    albums, photographs, and postcards from Woods' time in China; drawings and
                    photographs created by Margaret Woods; a travel journal and photographs of Tom
                    S. Woods; family correspondence of Fanny Sinclair Woods; reprints of articles by
                    Andrew Woods; clippings and medical journals from Woods's work in Iowa
                    hospitals; and miscellaneous diplomas and certificates.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>