<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Caroline McCormick Slade papers <date type="inclusive">1917-1951</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Caroline McCormick Slade papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1392</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1917-1951</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Caroline McCormick Slade (1874-1951) attended Bryn Mawr College as a graduate
                    student in history and political science from 1892-1894. She was active in the
                    women's suffrage movement, politics, and philanthropy. She was chairman of the
                    Women's Division of the War Personnel Board of the YMCA (1917-1919), one of the
                    founders of the League of Women Voters, Campaign Chairman of the National
                    Woman's Committee for the Election of Herbert Hoover in 1928, and Vice-Chairman
                    of the United Service Organizations during World War II. She was National
                    Chairman of the Bryn Mawr Endowment Fund Campaign and served on the college's
                    Board of Directors for more than 30 years.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of scrapbooks of Caroline McCormick Slade. Scrapbooks
                    contain newspaper clippings, letters, telegrams, announcements, and programs
                    related to her political work and her philanthropic endeavors. Notable
                    correspondents include Herbert Hoover and Carrie Chapman Catt. The collection
                    also includes a small batch of congratulatory letters for her work on the
                    Endowment Fund Campaign.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>