<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Carrie Chapman Catt papers <date type="inclusive">1890-1963</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1905-1945</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Carrie Chapman Catt papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1455</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1890-1963</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1905-1945</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Carrie Lane Chapman Catt (1859-1947) was an internationally recognized
                    suffragist, feminist, and political activist. She served two terms as President
                    of the National American Woman Suffrage Association, and is credited with
                    revitalizing the NAWSA during the struggle for passage of the nineteenth federal
                    amendment granting suffrage to women. Catt founded the International Woman
                    Suffrage Alliance in 1902 (later the International Alliance of Women) and served
                    as its president for many years. She formed the League of Women Voters in 1920
                    and was its honorary president until her death in 1947. In 1925, Catt founded
                    the National Committee on the Cause and Cure of War. During the 1930s and 1940s,
                    Catt was active in working against the Nazis, particularly their persecution of
                    Jews. Although she was a champion of world peace, Catt was a vocal supporter of
                    the Allied Forces during World War II.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of papers of Carrie Chapman Catt. Materials include:
                    correspondence; speeches and lectures; scrapbooks; suffrage cartoons (c.
                    1915-1920); newspaper clippings (1909-1943); articles by notable suffragists,
                    such as the British playwright Laurence Housman; and suffrage ephemera.
                    Correspondents include Susan B. Anthony's niece, Lucy Anthony, and Woodrow
                    Wilson. Speeches include an address entitled "A League of Nations," an address
                    at the Democratic National Convention in Philadelphia in 1912, and talks given
                    at the Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences (1905) and Bryn Mawr College
                    (1921). </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Manuscript Division,
                    Library of Congress: Papers of Carrie Chapman Catt; New York Public Library:
                    Carrie Chapman Catt papers; Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College: Carrie
                    Chapman Catt papers; Special Collections Department, Iowa State University:
                    Carrie Chapman Catt papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>