<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charles J. Rhoads papers <date type="inclusive">1916-1960</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charles J. Rhoads papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1346</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1960</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles James Rhoads (1872-1956) worked in the Banking Department of the Girard
                    Trust Company. He was the first governor of the Federal Reserve Bank in
                    Philadelphia. His association with Bryn Mawr College began in 1907 when he was
                    elected a Member of the Trustees and later in 1936 became President of the
                    Trustees and Chairman of the Board of Directors. He held both offices until his
                    death. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the papers of Charles Rhoads. Materials include
                    minutes of the Board of Trustees, financial statements, records relating to the
                    selection of Katharine McBride as President of Bryn Mawr, records concerning the
                    building of Rhoads Hall, and correspondence among members of the Board of
                    Trustees. Notable correspondence includes a series of letters on the "faculty
                    rebellion" of 1916 which arose after a professor was fired without the Board's
                    input.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Bryn Mawr College:
                    Bryn Mawr College Board of Trustees records; American Philosophical Society:
                    Charles James Rhoads papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>