<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Doris Hastings Darnell papers <date type="inclusive">1926-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Doris Hastings Darnell papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1432</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>30.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1926-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Doris Hastings Darnell (b. 1916) and May Shanfeng Chow were both 1939 graduates
                    of Bryn Mawr College. Darnell was a librarian at the Westtown School Library,
                    also working briefly at Bryn Mawr and Haverford. She worked for the American
                    Friends Service Committee in the personnel department from 1964 to 1978. May
                    Chow returned to China after graduating from Bryn Mawr. She was an English
                    teacher. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the papers of Doris Darnell. Materials include
                    correspondence, family photographs, school records, documents relating to her
                    jobs at the Bryn Mawr, Haverford, the Westtown School libraries, financial
                    records, documents relating to her work in the Personnel Department of the
                    American Friends Service Committee, correspondence from her children, Betts,
                    John, and Eric, and travel journals and photographs. Of note is her sixty-year
                    correspondence with May Chow, a fellow Bryn Mawr graduate. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>