<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Dorothy Burr Thompson papers <date type="inclusive">1926-1990</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1950-1970</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Dorothy Burr Thompson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1476</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1926-1990</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1950-1970</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dorothy Burr Thompson (1900-2001) was a prominent archaeologist and authority on
                    Hellenistic terra cotta figurines. She received two degrees from Bryn Mawr
                    College: a bachelor's degree, the College's first in Greek and archaeology, in
                    1923, and a Ph.D. in 1931. She studied at the American School of Classical
                    Studies in Athens and was the first woman appointed a Fellow of the Athenian
                    Agora excavations. In 1936, she unearthed and identified, in the Agora, the
                    garden of the Temple of Hepaistos. She taught at colleges and universities
                    including Bryn Mawr, Princeton University and the University of Pennsylvania and
                    published more than 50 scholarly papers and books.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the professional papers of Dorothy Burr Thompson.
                    Materials include correspondence, articles and reviews, lecture notes,
                    photographs, and postcards. The collection also includes a series of notebooks
                    on archaeological artifacts and sites. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>