<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Elizabeth Aiken Freund papers <date type="inclusive">1933-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Elizabeth Aiken Freund papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1425</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1933-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Elizabeth Aiken Freund graduated from Bryn Mawr in 1939. She received her
                    master's degree in City Planning from the University of Pennsylvania in 1956.
                    She worked for many years with the New York City Housing Authority, helping to
                    organize a union there. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the papers of Elizabeth Freund. Materials include:
                    notes and letters from Freund's time at Aberdeen Camp, an American Friends
                    Service Committee resettlement camp for war refugees in the 1930s;
                    correspondence relating to Hilda Worthington Smith's autobiography, which Freund
                    helped edit; a transcription of interviews on a planned oral history of worker's
                    education in the United States; and notes and drafts of Walter Baumgartel's Up
                    Among the Mountain Gorillas (1976), which Freund helped him edit. The Baumgartel
                    materials also include copies of Baumgartel's correspondence with Dian Fossey,
                    as well as correspondence between Baumgartel and Freund. The collection also
                    contains a thesis by Gene Bruce Milgram on New York's "Scatter-site" public
                    housing program and a series of audiotape recordings of Freund, Hilda Smith, and
                    Walter Baumgartel.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Bryn Mawr College:
                    Hilda Worthington Smith papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>