<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Emily Grace Kazakevich papers <date type="inclusive">1935-1989</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Emily Grace Kazakevich papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1426</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1935-1989</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Emily Grace was a graduate of Bryn Mawr College, receiving her BA in 1933 and her
                    master's in 1934. She received a doctorate from Yale on the literary sources for
                    the history of Sparta in the 3rd century BC. In 1949 she and her husband,
                    Vladimir Kazakevich, moved to Moscow, where she worked for the Institute of
                    Ancient History at the Academy of Sciences of the USSR, and continued her own
                    work on 4th and 5th century Greek law. She returned to the US in 1986 and took a
                    fellowship at Bryn Mawr. She died in 1987.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of an unpublished manuscript and notes for a monograph
                    entitled "The non-citizen offenser in attic and platonic Homicide Law" written
                    by Emily Grace. The work is in English and Russian. The papers include: index
                    card research notes in Greek, English, Russian, and German; manuscript chapters
                    with annotations; and correspondence with other scholars. The collection also
                    contains English and Russian reprints of Grace's articles, correspondence with
                    family, and a small collection of correspondence between Virginia Grace and
                    Michael Jameson about Grace's work.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>