<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Emmy Noether collection <date type="inclusive">1927-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Emmy Noether collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1281</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1927-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Amalie Emmy Noether (1882-1935) was a German-born, Jewish mathematician,
                    described by Albert Einstein at the time of her death as "the most significant
                    creative mathematical genius thus far produced since the higher education of
                    women began." She was known for her important, and controversial, work in
                    abstract algebra and number theory. Although she was a highly regarded scholar
                    and teacher, Noether's academic career in Germany was hampered by sexism and
                    racism. She fled to the United States in 1933 to escape a Nazi edict which
                    prohibited her from teaching. She joined the faculty at Bryn Mawr College with
                    assistance from the Emergency Committee to Aid Displaced German Scholars, but
                    died two years after her arrival in the United States.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of documents related to Emmy Noether. Materials include:
                    letters from Noether to R. Brauer in German (1927-1934); English translations of
                    those letters; correspondence regarding Noether's appointment at Bryn Mawr;
                    correspondence about a memorial service for Noether; bibliographies of Noether's
                    collection of reprints; and books and reprints on Noether's contributions to
                    mathematics. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>