<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Florence Bascom papers <date type="inclusive">1897-1937</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Florence Bascom papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC890</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1897-1937</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Florence Bascom (1862-1945) was an educator and geological survey scientist who
                    is considered to be the first American woman geologist. Bascom earned bachelor's
                    and master's degrees at the University of Wisconsin, and in 1893, she became the
                    first woman to receive a Ph.D. from Johns Hopkins University. Bascom taught at
                    Ohio State University from 1893 to 1895 before joining the faculty of Bryn Mawr
                    College, where she founded the geology department. Under her direction, the
                    department gained a national reputation. In 1896 Bascom was named assistant
                    geologist with the U.S. Geological Survey—the first woman ever to receive that
                    appointment. Her work on the Mid-Atlantic Piedmont region led to the
                    contributions for which she is best known—U.S. Geological Survey Folios on
                    Philadelphia (1909), Trenton (1909), Elkton-Wilmington (1920),
                    Quakertown-Doylestown (1931), and Honeybrook-Phoenixville (1938). Bascom also
                    wrote some 40 scientific articles on genetic petrography, geomorphology, and
                    gravels.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the professional papers of Florence Bascom. Materials
                    include incoming and outgoing correspondence, largely related to Bascom's work
                    with the U.S. Geological Survey; field notebooks, laboratory notes, maps,
                    photographs, drawings; manuscripts and reprints; and correspondence between
                    Dorothy Wyckoff and Howard Meyerhoff regarding the USGS scientific survey of
                    Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 80-1</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Sophia Smith
                    Collection, Smith College: Florence Bascom papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>