<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Harris Wofford papers <date type="inclusive">1957-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Harris Wofford papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1478</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>540 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1957-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Harris Wofford (b. 1926) is a politician, academic administrator and lawyer.
                    After serving in the United States Air Force from 1944-1945, he received his AB
                    from the University of Chicago in 1948. He received law degrees from both Yale
                    and Howard Universities. From 1954-1958 he practiced law with the Washington
                    firm of Covington and Burling. He taught law from 1959-1961 at Notre Dame Law
                    School. From 1958-1959, he was counsel to Reverend Theodore Hesburgh on the U.S.
                    Commission on Civil Rights. In 1959 Wofford joined Senator John Kennedy's
                    pre-convention campaign and organized and coordinated the new Civil Rights
                    Section of the presidential campaign. After the election, as Special Assistant
                    to President Kennedy, he served on a new sub-cabinet Group on Civil Rights. He
                    also sat on the task force which helped organize the Peace Corps and during the
                    years 1964-1966 was Associate Director of the organization. He was a member of
                    President Johnson's 1965 Smithsonian Task Force that prepared the President's
                    proposals for the International Education Act. Wofford was President of the
                    State University of New York's College at Old Westbury from 1966-1970 and then
                    President of Bryn Mawr College from 1970 to 1978. After his tenure at Bryn Mawr,
                    Wofford served as Pennsylvania's Secretary of Labor and Industry, where he
                    established and led the Pennsylvania Office of Citizen Service. From 1991-1994
                    Wofford served as a United States Senator from Pennsylvania. After leaving
                    office, he served as CEO of the Corporation of National Service.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes papers, books and videotapes. The bulk is devoted to
                    Wofford's campaigns for election and his papers from his term as a U.S. Senator
                    for Pennsylvania. A large collection of videotapes documents his second,
                    unsuccessful campaign for election against Republican Rick Santorum. Additional
                    material includes several book-length manuscripts, papers from his work as
                    Pennsylvania Secretary of Labor and Industry, and various papers and manuscripts
                    relating to his work in the fields of national service, civil rights, the Peace
                    Corps, and African and international development. Wofford's political papers
                    complement the papers from his tenure as President of Bryn Mawr College, also
                    held by the Bryn Mawr College Library.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Bryn Mawr College:
                    Harris Wofford presidential papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>