<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Helen Chapin papers <date type="inclusive">1915-1949</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Helen Chapin papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC868</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1915-1949</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Helen Burwell Chapin (1892-1950) attended Bryn Mawr College, graduating in 1915.
                    She was an expert in Asian art. Her interest in Chinese art began when she
                    worked in the Oriental Department of the Boston Museum of Fine Arts from 1917 to
                    1924 and again from 1928 to 1929. She learned Chinese and began to travel to
                    China, working for a time for the American Consulate in Shanghai. She also
                    studied at the Tokyo Imperial Museum and the Toyo Bunko Library and studied
                    Buddhist relics and temples in Korea. She received her master's degree from
                    Mills College in 1935 and her Ph.D. from the University of California in 1940.
                    During the Second World War, she worked as a Research Analyst for the Department
                    of Justice. From 1946 to 1948 she was the Asiatic Arts and Monument Specialist
                    with the Department of the Army stationed in Korea.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Helen Chapin. Materials include:
                    correspondence with Ananda K. Coomaraswamy and his wife about Asian art and
                    Chapin's career during the 1940s; photographs of Korean and Japanese temples,
                    artworks, street scenes, landscapes, and people; notes on the architecture of
                    various Buddhist sites in Korea; and notes on Asian art and on Chapin's own
                    collection of art and books.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 75-3; 76-2</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>