<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Helen Taft Manning papers <date type="inclusive">1869-1983</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1915-1983</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Helen Taft Manning papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC925</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1869-1983</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1915-1983</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Helen Herron Taft Manning (1891-1987) was the daughter of President of the United
                    States William Howard Taft and his wife Helen Herron. Taft graduated from Bryn
                    Mawr College in 1915, was named dean in 1917 and rose to acting president in
                    1919. She left to earn her doctorate at Yale, reclaiming the deanship in 1925.
                    In 1920, she married Frederick Johnson Manning, a history professor who taught
                    at Swarthmore College.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the papers of Helen Taft Manning and Frederick J.
                    Manning. Materials include: correspondence between the Mannings (1917-1966);
                    Manning family papers and records related to the William Howard Taft papers held
                    at the Library of Congress; correspondence, speeches, and other documents from
                    Helen Manning's time at Bryn Mawr College, both as a Dean and as an alumna;
                    correspondence between Helen Manning and friends and family; documents relating
                    to Helen Manning's publications; clippings; and sketches by Frederick
                    Manning.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 85-26; 95-4</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Library of Congress:
                    Papers of Helen Taft Manning and Papers of William H. Taft.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>