<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Henry Joel Cadbury papers related to the American Friends Service
                        Committee <date type="inclusive">1964-1970</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Henry Joel Cadbury papers related to the American Friends
                    Service Committee</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1413</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-1970</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henry Joel Cadbury (1883-1974) was one of the founders of the American Friends
                    Service Committee and served as its chair from 1921 to 1934 and from 1944 to
                    1960. He was professor of Biblical Literature at Bryn Mawr College from 1926 to
                    1934, and served as a trustee and director for many years. He was Chairman of
                    the Board of Directors from 1956 to 1969. He also served on the faculties of
                    Haverford and Harvard during his academic career.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes records related to the American Friends Service
                    Committee's Committee on Family Planning and Population Education. The records
                    are primarily related to a special report entitled "Who Shall Live? Man's
                    Control over Birth and Death," which was published in 1970. There are also
                    memoranda, reports, and correspondence from various family planning clinics and
                    administrators in Asia, Latin America, and Africa.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: American Friends
                    Service Committee: American Friends Service Committee archives; Haverford
                    College: Henry Joel Cadbury papers and Jones-Cadbury family papers; Friends
                    Historical Library, Swarthmore College: Henry Joel Cadbury papers; Peace
                    Collection, Swarthmore College: Henry J. Cadbury papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>