<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Hertha Kraus papers <date type="inclusive">1904-1968</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1930-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Hertha Kraus papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC854</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1904-1968</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1930-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Hertha Kraus (1897-1968) was a German-American social worker and professor of
                    social work at Bryn Mawr College. Kraus came to the United States in 1933 after
                    she was dismissed by the Nazis from her position as Director of Public Welfare
                    for the city of Cologne. In the 1930s and 1940s she was active in the refugee
                    placement programs of the American Friends Service Committee. She joined the
                    faculty of the Bryn Mawr Department of Social Economy and Social Research (later
                    the School of Social Work) in 1936. She retired in 1963.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of personal and professional correspondence and other items
                    relating to Kraus's activities as a social work educator and her involvement
                    with refugee placement programs of the American Friends Service Committee. The
                    collection includes her scholarly articles, course material notebooks, lecture
                    notes, and social work bibliographies. Also included are Kraus's school records
                    and a copy of her dissertation.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 70-8</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>