<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Hobson Pittman papers <date type="inclusive">1929-1988</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Hobson Pittman papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1439</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.85 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1929-1988</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Hobson Pittman (1899-1972) grew up in North Carolina and moved to Pennsylvania
                    when he was 18. He attended Pennsylvania State College, studied at the Carnegie
                    Institute of Technology, and for a number of years spent his summers at the art
                    colony in Woodstock, New York. He was made director of art at the Friends
                    Central Day School near Philadelphia in 1931, taught in the summer school at the
                    Pennsylvania State University from 1932 to 1965, and, in 1949, became a member
                    of the faculty at the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts. A painter as well
                    as a teacher, Pittman won numerous prizes and awards for his art and his
                    paintings hang in many museums, including the Metropolitan Museum of Art, the
                    Whitney Museum of American Art, and the North Carolina Museum of Art.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the scrapbooks and correspondence of Hobson Pittman
                    (1929-1966) and papers related to the Hobson Pittman estate and the Friends of
                    the Hobson Pittman House (1979-1989). The scrapbooks include newspaper
                    clippings, magazine articles, and brochures for exhibitions. Correspondence is
                    with friends and family, students, galleries, and art dealers. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Bryn Mawr College
                    Collections holds some of Pittman's paintings.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>