<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James Hanley papers <date type="inclusive">1971-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James Hanley papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1445</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.125 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James Hanley (1901-1985) was a British novelist. Born in Dublin, he went to sea
                    at a young age, joining the Canadian Expeditionary Forces during World War I.
                    His early writing focused on the lives of men who work on the sea. His novels
                    were critically acclaimed, but most of them did not sell very well. Frank
                    Harrington was a book collector who collected Hanley's works and corresponded
                    extensively with the author. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of correspondence and manuscripts of James Hanley,
                    collected by Frank Harrington. Many of the letters are between Hanley and
                    Harrington, written primarily in the 1970s and 1980s. This correspondence
                    relates to the publication of Hanley's works, his life in Great Britain, his
                    family, and the authors and poets that he enjoys reading. There is additional
                    correspondence between Hanley and Sven Tackmark about the publication of
                    Hanley's works and production of a play in Scandinavia, and correspondence from
                    Harrington about his collection of Hanley's works as well as of other writers.
                    The collection also includes reviews of Hanley's books, photographs, a
                    biographical essay on Hanley, and clippings. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: National Library of
                    Wales, Aberystwyth: James Hanley papers; Senate House Library, University of
                    London: James Hanley collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>