<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Jean Scobie Davis papers <date type="inclusive">1907-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Jean Scobie Davis papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1316</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>9 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1907-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Jean Scobie Davis (1892-1985) graduated from Bryn Mawr College in 1914. She
                    received her master's degree in 1921 from the University of Wisconsin. That
                    summer she was a tutor in Economics at the first session of the Bryn Mawr Summer
                    School for Women Workers in Industry. Over the course of her long career she
                    taught at several colleges including Agnes Scott College, Vassar, Pierce, Wells,
                    and the American Women's College in Beirut. She retired in 1957. Davis had a
                    lifelong interest in prison reform, and was a member of the Board of Visitors of
                    the New York State Correctional Facility in Bedford Hills, New York, for 36
                    years.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the diaries and papers of Jean Scobie Davis. Davis kept
                    daily diaries from 1911 to 1984. She also kept travel journals and a few
                    scrapbooks. This collection also includes: family histories compiled by Davis;
                    autobiographical notes; correspondence with family and friends; photo albums;
                    and records of her work with women's prison and reformatories for teenagers.
                </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>