<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Josephine and Pauline Goldmark papers <date type="inclusive">1930-1974</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Josephine and Pauline Goldmark papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1482</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1930-1974</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Pauline (1874-1962) and Josephine Goldmark (1877-1950 ) were both graduates of
                    Bryn Mawr College (1869 and 1898, respectively). Pauline Goldmark was a social
                    worker and Progressive reformer, focusing her attention on the research which
                    underlay the policies and programs of social reformers. Josephine Goldmark
                    volunteered at the National Consumers' League and served as publications
                    secretary (1903) and as chair of its committee on the legal defense of labor
                    laws. Pauline and Josephine, along with Frances Kelly, helped to research and
                    write the so-called Brandeis Brief, which the Goldmarks's brother-in-law, Louis
                    Brandeis, used to support protective laws for women workers.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence between the Goldmark sisters and their
                    cousins Evelyn and George Openhym. Also included are several letters from Henry
                    Goldmark, a video of Dr. Peter Goldmark receiving the Trustees Award from the
                    National Television Academy in 1974, and a copy of Nancy Woloch's Muller v.
                    Oregon, a book about the legal case for which Josephine Goldmark did extensive
                    research.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Schlesinger Library,
                    Harvard University: Josephine Clara and Pauline Dorothea Goldmark papers. </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>