<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Katharine McBride papers <date type="inclusive">1924-1976</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Katharine McBride papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1419</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1924-1976</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Katharine McBride (1904-1976) was a 1925 graduate of Bryn Mawr College. She was a
                    researcher in psychology, working with Dr. Theodore Weisenburg. She taught at
                    Bryn Mawr from 1935 to 1940, leaving to become a dean at Radcliffe College. In
                    1942, she was appointed President of Bryn Mawr College. She remained in this
                    post until 1970. In 1952 she was elected the first woman Trustee of the
                    University of Pennsylvania.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection is grouped into six sections. Personal research and
                    correspondence materials include: school records, speeches, notes from McBride's
                    committee activities, and bound typescripts of McBride's "A Psychological Study
                    of Aphasia." President's Office administrative files include: Presidents'
                    Reports, Tri-College Cooperation records, and records from departments within
                    Bryn Mawr. President's Office outgoing correspondence consists of letters sent
                    from McBride's office between 1951 and 1957. Trusteeships and non-Bryn Mawr
                    committee records include: correspondence, reports, minutes, and newsletters
                    from various committees on which McBride served, including the President's
                    Committee on Education Beyond High School, the National Science Foundation, and
                    the Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange Between East and West.
                    Financial records, covering the period 1946-1955, include: budgets,
                    scholarships, and faculty salaries. This section of the collection also includes
                    records on student attendance, honors, and financial aid. Grant materials
                    include documentation of awards and grants to the college and compliance with
                    governmental regulations for the period 1956 to 1970. The McBride collection
                    also includes materials relating to the establishment of the Graduate School of
                    Social Work and Social Research as a separate division of College.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Bryn Mawr College:
                    Alice Gore King scrapbooks and Edie McGrath office files.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>