<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Lily Ross Taylor papers <date type="inclusive">1916-1972</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Lily Ross Taylor papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC864</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1972</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Lily Ross Taylor (1886-1969) was professor of Latin and chair of the department
                    at Bryn Mawr College from 1927 to 1952. She was named Dean of the Graduate
                    School in 1942. Prior to teaching at Bryn Mawr, she had served on the faculty of
                    Vassar College and was the first female Fellow of the American Academy in Rome.
                    She earned both her master's degree and doctorate in Latin from Bryn Mawr. After
                    her retirement in 1952, she remained active as professor in charge of the
                    Classical School of the American Academy in Rome, Phi Beta Kappa Visiting
                    Scholar, visiting professor in various universities, and Member at the Institute
                    for Advanced Study in Princeton.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the professional and private papers of Lily Ross
                    Taylor. Materials include: lectures; notes, drafts, and manuscripts of articles,
                    reviews, and other writings; correspondence with professional organizations,
                    fellow scholars, and editors; correspondence related to the Friends of the
                    Library of the American Academy in Rome; Taylor's letter of appointment to Bryn
                    Mawr; documentation of honors and awards; newspaper clippings; bibliographies of
                    Taylor's publications; Latin exams and student translations from Vassar; and
                    letters of sympathy received by Agnes K. Michels upon Taylor's death.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 74-5</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>