<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Lucy Shoe Meritt papers <date type="inclusive">1898-2003</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1920s-1980s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Lucy Shoe Meritt papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1297</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>23 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1898-2003</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1920s-1980s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Lucy Taxis Shoe Meritt (1906-2003) was an archeologist, scholar, teacher, and
                    editor. She received her bachelor's degree from Bryn Mawr College in 1927, her
                    master's in 1928 and her doctorate in 1935. From 1929 to 1934, she studied at
                    the American School of Classical Studies in Athens. During those years she
                    visited many classical sites in Greece and Asia Minor and made the drawings of
                    the mouldings that appeared in her book, Profiles of Greek Mouldings, published
                    in 1936. She taught at Mount Holyoke College from 1937-1950. As a Fellow at the
                    American Academy in Rome in 1937 and 1950, she investigated architectural
                    mouldings in Italy. Her research was later published in two volumes, Profiles of
                    Western Greek Mouldings (1952) and Etruscan and Republican Roman Mouldings
                    (1965). When the American School of Classical Studies in Athens established a
                    publications office at Princeton, she was named Editor of Publications, a post
                    she held from 1950-1972. In 1972 Dr. Meritt returned to the family home in
                    Austin, Texas and was a Visiting Scholar in the Department of Classics at the
                    University of Texas at Austin from 1973 until her death.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the personal and professional papers of Lucy T. Shoe
                    Meritt, dating from 1898 to 2003. Records include: correspondence with family
                    members, other scholars and personal friends, including Rhys Carpenter, Homer A.
                    Thompson, Francis Henry Bacon, Katherine Donaldson and Dorothy Kent Hill;
                    publications, reviews, and lectures; records from her work at the American
                    School of Classical Studies at Athens; high school and college notebooks,
                    academic reports, and diplomas; photographs of family members, colleagues,
                    architectural sites, and artifacts; and diaries and travel journals.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Alexander
                    Architectural Archive, University of Texas at Austin: Lucy Shoe Meritt
                    collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>