<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>M. Carey Thomas estate papers <date type="inclusive">1913-1967</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1935-1938</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">M. Carey Thomas estate papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1418</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1913-1967</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1935-1938</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Martha Carey Thomas (1857-1935) received her bachelor's degree from Cornell
                    University in 1877. She did graduate work at Johns Hopkins University, the
                    University of Leipzig, and the University of Zurich where she earned a Ph.D. in
                    linguistics, in 1882. In 1884, Thomas became dean of the college and chair of
                    English at the new Bryn Mawr College for women. In 1894, the first president of
                    the college, James Rhoads, retired, and Thomas was narrowly elected to succeed
                    him. She was president until 1922 and remained as Dean until 1908. In 1908, she
                    became the first president of the National College Women's Equal Suffrage
                    League. She was also a leading member of the National American Woman Suffrage
                    Association. After 1920 she advocated the policies of the National Woman's
                    Party. She was one of the early promoters of an equal rights amendment to the
                    U.S. Constitution. Thomas lived for many years in a close relationship with her
                    friend and housemate Mamie Gwinn. After Gwinn left Thomas in 1904 to marry,
                    Thomas took up housekeeping with the philanthropist Mary Garrett, with whom
                    Thomas shared the campus home, living together until Garrett's death. Thomas
                    died in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. She is buried on the Bryn Mawr College
                    campus in the cloisters of the Thomas Library.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection includes documents pertinent to the settlement of M. Carey
                    Thomas's estate. In addition, there are accounts and other records relative to
                    the estates of Mary E. Garrett and Edith Lowber, Garrett County, Maryland,
                    properties, and to the Thomas family summer cottage, Coombe Edge.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Bryn Mawr College: M.
                    Carey Thomas papers and Mary E. Garrett papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>