<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Martha C. Johnson papers <date type="inclusive">1957-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Martha C. Johnson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1317</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1957-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Martha C. Johnson (d. 1988) was the manager of the Francis Scott Key Book Shop in
                    Georgetown, Virginia, and was a partner in the literary agency Johnson and
                    Thompson Authors' Representatives in Washington D.C. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of Johnson's records from her time at the Johnson and
                    Thompson agency and files from the Francis Scott Key Book Shop. Records from the
                    Johnson and Thompson agency include correspondence with authors and publishers;
                    manuscripts and galleys of books; clippings; a large scrapbook of publicity
                    material for Carp's Washington, the first book placed by the Johnson and
                    Thompson agency; financial records; and administrative documents, such as phone
                    lists of authors and publishers and a register of royalty payments. Records from
                    the book shop include customer orders, publicity materials about the shop,
                    financial records, photographs of the store, authors, and customers, sales
                    catalogs, and other ephemera.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>