<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Mary Helen Wingate Lloyd theater scrapbooks <date type="inclusive">1874-1930</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Mary Helen Wingate Lloyd theater scrapbooks</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1301</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1874-1930</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Mary Helen Wingate Lloyd (1868-1934) was an expert gardener and director of the
                    Garden Club of America from 1928-1933. She was an organizer and charter member
                    of American Iris Society, and was also active in the Pennsylvania Horticultural
                    Society. As a young woman, she was active in arts and horticultural
                    organizations and was interested in the cause of woman's suffrage. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of 20 scrapbooks of theatrical, musical, and sporting
                    events. Each scrapbook contains theater programs, playbills, announcements and
                    actor profiles. Theaters from New York and Philadelphia are well represented,
                    but there are also materials for other American and some European cities. Other
                    forms of entertainment are also well represented, including: football score
                    cards and programs; church bulletins; and programs for recitals, concerts,
                    readings and memorial services. In addition the volumes include several Bryn
                    Mawr May Day programs and playbills. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>