<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Mary Ritter Beard collection on women in politics in Japan after
                        World War II <date type="inclusive">1946-1951</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Mary Ritter Beard collection on women in politics in Japan
                    after World War II</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1452</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1946-1951</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Mary Ritter Beard (1876-1958) was an historian and a campaigner for women's
                    suffrage. She was the author of Women's Work in Municipalities (1915), A Short
                    History of the American Labor Movement (1921), On Understanding Women (1931),
                    America Through Women's Eyes (1933), and Women as Force in History (1946), among
                    other publications. She also collaborated with her husband, economic historian
                    Charles A. Beard, to produce The Rise of American Civilization (1927), a
                    celebrated two-volume history of the United States. Ethel B. Weed, a lieutenant
                    in the Supreme Commander of the Allied Forces Civil Information and Education
                    Office in Japan, provided research assistance to Beard for a proposed book on
                    Japanese women's history.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of documentation Beard and Weed compiled on the
                    activities of women in politics in Japan after World War II. Materials include
                    reports from the General Headquarters of the Supreme Commander of the Allied
                    Forces: Civil Information and Education Section on the women's bureaus of
                    Japan's political parties and on the individual elected women members of Japan's
                    Diet. Activities of a group of these politicians, under the name the Women's
                    Representatives Club, are documented in reports and newspaper articles. The
                    collection also includes a series of statements by and interviews of various
                    Japanese women on the subject of women's involvement in politics.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Sophia Smith
                    Collection, Smith College: Mary Ritter Beard papers; Depauw University: Charles
                    &amp; Mary Beard Papers 1874-1976.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>