<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Maurine La Barre papers <date type="inclusive">1863-1989</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1930s-1970s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Maurine La Barre papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1331</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1863-1989</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1930s-1970s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Maurine Boie (1907-1991) received her master's degree in social work from Bryn
                    Mawr in 1934, and taught and practiced social work in New York, Pennsylvania,
                    and North Carolina. During the late 1930s and early 1940s, she was
                    editor-in-chief of the The Family, the journal of the Family Welfare Association
                    of America in New York City, and in 1943 she wrote New York City's Baby Book,
                    which was given to every new mother in the city. In 1939, Boie married
                    anthropologist Weston La Barre. They moved to Durham, North Carolina, in 1946 in
                    order for Weston to accept a faculty position at Duke University. There Maurine
                    helped start the Durham Child Guidance Clinic and founded the Durham School for
                    Pregnant School Girls. In 1960, Maurine was appointed assistant professor of
                    Psychiatric Social Work at Duke University, and in 1971 she returned to
                    psychiatric social work at the Duke University Medical Center.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the personal and professional papers of Maurine Boie
                    La Barre. Included are publications, personal journals, family photographs,
                    notes on the development of her children, correspondence, a scrapbook of family
                    history, and clippings. Correspondence includes letters home from Bryn Mawr,
                    letters to Weston La Barre, and letters to her twin sister, Mildred.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Sophia Smith
                    Collection, Smith College: Mildred Louise Boie Saunders papers (MS 247); Duke
                    University: Weston La Barre papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>