<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Milton C. Nahm papers <date type="inclusive">1906-1990</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Milton C. Nahm papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1032</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1906-1990</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Milton Charles Nahm (1903-1991) joined the philosophy faculty of Bryn Mawr
                    College in 1930. He was named a professor in 1945 and served as chair of the
                    Department of Philosophy from 1946 to 1970, when he retired and was named
                    professor emeritus. In 1970 he became Leslie Clark Professor in the Humanities.
                    Nahm received undergraduate and graduate degrees (including a Ph.D. in 1933) at
                    the University of Pennsylvania and two additional undergraduate degrees at
                    Oxford University, England, which he attended as a Rhodes Scholar. He was the
                    author of five books, including Selections from Early Greek Philosophy.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Milton and Elinor Nahm. Included are
                    personal and professional correspondence; drafts and reprints of articles;
                    published and unpublished manuscripts; legal and financial documents; awards and
                    diplomas; photographs; materials related to the Owl Bookshop; journals kept by
                    Elinor Nahm's parents, and scrapbooks of class notes and articles from the Bryn
                    Mawr Alumnae Bulletin, 1928-1978. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 91-35</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>