<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Olivia Stokes Hatch papers <date type="inclusive">1874-1983</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Olivia Stokes Hatch papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1437</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1874-1983</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Olivia Stokes Hatch (1908-1983) attended Bryn Mawr College from 1925 to 1930.
                    Before her marriage in 1939 she was active in the American Red Cross and the
                    American Conferences of Social Work. After her marriage, she worked with the
                    League of Women Voters, the Race Relations Group, and the Red Cross Speaker's
                    Bureau. She traveled extensively in the United States, Africa, and Central and
                    South America.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the personal papers of Olivia Stokes Hatch. The bulk of
                    the collection consists of personal correspondence, much of it between Hatch and
                    her mother, Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes. Other correspondents include her
                    husband, John Davis Hatch, Jr., and his mother, Gethel Gregg Hatch. Another
                    portion of the collection consists of the papers of Anna V.S. Mitchell, Hatch's
                    aunt. These include letters to and from Mitchell, diaries, and miscellaneous
                    printed materials. The collection also includes photographs, invitations, and
                    calling cards.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>