<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Pennsylvania NOW records <date type="inclusive">1973-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Pennsylvania NOW records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1335</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The National Organization for Women (NOW) was founded in 1966 in Washington D.C.
                    to help achieve equality for women in all areas of life. The Pennsylvania
                    Chapter of NOW (known as Pennsylvania NOW) was formed in 1971 after many local
                    NOW chapters had already formed across the state, and in response to organizing
                    efforts to pass an Equal Rights Amendment to the Pennsylvania Constitution. As
                    of 2006, the organization has over 9000 members and 30 local chapters.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of Pennsylvania NOW from the mid-1970s to the
                    mid-1990s. Materials include subject files on a number of issues, such as
                    abortion rights, sex discrimination in insurance, the equal rights amendment,
                    AIDS, and comparable worth. The subject files include background articles and
                    research, letters to legislators, brochures and flyers, press kits and press
                    releases, and clippings. There is a small amount of administrative material for
                    Pennsylvania NOW, records of the chapter's Political Action Committee, and
                    printed materials and policy statements from the national organization.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>