<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Phebe Anna Thorne School records <date type="inclusive">1911-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Phebe Anna Thorne School records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1412</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>13 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1911-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Phebe Anna Thorne Model School of Bryn Mawr College was founded in 1910;
                    school facilities opened in 1913. Educating students ages 10 and older, the
                    school was cited by John Dewey of Columbia University as one of the "schools of
                    tomorrow," but closed in 1931. In 1952, Katharine Elizabeth McBride, then
                    president of Bryn Mawr, reopened it as a laboratory nursery school for the
                    Graduate Department of Education. The school promotes active participation of
                    parents in play-tutoring and advanced methods of child development. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records related to the two incarnations of the Phebe Anna
                    Thorne School. Materials include correspondence, student records, curricula and
                    pedagogical guides, publications, publicity materials, correspondence on
                    scholarship funding, files on various school activities and projects. There are
                    also reports from research projects conducted at the school. There is some
                    material related to Bryn Mawr students' engagement with the school. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>