<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Club of Advertising Women records <date type="inclusive">1916-1984</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Club of Advertising Women records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1448</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1984</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Philadelphia Club of Advertising Women was founded in 1916 to foster the
                    careers of women in the advertising business. The group held regular meetings,
                    sponsored courses for its members, raised funds for various philanthropic and
                    patriotic organizations, and funded scholarships, including one at the Charles
                    Morse Price School of Advertising and Journalism.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the records of the Philadelphia Club of Advertising
                    Women. Materials include minutes of the Board of Directors, Nominating
                    Committee, and dinner meetings; the bylaws and charter; membership records;
                    financial reports; copies of Adland News; programs for annual dinner dances;
                    programs and records related to the Eastern Conference of Women's Advertising
                    Clubs; scrapbooks, photographs, and ephemera. Also included are records related
                    to the association's various civic and philanthropic activities.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>