<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Queen Mary's Dolls' House collection <date type="inclusive">1922-1922</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Queen Mary's Dolls' House collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1424</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1922-1922</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Princess Marie Louise, of the British Royal Family, conceived of the idea of
                    creating a Dolls' House for Queen Mary (Consort of King George V). She asked Sir
                    Edwin Lutyens to design it and contacted numerous authors and artists to create
                    original miniature books and paintings for the Dolls' House. Rudyard Kipling
                    wrote his "If" in miniature specially for that purpose. Intended also as a
                    showcase for British craftsmanship, the dollhouse was originally exhibited at
                    the British Empire Exhibition in 1924. It is on permanent display at Windsor
                    Castle.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of letters relating to the production of miniature
                    paintings, drawings, etchings, and texts for miniature volumes for Queen Mary's
                    Dolls' House. The letters accompanied submissions for consideration by Princess
                    Marie Louise; some of the more famous artists and authors writing to the
                    princess include Bernard Partridge, Margaret Kemp Welch, Cecil Aldin, W. Heath
                    Robinson, A. E. Houseman, Henry Holiday, W. Russell Flint, Adrian Stokes, and
                    Marjorie Bowen. Drawings and paintings are not included in this collection. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>