<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rhys Carpenter papers <date type="inclusive">undated</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rhys Carpenter papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1285</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>From Wikipedia: "Rhys Carpenter (born 1889 Cotuit, Massachusetts; died January
                    2, 1980 Devon, Pennsylvania) was a classical art historian and professor at Bryn
                    Mawr College. Carpenter took his B.A. in Classics at Columbia University in
                    1909. Carpenter won a Rhodes scholarship at Oxford, studying at Balliol College.
                    There he published his own poetry and earned a second B.A. (1911) and an M.A.
                    (1914). He spent the year 1912-13 at the American School of Classical Studies in
                    Athens. The president of Bryn Mawr College, Martha Carey Thomas (1857-1935)
                    invited Carpenter to establish a department of classical archaeology at the
                    college, which he did while completing his own graduate work at Columbia
                    University; he completed his Ph.D. in 1916 with a dissertation on The Ethics of
                    Euripides. By 1918 he was already a full professor at Bryn Mawr. In 1918
                    Carpenter married Eleanor Houston Hill. In 1926 Carpenter became professor at
                    the American School of Classical Studies in Athens, and established the school's
                    journal, Hesperia in 1932. He also was instrumental in the planning of the
                    American excavations of the agora in Athens. He returned to teaching at Bryn
                    Mawr College and also delivered the Martin Classical Lectures at Oberlin
                    College, which appeared in print as The Humanistic Value of Archaeology (1933).
                    He delivered the Sather lectures in 1946 on "Folk tale, fiction, and saga in
                    the Homeric epics." He retired in 1955. In retirement he held visiting
                    professorships at the University of Pennyslvania (1960), was Andrew W. Mellon
                    professor at the University of Pittsburgh (1961-62), and visiting scholar at the
                    University of Washington (1963-64). He was awarded the Gold Medal of the
                    Archaeological Institute of America in 1969. Carpenter was unconventional as a
                    scholar. He analyzed Greek art from the standpoint of artistic production and
                    behavior. He argued for dating the Greek alphabet to the eighth century B.C.
                    Bryn Mawr College dedicated their newly built archaeology library in Carpenter's
                    name and memory in 1997."</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Teaching - Archaeology mainly publications and lectures</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>