<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Seymour Adelman collection of Thomas Eakins papers and photographs
                            <date type="inclusive">1845-1971</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1845-1938</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Seymour Adelman collection of Thomas Eakins papers and
                    photographs</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1479</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.85 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1845-1971</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1845-1938</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas Eakins (1844-1916) was a Philadelphia painter, photographer, sculptor, and
                    fine arts educator. He graduated from Central High School, studied at the
                    Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, and then in Europe 1866-1870, notably with
                    Jean-Léon Gérôme in Paris. Susan Macdowell Eakins (1851-1938) was a painter and
                    student of Eakins. They were married in 1884.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This a collection of Thomas Eakins and Susan Macdowell Eakins-related
                    photographs, correspondence, postcards and cartes de visite. Photographs
                    includes formal and informal portraits of Thomas Eakins, Susan Macdowell Eakins,
                    and Samuel Murray, as well some prints by Thomas Eakins. The collection includes
                    correspondence of John Sartain and his family, Susan Macdowell Eakins and
                    family, and Seymour Adelman and Charles Bregler. There are also postcards and
                    cartes de visites collected by Thomas Eakins during his travels in France,
                    Italy, and Spain. There are some copy prints of photographs by Thomas Eakins
                    that are in other repositories. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>