<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Speer family papers <date type="inclusive">1786-1988</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1860s-1960s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Speer family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1449</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>22 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1786-1988</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1860s-1960s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert Elliott Speer (1867-1947) was one of the leaders of the Protestant
                    missionary movement in the first half of the 20th century. In this capacity, he
                    made many trips to the Far East and to South America. His wife was Emma (Doll)
                    Bailey Speer (1872-1961). She attended Bryn Mawr College from 1890 to 1892. She
                    worked throughout her lifetime for the Young Women's Christian Association,
                    assuming the presidency of the National Board in 1915. Their daughter, Margaret
                    Bailey Speer also attended Bryn Mawr College, graduating in 1922. She was a
                    teacher, and traveled to China in 1925 as part of a Presbytarian mission to
                    teach English at the Women's College at Yenching. Upon the outbreak of war in
                    1941, she was detained by the Japanese, not returning to the United States until
                    1943. After her return she assumed the post of headmistress of the Shipley
                    School in Bryn Mawr. William McMurtrie Speer (1865-1923) was Robert Elliott
                    Speer's brother. He was a newspaperman and lawyer.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the papers of the Speer family. Materials are divided
                    into four major series for Robert Elliott Speer, Emma Bailey Speer, Margaret
                    Bailey Speer, and Robert Milton Speer. The Robert Elliott Speer papers include
                    letters to his wife and children, diairies, scrapbooks, account books, and
                    photos. This portion of the collection also includes correspondence of his
                    father, Robert Milton Speer (1838-1890), U.S. representative from Pennsylvania,
                    to family members. The Emma Bailey Speer papers include letters to her husband,
                    family and friends; diaries, talks, speeches, and notebooks, primarily
                    concerning family matters. Correspondents include Herbert Hoover, Elizabeth
                    Morrow, and John D. Rockefeller. The Margaret Bailey Speer papers chiefly
                    consists of letters (1925-1942) to her parents relating to her activities as
                    dean of the women's college at Yenching University, Peking, China. This section
                    of the collection also includes letters to other family members, and speeches
                    and talks (1943-1965) to students and other groups, given while Speer was
                    headmistress at the Shipley School. The Robert Milton Speer papers includes
                    correspondence with family members, including his parents, U.S. representative
                    Robert Milton (1838-1890) and Martha Ellen (McMurtrie) Speer; and brothers,
                    Robert Elliott (1867-1947) and Victor (1872-1905) Speer. These papers include
                    records of Robert Milton Speer's political career representing Pennsylvania
                    (1871-1875), and Victor's correspondence with family members. In addition to
                    these four major sections, the collection also includes genealogical materials
                    on the Elder family, religious pamphlets written by Emma Bailey Speer, and
                    printed articles by Margaret Bailey Speer on her work in China.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>