<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Susan Braudy papers <date type="inclusive">1941-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Susan Braudy papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1336</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1941-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Susan Orr Braudy graduated from Bryn Mawr College in 1963. She is the author of
                    Family Circle: the Boudins and the Aristocracy of the Left. Kathy Boudin (b.
                    1943) graduated from Bryn Mawr College in 1962 and is the daughter of attorney
                    Leonard Boudin who represented such controversial clients as Judith Coplon,
                    Fidel Castro, and Paul Robeson. Kathy Boudin was convicted in 1984 of felony
                    murder for her involvement in a Brinks armored car robbery, and the associated
                    killings of three people.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials gathered by Braudy for her book on the Boudin
                    family. Materials include FBI files, clippings, court transcripts, police radio
                    transcripts, and photocopies of articles. FBI files include those of Leonard
                    Boudin, Tyrone Rison, the Weathermen, Ted Gold, and Victor Rabinowitz.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>