<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Susan Kingsbury papers <date type="inclusive">1917-1949</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Susan Kingsbury papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC891</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1917-1949</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Susan Myra Kingsbury (1870-1949) was an early social welfare expert. She received
                    a bachelor's degree from the College of the Pacific in 1890, and was a history
                    teacher at Lowell High School in San Francisco (1892-1900). She received a
                    master's degree in history from Stanford University in 1899. In 1905 she
                    received a Ph.D. from Columbia University. She was a professor of economics at
                    Simmons College (1906-1915) and professor and head of the Graduate Department of
                    Social Economics and Social Research (later the School of Social Work) at Bryn
                    Mawr College (1915-1949).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the professional papers of Susan M. Kingsbury.
                    Materials include research notebooks related to studies of the conditions of
                    women workers and war relief work; correspondence related to the Study of Women
                    in Industry; incoming and outgoing departmental correspondence from Bryn's
                    Mawr's Department of Social Economics (1917-1940), including letters of
                    recommendation, advice to students and updates from students on their research
                    and academic endeavors; clippings on Kingsbury's work on the Prohibition
                    Committee; and biographical information about Kingsbury from the Public
                    Information department of Bryn Mawr College.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 80-42</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Bryn Mawr College:
                    Bryn Mawr College Graduate School of Social Work and Social Research
                    records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>