<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas Song office files <date type="inclusive">1962-1986</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas Song office files</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1322</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1962-1986</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Czetong Thomas Song was the assistant director of the Bryn Mawr College Library
                    from 1969 to 1986.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of office files from the Bryn Mawr College Library
                    director's office. Records include annual and treasurer's reports from Bryn Mawr
                    College; budgets; memoranda and minutes from various library committees; records
                    related to Tri-College library cooperation and comparative statistics for
                    college libraries; information on library catalog automation/computerization;
                    materials related to the building of Canaday Library, including correspondence,
                    architectural drawings, floor plans, and an inaugural brochure; computer program
                    operating manual; bound volumes of Data Processing Magazine for 1966-1967;
                    records of an EEOC lawsuit against Bryn Mawr College; an inventory of a
                    collection of Chinese and Korean books held by the library; and miscellaneous
                    books and administrative papers.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>