<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Zelma Corning Brandt papers <date type="inclusive">1906-1988</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Bryn Mawr College</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Zelma Corning Brandt papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">BMCSp.ACC1309</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Bryn Mawr College<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1906-1988</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Zelma Corning Brandt (1891-1990) attended Bryn Mawr College from 1909 to 1911.
                    She married Carl Brandt, of the Brandt &amp; Brandt publishing firm, where she
                    worked until 1927. After her divorce, she worked as a correspondent for the
                    Trans-Radio News Agency. She also worked as an observer for the United Nations
                    International League for Human Rights. She was keenly interested in women's
                    rights and was an original member of the Women's International Democratic
                    Federation. She was active in many social, environmental, and political
                    causes.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the papers of Zelma Corning Brandt. Documentation
                    includes: incoming and outgoing correspondence (1907-1988); photographs,
                    notebooks, and publications related to Brandt's travels in India, Africa, China,
                    and Japan; and printed matter from a variety of organizations, such as the
                    National Organization for Women, the Gray Panthers, and anti-Vietnam war groups.
                    The correspondence reflects Brandt's interest in and activities on behalf of a
                    wide range of causes. Although some of the mailings from organizations are
                    routine requests for donations, Brandt's responses are quite vibrant and
                    engaging. Personal correspondence in the collection also reflects her commitment
                    to social and political causes. The collection also includes photographs and
                    some of Brandt's early diaries (1906-1910).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>