<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Albert T. Lang papers <date type="inclusive">1899-1959</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Albert T. Lang papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC683</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.66 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1899-1959</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Albert Theodore Lang (1881-1956) was an Oiler on the USS Olympia and a member of
                    the ship's baseball team. He wife was Emilie Pauline Lang. Their son, Charles
                    Lang, served in the U.S. Navy during World War II.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Albert Lang. Materials include: correspondence
                    and other documents of Albert Lang and Emilie Lang from the Navy Department
                    related to retirement and veteran's benefits; service records including orders,
                    appointments, changes of duty, and discharges, 1914-1947, including a
                    certificate of appointment to the USS Olympia as Oiler, 1909; correspondence
                    between Albert Lang and his sister, 1899 and 1921; Albert and Emilie Lang's
                    marriage certificate; correspondence from the Cruiser Olympia Association; and
                    clippings related to the Olympia, circa 1959. Photos in the collection include:
                    portrait photographs, cabinet card photos, and photo postcards of Albert Lang
                    and other sailors, World War I period; reproduction photographs of the USS
                    Olympia baseball team (Lang was a member of the team); photos of a war-damaged
                    town (World War I period, unlabeled); panoramic photo of Company 1328 Civilian
                    Conservation Corps at Sunnamahoning, Pennsylvania, 1933; panoramic photo of the
                    crew of the USS New Jersey, 1913; and commemorative photos of ships USS Indiana,
                    USS New Hampshire, and others. Other materials in the collection include:
                    programs, menus, and other ephemera from events on board various ships,
                    including the USS New Hampshire, the USS Nebraska, and the USS Pennsylvania; and
                    miscellaneous printed volumes and souvenir booklets. The collection also
                    includes a letter related to Albert's son, Charles, attempt to enroll in the
                    U.S. Naval Academy and a copy of a report of physical examination.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Cabinet photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ephemera.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Military records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Postcards.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2008.3</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>