<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Albert family papers <date type="inclusive">1859-1956</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Albert family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC950</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1859-1956</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Seaman Albert (1835-1880) began his career in the US Navy in 1855, and
                    achieved rank of Chief Engineer in 1861. Took a leave of absence from the Navy
                    to serve as Chief of the Bureau of Machinery at the Philadelphia 1876 Centennial
                    -- he was in charge of Machinery Hall. He died two months after his last voyage
                    aboard the USS Quinnebaug, which sailed throughout the Mediterranean and North
                    Africa, 1879-1880. His brother Sidney Albert (1840-1874), began his career in
                    the US Navy in 1859, and achieved rank of Chief Engineer in 1870. Sidney retired
                    from the Navy in 1872, and moved to Minneapolis where he was Superintendent of
                    Water Works. Mary Jackson Seaman Albert (1815-1893) -- mother of John S. and
                    Sidney Albert (? -- check)</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Albert family papers. Materials include correspondence,
                    journals, scrapbooks of John Seaman Albert and his brother Sidney Albert during
                    their naval careers and gives insight into life aboard a US naval vessel during
                    the period just prior to the Civil War, political comments on world events and
                    particularly events in the Orient and events leading up to and during the Civil
                    War. John's journals cover the period of the Philadelphia Centennial, 1876. John
                    Albert materials include: correspondence from John to his mother, his brother
                    Sidney, and to his wife; appointments and orders; photographs, including a
                    photograph of the USS Quinnebang on the Delaware River; diary of a voyage
                    (1878-1880); journal (1864-1880); scrapbook of newspaper clippings; invitations
                    (1860s and 1876); and a report on the final trial trip of the USS Wampanoag;
                    1868. Sidney Albert materials include orders, letters to mother, his brother
                    John, and several to his father and others. Additionally there are letters from
                    Mary Albert to Sidney (1862-1866). John S. Albert, III materials include: a
                    photo album kept during his service aboard the USS Naifeh and a log book from
                    that time (1944-1945); scrapbook of clippings related to the attack on the USS
                    Kearny, 1941; personal papers related to his US Navy service; and photos of the
                    Naifeh, its officers and crew,and the Kearney. The collection also includes
                    photographs of Mary Albert, Sadie Albert (aunt), Sarah Albert (wife of John S.)
                    (photographs, daguerreotypes and tintypes, carte de visite, and cabinet
                    cards.)</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Cabinet photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Daguerreotypes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Diaries.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Military records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships' logs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Tintypes.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 87.43; 85.73; 86.107</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>