<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>B. H. McCalla papers <date type="inclusive">1897-1903</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">B. H. McCalla papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC460</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1897-1903</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Bowman Hendry McCalla (b. 1844) was born in Camden, New Jersey. McCalla was
                    appointed a midshipman in 1861. In 1885, he led an expeditionary force of 750
                    seamen and Marines in landing at Panama to protect American treaty rights as a
                    revolution there threatened to block transit across the isthmus. In 1897, while
                    commanding Marblehead in blockading Cuba, he cut cables to isolate the Spanish
                    garrison at Cienfuegos. On 10 June 1898, with Lieutenant Colonel Robert
                    Huntington, USMC, Commander McCalla led a joint Navy and Marine Corps expedition
                    into Guantánamo Bay, Cuba, seizing the anchorage and thereby enabling a close
                    blockade of Spanish warships at Santiago de Cuba, about forty miles west.
                    Commanding Newark during the Boxer Rebellion, he was second in command of an
                    international force under British Admiral Sir Edward Seymour, including 112
                    bluejackets, that advanced from Tientsin to Peking to relieve foreign legations
                    under siege there. In battle at Hsiku Arsenal, McCalla and 25 of his force were
                    wounded; five were killed. For this action, he received a Congressional medal,
                    the Order of the Red Eagle by the German Emperor and another medal from the King
                    of England. Commissioned rear admiral in 1903, he retired in 1906. He died in
                    1910. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Journal belonging to Bowman Hendry McCalla dating from the Spanish American War.
                    Outlines his command on Marblehead from Sept. 1897 to Nov. 1897. Journal is
                    dedicated to his wife and contains a full description of his activities aboard
                    as well as the men in his command. Some reference to his earlier court-martial
                    and his command of Enterprise. The journal is continued over four volumes. The
                    journal continues through 1899, when McCalla was commander of Newark [he was
                    promoted to a captaincy in 1898]. The collection also includes: printed reports
                    about a cable-cutting operation performed by the crew of Marblehead in 1989;
                    recommendations for medals of honor related to that operation; a 1903 invitation
                    to the dedication of the Champlain Monument; and a printed volume Inauguration
                    du Monument Camplain A Quebec le 21 Septembre 1989 (published 1902), inscribed
                    to Admiral McCalla by Alexandre Chauveau, President to the Champlain Monument
                    Committee. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Diaries.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1984.68; 1984.78</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>