<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Bethlehem Steel Corporation business papers <date type="inclusive">1910-1959</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Bethlehem Steel Corporation business papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC520</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1959</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Bethlehem Steel Corporation was once America’s second largest steel company.
                    Founded as a quasi-subsidiary of the Lehigh Valley Railroad, under the direction
                    of Robert H. Sayre and John Fritz the company pioneered production of steel
                    products and gave birth to the modern American defense industry. Reorganized in
                    1904 by Charles M. Schwab, a protégé of Andrew Carnegie, Bethlehem Steel became
                    a manufacturing giant possessing steel mills, coal mines, and shipyards
                    throughout the country and even the world. From the Spanish-American War through
                    World War II, Bethlehem Steel was the single most important source of military
                    products for our armed forces. During the final decades of the 20th century,
                    Bethlehem Steel became notable as one of the most dramatic casualties of free
                    trade policies. [possibly a bit too dramatic for a bio note -- this is from a PA
                    Legacies articles]</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of approximately 600 black and white photographs from the
                    early 20th century. Images are of ships under construction, ships underway,
                    parts, and launchings. Some of the photos are from Harlan and Hollingsworth and
                    Federal Shipbuilding. Also included in the collection are printed materials from
                    Bethlehem Steel Corporation and its shipbuilding division. These materials
                    include: brochures, newsletters, and periodicals (1914-1976); biographical
                    information on Charles Schwab and memorials to Schwab; Newsletters include
                    copies of the Fore River Log (1915-1920) and the Bethlehem Booster
                    (1918-1919).</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1993.35.22-66; 1986.10 (photos)</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>