<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Captain John Green papers <date type="inclusive">1781-1801</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Captain John Green papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC452</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1781-1801</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Capt. John Green (1736-1796), was commissioned in the Pennsylvania State Navy in
                    October of 1776 and commanded the ship Nesbitt. He was later commissioned into
                    the Continental Navy and was captured by the British and imprisoned in the Mill
                    Prison near Plymouth, England in 1779. The last naval engagement of the American
                    Revolution took place in place 1783 between Captains John Green of New York on
                    the ship Duc De Lauzon and John Barry of Philadelphia on the Alliance and the
                    British frigates Alarm and Sybil. In 1784 was the captain of the Empress of
                    China the first American ship to sail to Canton, China for trade purposes. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of John Green. Materials include: a letterbook of
                    John Green, 1781-1783 and letters 1782. Most of the letters were written during
                    Green's imprisonment at Mill Prison in Plymouth, England. There are also several
                    incoming letters; a log book of the Empress of China, 1784-1785 and ledger of
                    the China voyage, 1784. The log book notes daily position, weather, and
                    shipboard activities from the beginning of the voyage until the ship reached the
                    lower end of the Malayan peninsula (last entry is January 12, 1785). The ledger
                    records sales and purchases of merchandise in Canton, listed by merchant. Other
                    items in the collection include: a copy of the manifest of the Empress of China;
                    certificates of permission to depart and of safe conduct for the Empress of
                    China, 1784; a patent granting John Green land in Luzerne County, Pennsylvania;
                    1801 passport for John Green, signed by Rufus King; a manuscript document of
                    Proceedings and Court Decision of April 1, 1799 in the matter of American ship,
                    Pegou, Captain John Green, Master, with a typescript of this document in French
                    and an English translation. The collection also has typed transcriptions of
                    papers of John Green, including the letterbook and letters from this collection
                    and letters and other documents held by the Historical Society of Pennsylvania,
                    the American Philosophical Society, and other repositories. British Signal book,
                    1782 (what was this?)</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Empress of China (Ship)</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ledgers (account books).</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Legal documents.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Letterbooks.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Passports.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships' logs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1981.38</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>