<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charles Kurz II papers <date type="inclusive">1926-1990</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charles Kurz II papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC589</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1926-1990</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles Kurz II was born in 1945. He received his BA in 1967 from Trinity
                    College, Hartford, CT and his MBA from UPenn, Wharton Graduate Division. He was
                    president of Kurz-Allen Inc. and Vice President of Keystone Shipping Co. He was
                    also Director of the International Tanker Indemnity Association and Director of
                    the American Steamship Owners Mutual Protectuion and Indemnity Association.
                    Established in 1965, the non-profit, quasi-public Philadelphia Port Corporation
                    had the power to issue municipal bonds to raise funds for port improvements.
                    Revenue to pay the bonds' debt service was realized primarily through leasing
                    the agency's port facilities to private operating companies. These private
                    companies operated their respective port facilities on a day-to-day basis, with
                    marketing assistance from the Philadelphia Port Corporation. Major port
                    improvements were made in the 1960s and 70s under the auspices of the
                    Philadelphia Port Corporation. These included the construction of the 106-acre
                    Packer Avenue Marine Terminal (still the Port of Philadelphia's largest
                    facility) and the Tioga Marine Terminal in the 1970s. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Charles Kurz II. Materials include:
                    correspondence, memoranda, minutes, newspaper and magazine clippings, and
                    background materials related to the Philadelphia Port Corporation (1984-1990);
                    memoranda, proposals, agendas, and correspondence of the Corporation's Real
                    Estate Committee (1987-1988); and memoranda, minutes, and status reports of the
                    Strategic Capacity Committee (1988). Additional reports include Strategic
                    Business Plan for the Philadelphia Port Corporation. (1988) and a report of the
                    Economic Development Partnership Committee on the Ports of Pennsylvania. (1988).
                    Charles Kurz II materials include a 1969 MBA thesis entitled Oil Tanker
                    Chartering: An Economic and Historical Analysis and materials used by Kurz in
                    preparation for his thesis including brochures, reports and data tables
                    (1926-1968). Other materials in the collection include: a bound volume of
                    correspondence of the Keystone Shipping Company and the Chestnut Shipping
                    Company with the U.S. Department of Commerce on maritime subsidy matters (1973);
                    conference papers from the Safe Navigation Symposium (1978) and from meetings of
                    the International Tanker Safety Conference (1975 and 1979); a Handbook on
                    International Trade Procedures sponsored by Kurz &amp; Allen (1989); printed
                    materials on oil spills and collision protection for tankers; video on the
                    environmental impact of the wreck of the tanker Braer; and several other printed
                    volumes. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Port Corporation.</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Video recordings.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1998</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>