<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charles B. Edwards diary <date type="inclusive">1901-1933</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charles B. Edwards diary</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC656</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1901-1933</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles B. Edwards was born 1869. In 1913 Edwards was hired by Westinghouse
                    Machine Company and in 1914, the Edwards family moved to England, where he was
                    probably still employed by Westinghouse. Edwards returned to the United States
                    in 1916 and by 1918, Edwards was working mainly in New York, and the family
                    moved to Forest Hills, Long Island and soon thereafter moved again to
                    Haddonfield, NJ. Probably around the same time, he began working for New York
                    Shipbuilding Co. in Camden. By 1932, Edwards was retired.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of diaries kept by Charles B. Edwards. The nine diaries,
                    dating from 1913-20 and 1932, note the weather and daily activities of Edwards.
                    Entries are typically brief. One notebook, kept from 1901 to 1906, lists
                    specifications for a number of ships, including the torpedo boat Lawrence, the
                    cruiser Des Moines, the battleships Pennsylvania, Vermont, Rhode Island, New
                    Jersey, and a number of other ships. This notebook also includes a table of
                    insurance for buildings owned by the Fore River Ship Building Co. The other
                    notebook dating roughly from 1914-1915, contains rough notes and calculations,
                    and is not clearly connected to particular ships. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Diaries.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Notebooks.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2004.19</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>