<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edmund A. Crenshaw collection <date type="inclusive">1912-1956</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1919-1946</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edmund A. Crenshaw collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC445</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1912-1956</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1919-1946</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Capt. Edmund A. Crenshaw Jr. was an officer in the US Navy and later in the US
                    Naval Reserve. He entered the US Naval Academy in 1908, graduating and being
                    commissioned Ensign in 1912. By 1918 he had been promoted to
                    Lieutenant-Commander. He resigned from the regular Navy in 1919. In that same
                    year he was commissioned Lieutenant-Commander in the USNRF. He rose to the rank
                    of Captain in 1943. He was ordered to active duty in February 1941 and released
                    February 1946. Crenshaw was involved with mercantile escort convoys in the
                    Atlantic during WWII. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Papers of Edmund Crenshaw documenting his career in the U.S. Navy. Materials
                    include: a small number of memos related to his commission in the Navy,
                    initially assigned to USS Connecticut in 1912 and then to USS Chester in 1915;
                    memos and correspondence from 1919 regarding Crenshaw's resignation as
                    Lieutenant-Commander of USS Alert (Submarine Base); and records related to
                    training cruises, including authorizations to report for active duty for
                    training and reports on cruises, ca. 1920's. Records from WWII period include:
                    commissions; memos regarding promotions; orders and ships' itineraries; travel
                    records; leave notices; and reports of convoy movements submitted by Capt.
                    Crenshaw. Other materials in the collection include: a copy of a 1923 speech on
                    submarines by Commander H. M. Bemis, US Navy; and a 1956 letter related to an
                    article on submarines; photographs of the USS Olympia, USS Philadelphia, USS
                    Hartford, USS Portsmouth, the fleet in San Francisco, sailors; and a painting of
                    a gun being fired. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Military records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Speeches.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1976.006</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>