<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edward O. Clark papers <date type="inclusive">1840-1990</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edward O. Clark papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC522</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>16.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1840-1990</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Edward O. Clark (1918-1994) was a marine historian and photographer. Clark was
                    born in New York and later lived in Chalfont, Pennsylvania. Clark traveled
                    across the country pursuing interesting vessels, ports of call, and documenting
                    the vanishing heritage of American steam navigation. He was a member of the
                    Steamship Historical Society of America.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials concerning Delaware River steamboats, assembled
                    by Edward O. Clark. The bulk of the collection consists of photographs of
                    vessels, engines, and engine components. There are also some photographs of
                    interiors of vessels, passengers, and shipyards. Photographs are roughly grouped
                    by vessel, line, or builder. There is a large collection of images related to
                    the Wilson line. Many of the photographs in the collection were taken by Clark.
                    Also included in the collection are histories and chronologies of vessels and
                    lines; clippings on vessels and lines; illustrations of engine and wheel plans;
                    lists of vessels; lists of engines and machinery by builder; several school
                    papers by Clark on propulsion machinery for shallow draft vessels, including his
                    1940 college thesis; correspondence with Edward T. Francis, 1984-1990; other
                    research and general correspondence; newsletters from steamship and engineering
                    history societies; files related to the sale of two Horace Pippin paintings
                    owned by Clark; index card files of Delaware steamboats, ferries, and lines; an
                    index of engines; notes on engines and other nautical equipment; and notes on
                    machine and iron works. The collection also includes records on and photographs
                    of railroad engines, steam whistles, and organs, and an 1840 map of the
                    Baltimore Union Line.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Wilson Line (Wilmington, Del.)</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Paddle steamers.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Steam engineering.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Steamboat lines.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Steamboats.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Maps.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Registers (lists)</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1993.57</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Camden County
                    Historical Society: Edward O. Clark's Steamboats on the Delaware collection;
                    Steamship Historical Society: Edward Clark photographs (available online through
                    the Society's Image Porthole, but currently there is next to no metadata for the
                    images).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>