<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Francis A. Lewis papers on Robert Morris <date type="inclusive">1790-1932</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1790-1830</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Francis A. Lewis papers on Robert Morris</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC447</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1790-1932</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1790-1830</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert Morris, Jr. (1734-1806) was an American merchant and a signer to the
                    United States Declaration of Independence, the Articles of Confederation, and
                    the United States Constitution. Morris was known as the Financier of the
                    Revolution, because of his role in personally financing the American side in the
                    Revolutionary War from 1781 to 1784. Morris was ruined by land speculation and
                    in 1798 was taken to debtor's prison where he spent three and a half years. For
                    the benefit of his creditors he assigned certain real estate that he owned in
                    New York to trustees. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Records related to the repayment of the creditors of Robert Morris and to the
                    administration and gradual liquidation of his lands that placed in trust by
                    Morris to protect his equity. Correspondence, indentures, deeds, receipts, and
                    other records document the sale and sub-division of lands and taxation on lands.
                    Items of note include a copy of a deed for land conveyed to Mary Jemison by the
                    Seneca Indian Nation and a certified true copy of bill from the New York
                    legislature guaranteeing Jemison's title to the land. Papers of Lawrence Lewis
                    (Sr.), including correspondence and receipts. Correspondence from John Young to
                    Lawrence Lewis regarding the sale of coal lands in Schuylkill County, PA and to
                    the coal and barge operations connected to the mining of coal; There are also
                    some papers related to Robert Lewis (brother of Lawrence Lewis Sr.), Lawrence
                    Lewis Jr. (d. 1915), and Frederick A. Lewis. Letters, receipts, deeds of Joseph
                    Higbee. Correspondence related to the sale and subdivision of lands in Ohio; and
                    letters from Higbee to his father, mother, and sister. Papers of John Phillips,
                    captain of the William Savery and of the Superior, both of which were engaged in
                    trade with China. Includes invoices, bills of lading, and accounts for goods
                    shipped. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Bills of lading.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Deeds.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Receipts (financial records).</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1979.83; 1979.83.5</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>