<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>George Sproule papers <date type="inclusive">1884-1946</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">George Sproule papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC473</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1884-1946</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>George F. Sproule was born in Ireland in 1867. In 1884, Sproule entered the
                    office of Board of Port Wardens of Philadelphia as a Vessel Clerk. 1888, he was
                    elected secretary of the Board of Port Wardens and served in this role until the
                    Board was abolished in 190. Sproule served for 12 years as secretary of the
                    Commissioners of Navigation, which replaced the Board of Port Wardens. In 1920,
                    he was appointed by Mayor J. Hampton Moore to serve as Director of Wharves,
                    Docks and Ferries. Sproule married Nora Louise Gerrish in 1896 and lived in
                    Overbrook. He died in 1928. Sproule was responsible for much of the development
                    of the Port of Philadelphia, improvements to Delaware Avenue and construction of
                    municipal piers. George F. Sproule, compiler of The port of Philadelphia: its
                    facilities and advantages, published by the Board of Commissioners of Navigation
                    for the River Delaware and its Navigable Tributaries, 1914 (HSP has this)</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Collection of scrapbooks, photo albums, and papers of George F. Spoule.
                    Scrapbooks contain period newspaper clippings and related ephemera, relating to
                    George F. Sproule's professional career with the Port of Philadelphia. Also
                    scrapbooks of Philadelphia Shipping News clippings. The scrapbooks date from the
                    end of 1884 to 1928. Photo albums include: images from a trip taken by the
                    Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, US Congress,aboard the pilot-boat
                    Philadelphia in 1911; and photos of the Raritan Canal taken during an inspection
                    by the Rivers and Harbors Committee of the US Congress, 1911. Other photographs
                    in the collection include: portraits of Sproule; pictures of Sproule and other
                    members of several committees; images the Municipal Piers constructed by the
                    Department of Docks Wharves and Ferries, ca. 1920s; images of Delaware Ave,
                    1890s; images of various ships on the Delaware River, including the John
                    Wanamaker. Papers in the collection include cards, passes, programs, legal
                    briefs, speeches, invitations, letters, manuscripts, and typescripts, related to
                    the career of George F. Sproule, dated 1887 to 1927. A number of these items
                    also document the history of the city and the Port of Philadelphia. Additional
                    materials include: two appointment books of George F. Sproul, 1926-1927; and
                    letters and documents and photographs and newspaper clippings related to the
                    career of S. Jackson Sproule as Port of Philadelphia representative during WWII.
                </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Harbors--Delaware River.</subject>
                <geogname encodinganalog="651">Philadelphia (Pa.)--Harbor.</geogname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photograph albums.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1987.16</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>