<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Harlan &amp; Hollingsworth records <date type="inclusive">1917-1947</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Harlan &amp; Hollingsworth records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC2491</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1917-1947</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Harlan &amp; Hollingsworth Co., of Wilmington, Delaware, was the first firm in
                    the United States to combine the shipyard and the foundry. Mahlon Belts and
                    Samuel Pusey began partnership in 1836 as Betts and Pusey, with Samuel Harlan
                    joining a year later to form Betts, Pusey &amp; Harlan. When Pusey retired in
                    1841, his interest in the company was purchased by Harlan's brother-in-law,
                    Elijah Hollingsworth and the firm name was changed to Betts, Harlan &amp;
                    Hollingsworth. It changed to Harlan &amp; Hollingsworth in 1849. In 1867 the
                    firm was incorporated under the name The Harlan &amp; Hollingsworth Company. On
                    December 10, 1904, the company was acquired by Bethlehem Steel and operated as
                    part of their shipbuilding division. The name changed from Harlan &amp;
                    Hollingsworth to the Harlan Plant of Bethlehem Steel. The shipyard closed in
                    1926, although it was reopened for a time during the Second World War and part
                    of the shipyard was used by the Dravo Corporation until 1964. Railcars were
                    built on the site until 1940, and parts for railcars until 1944.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Harlan Plant of Bethlehem Shipbuilding.
                    Materials include: tonnage statements (listing ships that have been delivered,
                    with their hull numbers and dimensions); list of vessels with the Dahl oil
                    burning system; news releases and telegrams related to Bethlehem Steel workers'
                    purchase of war bonds, 1942; and a letter regarding improper loading of rail
                    cars, 1947. The collection also contains newspaper clippings about the Harlan
                    Plant and Bethlehem Steel/Bethlehem Shipbuilding, 1922-1926, 1931. Clippings
                    relate to construction contracts, safety issues for workers, a 1923 fire in
                    which ship patterns were lost, and a lawsuit between Bethlehem Steel and the US
                    government related to payment for patents. Other materials in the collection
                    include: aerial photos of Harlan plant; photo of Bangor (later called Scourge)
                    built by Harlan &amp; Hollingsworth; and plans of the Wilmington Yard of
                    Bethlehem Steel (Harlan yard), 1942. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Bethlehem Steel Corporation.</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>