<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Henry S. Stellwagen papers <date type="inclusive">1820-1921</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1842-1865</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Henry S. Stellwagen papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC437</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1820-1921</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1842-1865</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henry Schreiner Stellwagen (1803-1866) was raised in Philadelphia. In his youth
                    he traveled to Calcutta in an East India merchantman. In 1828 Stellwagen entered
                    the US Navy as a midshipman. He was promoted in 1840 to Lieutenant. His first
                    active service was in Africa helping to control the slave trade. Stellwagen then
                    served under Commodore Perry at the fall of Vera Cruz in 1847. In 1854 he had
                    command of a fleet of surveying vessels which discovered and accurately
                    described a large submarine bank in Massachusetts Bay. It was named Stellwagen
                    Bank. In 1855, Stellwagen was promoted to Commander. In 1861, he helped plan and
                    execute attacks on Forts Hatteras and Clark at Hatteras Inlet. In 1862 he was
                    commissioned Captain. In mid 1863, he was given command of the Mediterranean
                    Squadron and remained there until 1864 aboard the flagship Constellation.
                    Stellwagen retired from the navy in 1865. He died at Cape Island, New Jersey in
                    1866. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Collection of papers documenting Henry Schreiner Stellwagen's service in the
                    United States Navy. Materials include: orders and appointments for Stellwagen;
                    copies of general Navy orders related to uniforms; letter from Secretary of the
                    Navy Gideon Welles informing Stellwagen of his placement of the list of retired
                    officers; letters related to Stellwagen's Naval service; an 1848 report from the
                    Franklin Institute of Science on a patent for a sounding apparatus invented by
                    Lt. Stellwagen; and a patent certificate, 1842, including an illustration of the
                    device. Cartes de visite of naval officers, including: Captain Percival Drayton
                    (flagship Hartford), Rear Admiral David Glasgow Farragut, Colonel William L.
                    Long, Commander George Henry Preble, Rear Admiral S.P. Lee, Commodore A.S.
                    Glisson, and others. Includes several images of European officers and civilians,
                    including General and Governor Tunis, Othman Bey, Italian Vice Admiral
                    Almiraglio Albini, and others. The collection also includes a photograph of the
                    steam and sail powered ships California and Unadilla, and photographs of a
                    trophy and a plaque awarded in 1912 to the Colorado.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Oceanographic instruments.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Military records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Patents.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1969.58</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>