<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Herman Wolter papers <date type="inclusive">1886-1901</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Herman Wolter papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC553</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1886-1901</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Herman Wolter was born in Prussia in 1839. At 17 he went to sea, working as a
                    sailor for 15 years. While on an American merchantman bound for India, he was
                    captured by the Confederate cruiser Alabama, off the east coast of Africa, and
                    sent as a prisoner to Baltimore. Upon his release, he enlisted in the Union
                    Navy. He participated in the second battle of Fort Sumter and the battle of Fort
                    Moultrie. After the war, he settled in Philadelphia and began his career as a
                    diver. In this work, he was involved in raising sunken ships, and he did much
                    work in the Delaware and Schuylkill rivers on bridge and road construction
                    projects. He died in 1901.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection documents the diving career of Herman Wolter. Materials include a
                    scrapbook of news clippings about Wolter and about other divers and salvage
                    operations; bill heads and letter heads of businesses involved in construction,
                    engineering, dredging, and others fields related to Wolter's work; and business
                    cards of other professional divers. Most of the businesses represented are in
                    Philadelphia, Camden, Delaware, and the surrounding region. The scrapbook
                    includes a small amount of correspondence concerning diving equipment. The
                    collection also includes a framed photograph of Wolter in a diving suit, and
                    framed newspaper obituaries for Wolter.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Deep diving.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Salvage.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Obituaries.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1995.104</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>