<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Horace Holden Thayer papers <date type="inclusive">1893-1943</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Horace Holden Thayer papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC455</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1893-1943</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Horace Holden Thayer was a naval architect and marine engineer. His office was
                    located in the Witherspoon Building, Philadelphia. Thayer was a graduate of
                    Cornell University with a degree in Mechanical Engineering, specializing in
                    naval architecture. He was Assistant Naval Architect and later Naval Architect
                    of the U.S. Shipping Board Emergency Fleet Corporation during the First World
                    War. He was a member of the Society of Naval Architects and Marine Engineers,
                    the Society of Naval Engineers, the Society of American Military Engineers, and
                    the American Society for Testing Materials.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records related to Thayer's work for the U.S. Shipping
                    Board Emergency Fleet Corporation during World War I. These records include
                    correspondence and memoranda; general, special, and technical orders to
                    personnel; plans, specifications, and technical data on ships and equipment; a
                    list of ships (wood and steel) built by the U.S. Shipping Board; progress charts
                    for Emergency Fleet ships; and contracts for ships built by the Emergency Fleet
                    Corp. Other records include: correspondence related to a floating drydock built
                    for the Venezuelan government around 1911; survey and damage reports; and plans
                    and specifications for various ships. Other papers include: investment records;
                    a small amount of personal correspondence; data used by Thayer to prepare a
                    series of articles on shipbuilding materials published in Marine Engineering and
                    Shipping Age, 1922; and work journals with notes, technical data, calculations,
                    and several sketches.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">United States Shipping Board Emergency Fleet
                    Corporation.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Marine engineering--United States.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Naval architecture--Designs and plans.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Notebooks.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships plans.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Sketches.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Technical reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1982.156</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: National Archives:
                    Records of the United States Shipping Board, Record Group 32, 1914-38 </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>