<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Independence Seaport Museum Becuna veterans collection <date type="inclusive">1943-2003</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 2000-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Independence Seaport Museum Becuna veterans
                    collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC2539</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1943-2003</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 2000-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials assembled by Douglas Buchanan, Ships Program
                    Coordinator for ISM for the 25th anniversary [of what? possibly the
                    restoration?] and 2000 reunion of Becuna veterans. Materials include:
                    correspondence (letters and email), photographs, color photocopies of
                    photographs, videos, reminiscences, index to oral histories (oral history tapes
                    are not included), snapshots from the 2000 reunion, order of events for the 2000
                    reunion, brief biographies of Becuna veterans print-outs from Sandy MacNaught's
                    Becuna history website (g-macnaught.com) CDs of drawings of the Becuna, and
                    photos and reminiscences a small number of items of ephemera from 1943-1945,
                    including menus, invitations, programs, ration cards, and photographs (recent
                    reproductions) donated by William Ambrose (a Becuna vet) volunteer forms, gift
                    and release forms for oral histories, interview data forms notebook of contact
                    information for veterans correspondence from veterans to Buchanan about reunion
                    attendance restoration done in 1976 secondary resource materials on US Navy
                    submarines, a xerox of a Guppy class submarine manual, a history of torpedo
                    technology, a fleet sub manual (on CD), 1961-1964 issues of Dolphin, the US
                    Naval Submarine Base, New London, CT newsletter</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Independence Seaport
                    Museum: Becuna collection</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>