<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Independent Pier Company records <date type="inclusive">1909-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Independent Pier Company records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC575</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>13.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1909-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Independent Pier Company (IPC) was founded by Emil Meyle about 1895. It was
                    operated originally under the name of E. Meyle. The services included wharfage,
                    towing, lighterage, and stevedoring. In 1909 the business was incorporated as
                    Independent Pier Company. In 1931, the Pennsylvania charter was surrendered and
                    the company was incorporated under Delaware law in order to obtain authority for
                    a broader scope of operations. In 1915 IPC acquired control of the business of
                    Chas. Killam &amp; Co., which owned five lighters. Independent Towing Company, a
                    subsidiary of IPC, was incorporated in 1926. The Tug Triton Company, Tug Neptune
                    Company, and Tug Spartan Company were also incorporated in 1926; the Tug Jupiter
                    Company was incorporated in 1939. The Tug Mercury Company was incorporated in
                    1942. These companies were all owned by IPC.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Independent Pier Company. There are a
                    number of logs of tugs, including: Jupiter (1962-1974); Mercury (1965-1978);
                    Saturn (1971); Silver Comet (1979); Venus (1955-1977); Triton (1950-1977);
                    Trojan (1971); unidentified (1949-1975) [note, these dates are not
                    comprehensive]; maintenance logs for various tugs, 1967-1980; and
                    towing/lighterage logs (1942-1946, 1949-1951, 1961). Records for the tug Neptune
                    include certificates of inspection, capital stock reports, receipts and bills of
                    sale for shares. The collection contains manuscript specifications for a tug
                    boat, undated, and plans for various engine components and other ship's
                    equipment, mostly dating from 1955. Other records include: account books of
                    Independent Pier Co., 1932-1939 and 1944-1951; cash books, 1932-1934 and 1950s;
                    financial statements, 1948-1954; a time book, 1957-1959; tug assistance
                    contracts, 1969; stock share certificates for Spartan, Neptune, Mercury; a list
                    of employees, with name, birth date, and social security number; and bills and
                    receipts for orders of seafood and meat. Independent Towing Company records
                    include letterhead, an agreement form for stevedoring services, bumper stickers,
                    and business cards. The collection also contains records related to the
                    Independent Pier Co.'s involvement with the War Shipping Administration
                    (1941-1947), including contracts, correspondence and memoranda, financial
                    statements, records related to contractors, stevedores, and overtime expense
                    recovery following the war.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Tugboats. </subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ledgers (account books).</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Receipts (financial records).</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships plans.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships' logs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1996.5</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>