<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Jacob Koch account book <date type="inclusive">1801-1805</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Jacob Koch account book</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC2504</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.12 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1801-1805</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Jacob Gerard Koch (1784?-1830), originally from Holland, was an affluent
                    Philadelphia merchant who imported German linens to the United States from
                    approximately 1796 to 1816. He resided at the northeast corner of Ninth and
                    Market Street and operated his business from a store on the corner of Lombard
                    Alley and Little Water Street. During the War of 1812, Koch reportedly
                    subscribed $5000 for the construction of a frigate to support the American
                    government in its defense. In 1819 Koch moved to Paris, France, with his wife,
                    Jane Griffith Koch. According to the Reminiscences of Charles N. Buck, also a
                    merchant in Philadelphia at the turn of the nineteenth century, controversy
                    ensued concerning the marriage of Koch to Jane Griffith. Before their marriage,
                    she apparently served as his laundry maid. When he fell ill during the Yellow
                    Fever Epidemic of 1798, she allegedly promised to nurse him back to health if
                    he, in return, would marry her. Buck stated that society regarded Jane Griffith
                    as a "poor, ignorant, ill -tempered, and very homely Irish girl," and frowned
                    upon Koch's marriage to her. Koch died on July 2, 1830, in Paris at age
                    seventy.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Account book of Jacob Koch, 1801-1805. The volume includes records of insurance,
                    purchases, sales, and receipts. Koch insured ships traveling to Canton,
                    Calcutta, Liverpool, Amsterdam, and other ports around the world. Goods the firm
                    traded include spices, tea, coffee, wine, muslin and silk.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Account books.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>