<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James W. Southard papers <date type="inclusive">1825-1828</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James W. Southard papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC430</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1825-1828</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The three masted square-rigger North Carolina's keel was laid in 1818 at the
                    Philadelphia Navy Yard. She was launched in 1820 after being fitted out in
                    Norfolk Navy Yard. Considered the most powerful vessel afloat in her day when
                    commissioned in June 1824, North Carolina was invited to many foreign ports.
                    From April 1825 until May 1827, North Carolina served in the Mediterranean fleet
                    as Commodore John Rogers flagship. Again flagship of her station, flying the
                    pennant of Commodore Henry E. Ballard, North Carolina reached Callao, Peru in
                    May of 1837. With war raging between Chile and Peru, and relations between the
                    United States and Mexico strained, North Carolina protected the important
                    American commerce of the eastern Pacific until March 1839. Since her great size
                    made her less flexible than smaller ships, she returned to the New York Navy
                    Yard in June, and served as a receiving ship until placed in ordinary in 1866.
                    She was sold at New York 1 October 1867.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Logbook entitled, "A Journal Kept by Midshipman James W. Southard on board the
                    United States' Ship of the Line the North-Carolina," recording observations of
                    wind, weather, latitude, course, and remarks during the ship's cruise of the
                    Mediterranean, 1825-1827. There are two watercolor drawings of ships at the
                    front of the journal. The collection also includes a notebook with questions and
                    answers on the practice of seamanship, 1828.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">North Carolina (Ship-of-the-line)</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Seamanship.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships' logs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1965.001; 1965.002</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>