<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James Dugan papers <date type="inclusive">1880-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James Dugan papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC557</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>29 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1880-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James Dugan (1912-1967) was born in Altoona, Pennsylvania. Dugan attended Altoona
                    High School and graduated in 1929. He studied at Penn State University from
                    1933-1937. After graduating Dugan moved to New York. During the Second World
                    War, he supervised French, German, Spanish and Russian classes for soldiers. He
                    also worked as a war correspondent. During this time he wrote articles for
                    magazines such as the Saturday Evening Post, Holiday, National Geographic and
                    New York Times. In 1946 he married Ruth Mae Lonergan, whom he met while she was
                    a WAC in London during the war. Much of his writing in the 1950s and 1960s
                    concerns underwater exploration with Captain Jacques Cousteau. Dugan first met
                    Cousteau in 1944 during the liberation of France. Dugan was the author of Man
                    Under the Sea, American Viking, The Great Iron Ship, and editor of Captain
                    Cousteau's Underwater Treasury. He helped Cousteau with the presentation of his
                    underwater documentaries, which helped to inform the general public about the
                    sea. Dugan received the Grand Prix, Cannes International Film Festival award for
                    The Silent World in 1956, and was part of the team that produced the Academy
                    Award-winning documentaries The Silent World (1956) and World Without Sun
                    (1964). Dugan was a member of the American Littoral Society and the American
                    Geographical Union. With his wife Ruth, he helped to found the United States
                    Liaison Committee for Oceanographic Research in 1951. The purpose of the
                    committee was to raise and grant money for marine research.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of James and Ruth Dugan on diving, marine science,
                    and other related topics. Materials in the collection include photos, films,
                    periodicals, correspondence, clippings, and miscellaneous records. Photographs
                    in the collection include: images of dives off the French coast of the
                    Mediterranean; images of Jacques Cousteau and his crew at work and candid shots
                    of them (Cousteau playing an accordion and photos of John F. Kennedy and
                    Cousteau); slides from Hawaii and San Francisco. Printed materials in the
                    collection include: magazines, reprints and extracts; newspaper clippings, many
                    of which deal with Jacques Cousteau and the Cousteau Society; newsletters;
                    directories; diving equipment catalogs; a private cable code book from 1955;
                    programs and brochures; and several books, including an oversize volume "Greek
                    Ships of 1821". Audiovisual materials in the collection include: reel-to-reel
                    audio tapes, including interviews (Admiral Momsen on submarines; and JYC),
                    talks, meeting of the MAVC convention, 1961, and audio of sounds made by the
                    Weddell seal; film reels, including footage of the dive at Fontaine de Vaucluse;
                    and a number of commercial videos related to marine subjects. Records related to
                    the United States Liaison Committee for Oceanographic Research includes Ruth and
                    James Dugan correspondence. The correspondence largely relates to the tax status
                    of the organization. Records also include one grant application, bank
                    statements, and canceled checks. Other materials in the collection include:
                    typescripts of articles and other writings; multiple copies of a brochure
                    written by Dugan for an extermination company; plans for an underwater exhibit
                    at the Philadelphia Maritime Museum, 1974; and several maps and charts,
                    including a chart of New York Harbor, the ocean floor, and other locations; a
                    can of Evian water;a diving mask; and a metal valve handle. The collection also
                    includes items related to Auguste and Louis Boutan. Materials include: plans of
                    diving apparatus; manuscript of a chapter on Louis Boutan in Man Under the Sea,
                    by Dugan; typed notes on Boutan, in English and French; instruction booklet and
                    brochure for Boutan's Scaphandre Autonome; articles on Boutan; photos of Boutan
                    (1880-1930); prints of underwater photos by Boutan (1890s) and a portfolio
                    containing 4 of Boutan's underwater photograph: "Photographies Sous-Marines par
                    L. Boutan", 1898; photos of Boutan's diving apparatus; several drawings of
                    diving apparatus; plans for a diving vessel; and charts of weight, displacement,
                    and so on for the vessel.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Manuscripts.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Maps.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Motion pictures.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reprints.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Schematic drawings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Slides (Photographs)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Sound recordings.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1995.60</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>