<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James P. Lindsay papers <date type="inclusive">1861-1945</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1861-1908</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James P. Lindsay papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC643</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1861-1945</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1861-1908</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James Patrick Lindsay was born in Ireland and came to the United States at the
                    age of 14. He worked in various capacities on merchant vessels out of Boston. At
                    the outbreak of the Civil War, he was appointed Acting Master in the US Navy and
                    was assigned to the USS Pawnee. He served as master and navigating officer until
                    April of 1864, when he resigned and was honorably discharged from naval service.
                    He returned to the merchant marine, and entered the employ of Dallett, Bolton
                    &amp; Co. In 1865 he was named captain of the US Steamer Transport Welles. [when
                    did he leave this post?] In 1883, he was appointed Harbor Master of the Port of
                    Philadelphia. His service in that role expired with the term of the Governor who
                    appointed him. He was then appointed to the US Mint at Philadelphia, where he
                    worked for six years until his retirement. He was also a manager of the Society
                    of Distressed Masters of Ships.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of orders, certificates, correspondence, and ship papers of
                    James P. Lindsay covering the period 1861 to 1908. This material documents his
                    service as a ship's captain in the Civil War and his appointment as Harbor
                    Master of the Port of Philadelphia. Correspondence discusses the seizure of the
                    barque Fanny Laurie in 1862. Other materials include: orders to Lindsay as
                    captain of the Welles, 1865; a certificate of appointment as Acting Master in
                    the Navy, papers related to Lindsay's Navy pension; a report of vessels arriving
                    at the Port of Philadelphia for the year 1885; a printed statement from the
                    Society for the Relief of poor and Distressed Masters of Ships; and a photograph
                    of Lindsay. The collection also includes a small amount of correspondence and
                    other records of James P. Lindsay (grandson of Captain James P. Lindsay) related
                    to the family's membership in the Military Order of the Loyal Legion of the
                    United States (1940-1943); and a notice of classification from the Selective
                    Service for James P. Lindsay (grandson), 1945.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Harbors--Delaware River.</subject>
                <geogname encodinganalog="651">Philadelphia (Pa.)--Harbor.</geogname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Military records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2003.28.5</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>