<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Jay S. Rogers papers <date type="inclusive">1918-1983</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1918</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Jay S. Rogers papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC618</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1918-1983</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1918</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>USS Olympia (C-6/CA-15/CL-15/IX-40) was a protected cruiser in the United States
                    Navy during the Spanish-American War. She is most notable for being the flagship
                    of Commodore George Dewey at the Battle of Manila Bay. The cruiser continued in
                    service throughout World War I and was decommissioned in 1922. As of 2008,
                    Olympia is a museum ship at the Independence Seaport Museum in Philadelphia,
                    Pennsylvania. Jay S. Rogers served as a junior officer aboard the Olympia for
                    six months in 1918 when she was escorting a convoy to Murmansk.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Journal kept by Ensign Jay S. Rogers during his service aboard USS Olympia, April
                    28, 1918 to October 30, 1918. In the rear of the journal there is a hand drawn
                    map of the movements of Olympia and several poems. Photo postcards illustrate
                    many of the places and things described in the journal, and include photos of
                    Olympia sailing in heavy weather, images of Olympia's crew members, images of
                    USS San Diego, the British cruiser Cornwall, and other vessels, and images of
                    Murmansk. The collection also includes a photograph of Rogers aboard USS Olympia
                    in 1983 and a transcription of the journal.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Olympia (Cruiser) </corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Diaries.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Postcards.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2001.26</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>