<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Roach business papers <date type="inclusive">1860-1956</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1870-1910, 1943-1956</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Roach business papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC458</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1860-1956</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1870-1910, 1943-1956</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Roach (1813-1887) was a noted manufacturer and iron ship builder. He was
                    born at Mitchellstown, County Cork, Ireland, and came to America at the age of
                    16. He purchased the Reaney, Son &amp; Archbold shipyard in Chester,
                    Pennsylvania, and in 1871 renamed it John Roach and Sons. The shipyard had a
                    distinguished career building fine ships before it closed in 1922. It was
                    revived for the war effort in 1917 but was acquired by Averell Harriman's
                    American Ship &amp; Commerce Corporation in 1919 and renamed Merchant
                    Shipbuilding. Roach and his wife Emeline had several children, including John B.
                    Roach. John B. Roach (1839-1908) was the head of the Delaware River Iron
                    Shipbuilding &amp; Engine Works of Chester, and vice president of the Morgan
                    Iron Works of New York City.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of papers of John Roach, John B. Roach, and the Roach
                    family. Records related to Roach and Sons shipyard include: souvenir books,
                    1895; lists of ships and boilers built; patents, receipts, work reports, bids,
                    and a list of sponsors (1873-1891); a photocopy of a register of ships built by
                    Roach between 1872 and 1907, in two volumes; brochures of ships built by Roach;
                    and a printed register of contracts for Reaney, Son and Archbold, Roach and
                    Sons, and Merchant Shipbuilding Corp, 1859-1921. John Roach papers include:
                    draft notice; deeds, leases, and mortgages; papers related to Roach's estate;
                    several speeches and manuscript; correspondence sent to him during his illness;
                    printed memorials and obituaries; and correspondence sent to him during his
                    dispute with the Navy. Other materials related to the "Navy controversy"
                    include newspaper clippings and articles, congressional bills, correspondence,
                    statements, and a galley proof of "Secretary Whitney and the Dolphin," by John
                    Roach, 1886. Family papers include: correspondence of Mrs. G. R. Forbes related
                    to Roach family genealogy; photographs from County Cork, Ireland; a family
                    genealogy; photographs of Roach, Roach family members, and a small number of
                    photos of ships; and a 1914 photo album of the Roach family in Cape Cod. The
                    collection also contains newspaper clippings and magazine articles on Roach's
                    Shipyard, launchings and new contracts, the Dolphin controversy, and on John
                    Roach and members of the Roach family. There are also a number of pamphlets on
                    tariff laws (undated).</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">John Roach and Sons (Chester, Pa.)</corpname>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Roach, John B.</persname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Shipbuilding--Pennsylvania--Chester.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Deeds.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photograph albums.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Receipts (financial records).</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Registers (lists)</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1984.13; 1996.39; 1988.53</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>