<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John H. Mathis Company records <date type="inclusive">1919-1965</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John H. Mathis Company records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC524</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>195 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1919-1965</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The John H. Mathis Co at Point &amp; Erie Streets in Camden, New Jersey, built
                    yachts and also produced ships for the Navy and Coast Guard. Famed yacht
                    designer John Trumpy began building yachts at the Mathis yard in 1910, and
                    remained there until he opened his own shipyard in Maryland. During World War II
                    a variety of ships were built, including minesweepers, transports, Coast Guard
                    cutters, and ferries, among others. The Mathis Shipyard closed in the 1960s. The
                    Mathis shipyard was later used by the firm Camden Ship Repair.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of plans and records for ships built by Mathis, including
                    barges, tugs, tankers, patrol vessels, cargo vessels, trawlers, yachts, and
                    fireboats. Rolled plans for hulls 93-216 include general arrangement plans
                    (present for most hulls) and inboard and outboard profiles and plans of systems,
                    machinery, infrastructure, ordnance, and other particulars (present for many
                    hulls, with a large number of plans present for hulls 136, 147, 166). In
                    addition there are plans for the minesweeper AM 57 USS Auk; 418, 1942 YO; W2
                    82/83 US Net Tenders; other ships for which Mathis did design or repair work;
                    and plans of the yard. Folded plans and accompanying records for hulls 96-214
                    include: drawings and blueprints, notes on measurements; structural
                    calculations; material orders and lists; labor and materials costs; hull and
                    machinery plan lists; inventories of parts, machinery, appliances, and
                    equipment; photographs and negatives; specification books; test notes;
                    correspondence with the American Bureau of Shipping; a small amount of
                    correspondence with suppliers, vendors, and customers; work schedules with
                    estimated completion dates; a printed proposal for bid and specifications for a
                    New York City fire boat, along with the typed Mathis bid; and a specification
                    for bidders from the War Department for a cargo vessel (hull 147). The
                    collection also features photographs and negatives of hulls 130-185, including
                    images of ships during various stages of the construction and launches; photos
                    of the yard; photos of yard workers; photos of the interior of Mathis
                    Shipbuilding; photos of executive staff; and photos of piers 1, 2, and 4.
                    Additional materials in the collection include: receipts for stocks bought and
                    sold for W. W. Robinson; a small amount of financial information, circa 1945;
                    product brochures; employee identification badges; a small number of newspaper
                    clippings; and an index of plans (not complete).</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Naval architecture--Designs and plans.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Shipbuilding--New Jersey--Camden.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Negatives (Photographic)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships plans.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1993.87, multiple other accessions</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>