<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John S. Whitall papers <date type="inclusive">1774-1845</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John S. Whitall papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC459</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.833 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1774-1845</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Siddon Whitall was a merchant in Philadelphia. This was his second career;
                    as a young man, he sailed as a supercargo in the West India Trade. In 1815, his
                    business investments failed. Because of these losses, his son John Mickle
                    Whitall (b. 1800), then 15, was obliged to leave school to be apprenticed as a
                    ship hand on the William Savery. Beginning in 1818, he made several voyages to
                    the Far East, including Calcutta and Canton. By 1822 he sailed as Chief Mate
                    aboard the ship Dorothea. In 1824, Whitall was contracted by Whitton Evans to
                    oversee the construction of a new sailing ship, the New Jersey, the largest
                    "Indiaman" yet constructed in Philadelphia, and was given command as captain.
                    Between 1824 and 1829, he made several voyages to Canton. In 1829, Evans died
                    and the ship was sold; Whitall retired from the sea and became a merchant. His
                    firm, like his father’s, eventually failed, but he found success as a partner in
                    a glass business in Philadelphia.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of John M. Whitall and John S. Whitall. The
                    majority of the items in the collection belong to John M. Whitall; a small group
                    of letters document John S. Whitall's relationship with and subsequent marriage
                    to Sarah Mickle. The collection focuses primarily on four voyages to Canton
                    (1824, 1826, 1827, and 1828) made by Captain John M. Whitall aboard the ship New
                    Jersey. Materials include business and personal letters from John M. Whitall to
                    his father and other family members, and business letters related to the ship
                    New Jersey; charts covering the route to Canton, the first stop being Liverpool
                    (where Whitton Evans lived); bills of lading, invoices, receipts, promissory
                    notes, and custom house bonds; an account of crew wages; log books (1824-1827)
                    for New Jersey; a journal with "Observations on Thermometer and Barometer"
                    made during two of the voyages to Canton (1827-1829); and journal containing
                    coastal drawings of island in the South China Sea and algebra exercises. Other
                    items in the collection include: an oversized manifest of cargo and insurance
                    certificate; a reproduction photograph of Captain John M. Whitall; and several
                    samples of silk from China. In addition to papers related to New Jersey, the
                    collection contains some records of other ships, including William Savery (log
                    books, 1817-1820), Mary Lord, and Nancy. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <geogname encodinganalog="651">China--Commerce--United States.</geogname>
                <geogname encodinganalog="651">United States--Commerce--China.</geogname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Bills of lading.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Business records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Diaries.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships' logs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1984.37; 3-85 non acc. (photograph)</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>