<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John MacDonald papers <date type="inclusive">1936-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John MacDonald papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC1101</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Luckenbach Steamship Co. (1850-1974), New York, was one of the longest-lived and
                    most successful of US shipping companies. Lewis Luckenbach started with a single
                    tugboat in New York and initially built his fortune by pioneering tug-and-barge
                    transport of coal from Norfolk, Virginia (the outlet for the coal fields in what
                    is now West Virginia), to New England. Luckenbach was later a major force in the
                    intercoastal trade. John Hugh MacDonald (b. 1915) was master of the SS J.L.
                    Luckenbach.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of business records of the Luckenbach Steamship Co.
                    Materials include: order books of SS J.L. Luckenbach, 1951-1954, including
                    standing orders for Deck Officers and Night Orders; pilot's licenses, 1987-1990;
                    copies of US Customs Department regulations related to repairs in foreign ports
                    and lading; charts for determining ballast requirements; blank inspection report
                    forms; a blank checklist for official ship documents; a blank fire investigation
                    report; and a sheet of Luckenbach letterhead. Materials related to John Hugh
                    MacDonald include: discharge papers from the USCG-Merchant Marine; two discharge
                    books with records of MacDonald's service aboard ships, 1937-1955; certificate
                    for service in the US Merchant Marine; a diploma from the Sperry Gyroscope
                    Company, 1936; and a record of MacDonald's employment with the Luckenbach
                    Steamship Co. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Military records.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 94.31</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>