<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Josef Liener collection of Philadelphia Naval Shipyard photographs
                            <date type="inclusive">1916-1957</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Josef Liener collection of Philadelphia Naval Shipyard
                    photographs</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC491</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1957</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Philadelphia Naval Shipyard was the first Naval Shipyard in the Nation. In 1799
                    Congress authorized $522,678 in funds for the purchase of land to establish the
                    Philadelphia Naval Shipyard. The shipyard was originally located in the
                    Southwark region of Philadelphia. However, with growth of the city, the shipyard
                    was relocated to its present site. For many years, the workload at the shipyard
                    consisted primarily of new construction and conversions of ships. For example,
                    during World War II the battleship Wisconsin, the aircraft carrier Antietam, and
                    the cruisers Chicago and Los Angeles were launched in a period of seven months.
                    However, during the late 1960s at the direction of Defense Secretary McNamara
                    the Navy gradually phased out of the new construction business, turning this
                    work over to the private sector. The last ship built at the Philadelphia Naval
                    Shipyard was the command ship USS Blue Ridge in 1970.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of approximately 450 black and white photos from the
                    Philadelphia Navy Yard. Images document modeling, construction, and testing of
                    vessels at the Yard. Ships represented in the photographs include 40-foot and
                    50-foot utility boats, personnel and rescue boats, minesweeping launches, a LCVP
                    (landing craft vehicle, personnel), and area command cutters. The collection
                    also includes some photographs of personnel. Memos from the Industrial
                    Department of the Navy Yard in Portsmouth, New Hampshire, and from the Navy
                    Department, dated 1921 and 1942-1943, relate to materials and procedures to be
                    used in glue-laminated wood construction.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Naval Shipyard (Philadelphia,
                    Pa.)</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1989.21</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>