<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph F. Larkin papers <date type="inclusive">1953-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph F. Larkin papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC599</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The SS United States (also known as "The Big U") is an ocean liner built in
                    1952 for the United States Lines. At 53,329 gross tons, she is the largest ocean
                    liner to date built entirely in the United States and still holds the record for
                    the fastest westbound transatlantic crossing. In 1952, on her maiden voyage as
                    the new flagship of the United States Lines, the United States captured the Blue
                    Riband with the fastest eastbound and westbound transatlantic crossings on
                    record. The entry of the United States marked the first time a U.S.-flagged ship
                    held the Blue Riband, surpassing European speed records which had stood for
                    decades. The United States lost the eastbound record in 1990, but still holds
                    the westbound record. The United States plied the transatlantic with passenger
                    service until 1969. The ship is currently docked in Philadelphia. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Joseph Larkin related to the SS United States.
                    Materials include: correspondence from the public relations department of the
                    United States Lines company, related to Larkin's model of the SS United States
                    and a visit made by the Larkin family to the ship; a photo of the Larkin family
                    with Commodore Anderson during their 1954 visit to the ship; photographs of
                    Larkin working on a model of the SS United States, 1953; and a Popular
                    Mechanics, Jan. 1953, featuring part 2 of an article on building a 36" model of
                    the SS United States; plans for a model of the USS United States; and a plan for
                    the rowboat Snuffy. Memorabilia in the collection includes: a brochure; a menu;
                    paper napkins; envelopes; postcards; visitor's pass; a news release listing
                    notable passengers on a 1954 sailing; and a Westinghouse brochure featuring an
                    image of the SS United States on the cover. Other items in the collection
                    include: a copy of The Superliner United States, Rand McNally, 1953; newspaper
                    clippings, 1991-1999, about efforts to refurbish the SS United States; and a
                    handwritten address by Larkin about his model of and visit to the ship, 1996.
                </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ephemera.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships plans.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1999.29; 1999.29.14</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>