<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>J. Welles Henderson manuscript collection <date type="inclusive">1761-1909</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">J. Welles Henderson manuscript collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC1229</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1761-1909</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>J. Welles Henderson (d. 2007) was the founder and former Chairman of the Board of
                    Independence Seaport Museum. Henderson was a graduate of Princeton University
                    and Harvard Law School. After graduating Harvard Law School and establishing
                    himself as an admiralty attorney in Philadelphia, Mr. Henderson began collecting
                    maritime artifacts, amassing an extraordinary collection of maritime books,
                    paintings, and assorted artifacts. A majority of the Independent Seaport
                    Museum's collection was either donated to the Museum by Mr. Henderson or given
                    by donors he cultivated. In 1960, Mr. Henderson drafted the charitable trust
                    document that founded the Museum. In 1961, the U.S. Treasury Department
                    accredited the Museum's tax-exempt status. French Spoliation Claims, demands
                    made upon the U.S. government by American merchants for shipping losses incurred
                    at the hands of the French between 1793 and 1800. The American merchant vessels
                    were sunk by the French, after the U.S. had been charged by France with
                    violating the terms of a commercial treaty concluded between the two countries
                    in 1778, during the American Revolution. The spoliation claims were settled when
                    the U.S. government effectuated the Louisiana Purchase in 1803 and, in addition,
                    assumed the claims of the American merchants against the French to the amount of
                    $3,750,000. Between 1800 and 1850, approximately 50 legislative bills to
                    reimburse the claimants or their descendants came before Congress.
                    Appropriations were voted on two occasions but were vetoed by Presidents James
                    Polk and Franklin Pierce. Finally, in 1885, the claims were adjudicated and the
                    descendants of the original claimants were awarded $4.8 million. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Manuscripts in this collection include invoices and shipping documents from
                    various merchants (late 1700s-late 1800s); an 1802 manuscript of references to
                    the plan of the Navy Yard in Washington; printed broadsides and advertisements;
                    a copy of minutes of an 1800 meeting of the Board of Property of Philadelphia in
                    the hand of Tench Coxe, along with an obituary of Coxe; a small number of
                    business financial documents related to Stephen Girard; and issues of American
                    Military Magazine, 1839-1842); and miscellaneous newspapers 1761-1868. A portion
                    of the materials relate to "French Spoliation," legal claims for payment for
                    lost or seized goods and vessels. Materials include: correspondence between
                    claimants and lawyers; indentures and shipping papers; powers of attorney;
                    statements. A number of the papers relate to the lawyers Lawrence Lewis, Jr. and
                    John Gerhard (1880s). The collection also includes records of a spoliation case
                    handled by William Meredith regarding a ship captured by the Spanish (1797).
                </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">French spoliation claims.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Broadsides.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Business records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Legal documents.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Powers of attorney.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: When processing this collection, we may want to re-integrate material
                    from (1969.120 and others?) that is in the Maritime Document Collection, but was
                    donated by Mr. Henderson.</p>
                <p>Accession number: L94.64; L94.64.1; 1969.120</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>