<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Keith Johnson scrapbook <date type="inclusive">1949-1964</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960-1964</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Keith Johnson scrapbook</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC607</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1949-1964</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960-1964</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The second USS Thresher (SSN-593) was the lead ship of her class of
                    nuclear-powered attack submarines in the United States Navy. Her loss at sea
                    during deep-diving tests in 1963 is often considered a watershed event in the
                    implementation of the rigorous submarine safety program SUBSAFE. The contract to
                    build Thresher was awarded to Portsmouth Naval Shipyard on 15 January 1958, and
                    her keel was laid on 28 May 1958. She was launched on 9 July 1960, was sponsored
                    by Mrs. Frederick B. Warder (wife of the famous Pacific War skipper), and was
                    commissioned on 3 August 1961, with Commander Dean L. Axene in command. Keith
                    Johnson was a Torpedoman Third Class, Silent Service and a member of the crew of
                    the USS Thresher until his wife convinced him not to reenlist when his
                    enlistment was up. Shortly after he left the ship, it was lost in the Atlantic
                    Ocean while performing deep sea diving tests. After the accident, extensive
                    searching was undertaken by the bathyscaphe Trieste, the oceanographic ship
                    Mizar and other ships. The remains of the vessel were finally located some 8400
                    feet below the surface.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Disbound scrapbook of clippings on the nuclear submarine Thresher, including
                    articles about its commissioning, sea trials, and its sinking in 1963 and the
                    resulting search efforts. The bulk of the items in the collection are newspaper
                    clippings. There are also clippings from magazines, a photograph of the
                    Thresher, and envelopes bearing a USS Thresher rubber stamp; an invitation for
                    the commissioning; and several letters to the crew about the shock acoustical
                    trials. The collection also includes several certificates and a submarine
                    qualification card belonging to Keith Johnson.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2000.133</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>