<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Margarethe and Berthold Stern liner ephemera <date type="inclusive">1911-1978</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Margarethe and Berthold Stern liner ephemera</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC586</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1911-1978</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Margarethe (b.1908) and Bertold Stern (b.1900) were married in 1930 in Germany.
                    For their honeymoon, they sailed on the Norddeutscher Breman. In 1933, they
                    immigrated to the United States. They became citizens in 1939. Margarethe's
                    father, Louis Liebmann (b.1873), immigrated to the US and applied fro U.S.
                    citizenship in 1937. Berthold Stern was an allergist and a Captain in the US
                    Army. He was on active duty from 1943 to 1946 and from 1946 to 1953 he was in
                    the officers reserve corps.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of personal papers, photographs, and ephemera of Margarethe
                    and Berthold Stern and Margarethe's father, sister, and brother Louis, Lore, and
                    Fritz Liebmann. Personal papers include: passports and immigration forms and
                    naturalization certificates for Louis, Margarethe, and Lore Liebmann; divorce
                    papers for Lore Leibmann Serlin; identity card of Fritz Liebmann; certificates
                    of appreciation to Berthold Stern for his work for the Selective Service, 1940s;
                    and US Army service records for Berthold Stern. Other items in the collection
                    include: Margarethe's autograph book, 1927; a scrapbook of Lore Liebmann
                    Serlin's wedding and honeymoon; loose, framed, and mounted family photographs;
                    photo albums, including a photo album from trip to Yugoslavia, undated, and a
                    photo album of a trip on the SS Bremen; photo album of Fritz M. Liebmann with
                    photos and postcards from Germany, England, and the United States; souvenir
                    photographs from Bremen, Darmstadt, Yosemite National Park, New York City,
                    Pike's Peak, and other destinations; and a panoramic photo of Berthold Stern's
                    medical training group (24th officer's training battalion) in Carlisle, PA Liner
                    materials include Hamburg-Amerika Line: traveler's checks, luggage stickers, and
                    a letter. A printed guide to the Western Pacific issued to members of the Army,
                    Navy, and Marine Corps </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <famname encodinganalog="600">Liebmann family.</famname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Autograph albums.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Certificates.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ephemera.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photograph albums.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1997.26</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>