<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Marvin Rosefield Keck papers <date type="inclusive">1916-1972</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1916-1920</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Marvin Rosefield Keck papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC679</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1972</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1916-1920</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Marvin Rosefield Keck, (1895-1971) was born in Odebolt, Iowa. During World War I,
                    Keck enlisted in the Navy and was assigned to Admiral Niblack's Flagship Band of
                    the Mediterranean Fleet. During the summer of 1919, the fleet was sent to the
                    Adriatic Sea to sweep mines, and the band played concerts in the Balkan States
                    and Italy. Later in the year, the Flagship Olympia was sent to the Black Sea to
                    inspect ports of Asia Minor. The band played concerts in Constantinople and many
                    other ports. In 1920, Keck married his wife Ethel. In 1921 the Kecks moved to
                    Onida, South Dakota, where Marvin served as the Register of Deeds and Justice of
                    the Peace. While living in Onida, Keck organized a children's band called Keck's
                    Kornet Kids. The Kecks moved to Rapid City in 1934, and Marvin served as a
                    member of the police force for one year before opening a dry cleaning business,
                    which he ran until 1938, when he went to work for the Post Office. Keck directed
                    the Rapid City Post Drum and Bugle Corps, and helped to organized the (South
                    Dakota) State Legion Band, was a member of the Rapid City Municipal Band and the
                    Rapid City Symphony Orchestra, and played bugle for many military funerals. Keck
                    was also a member of the American Legion. He died in 1971. USS Olympia
                    (C-6/CA-15/CL-15/IX-40) was a protected cruiser in the United States Navy during
                    the Spanish-American War. She is most notable for being the flagship of
                    Commodore George Dewey at the Battle of Manila Bay. Olympia continued in service
                    throughout World War I and was decommissioned in 1922. As of 2008, she is a
                    museum ship at the Independence Seaport Museum in Philadelphia,
                    Pennsylvania.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Marvin Rosefield Keck. The collection includes
                    letters sent to Ethel (who would become his wife) from 1916 to 1920, along with
                    typed transcripts of those letters. The letters describe Keck's daily life
                    during training and then as a sailor and musician in the Flagship Band. There
                    are several scrapbooks and photo albums of Keck's Navy service, 1917-1920. The
                    albums include commercial postcards and photo postcards from the fleet's voyages
                    to the Mediterranean, the Adriatic Coast, and the Balkans; photographs of
                    members of the Flagship Band and other sailors; a few images that appear to be
                    earlier photographs of Keck and his family; currency; band programs; calling
                    cards; and other ephemera. Notable among the items in the collection are a set
                    of diaries kept by Keck during his service. The diary entries are brief daily
                    descriptions of training, life aboard the Olympia, and the many concerts played
                    by the band. A printed transcript of diaries and a copy of the transcript on CD
                    are kept with the collection. Also of note are a series of cartoons on political
                    and naval topics drawn by Keck for a cartooning correspondence course; as well
                    as an instruction booklet from the W.L. Evans School of Cartooning of Cleveland,
                    OH. Many of Keck's cartoons are annotated with comments by his instructor. The
                    collection also includes an undated typescript autobiography by Keck; a
                    typescript of Keck's spoof of a war diary, entitled Ezekel's War Diary;
                    typescripts of talks by Keck; photos, news clippings, and programs related to
                    musical groups Keck directed or participated in; and letters related to Keck's
                    nomination as Civil Servant of the Year in Rapid City (of which he was a
                    co-winner).</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Olympia (Cruiser) </corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Autobiographies.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Cartoons (Humorous images)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Diaries.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ephemera.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photograph albums.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Postcards.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Programs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Speeches.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2006.24</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>