<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Mary West collection of RTC Shipbuilding Company records <date type="inclusive">1936-1947</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Mary West collection of RTC Shipbuilding Company
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC2528</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1947</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1940, Leroy M. Robinson (president), George R. Taylor (Vice-president), and
                    John P. Carson (secretary and treasurer) formed RTC Shipbuilding Company in
                    Camden, New Jersey. All three men were former executives at J. H. Mathis
                    Company. Subsequent to the death of Robinson and the retirement of Taylor in
                    1946, Carson became the firm's president and assumed sole ownership. Prior to
                    World War II, the yard produced two oil barges, one tugboat, and six oil
                    tankers. During World War II, 28 self-propelled oil tankers were built for the
                    U.S. Navy. For excellence in workmanship and its high rate of production, the
                    company received two Army-Navy "E" awards, each with four stars. After the
                    war, the yard returned to commercial work and developed the largest trade in
                    repair of medium size work boats and naval vessels in the Delaware Valley Area.
                    Mary West is the granddaughter of George R. Taylor.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of photographs and other materials related to RTC
                    Shipbuilding Co. Subjects of photographs in the collection include: George
                    Taylor and Leroy Robinson; launches, including a launch where Mary West's mother
                    was the sponsor; "E" award ceremony; ships built by RTC and Mathis; and
                    workers. Other items in the collection include: a plan of plant layout; 1940
                    newsletter "Maritime Reports Activity"; and a letter and certificate of
                    commendation of George R. Taylor from the Bureau of Ships, Navy Department,
                    1947.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">RTC Shipbuilding Co. (Camden, N.J.)</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Architectural drawings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Certificates.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>