<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Maurice River Cove and Delaware Bay Oyster Association records
                            <date type="inclusive">1895-1898</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Maurice River Cove and Delaware Bay Oyster Association
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC450</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1895-1898</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1893, the state of New Jersey was divided into seven districts "with a
                    commission of fourteen members to promote the propagation and growth of seed
                    oysters and to protect the natural seed grounds." The legislature empowered the
                    planters' association of Maurice River Cove to make rules governing the
                    industry, to employ guards, and to assess fees. In 1899 the state passed yet
                    another bill to enhance the protective stances of the first two bills. Fifteen
                    years later, New Jersey created the Board of Shell Fisheries to further ensure
                    the longevity of the Delaware Bay oyster harvest, which by 1917 had evolved into
                    a $10 million a year industry.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Maurice River Cove and Delaware Bay Oyster
                    Association. Materials include an account book of the Maurice River Cove and
                    Delaware Bay Oyster Association, 1895-1898. Entries record monies received for
                    licenses; salaries of officers; and expenses, such as printing costs, lobbying
                    costs, and annual meeting costs. The collection also includes a single sheet
                    report of the Collector of the Association, 1898. Bound volume of licenses to
                    plant, grow, and catch oysters in Maurice River Cove and the Delaware Bay,
                    issued to oystermen by the Maurice River Cove and Delaware Bay Oystering
                    Association, 1896. The front flyleaves of both volumes are inscribed with the
                    name of E.B. Cobb, Sailmaker, Bivalve, NJ.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Account books.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1980.6.25</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>