<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Nathan Trotter &amp; Co. records <date type="inclusive">1798-1925</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1798-1862</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Nathan Trotter &amp; Co. records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC451</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.91 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1798-1925</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1798-1862</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Trotter began his apprenticeship with the William Sansom's firm in 1789;
                    after a 7 year apprenticeship, Trotter entered into business with Joseph Sansom,
                    brother of his former employer. In 1803, the Sansom and Trotter partnership was
                    dissolved and William Trotter went into business by himself. In that same year,
                    Nathan Trotter (1787-1853) joined his older brother in business. When William
                    Trotter died in 1815, Nathan Trotter took over as the head of the business and
                    in 1817 the firm's name was changed to Nathan Trotter &amp; Co. Today, the firm
                    is the oldest continuously operated metals manufacturer/distributor in the
                    United States.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of business papers of Nathan Trotter &amp; Co. The bulk of
                    the materials are bills of lading (1803-1850) for items shipped to and by Nathan
                    and William Trotter. There are also bills of lading for goods shipped to William
                    Joseph Sansom, James McAlpin, and other merchants. Other materials in the
                    collection include receipts; bills of freight; sales records; and a small amount
                    of business correspondence. The papers largely relate to trade in hardware items
                    such as iron wire, bundles and bars of steel, and lead sheets shipped during the
                    first half of the nineteenth century.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Bills of lading.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Business records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Receipts (financial records).</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1980.71, 1981.15; 1984.20; L85.005; 1996.22</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Harvard University
                    Business School Baker Library: Nathan Trotter and Company Records, 1798-1955
                    (inclusive); Historical Society of Pennsylvania: Trotter, Nathan and Company
                    Correspondence, 1825-1859 (#1674). </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>