<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Naval correspondence collection <date type="inclusive">1831-1842</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Naval correspondence collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC2505</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1831-1842</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Board of Naval Commissioners was a United States Navy administrative body in
                    existence from 1815 to 1842. The establishment of the Board of Navy
                    Commissioners by act of Congress on February 7, 1815 (3 Stat. 202), was the
                    outgrowth of efforts to relieve the Secretary of the Navy of some of his
                    responsibilities connected with the civil functions of the Navy so that he could
                    devote more time to overall administration. The procurement of naval stores and
                    materials; construction, armament, equipment, repair, and preservation of naval
                    vessels; establishment of regulations to secure uniformity in the classes of
                    naval vessels; preparation of estimates of expenditures for different parts of
                    the naval service; and supervision of navy yards, naval stations, and Navy
                    agents became the responsibilities of the board. The Secretary retained control
                    over personnel and appointments, movement of ships, and other administrative
                    matters not delegated to the board.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of letters (1831 and 1842) to commanders of the
                    Philadelphia Navy Yard, including William Bainbridge, James Barron, George C.
                    Read, and Charles Stewart, from the Navy Commissioners Office. Letters relate to
                    construction and maintenance of Navy Yard facilities; contracts for timber,
                    hardware, and rope; and contracts for the construction of new vessels, including
                    the Raritan and the Philadelphia. Several letters mention the naval architect
                    John Lenthall.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>