<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>New York Shipbuilding Corporation business papers <date type="inclusive">1895-1967</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">New York Shipbuilding Corporation business
                    papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC596</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>28.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1895-1967</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The New York Shipbuilding Corporation (or New York Ship for short) was founded in
                    1899 and opened its first shipyard in 1900. Located in Camden, New Jersey on the
                    east shore of the Delaware River, New York Ship built more than 500 vessels for
                    the U.S. Navy, the United States Merchant Marine, the United States Coast Guard,
                    and other maritime concerns.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Photos and negatives of ships built by the New York Shipbuilding Corporation,
                    contracts #1-542 (not complete). Images include ships during construction,
                    completed ships, launches, a few interior and deck views. There are also
                    photographs of the yard facilities, docks, shops, and equipment; executive
                    staff; participants in the apprentice program; open houses; awards ceremonies;
                    and aerial views of the yard taken in 1960. There are a number of photograph
                    albums of keel laying and launching events (1958-1965). Other materials in the
                    collection include: a small number of general body plans for ships; several
                    plans for shipboard systems; plans and drawings of NYSC yards and buildings;
                    scrapbook of newspaper clippings, 1955-1956, with articles on NYSC and on Louis
                    E Wolfson (board chairman of NYSC); newspaper clippings about a 1935
                    shipbuilders' strike. There are a small number of records records related to
                    specific contract numbers. These materials include job orders, blueprint
                    logbooks, and specifications. Printed materials include: printed contract and
                    specification books, for contract #5-387 (not complete); newsletters (York Ship
                    News, 1919-1921 and Shipways, 1958-1959); histories of NYSC; brochures on ships;
                    launch invitations; and engineering manuals. Other items include facilities
                    inventory, 1964; printed agreement between NYSC and the AFL-CIO, 1966; printed
                    rules of employment, 1966; list of contracts; and a claim by NYSC for an
                    adjustment to the contact with the US Bureau of Ships for USS Kitty Hawk, 1961,
                    and other assorted materials. The collection also includes a small number of
                    materials related to Sun Shipbuilding, including copies of the newsletter Our
                    Yard and plans for a hydro-test stand. And published volumes on the [naval
                    engineering] firm of Merritt-Chapman and Scott. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Architectural drawings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Negatives (Photographic)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1998.15</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>