<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>O. P. Merrill papers <date type="inclusive">1926-1981</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">O. P. Merrill papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC492</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>20.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1926-1981</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Owen P. Merrill (1909-1989) was a noted yacht designer, yachtsman, and sailmaker.
                    As a young man, Merrill worked for Olin Stephens at Sparkman &amp; Stephens in
                    Scarsdale New York. In 1931, he was a member of the crew aboard Dorade which won
                    the Transltlantic Race and the Fastnet race. He also worked for the H. B. Nevins
                    yard in City Island, New York. Initially a chief bosun in the U.S. Coast Guard
                    Temporary Reserve, he skippered Edlu in the "off-shore yacht patrol" in the
                    early part of World War II. Later, he joined the Naval Reserve and commanded a
                    110' wooden subchaser. Following that assignment, he served as navigator aboard
                    an LSD and Fleet Tanker, seeing action at Luzon's Leyte Gulf and Lingayen Gulf,
                    as well as Okinawa. After the war, he worked in Philadelphia for Thomas Bowes,
                    designing small steel commercial vessels. In 1952, he went into the sailmaking
                    business in Delanco, New Jersey , which he continued into his late 60s.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the personal and professional papers of O.P. Merrill.
                    Materials include: photographs and slides of sailboats (many of Comet class
                    boats) with Merrill sails and photos of sailing races (specific vessels include
                    Brilliant, Dorade, Tradescantia, Edlu, and Barfly); photo albums of 1936 Bermuda
                    Race and the crew of Edlu; photo album of 1926-1932 New York Yacht Club cruises;
                    photo album of model yacht and toy boat races in Bristol Harbor (and letter from
                    N.G. Herreshoff to Merrill dated 1931); photo album of a San Francisco Chamber
                    of Commerce cruise, 1929; a photo album from a trip to Portugal and Spain, 1954;
                    log book of the yacht Dorade kept during the 1932 Bermuda Race; and a travel
                    journal from Merrill's trip to Italy in 1978. Plans in the collection include:
                    folded plans for subchasers (designed by Luder's Marine Construction Co. and
                    Sparkman &amp; Stephens), 1941-1942; rolled boat plans by Merrill and others;
                    these include sloops, dinghies, Penguins, Dusters, Comets; plans by Merrill for
                    various types of sails for small craft. Records related to Merril’s business
                    include: business correspondence, including letters from vendors and customers;
                    outgoing correspondence (1961-1965); bills and receipts; product flyers and
                    brochures; files on materials and equipment; financial records, including tax
                    forms, check stubs; Merrill Sails agreement of partnership (between Merrill and
                    Charles W. Lyon, Jr.); dissolution agreement between Merrill and Lyon; a
                    looseleaf binder of sail specifications for Merrill Sails; and several sailcloth
                    sample books and some loose sail cloth samples. Additional materials in the
                    collection include: personal correspondence, 1941-1943, primarily from Merrill's
                    parents (Mr. and Mrs. Edward K. Merrill); personal financial papers, including
                    health records, financial investments, tax returns; Merrill's high school
                    diploma and grammar certificate, mid 1920s; diaries 1927-1930; address books;
                    and ephemera. Printed materials include yearbooks for various classes of
                    sailboats and several bound volumes of Transactions of the Society of Naval
                    Architects and Marine Engineers.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Dorade (Yawl)</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Naval architecture--Designs and plans.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Sails.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Diaries.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Financial records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photograph albums.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships plans.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships' logs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1989.27</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>