<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Pennsylvania Nautical Schoolship Association records <date type="inclusive">1795-2006</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1889-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Pennsylvania Nautical Schoolship Association
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC959</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1795-2006</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1889-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Pennsylvania Nautical School was formed in 1889 by the Pennsylvania State
                    Legislature to fulfill the nation's demand for trained seamen. For 58 years
                    cadets were instructed by U.S. Navy officers in the arts of navigation, marine
                    engineering and seamanship to prepare them for careers in the maritime trades
                    and professions. In 1942 the school was renamed Pennsylvania Maritime Academy
                    (based in Morrisville, Pennsylvania) and in 1947 the Academy closed. Between
                    1889 and 1947, close to 2000 cadets graduated from the program. The Alumni
                    Association was formed in 1955 and publishes two periodicals: The Lookout and
                    The Chronicle. Ships retired from the Navy were retrofitted into schoolships.
                    The Nautical School taught aboard seven different ships over its 58 year
                    history: Sloop-of-War USS Saratoga (1889-1907); Cruiser USS Adams (1907-1914);
                    Gunboat USS Annapolis (1919-1942); Light Cruiser USS Omaha (1940); Ammunition
                    Ship USS Pyro (1940); Cutter USS Keystone State, ex Seneca (1942-1946); and
                    Attack Cargo Ship USS Keystone State II, ex. USS Selinur (1946-1947).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers related to the Pennsylvania Nautical School and
                    the Pennsylvania Nautical Schoolship Association, the Nautical School's alumni
                    association. Files on cadets include: photographs; correspondence from cadets to
                    their families and from the school to families; itineraries; grade sheets;
                    programs; diaries; newspaper clippings; and ephemera. Files on ships include:
                    photographs, negatives, and other images of ship layouts. General school
                    materials include: course materials from the Densmore textbook on various
                    aspects of nautical engineering; newspaper clippings; an 1889 prospectus for the
                    school; diplomas and certificates; copies of The Helm (1924-1946); and copies of
                    The Log of the Pennsylvania Nautical School and The Log of the American Merchant
                    Training Ships (1912-1915). Among the PNS files, a number of items are present
                    as photocopies. Material related to the Schoolship Association includes:
                    invitations and programs from Association events; memorials; directories; a 50th
                    anniversary booklet; copies of The Lookout (1956-2006) and The Chronicle; and a
                    drawing of USS Annapolis. Also included in the collection are a 1795 copy of the
                    Naval Gazetteer, a 1859 bible presented to H. Brower, and a set of 1989 drawings
                    of the Steam Tug Hercules from the San Francisco Maritime National Historical
                    Park.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Seamanship--Study and
                    teaching--Pennsylvania.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Diaries.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Diplomas.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ephemera.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 88.66; 94.20; 86.79; 60.65; non-acc.</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: RG-41 PA State
                    Archives: RG 41, Records of the NAVIGATION COMMISSION FOR THE DELAWARE RIVER AND
                    ITS NAVIGABLE TRIBUTARIES, RG 41.48-41.55 </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>