<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Naval Shipyard collection <date type="inclusive">1862-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Naval Shipyard collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC1247</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.9 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1862-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Philadelphia Naval Shipyard, formerly Navy Yard, was the first naval shipyard
                    of the United States. The site's role as a U.S. Navy facility ended on 30
                    September 1995. Soon after, the West end of the site became a commercial
                    shipyard, currently called the Aker Philadelphia Shipyard. The Navy still
                    maintains a presence at the location, especially via Naval Surface Warfare
                    Center Ship Systems Engineering Station, and the Naval Inactive Ship Maintenance
                    Facility (NIMSF), which continues to store decommissioned and mothballed
                    ships.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>A collection of papers, personnel records and memorabilia related to the
                    Philadelphia Navy Yard. Personnel materials include: employee/telephone
                    directories; employee manuals; instruction manuals for shipriggers, shipfitters,
                    machinists, and welders; trade skills description; glossary of shipbuilding
                    terms; photographs of workers (portraits and candids of people at work and
                    social gatherings); ID badges, stickers, and other ephemera; receipts and notes;
                    and schedules of wages. Other papers and records include: roll of Sparmakers and
                    Boatbuilders, 1873-1881; Foreman's muster book of boatbuilders, coopers, and
                    blockmakers, 1900-1905; List of vessels ordered, 1918-1920; time study for US
                    Navy shipbuilding, 1900-1910; plans on mylar of Naval Shipyard facilities and
                    shops, 1974; booklet of general plans for USS Cimarron, 1939; an 1862 pamphlet
                    "Navy Yard on the Delaware"; several Navy Day programs between 1914 and 1952;
                    Appreciation Week program, 1983; invitations for launchings; Visitors register
                    from the office of the Shipyard Commander, 1964-1996; and PNSY letterhead.
                    Apprentice school materials include: timesheets and schedules; commencement
                    programs and certificates; graduation photographs of apprentices; and yearbooks.
                    Printed materials in the collection include: manuals and journals on equipment
                    and trade skills, many published by the Naval Training and Training Support
                    Command; and printed labor agreements between Philadelphia Naval Shipyard and
                    the Metal Trades Council and the Planners, Estimators &amp; Progressmen
                    Association. Photographs in the collection include: images of the shipyard, a
                    number related to the construction of the USS Dobbin, ca. 1920; other
                    photographs of ship construction from the era of the 1920s; snapshots around the
                    Navy Yard from the 1940s; shots of the drydocks and USS Valley Forge;
                    photographs of the USMC Depot of Supplies, ca. 1940s; a 1981 photograph of the
                    construction of I-95; approximately 150-200 glass lantern slides, c. 1919 and
                    1940s; and slides of "72 shop" ships, machine shops, workers. Closing Ceremony
                    materials include: 4 copies of a video "Historical Journey of Excellence";
                    "Philadelphia Quality Process" video; "Meritorious Commendation Award
                    Ceremony" video; the last ship deck log kept at the PNSY, 1996; 1991 photo of
                    shipyard employees; statements on the yard's closing by members of the "17
                    Shop"; a program and other materials for the 1996 closing ceremony. Additional
                    items include; strategic planning reports; a 1993 Historic Preservation planning
                    report; and a 1989 set of microfiche card index of Navy publications and forms.
                </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Naval Shipyard (Philadelphia,
                    Pa.)</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Architectural drawings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Directories.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ephemera.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Lantern slides.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Manuals (Instructional materials)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Microforms.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Programs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Registers (lists)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships plans.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Slides (Photographs)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Video recordings.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: multiple acc.</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>