<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Pusey &amp; Jones business papers <date type="inclusive">1905-1921</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Pusey &amp; Jones business papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC454</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1905-1921</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Pusey and Jones Corporation was a major ship and equipment manufacturer from
                    1846 to 1959. Ship building was the primary focus from 1853 until the end of
                    World War II, when the company converted the shipyard to production of paper
                    manufacturing machinery. During the operation of the shipyard over 500 ships
                    were produced ranging from large cargo vessels, to small warships and yachts,
                    including “Volunteer” the winner of the 1887 America’s Cup. The company began in
                    1848, with the partnership between Joshua L. Pusey and John Jones in the
                    operation of a machine shop in space rented from a whaling company, in
                    Wilmington, Delaware. The shipyard was located between the Christina River and
                    the main line of the Pennsylvania Rail Road. In 1851 Edward Betts and Joshua
                    Seal, who were operating an iron foundry in Wilmington purchased an interest in
                    the business, and the name of the company then became Betts, Pusey, Jones &amp;
                    Seal. From Wikipedia</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Pusey and Jones. Materials in the collection
                    include: Photographs and/or specifications for hulls #82-323 (not complete);
                    survey of vessels, 1910-1921, listing ships by type, with valuation of vessels
                    when first built and present valuation; preliminary specifications for twin
                    screw and paddle wheel steamers; miscellaneous articles, memos, and technical
                    specifications for WWI and WWII ship construction; and two illustrated
                    catalogues of iron and steel ships produced by Pusey and Jones, early 1900s. The
                    collection also includes engineering logs of H.H. Thayer Jr., 1894-1908. Logs
                    list construction specifications and data, weight summaries, notes on engine
                    performance,and information on materials, displacement, and other naval
                    engineering topics. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Notebooks.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1982.139; 1992.4</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>