<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rice, Unruh, Reynolds Co. records <date type="inclusive">1909-1935</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rice, Unruh, Reynolds Co. records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC433</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1909-1935</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Philadelphia-based ship agency Rice, Unruh, Reynolds Co. For each ship under its
                    management, the company sets the arrival time based on tidal currents, obtains
                    the necessary permission to come into port and arranges for the pilots, tugboats
                    and line handlers. During the 24 hours that a ship is in port, the agents work
                    closely with the Coast Guard and deal with officials at the Customs Border
                    Patrol. They get the ship stored with provisions and spare parts, arrange any
                    repairs that are needed and deal with the medical or dental needs of the seamen
                    on board. If crew members are being repatriated to their homeland, they even
                    arrange for flights home and transportation to the airport.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Collection of records of Rice, Unruh, Reynolds Company. Materials include: index
                    of vessels with information on dates of arrival, where from, broker, master,
                    remarks, tugs, and carrying capacity, 1910-1917; booklet with index of vessel
                    names; card file of employees with name, address, nationality, occupation, and
                    age, many of the cards paired with a Water Front Pass which includes a
                    photograph, 1918; and envelopes from Vincent-Mitchell Studios, with
                    identification photographs of employees. Other files include: an index of
                    barges, alphabetically arranged, and include date, master, carrying capacity,
                    and remarks. (1909-1913); cards listing companies and supplies delivered; lists
                    of ships with arrival date, where from, and cargo, 1920-1926; and list of
                    shipping companies, mostly European addresses, 1934-1935.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Shipping--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Business records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1967.193</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>