<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>R. P. Leary papers <date type="inclusive">1880-1900</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">R. P. Leary papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC453</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1880-1900</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Richard Phillips Leary (1842-1901) was an admiral in the United States Navy who
                    served from the American Civil War through the Spanish-American War. Leary
                    entered the United States Naval Academy in 1860. During the Civil War, he served
                    in screw sloop Canandaigua and monitor Sangamon assigned to the Atlantic
                    blockade. The USS Adams was commissioned to the Pacific Station in 1885 and
                    cruised along the west coast and in Hawaiian and Samoan waters. During tension
                    with Germany over Samoa, Leary commanded the USS Adams at Samoa from October to
                    December 1888. In the Spanish-American War, he commanded the San Francisco (C-5)
                    off Havana, Cuba. From 1899 to 1900, Captain Leary served as Naval Governor of
                    Guam. Retiring in 1901, Rear Admiral Leary died 27 December at Chelsea, Mass. In
                    1943, the destroyer USS Richard P. Leary (DD-664) was named in his honor.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Leatherbound letterbook of Captain R.P. Leary, US Navy, 1896, 1888-1889, and
                    1899-1900. Includes correspondence while Leary was captain of the USS Adams and
                    during his tenure as Governor of Guam. The volume also includes Leary's printed
                    proclamations and general orders. The correspondence from the USS Adams
                    describes conditions in Samoa, attacks on American property, and the rebellion
                    led by Chief Tamasese. The correspondence from Guam includes reports to the
                    Secretary of the Navy on military and civil affairs. These reports also discuss
                    outbreaks of typhoid fever and other medical matters and request supplies and
                    machinery. Other letters relate to staff postings and personnel matters and
                    orders for USS Yosemite, USS Brutus, and other vessels. Proclamations include
                    the announcement of the US occupation and administration of Guam, the outlawing
                    of the practice concubinage; prohibition of the sale of "any intoxicating
                    stimulant, liquid, gelatinous, or solid"; and the abolition of slavery. There
                    are copies of proclamations in English, Spanish, and Chomarro. Some letters
                    relate to issues of religious liberty in Guam under Leary's governorship. Leary
                    expelled a number of Catholic friars from Guam, arguing that they had too much
                    influence on native officials. The collection also includes; a telegram (in
                    code); a passenger list of the US Mail Steamer St. Paul, 1900; copies of general
                    orders of Leary as Governor of Guam, 1899-1900; and several additional letters.
                </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <geogname encodinganalog="651">Guam--Politics and government.</geogname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Letterbooks.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1982.005</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>