<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>RTC Shipbuilding Co. records <date type="inclusive">1934-1965</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">RTC Shipbuilding Co. records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC478</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1934-1965</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1940, Leroy M. Robinson (president), George R. Taylor (Vice-president), and
                    John P. Carson (secretary and treasurer) formed RTC Shipbuilding Company in
                    Camden, New Jersey. All three men were former executives at J. H. Mathis
                    Company. Subsequent to the death of Robinson and the retirement of Taylor in
                    1946, Carson became the firm's president and assumed sole ownership. Prior to
                    World War II, the yard produced two oil barges, one tugboat, and six oil
                    tankers. During World War II, 28 self-propelled oil tankers were built for the
                    U.S. Navy. For excellence in workmanship and its high rate of production, the
                    company received two Army-Navy "E" awards, each with four stars. After the
                    war, the yard returned to commercial work and developed the largest trade in
                    repair of medium size work boats and naval vessels in the Delaware Valley
                    Area.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the RTC Shipbuilding Company. Materials
                    include: plans and specifications for vessels built, repaired, and repowered by
                    RTC (#134-243, not complete); a variety of calculations including hold and tank
                    capacities, displacement, rudder torque, and power and weight; cost estimates
                    for materials and labor; proposals; a small amount of correspondence with parts
                    and equipment suppliers, customers, and the American Bureau of Shipping;
                    materials orders and receipts; product brochures for RTC vessels; trial trip
                    notes; newspaper clippings; and a listing of hulls built by RTC (#131-211).
                    Vessels represented include tugs, barges, yachts, fishing vessels, cruisers,
                    tankers, seine boats, and fire boats. The collection also includes photographs
                    and negatives, 1930s and 1940s, for hulls 131-237 (not complete). Photos
                    document launchings, vessels during construction, vessels on the river, the
                    shipyard, group portraits of staff, launching party guests, and the awarding of
                    the "Army/Navy 'E'" banner to RTC. Subject files in the collection include
                    shipbuilder product brochures, plans, magazine articles, and general design
                    information on yachting, yacht machinery, design, hull data, spar sails,
                    rigging, and ice skimming boats (mid-1930s to mid-1940s). The collection also
                    includes glass plate negatives of ship prints (Jean-Jerome Baugean engravings,
                    and others).</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Naval architecture--Designs and plans.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Glass plate negatives.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Negatives (Photographic)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships plans.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1988.5</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>