<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Samuel M. Vauclain papers <date type="inclusive">1869-1930</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Samuel M. Vauclain papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC2497</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1869-1930</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>USS Periwinkle (1864) was a steamer procured by the Union Navy during the final
                    months of the American Civil War. She served the Union Navy’s struggle against
                    the Confederate States of America as a patrol gunship. USS Standish was an
                    iron-hulled screw tug built at Boston in 1864, completed too late for service in
                    the American Civil War. After completing her trials in January 1866, the ship
                    was laid up at Norfolk until 1871 when she was placed in service at the Norfolk
                    Navy Yard. She was sold on 5 August 1921 to B. Wever &amp; Sons, Baltimore, Md.
                    Samuel Matthews Vauclain (1856 -1940) was a lifelong employee of the Baldwin
                    Locomotive Works Company. He was a locomotive manufacturer, inventor, salesman,
                    and international businessman. One of his many achievements was the invention of
                    the compound locomotive in 1889. His brother James L. Vauclain (1838 and 1874)
                    was 1st Assistant Engineer on the USS Periwinkle and the USS Standish. In 1861,
                    James L. Vauclain a mechanic for the Lafayette and Indianapolis Railroad,
                    patented a locomotive smokestack that saved fuel and increased power by means of
                    a moveable throat that could be controlled by the engineer, and by employing a
                    smaller stack from which ashes and dust would be thrown higher.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of the Vauclain family. Materials include: logbook
                    of USS Periwinkle &amp; USS Standish, 1869-1870; certificate of appointment of
                    James L. Vauclain as 3rd Assistant Engineer, US Navy; passports for Samuel M.
                    Vauclain, Anna Vauclain and her children; certificates of appointment of Samuel
                    M. Vauclain as member of the Pennsylvania Commission to construct a bridge over
                    the Delaware River; and a small collection of correspondence between Matthew
                    Branch, president of American International Shipbuilding Corporation and Samuel
                    M. Vauclain and his daughter Constance regarding her sponsorship of the Quaker
                    City, which was launched in 1919.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Periwinkle (Steamer)</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Standish (Tug)</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Certificates.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Passports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>