<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Schuylkill Navy records <date type="inclusive">1865-1977</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Schuylkill Navy records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC466</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>24 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1865-1977</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Schuylkill Navy of Philadelphia is the oldest amateur athletic governing body
                    in the United States. It was founded in 1858 with nine clubs and approximately
                    300 members. . The member clubs of the Navy are all located on the Schuylkill
                    River where it flows through Fairmount Park in Philadelphia, with most of the
                    clubs being located on the historic Boathouse Row. Clubs represented at the
                    founding of the society in October 1858 included America, Camilla, Chebucto,
                    Falcon, Independent, Keystone, Neptune, Pennsylvania, and University. Later that
                    month Nautilus and Quaker City joined. Half of the clubs lapsed during the Civil
                    War. Current member clubs include Fairmount Rowing Association, Crescent Boat
                    Club, Bachelors Barge Club, University Barge Club, Malta Boat Club, Vesper Boat
                    Club, College Boat Club, Penn Athletic Club Rowing Association (Penn AC), Undine
                    Barge Club, Philadelphia Girls' Rowing Club (PGRC), Gillin Boat Club and St.
                    Joseph's University and St. Joseph's Prep. At least 23 other clubs have belonged
                    to the Navy at various times. By charter, "its object is to secure united
                    action among the several Clubs and to promote amateurism on the Schuylkill
                    River." Each club sends a delegate to the monthly meetings and the clubs elect
                    the officers of the Schuylkill Navy at the January meeting. The Schuylkill Navy
                    and its member clubs still host many races. In 1953, the Navy convinced the Dad
                    Vail Rowing Association to move its regatta to Philadelphia. It has remained
                    since. The Dad Vail is probably the largest collegiate regatta held and usually
                    signifies the end of the spring rowing season for most collegiate teams. Other
                    major regattas held each year include the Thomas Eakins Head of the Schuylkill
                    Regatta (sponsored by the University Barge Club) and the Frostbite Regatta. The
                    Navy also sponsors other athletic endeavors including a basketball league and an
                    annual cross country race. The latter has been held since 1899, with a few
                    interruptions during World War II.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of the Schuylkill Navy. Materials include: minutes
                    of meetings of the Schuylkill Navy, attended by representatives of each of the
                    Navy's constituent clubs, 1865-1954 (missing 1883-1888) and 1955-1966. The
                    minutes discuss routine business, including committee reports and rewriting of
                    the group's constitution and by-laws, preparation for regattas, and activities
                    of member clubs. Correspondence of the Schuylkill Navy’s secretaries include
                    incoming and outgoing correspondence to member rowing clubs, individual members,
                    and other Philadelphia area clubs and organizations. Letters discuss planning of
                    regattas and other events, membership, meetings, and equipment and property of
                    the Schuylkill Navy. Office records, 1940s-1960s, include files on regattas,
                    treasurer's files, financial records, including account books, check registers,
                    and member lists, by-laws, charter, and other records. Materials related to
                    regattas include: correspondence, programs, announcements, 1867-1972 (bulk 1930s
                    and 1960s); logbooks of participants and outcomes, 1873-1965; photos,
                    correspondence, programs, and clippings related to the Philadelphia Gold
                    Challenge Cup, 1930s-1950s; scrapbooks (disbound) of programs and clippings,
                    1913-1940: programs are annotated with scores and outcomes of races); clippings;
                    and regatta programs, 1880-1955, of regattas held by the Schuylkill Navy and
                    local and regional regattas held by other rowing clubs. Records related to other
                    rowing organizations include: files related to FISA, the international rowing
                    federation, including member bulletins, annual reports, and proceedings of
                    annual congresses; National Association of Amateur Oarsmen records including
                    correspondence, minutes, financial information, and office files; correspondence
                    related to donations for the US Olympic Rowing Team (1950-1952); and minutes of
                    the Middle States Regatta Association, 1888-1961. Records for the Schuylkill
                    Navy Basketball League, 1957-1970, include schedules, player lists, and score
                    books. Files related to the Schuylkill Navy Cross Country Run, 1925-1965,
                    include programs, race results, reports, and correspondence. Scrapbooks, 1928,
                    1935-1946, 1947-1960, 1966, include clippings, programs, and photographs.
                    Photographs in the collection, 1940s-1970s, include portraits of rowing crews,
                    photos of crews during races, (some with information about the crew). Many of
                    these are of university or prep school crews. The collection also contains bound
                    and some loose copies of Rowing News, 1943-1959, and flags of the United States,
                    Canada, and the Soviet Union.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">National Association of Amateur Oarsmen
                    (U.S.)</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Regattas--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Rowing clubs--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Rowing--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Bylaws.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Constitutions.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Programs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1985.23</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>