<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Schuylkill Canal Transportation Line records <date type="inclusive">1872-1875</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Schuylkill Canal Transportation Line records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC440</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1872-1875</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Schuylkill Navigation Company was chartered in 1815 to build a series of
                    navigation improvements in the Schuylkill River. A 108-mile waterway was
                    completed in 1827 linking Philadelphia to Port Carbon in the anthracite coal
                    fields above Pottsville, Pennsylvania. During the 1860s the canal entered a
                    period of decline. In 1869 it was damaged by a flood. Surrendering to the
                    competition in 1870, the Schuylkill Navigation Company leased its waterway to
                    the Philadelphia and Reading Railroad for a period of 979 years. Under the
                    railroad's control, the Schuylkill Navigation continued to decline. Since the
                    Delaware and Raritan Canal was owned by the competing Pennsylvania Railroad,
                    Schuylkill boats were denied access to this important New Jersey waterway. As a
                    result, traffic on the Schuylkill decreased rapidly. By 1890 only 144,994 tons
                    of cargo passed through the Schuylkill Navigation. The Schuylkill Navigation was
                    also greatly hindered by the problems of coal silt deposits which made its upper
                    sections almost unusable. By 1891 the portion of Navigation above Port Clinton
                    was abandoned. By 1904 the anthracite traffic had almost completely ceased, and
                    after 1913 only an occasional cargo passed between Port Clinton and
                    Philadelphia. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>One volume of records of the Schuylkill Canal Transportation Line. Volume
                    includes: lists of canal barges, with captain, address, year built, builder,
                    where wintered and notes; list of letters sent, 1874; list of discharged
                    captains, 1873. Includes reason for discharge; a list of captains who quit
                    dishonorably, 1874; lists of damages and collisions, 1872-1875. Includes notes
                    about the incidents and costs of repairs; Engineer's Department charges for
                    assistance and repairs to boats, 1874-1875; and a list of P&amp;R RR Co.
                    officers for 1874. The cover of the volume is inscribed "G.T. Philips, Boat
                    Agent, Office Schuylkill Canal Transportation Line, Fairmount Locks,
                    Philadelphia, PA. P &amp; R RR Co."</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia &amp; Reading Railroad Co.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Schuylkill Navigation Company.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Inland waterway vessels.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Business records.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1971.9</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>