<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Stephen Girard business papers <date type="inclusive">1792-1800</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Stephen Girard business papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC1115</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1792-1800</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Philadelphia businessman, shipbuilder, banker, humanitarian, Stephen Girard
                    (1750–1831), played a major role in the early trade with China. Girard was
                    French-born, but after nine years as a sailor, he found his way to America. He
                    then found his way to the city of Philadelphia at the beginning of the
                    Revolutionary War. Philadelphia’s shipbuilding industry was expanding and
                    Girard, a former sea captain who understood sailing and ships, was placing
                    orders for the construction of an advanced fleet of ships. His ships sailed
                    regularly to China. As a tribute to his homeland’s philosophers he named his
                    ships Rousseau, Voltaire, Montesquieu, and Helvetius. By 1793 Girard’s business
                    was international and his China trade business was of major importance in making
                    him one of the few millionaires in America. He helped establish the First Bank
                    of America in Philadelphia. Girard was so wealthy that he was able to loan the
                    U.S. government $1.5 million during the War of 1812. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Freight books and disbursements for the ship Good Friends, the brig Sally, the
                    brig Liberty, the Voltaire, and other vessels, 1795-1800. Also included are
                    miscellaneous invoices and a customs permit (1792-1794). </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Business records.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 95.63, 78.58, 82.21</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>