<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sun Shipbuilding &amp; Dry Dock Company records <date type="inclusive">1916-1986</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sun Shipbuilding &amp; Dry Dock Company records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC917</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>26 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1986</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Sun Shipbuilding and Dry Dock Company was incorporated in May 23, 1916 as a
                    tanker-building subsidiary of the Sun Oil Company. Soon after its founding it
                    began building ships for other companies. During World War II, the National
                    Defense Program helped make the Sun shipyard one of the world's biggest
                    producers of oil tankers. The company launched its final ship in 1980.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of Sun Shipbuilding plans, photographs, and
                    printed materials. Plans for vessels built by Sun Shipbuilding are arranged in
                    hull number order from #1 to 683. Most of the plans are general arrangements,
                    with a small number of plans for other systems, including shell plating,
                    trusses, and propellers. The collection also includes aperture cards of plans
                    for hulls #3-100 (not complete). Most of the photographs and negatives document
                    vessels built by the company (hull #17 to 678), but there are also photographs
                    of executive staff and images of the yard, including several aerial views.
                    Business records of Sun Shipbuilding include: lists and registers of ships;
                    rolled charts of hulls built by Sun from 1931 to 1981 (listing ship name,
                    construction and delivery dates, measurements, owner, engine type, cargo
                    capacity, and other information); launching brochures (1950s-1970s); records
                    related to trial trips, including schedules and personnel lists; typescripts of
                    articles on ship design by Merville Willis (a naval architect for Sun
                    Shipbuilding) on naval design; a small collection of papers of George Blair (an
                    employee of Sun), including an identification card, pay sheets, and photographs;
                    specification books for specific hulls; an Engineer's Operating Manual for hull
                    610/611, including system blueprints and text descriptions; course materials on
                    engineering topics including a set of “class notes” on combustion, 1948, and
                    diesel test questions from the 1940s; and magazine and newspaper clippings about
                    Sun (1930s-1981). Materials printed by Sun Shipbuilding include: advertising
                    booklets and brochures on products and services; Our Yard (1945, 1954-1956,
                    1960-1965); Sun Ship Log, 1978-1979; miscellaneous staff newsletters; and a copy
                    of the 1986 Centennial Celebration: The Story of Sun Company. The collection
                    also includes brochures, booklets, and reports of the United Seaman's Service
                    and the U.S. Maritime Service (1940s); various other printed materials on
                    shipfitting, rigging, pumps, and engines; and brochures of other shipbuilding
                    and transportation companies.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Naval architecture--Designs and plans.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Shipbuilding--Pennsylvania--Chester.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Negatives (Photographic)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Registers (lists)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships plans.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 84.76; 94.115; 93.80; 85.72; 85.62; 86.9; 93.78; non-acc.</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>