<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sylvester M. Kohut papers <date type="inclusive">1937-1990</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sylvester M. Kohut papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC642</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1937-1990</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Sylvester Kohut (b. 1913) was born in McAdoo, PA. He attended McAdoo High School
                    and Valparaiso University. In 1936 he enlisted in the US Navy. After boot camp
                    at Newport, R.I., he also completed Torpedo School. He served on several Naval
                    Ships. In June 1942, he was assigned to Submarine School, New London CT. On Feb.
                    15, 1943 he was transferred to the USS Jack. He also served aboard the Dixie,
                    Balch, Grouper, Trutta, Queenfish, and Argonaut. In 1944 he was awarded the
                    Silver Star for gallantry in action against the Japanese. He entered the Naval
                    Reserves in 1956, and retired in 1966. After his retirement Kohut obtained a
                    degree from the Banking Institute and worked in a Philadelphia bank. Prior to
                    his enlistment in the Navy, he served in "some kind of army unit or defense
                    unit" (photo of Kohut at Fortress Monroe, VA, 1928-1932) that was "set up
                    during the depression." </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers documenting the naval career of Sylvester Kohut.
                    Materials include: correspondence, service records, and certificates, including
                    a "crossing the line" certificate; Navy basic training handbook on the use of
                    tools, 1945; newspaper clippings; "Ancient Order of the Deep" wallet card;
                    sketch of Kohut drawn by a member of his crew; miscellaneous materials related
                    to ships on which Kohut served, including a history of the USS Jack, and a
                    photocopy of the log of the USS Grouper. Photographs in the collection include:
                    a photo of Kohut in uniform and with his wife; his training company at Newport,
                    RI; crews of the Alstede, the Balch, the Trutta, and the Grouper; photos of the
                    USS Jack, the Dixie, and the Trutta; and of social gatherings. The collection
                    also contains documents related to Kohut's receiving the Silver Star in 1944,
                    including photographs, news clippings, and a citation. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Certificates.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Military records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2003.18</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>