<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas W. Walsh papers on USS Lawrence <date type="inclusive">1960-1962</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas W. Walsh papers on USS Lawrence</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC680</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.66 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-1962</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>USS Lawrence (DDG-4), the fifth ship named for Captain James Lawrence USN
                    (1781-1813), was a Charles F. Adams-class destroyer commissioned in 1962, and
                    serving until 1994. The ship's motto was "Don't Give Up The Ship" Commander
                    Thomas W. Walsh (b. 1921), was a graduate of the United States Naval Academy,
                    the United States Naval Post-Graduate School (Naval Intelligence), and the Armed
                    Forces Staff College. Walsh served during World War II aboard the USS Nevada and
                    participated in the invasions of Normandy, Southern France, Iwo Jima, and
                    Okinawa. After the war he served on the USS Joseph P. Kennedy, as Executive
                    Officer of the USS Dortch, and Commanding Officer of USS Tweedy. He also served
                    in several staff appointments, including as Head of Cold War Intelligence
                    Section in the Office of the Chief of Naval Operations. In 1961 he reported at
                    New York Shipbuilding Corporation, Camden, NJ under orders to commission and
                    command Lawrence. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers related to the launch, commissioning, and
                    shakedown cruise of USS Lawrence, 1960-1962. Materials include: correspondence,
                    including letters of appreciation to Walsh as commander of USS Lawrence from
                    various naval officers, politicians, and business figures; launch invitations,
                    programs, and photos; brochures and pictorial booklet for commissioning;
                    transcript of remarks by Cdr. Walsh given at the commissioning of USS Lawrence;
                    newspaper clippings about the visit of the USS Lawrence to Quebec, Cleveland,
                    Detroit, Buffalo, Toronto, Montreal, and Halifax; press releases; and an
                    itinerary for the commissioning ceremony and the Great Lakes Cruise. Other items
                    in the collection include: portraits of the ship and photos of launching,
                    commissioning ceremony, crew at work, and officers; reel-to-reel audio; reel of
                    movie film; an ash tray; and a pennant. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Lawrence (Guided Missile Destroyer)</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Artifacts.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Motion pictures.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Sound recordings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Speeches.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2007.008</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>