<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas D. Bowes, M.E., Associates records <date type="inclusive">1905-1982</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1905-1965</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas D. Bowes, M.E., Associates records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC463</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>129.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1905-1982</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1905-1965</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas D. Bowes (1883-1965) was graduated from Cornell University in 1905. In the
                    same year, he founded the naval architecture firm of Thomas D. Bowes, M.E.,
                    Associates, Inc. The firm designed over eighty tugboats and several of
                    Philadelphia's fireboats. The firm also designed over 300 yachts, mostly
                    "commuter" and "houseboat" yachts. Bowes designed the 23' 9" "A" class
                    sloop for the Corinthian Yacht Club of Philadelphia, of which he was a member.
                    In addition to being a businessman, Bowes served on the advisory committee of
                    the U.S. Council of National Defense and the Anti-Submarine Warfare Committee of
                    the U.S. Naval Consulting Board during the first World War. During the Second
                    World War, he designed minesweepers and submarine chasers for the U.S. Navy.
                    Bowes also designed and patented the Bowes Drive, an electric device for the
                    reduction of speed between engine and drive shaft in marine installations.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of plans and records of the naval architecture firm of
                    Thomas D. Bowes, M.E., Associates, Inc. Materials include: rolled design plans,
                    design #1-878 (1906-1964); and rolled design plans by job order, #9131-9504
                    (1944-1963). These include construction plans, deck plans, general arrangement
                    plans, inboard and outboard profiles, lines and offsets, hold plans, rigging and
                    sail plans, midship section plans, and other machinery, equipment, and
                    structural plans. Vessel types include barges, cargo vessels, catboats,
                    cruisers, ferries, fireboats, houseboats, runabouts, schooners, sloops, tankers,
                    tugs, and yachts. Designs are by Bowes, Bowes and Mower, and Bowes and Watts.
                    The collection also includes design plan files for designs #710 to 857 and some
                    job order records. These files include drawings and machinery plans,
                    specifications, correspondence, calculations, inspection reports, engine and
                    generator tests, work orders, product catalogues, and press releases. Business
                    records of the firm include: correspondence, patents, and descriptions with
                    plans and photos of the Bowes Drive; patents for other inventions by Bowes;
                    correspondence related to patent applications and renewals; description and
                    drawings of the "Magnetic 4" a car designed by Bowes to run on a magnetic
                    transmission; a brochure of tugs designed by Bowes and built by RTC
                    Shipbuilding; 1961-1964 corporate records, including bylaws and board of
                    trustees minutes; contracts and bids; publicity on vessels designed by Bowes,
                    including tugs and fireboats; correspondence related to sales of fireboats to
                    various port cities in the United States and abroad; legal agreements,
                    correspondence, plans, and other records related to work done for Fiedler and
                    Sellers on diesel engines (mid-1940s); reprints and extracts of articles on
                    naval engineering and architecture; product catalogues; reports, including a
                    1960 Delaware River Basin study by the U.S. Army Engineers; photographs of
                    vessels, including tugs, fireboats; and a photo album (disbound) with images of
                    the construction of Arthur Hoyt Scott. Printed volumes in the collection include
                    Machine Design (1903), Shipfitting Practice (1941), and Shipbuilding Shop
                    Fabrication (1943). The collection also includes personal papers of Thomas D.
                    Bowes, including a small amount of personal correspondence, photographs, a 1905
                    Cornell University yearbook, and Bowes' will and related estate documents.
                    Materials in the collection related to the Corinthian Yacht Club, 1951-1970,
                    include; minutes, treasurer's reports, race committee reports, race results,
                    memoranda, and correspondence, and photographs and negatives of launches and
                    trials of sailing vessels.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Corinthian Yacht Club of Philadelphia.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Marine engineering--United States.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Naval architecture--Designs and plans.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Naval architecture--United States.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Yachts--Design and construction.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Press releases.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships plans.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1984.9, 1984.10, 1997.19, 1994.109, and non-acc.</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>