<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>U.S. Arsenal records <date type="inclusive">1804-1817</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">U.S. Arsenal records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC431</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1804-1817</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The US Arsenal (known after 1860 as the Schuylkill Arsenal) was constructed in
                    Philadelphia 1800. It began as a warehouse for ammunition and other military
                    supplies used by the United States armed services. It was the third such federal
                    facility in the young nation. It outfitted the Lewis and Clark Expedition in
                    1803 and supplied arms for the War of 1812. After that war, the US Arsenal
                    ceased to be the main storehouse for ammunition and arms, that branch of
                    supplies being transferred to the Frankford Arsenal. In 1818, the US Arsenal
                    gave up its distribution of arms altogether to dedicate itself to manufacturing,
                    storing and distributing clothing and textile materials. The original site of
                    the arsenal at Grays Ferry Avenue and Washington Avenue was closed and razed in
                    1963. Other names by which the arsenal was known during its history are the
                    Philadelphia Depot of the Quartermaster's Department and the Philadelphia
                    Quartermaster's Intermediate Depot.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is an account book of the US Arsenal containing a detailed listing of
                    receipts and disbursements for armed services including the US Navy and US
                    Marine Corps for the period 1804-1817. Notable entries include supplies for the
                    frigate Guerriere, numerous mentions of the gun ship Franklin, cannisters for
                    the Prometheus, and a mention of Commodore Rodgers. A number of entries are for
                    supplies received from George Harrison, Navy agent.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Arsenals--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Military supplies.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Account books.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Military records.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1965.18</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>