<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>United States Shipping Board Emergency Fleet Corporation records
                            <date type="inclusive">1918-1919</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">United States Shipping Board Emergency Fleet Corporation
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC521</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Because of the need during World War I to build ships rapidly, on 16 April 1917
                    the U.S. Shipping Board incorporated the Emergency Fleet Corporation to build,
                    own, and operate a merchant fleet for the U.S. government. It performed these
                    functions until 11 February 1927, when Congress changed its name to the Merchant
                    Fleet Corporation. In 1916 the shipbuilding industry completed only 300,000
                    deadweight tons of ships, whereas the United States during war needed an annual
                    output of 6 million to 10 million deadweight tonnage. To meet this emergency the
                    Fleet Corporation first requisitioned the 431 steel ships being built in
                    American yards for foreign operators. Second, the corporation built three great
                    steel shipyards and invested in many other yards. To speed up construction,
                    yards assembled "fabricated" ships of standard design out of plates and parts
                    made in factories as far west as Kansas.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Collection of records of the United States Shipping Board Emergency Fleet
                    Corporation. Materials include: bound set of charts of shipyard locations and
                    plans of plant layouts of facilities building vessels for the Emergency Fleet
                    Corporation; information for bidders on the fabrication of the steel work for
                    7500 ton class A vessel at Hog Island, to be constructed by the American
                    International Shipbuilding Corporation; a wage scale for employees in shipyards;
                    and lists of vessels being built for the Emergency Fleet Corporation, including
                    vessel name, class, hull number, builder, and location. Other items in the
                    collection include: vessel registration cards; an application for leave; a pass
                    property issued to L. Snyder; two published volumes prepared by the Emergency
                    Fleet Corporation: Hull Specifications and Fastening Specifications; and pay
                    packets from the American International Shipbuilding Corporation, agent for the
                    Emergency Fleet Corporation. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">American International Shipbuilding
                    Corporation.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">United States Shipping Board Emergency Fleet
                    Corporation.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Shipbuilding--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Architectural drawings.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1993.37, 1994.97.1-6, 1982.156.42-52; 88.20, 87.41, 90.49, and
                    non-acc.</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>