<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William McCoy papers <date type="inclusive">1893-1986</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1920s-1950s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William McCoy papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC509</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1893-1986</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1920s-1950s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William (Bill) McCoy graduated from the Pennsylvania Nautical Schoolship Saratoga
                    in 1895. After graduation, he and his brother and lifetime companion, Ben, moved
                    to Holly Hill, Florida, near Daytona Beach to establish a boatbuilding and
                    passenger service. During the Prohibition era, Bill McCoy became a national
                    legend. He went to Nassau, Bahamas and bought a 130' schooner named Arethusa. He
                    made frequent trips to rendezvous with rumrunners in international waters 12
                    miles off the coast of New York. Between 1921 and 1926, Arethusa had landed
                    170,000 cases of whiskey to rumrunners. Technically, McCoy never broke U.S. law
                    because he sold his whiskey outside of government jurisdiction. He is credited
                    with coining the phrase "the real McCoy," referring to his "patented"
                    whiskey: the catchy phrase and a facsimile of his signature appeared on the
                    bottle. According to his brother Ben, "when the country went dry, [Bill]
                    irrigated it."</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists primarily of three scrapbooks about Bill and Ben McCoy.
                    The scrapbooks contain photographs of the McCoy brothers, their mother, father,
                    and sister Violet; photographs of Arethusa, Blue Lagoon, and other vessels;
                    photographs of USS Saratoga and its crew; photographs from the Bahamas and
                    Florida; photographs of models and paintings of ships by Bill McCoy; magazine
                    articles and newspaper clippings on rum running, on Bill McCoy, on the Stetson
                    mansion in Florida (owned by the McCoy family), and other topics; letters to
                    Bill McCoy, Ben McCoy, and Rosemary Clarke from various correspondents,
                    including Gertrude "Cleo" Lythgoe; brochures and photographs from the McCoy
                    Brothers Everglades Steamer Line; Ben McCoy's passport; cartoons; whiskey
                    labels; sketches of ships; membership cards; and maps, postcards, and stamps.
                    There are also several published volumes: The Real McCoy by Frederic Van de
                    Water; The Bahama Queen by Gertrude "Cleo" Lythgoe; and Home is the Sailor, by
                    Commodore Herbert Hartley. The volumes include photographs, letters, and
                    clippings. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Smuggling.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Cartoons (Humorous images)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ephemera.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Passports.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Postage stamps.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Postcards.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1991.23; 1989.57</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>