<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William Cummings and Son records <date type="inclusive">1853-1879</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Independence Seaport Museum</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William Cummings and Son records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">ISMSp.ACC499</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Independence Seaport Museum<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1853-1879</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Cummings and Son were shipping merchants in Philadelphia. William
                    Cummings (b. 1806) went into business with his uncle (also named William
                    Cummings) in 1826. In 1830 he went into business for himself. He owned several
                    schooners, brigs, barques, and ships, including the ship William Cummings. Some
                    time before 1864, Cummings' son, Norris S. Cummings, joined the business. Over
                    its history, the firm operated out of various locations near the Delaware River,
                    including South Delaware Avenue, Walnut Street and Dock Street. The firm was in
                    operation until at least 1880.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of William Cummings and Son. The collection
                    consists of three volumes. The first volume is a receipt book (1864-1879) of the
                    firm of William Cummings and Son, listing amounts paid for crew wages, pilotage,
                    wharfage, labor and supplies. The ships William Cummings and Ann Elizabeth are
                    mentioned frequently in this volume. The second volume is a letterbook of the
                    firm kept between 1853 and 1866. Letters to ships' captains and merchants
                    discuss market conditions, shipments of goods, bills and accounts, damages to
                    vessels, and other business matters. This volume also includes several lists of
                    cargoes and notes on freights and freighting. The third volume is a record book
                    of a voyage of the ship William Cummings from Callao, Peru to Calcutta, India,
                    to Philadelphia, PA (1858-1859). Most entries list winds, weather, courses, and
                    remarks on unusual occurrences, such as punishments of crew. This volume also
                    includes logs of the time the ship was in harbor in Callao and Calcutta, and a
                    list of stores received at Calcutta.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Shipping--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Letterbooks.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Receipts (financial records).</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ships' logs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1990.31; 1976.52; and 82.259</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>