<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edwin Wolf and John Fleming working papers for Rosenbach: a
                        biography <date type="inclusive">1953-1974</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edwin Wolf and John Fleming working papers for Rosenbach: a
                    biography</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">RM&amp;Sp.ACC1769</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953-1974</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Edwin Wolf 2nd (1911-1991) was a librarian, bibliophile, author, historian,
                    Franklin scholar, and civic leader. Wolf worked with Dr. A.S.W. Rosenbach for
                    nearly twenty years, compiling many of the company's catalogs. He was the
                    Curator of the Library Company of Philadelphia from 1953 to 1955, and its
                    Librarian from 1955 to 1984. John Fleming worked with Dr. Rosenbach from 1925
                    until the latter's death in 1952. He became a Vice President of the Rosenbach
                    Company in 1948 and succeeded to the business in 1954. He was also a member of
                    the Board of Trustees of the Rosenbach Foundation. Wolf and Fleming co-authored
                    Rosenbach: A Biography, which was published in 1960.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the working papers for Wolf and Fleming's biography of
                    A.S.W. Rosenbach. The collection includes: typescripts with annotations; page
                    proofs; pre-publishing reader's and editor's comments; clippings of reviews; a
                    small amount of publicity materials, including a sales brochure for the book;
                    correspondence with publishers, reviewers, and readers; and typed and
                    handwritten notes on Rosenbach's business transactions.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>