<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>George Sims papers <date type="inclusive">1666-1924</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1873-1924</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">George Sims papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">RM&amp;Sp.ACC1764</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1666-1924</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1873-1924</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>George Robert Sims (1847-1922) was an English journalist, dramatist, and poet. In
                    1874, Sims was invited to join the staff of Fun, a downmarket Punch, to replace
                    Tom Hood. In 1876, employing the pseudonym Dagonet, he began to write "Mustard
                    and Cress," a weekly column for the Referee that appeared without fail until
                    the week of his death forty-six years later. His reports of some of his forays
                    into the worst of London slums, commissioned by Pictorial World, were
                    subsequently published as How the Poor Live (1883). Sims's first play, Crutch
                    and Toothpick, was produced at the Royalty Theatre in April 1879, and was
                    followed by a number of plays of which he was author or part-author. After long
                    runs at West End houses, many of these became stock pieces in suburban and
                    provincial theaters. His most famous melodramas were The Lights of London, In
                    the Ranks, and Harbour Lights.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the correspondence of George Robert Sims. Included in the
                    collection are letters from J.M. Barrie, Jerome K. Jerome, Hall Caine, Ingleby
                    Oddie (on the subject of Arthur Conan Doyle and spiritualism), Lillie Langtree,
                    Andrew Chatto, H.B. Irving, and others. Many of the letters discuss Sims'
                    journalism and plays, social work, and appointments. The collection also
                    includes letters from Sims to Clement Scott, a dramatic critic (mainly for the
                    Daily Telegraph) and playwright. In addition the collection contains a small
                    batch of playbills, cabinet cards, postcards, menus, tickets, and clippings.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>