<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Thurloe papers <date type="inclusive">1654-1659</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Thurloe papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">RM&amp;Sp.ACC1765</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.58 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1654-1659</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Thurloe (1616-1668) was a secretary to the council of state of the
                    Commonwealth of Great Britain under Oliver Cromwell. He was given charge of the
                    intelligence department in 1653, which included foreign and domestic espionage,
                    and the post office in 1655. Through the post office Thurloe was able to
                    intercept information of plots against the government. He entered Parliament in
                    1654, and supported the succession of Richard Cromwell in 1658. He was deprived
                    of office after the fall of the Protectorate, and was arrested for high treason
                    after the Restoration in 1660. He was not tried, and was released on the
                    condition that his services be available to the Restoration government.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection of five volumes contains copies of letters received by John
                    Thurloe and important state papers and news letters. The volumes correspond to
                    six of Thurloe's original volumes (which appear to have numbered at least 66)
                    and cover the years 1654 to 1659. The letters discuss some of the most important
                    events of the period, including the plot to assassinate Cromwell, naval affairs,
                    and Cromwell's death in 1658 and the succession of his son Richard as Lord
                    Protector. The original volumes are in the holdings of the Bodleian Library and
                    the British Museum.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Pennsylvania, Rare Book and Manuscript Library: Copies of letters and reports
                    sent to, or prepared for, John Thurloe as head of the English Intelligence
                    Department, November-December 1656 : manuscript, 1706.; Ms. Codex 215.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>