<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Katherine Minehart Lewis Carroll collection <date type="inclusive">1932-2003</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1967-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Katherine Minehart Lewis Carroll collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">RM&amp;Sp.ACC1767</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1932-2003</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1967-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Katherine "Kitty" Minehart was the director of the Germantown Theatre Guild.
                    She was married to the actor and writer Dan Lounsbery, who died in 1993. In
                    1963, the Germantown Theatre Guild staged a production of "Alice," a dramatic
                    adaptation of Lewis Carroll's Alice in Wonderland. This production sparked
                    Minehart's interest in Lewis Carroll and his characters, particularly Alice.
                </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection of Alice in Wonderland ephemera falls into two basic segments:
                    theatrical adaptations of the Alice story and the use of images and themes from
                    the story in media (advertising, greeting cards, cartoons, newspaper articles).
                    The theater-related ephemera includes playbills, announcements, newspaper and
                    magazine clippings of reviews and advertisements, posters, and a copy of Eva le
                    Galienne's annotated script for her adaptation of "Alice in Wonderland." Other
                    ephemera includes clippings, cartoons, advertisements, greeting cards, auction
                    catalogs, magazines, announcements and catalogs for exhibitions, and programs
                    and announcements from the Lewis Carroll Society of North America. The
                    collection also includes several books, including a memorial tribute to Charles
                    Dodgson, parodies of Alice in Wonderland and adaptations of the story.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>