<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Phil Phillips papers <date type="inclusive">1944-1975</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Phil Phillips papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">RM&amp;Sp.ACC1768</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1944-1975</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Philip Phillips (1900-1994) was an American archaeologist and an amateur Joyce
                    scholar. He graduated from Williams College in 1922 and received his master's
                    degree in architecture in 1927 from the graduate School of Design at Harvard
                    University. In 1930, he returned to Harvard to study under Professor Alfred M.
                    Tozzer in the department of anthropology, receiving his doctorate in 1940. He
                    began work at the Peabody Museum in 1937 as an assistant curator of southeastern
                    archaeology, was named curator of southeastern archaeology in 1949, and held
                    this post until 1967, when he was named honorary curator. He was an avid student
                    of literature, with a profound knowledge of Proust and Joyce.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Philip Phillips papers related to James Joyce. Materials
                    include; correspondence from Horace Middleton to Phillips (1946-1961), along
                    with copies of various iterations of textual fragments from Finnegan's Wake;
                    black and white photographic prints of Joycean locations in Dublin and
                    elsewhere, including some photos of Horace Middleton; photocopies of Finnegan’s
                    Wake in various states -- some annotated (possibly made from microfilm at
                    British Museum); notes and drafts by Philips for a proposed book on Finnegan’s
                    Wake; book reviews and newspaper articles about Joyce scholarship collected by
                    Phillips; and record albums of Joyce readings.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>