<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rosenbach Company records <date type="inclusive">1888-1954</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rosenbach Company records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">RM&amp;Sp.ACC1760</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>130 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1888-1954</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Rosenbach Company was a Philadelphia firm dealing in rare books and
                    manuscripts, and fine and decorative arts. The company was established by
                    Abraham Simon Wolf Rosenbach and his brother Philip Rosenbach in 1903. Philip
                    Rosenbach was elected president of the company and A.S.W. Rosenbach was elected
                    secretary-treasurer. The company, with offices in Philadelphia and New York
                    City, became recognized as one of the country's preeminent dealers in rare books
                    and literary manuscripts, and A.S.W. Rosenbach is credited with helping build
                    the collections of Harry E. Widener, J. P. Morgan, Henry C. Folger, and Henry E.
                    Huntington. He also bought and sold some of the most famous literary
                    manuscripts, including part of Chaucer's Canterbury Tales, Lewis Carroll's
                    Alice's Adventures under Ground, and James Joyce's handwritten Ulysses (which he
                    kept). A.S.W. Rosenbach died in July of 1952, Philip Rosenbach died in March of
                    1953, and the Rosenbach Company was closed. Both men left the bulk of their
                    estates to the Rosenbach Foundation. The Foundation maintained the family house
                    on Delancey Street in Philadelphia, and in 1954 opened the Rosenbach Museum and
                    Library to preserve the Rosenbachs' collection of books, manuscripts, fine art,
                    and antiques.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Rosenbach Company from its establishment
                    in 1903 to 1953, when the firm closed. Financial records include sales books,
                    cash books, general ledgers, account books, accounts receivable cards, vouchers,
                    bank statements, and check stubs. Records of the company's inventory include
                    catalogues, bound and card-file listings of book and decorative arts stock, and
                    volumes listing the items within particular collections. The collection also
                    includes folders and scrapbooks of newspaper clippings on the Rosenbach Company
                    and its purchases and sales, an album of photographs, and information on the
                    Rosenbach Fellowship at the University of Pennsylvania.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>