<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rosenbach family papers <date type="inclusive">1828-1979</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1840s-1940s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rosenbach family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">RM&amp;Sp.ACC1761</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>16.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1828-1979</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1840s-1940s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Rosenbachs were a prominent Jewish Philadelphia family. Morris (born Meier)
                    Rosenbach emigrated from Germany to the United States in 1844, and became a US
                    citizen in 1855. In 1857 he married Isabella H. Polock. They had eight children:
                    Hyman Polock (1858-1892), Philip Hyman (1863-1953), Morris (1865-?), Rebecca H.
                    (1866-1926), Adalaide (1868-1872), Moses Polock (1870-1953), Miriam H. Wolfe
                    (1873-1926), and Abraham Simon Wolf (1876-1952). Morris Rosenbach, Sr. was a
                    soft goods merchant. His wife Isabella was involved with the Hebrew Sunday
                    School Society, the Hebrew Female Benevolent Society, the Jewish Orphans Home,
                    and Congregation Mikveh Israel. Moses Polock (1817-1903) was the brother of
                    Isabella Polock Rosenbach. As a young man, he was employed by the publishing and
                    bookselling firm of M'Carty &amp; Davis as a clerk. Twenty years later Polock
                    acquired the business and upon his death, the firm descended to Abraham
                    Rosenbach. Hyman was a freelance journalist and later worked as a regular staff
                    member at the Public Ledger. Morris Jr. was an engineer who worked for a time
                    for the Missouri River Commission. He eventually settled in Chicago and was an
                    executive for the packing house of Wilson and Company. Abraham received his
                    Ph.D. from the University of Pennsylvania in 1898. In 1903, he and his older
                    brother Philip established the Rosenbach Company to sell rare books and fine and
                    decorative arts.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the Rosenbach family papers. Materials in the collection
                    include: correspondence between family members, including a series of letters
                    from Morris (Jr.) to his mother, sisters, and Abraham describing his travels in
                    the western United States in the late 1890s; the passport, naturalization
                    papers, and military service records of Morris Rosenbach (in German); business
                    books related to Morris Rosenbach's business; school notebooks and a penmanship
                    book of Isabella Rosenbach; a scrapbook, minutes, and histories of the Hebrew
                    Sunday School Society; school notebooks, composition books, notes, and school
                    papers of Abraham; honorary degrees and awards belonging to Abraham; clippings,
                    printed profiles, and a typescript of a speech by Edwin Wolf related to Abraham;
                    bibliographic cards for works on and by Tennyson (probably compiled by Abraham);
                    address and phone books of Philip and Abraham; business books related to
                    Philip's Carlton Club; estate papers of Philip and Abraham; blueprints for the
                    building at 1618 Locust street; printed copies and a manuscript of Hyman Polock
                    Rosenbach's Jews in Philadelphia Prior to 1800; commonplace books; calling cards
                    of family members; and a typescript of the memoirs of Cyrus Adler.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>