<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rufus King papers <date type="inclusive">1756-1892</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rufus King papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">RM&amp;Sp.ACC1770</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1756-1892</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Rufus King (1755-1827) was a Continental Congressman, Senator, and Minister to
                    Great Britain. Born in Scarboro (then a district of Massachusetts), King
                    graduated from Harvard College in 1777. He served in the Revolutionary War, and
                    then studied law, beginning a practice in Newburyport in 1780. He was a delegate
                    to the Massachusetts General Court, 1783-1785, a member of the Continental
                    Congress from Massachusetts, 1784-1787, a delegate to the Federal constitutional
                    convention at Philadelphia in 1787 and to the State convention in 1788. That
                    year, he moved to New York, where he served as a member of the New York
                    assembly. He was elected to the United States Senate in 1789, reelected in 1795
                    and served from July 16, 1789, until May 1796, when he resigned to become United
                    States Minister to Great Britain. He returned to the United States in 1803 to
                    run for Vice President as a Federalist candidate, but was unsuccessful. In 1813
                    he was again elected as a Federalist to the United States Senate in 1813,
                    retaining his seat until 1825. From 1825 to 1826 he served again as United
                    States Minister to Great Britain. King died in New York in 1827. Charles Lennig
                    (b.1810) was the son of Nicholas Lennig and Elise de Boulignez. In 1831 Nicholas
                    and Charles established the Tacony Chemical Works in Port Richmond, one of the
                    first chemical works in the United States.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of correspondence and other documents of Rufus King and
                    several of his descendants, and family papers of the Lennig family. The
                    correspondence of Rufus King, Charles King, Cyrus W. King, and John A. King
                    includes letters from prominent figures such as John Quincy Adams, Daniel
                    Webster, DeWitt Clinton, John Jacob Astor, George Washington, Dorothea Dix,
                    Lafayette, and Alexander Hamilton. The letters consist of invitations,
                    introductions, and diplomatic matters. Other documents related to the King
                    family include: bonds, receipts, an agreement of sale of property, fragments
                    containing signatures, and a document, signed by John Quincy Adams and Henry
                    Clay, sent to King George regarding Rufus King's return to the U.S. The Lennig
                    family papers include correspondence on financial matters between Elise de
                    Boulignez, Elise Lennig, and Nicholas Lennig; a small number of legal documents
                    related to financial matters, and a passport of Charles Lennig. The Lennig
                    correspondence and papers are in French, with a few in German.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: New-York Historical
                    Society: Rufus King papers; Huntington Library: Rufus King papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>