<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William, Lord Nelson papers <date type="inclusive">1739-1904</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William, Lord Nelson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">RM&amp;Sp.ACC1766</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Rosenbach Museum &amp; Library<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.85 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1739-1904</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William, Lord Nelson (1757-1835), was the elder brother and heir of Horatio of
                    Nelson. He was ordained in 1781 and served very briefly under his brother as
                    chaplain to his command, the frigate Boreas (1784-1786). The seagoing life did
                    not suit him, and he returned to Norfolk where he married and eventually settled
                    in Hilborough in Norfolk. In 1802 Nelson was awarded a doctorate of divinity
                    from the University of Cambridge, and in 1803 he received the same degree from
                    Oxford. Later the same year, he was appointed a prebendary of Canterbury. Upon
                    Horatio Nelson's death in 1805, William inherited the Duchy of Bronte (which had
                    been awarded to Horatio by the King of the Two Sicilies in 1799), along with the
                    title of Baron Nelson of the Nile, and an annual pension of £5000. Nelson died
                    in London on 28 February 1835. His daughter, who had married Baron Bridport in
                    1810, now succeeded to the Sicilian title of Duchess of Bronte. Lady Bridport's
                    inheritance was compromised by Horatio’s will endorsing the rival claims of his
                    sisters, Susannah Bolton and Catherine Matcham, who both had sons. Litigation
                    between the two sides of the family continued for roughly ten years after the
                    death of William Nelson. J. Hutchinson was one of William Nelson's solicitors;
                    W. Bryant Barrett was agent for the Duchy of Bronte. After Barrett's death, his
                    widow Martha Barrett took over supervision of the estate for a period of time.
                    After this, A. Nelson Hood acted as agent for the Duchy.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of papers mainly relating to estates of Nelson's Dukedom
                    of Bronte in Sicily. Materials include: manuscript letters and copies of
                    letters, legal papers, drafts and final versions of wills, and codicils (1806 to
                    1904). The collection also includes several other documents relating to the Lord
                    Nelson trust, and a 1739 indenture between Thomas Fergison and his wife Mary,
                    who was the heir of both Samuel Pitt and William Pitt.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>