<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academic Affairs records <date type="inclusive">1938-2006</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960s-1990s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academic Affairs records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2431</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>14.91 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1938-2006</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960s-1990s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The educational work of Villanova University is under the direction of the Vice
                    President for Academic Affairs. The various undergraduate colleges of the
                    University--Liberal Arts and Sciences, Engineering, Business, and Nursing--as
                    well as the Division of Part-Time and Continuing Studies and Falvey Memorial
                    Library--are supervised by the deans and directors who report directly to the
                    Vice President for Academic Affairs. The Office of Research and Sponsored
                    Projects (ORSP) serves and assists research investigators in seeking the
                    necessary resources and in managing their use in accordance with the objectives
                    of the University and of external sponsors.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of Villanova's Vice President for Academic
                    Affairs and the Office of Research and Special Projects. The records consist of
                    administrative files, correspondence, minutes, legal records, and reports.
                    Administrative records include Board of Trustees Academic Affairs Committee and
                    Faculty Affairs Committee records (1975-1987); policies on salaries, rank and
                    tenure, sabbaticals, faculty dismissal and suspension, and evaluations; grant
                    manuals; and policy manuals for research on human subjects. Correspondence
                    (1947-2002) covers a range of topics related to academic affairs, such as tenure
                    and rank matters, programs and departments, appointments and hiring searches.
                    Legal records include an Asbestos Materials Survey, information on the
                    Cooperative Education Program, and information on a patent for a Hepatitis test
                    (1971). Minutes are present for the Board of Trustees Academic Affairs Committee
                    (1980-1989); the Rank and Tenure Committee (1968-1984); the University Senate
                    (Rank and Tenure and Faculty Affairs Committees) (1976-1988); the Faculty
                    Affairs Committee (1963-1974); the College of Commerce and Finance (1990-1995);
                    and several other committees. Reports make up the largest portion of this
                    collection, and include tenure and promotion reports for individual faculty
                    members; reports of the Rank and Tenure Committee; annual reports of the ORSP
                    (1949-1951 and 1983-1992); and reports from several other University departments
                    and committees.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Villanova University--Faculty</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Villanova University. Board of Trustees.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Universities and colleges--Administration.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>