<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>College of Liberal Arts and Sciences records <date type="inclusive">1922-1999</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">College of Liberal Arts and Sciences records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2438</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1922-1999</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Villanova University traces its origins to old Saint Augustine's Church in
                    Philadelphia, which the Augustinians founded in 1796, and to its parish school,
                    Saint Augustine's Academy, established in 1811. Villanova University has been
                    sponsored by the Augustinian Order since its founding in 1842. Today, the
                    University is comprised of five colleges: Liberal Arts and Sciences (Villanova
                    College), Engineering, School of Business (formerly known as the College of
                    Commerce and Finance), Nursing and the School of Law.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of files from the office of the Dean of Liberal Arts and
                    Sciences. Administrative records include policy manuals, admissions statistics,
                    evaluations, and job descriptions. Correspondence files date from 1972 to 1997;
                    correspondence relates to the curriculum assessment, Campus Ministry, department
                    and faculty matters, institutes and societies, and the Honors Program. Minutes
                    are present for the Ad Hoc Committee on Core Curriculum (1986-1990), Dean and
                    Chairmen's meetings (1973-1997), and for meetings of various College departments
                    and committees. Printed materials in the collection include a grant manual,
                    brochures, and descriptions of the Honors Program. The collection also includes
                    reports related to programs and departments, curriculum and academic status, and
                    various task forces and committees.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>