<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>College of Engineering <date type="inclusive">1905-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">College of Engineering</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2437</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1905-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The second degree-granting unit inaugurated at Villanova University was the
                    College of Engineering, which began instruction in 1905 under the name of the
                    School of Technology. Dr. A. B. Carpenter was hired in 1904 to organize and
                    direct the school. In 1908 an undergraduate program in Mechanical Engineering
                    was established, and in 1909 the first engineering bachelors degrees were
                    awarded. An undergraduate program in Chemical Engineering was established in
                    1919. In the years following the Second World War, the College expanded its
                    degree offerings to the masters level, establishing graduate programs in each of
                    its four engineering departments. A fifth undergraduate degree program, in
                    Computer Engineering, was added in 1993. In the 1990s, research units were
                    established in the areas of advanced communications and environmental
                    engineering.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The records of the College of Engineering include records of the Dean of the
                    College and records of programs and departments within the College. The papers
                    of the Dean of the College of Engineering consist of administrative records,
                    reports, and printed materials. Administrative records include a 1939 chemical
                    engineering curriculum; information on the "Engineering personnel service" (a
                    career preparation program), 1939; and a faculty and student directory of the
                    College from 1980-1981. Reports range in date from 1905 to 1990 and cover a
                    variety of topics, including the College’s marking system, statistics on the
                    College, proposals for expansion of the facilities, and curriculum and program
                    reviews and self-studies. Printed materials include brochures for the College,
                    posters for the Graduate Studies program, a Sophomore class notebook from
                    1924-1925, and other items. Records of the Electrical and Computer Engineering
                    Department include a policy and procedure manual, faculty profiles, annual
                    department reports (1985-1991), and proposals for Bachelor of Science and Doctor
                    in Philosophy degrees in Electrical Engineering. Records of the Mechanical
                    Engineering Department include laboratory instruction manuals, homework and
                    examination problems, course notes, and a student notebook.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Engineering--Study and teaching.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Directories.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Laboratory notebooks.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Posters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>