<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Dean, College of Nursing records <date type="inclusive">1952-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Dean, College of Nursing records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2480</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>13.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1952-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The College of Nursing at Villanova University, established in 1953, has
                    bachelor's, master's, and doctoral programs fully accredited by the Commission
                    on Collegiate Nursing Education and approved by the State Board of Nursing of
                    the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, as well as an American Nurses Credentialing
                    Center accredited program in Continuing Education. The nurse anesthesia program
                    is accredited by the Council on Accreditation of Nurse Anesthesia Educational
                    Programs. In 1978, M. Louise Fitzpatrick, EdD, RN, FAAN was named as the third
                    dean of the College of Nursing.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Dean of the College of Nursing, consisting
                    of administrative files, correspondence, minutes, printed materials, and
                    reports. Administrative materials include orientation handbooks and policy
                    procedure manuals. Correspondence dates from 1951 to 1994 and relates to
                    accreditation, the State Board of Nurse Examiners, faculty development, alumni
                    and student associations, and various University committees. Minutes document
                    meetings of faculty, administration, and Nursing curriculum and program
                    committees, including the Academic Standing and Records Committee (1968-1995),
                    the Curriculum Committee (1955-1995), and the Admissions Committee (1970-1990).
                    The collection includes a large number of reports. These include Academic
                    Standing Committee reports for Villanova University departments and programs;
                    reports on College of Nursing accreditation, curriculum, and self-study
                    assessments; nursing program standards and policies; State Board of Nurse
                    Examiners evaluations; and reports of various University committees.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Nursing--Study and teaching</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Universities and colleges--Administration.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>