<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Departments and Programs records <date type="inclusive">1943-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Departments and Programs records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2440</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1943-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Villanova University traces its origins to old Saint Augustine's Church in
                    Philadelphia, which the Augustinians founded in 1796, and to its parish school,
                    Saint Augustine's Academy, established in 1811. Villanova University has been
                    sponsored by the Augustinian Order since its founding in 1842. Today, the
                    University is comprised of five colleges: Liberal Arts and Sciences (Villanova
                    College), Engineering, School of Business (formerly known as the College of
                    Commerce and Finance), Nursing and the School of Law.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of various academic departments and programs of
                    Villanova University. Types of materials found in the department records include
                    faculty meeting minutes, correspondence, annual departmental reports, and
                    program brochures. The programs with the most material in this collection are
                    Library Sciences and the NROTC program. Other departments and programs
                    documented here include Biology, Chemistry, Computer Science, Education and
                    Human Services, Mathematics, Physics, Theater, Theology and Religion, Women's
                    Studies, and the Internship program.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Villanova University. Graduate Dept. of Library
                    Science.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Villanova University. Naval Reserve Officer Training
                    Corps.</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Programs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>