<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edmund J. Dobbin, O.S.A. records <date type="inclusive">1982-2006</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1988-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edmund J. Dobbin, O.S.A. records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2475</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>35.95 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-2006</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1988-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Raised in Staten Island, New York, Father Edmund J. Dobbin received his B.A. in
                    Philosophy from Villanova in 1958. In 1962, he received his Master of Arts from
                    Augustinian College as theological preparation for his ordination to the
                    priesthood. In 1964, Father Dobbin received his Master of Science in
                    Mathematics, with a minor in Physics, and in 1968, he received his Licentiate in
                    Sacred Theology, both degrees from the Catholic University of America. In 1971,
                    he received his Doctor of Sacred Theology from the University of Louvain,
                    Belgium. A recognized scholar and administrator, Father Dobbin served as a
                    member of the Villanova University Board of Trustees from 1979 to 1987. He was
                    appointed associate vice president for Academic Affairs in 1987, a position he
                    held until his inauguration as president of Villanova University in 1988. In
                    2006, after 18 years as president, Father Dobbin stepped down to resume teaching
                    at the University.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Father Edmund J. Dobbin. The collection
                    includes administrative files, correspondence, legal records, minutes, personal
                    papers, printed materials, and programs and reports. Administrative records
                    include information on the Alumni Association, Board of Trustees resolutions and
                    membership lists, policy statements, and a list of recipients of honorary
                    degrees (1877-1992). Correspondence makes up a large portion of the collection
                    and dates from 1988 to 2005. The correspondence covers a wide range of
                    University matters, including alumni affairs, athletics, faculty matters,
                    commencements and honorary degrees, admissions, Ex Corde Ecclesiae, public
                    relations, dissolution of the Library Science department, development, and
                    student life. The legal documents include records on estates, zoning, leases,
                    West Campus development, and faculty and student legal matters. Minutes,
                    agendas, and related memoranda are present for various committees of the Board
                    of Trustees (1988-2006); the University Senate and a number of its committees
                    (1988-2005); the Vice President’s Council (1989-2006); and other University
                    committees and councils. Personal papers include daily calendars (1988-2005);
                    correspondence (1987-2005); and addresses delivered by Father Dobbin at
                    commencements and meetings of the Faculty Council and University Senate.
                    Finally, the collection includes a large number of printed materials, programs,
                    and reports from a variety of University offices and committees as well as other
                    associations. These materials cover topics ranging from athletics, academics,
                    student life, development, strategic planning, facilities management, and
                    self-studies and assessments. The collection also includes newspaper clippings
                    and articles about Father Dobbin.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Dobbin, Edmund J.</persname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Villanova University. Board of Trustees.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Villanova University. Graduate Dept. of Library
                    Science.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">College presidents</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Universities and colleges--Administration.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Programs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>