<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edward James McCarthy, O.S.A. records <date type="inclusive">1971-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edward James McCarthy, O.S.A. records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2464</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Father Edward James McCarthy (1912-1996) graduated from Villanova College in 1934
                    with a bachelor’s degree in philosophy. He pursued theological studies at
                    Augustinian College, Washington, D.C., and was ordained a priest there in 1937.
                    After ordination he earned an M.A. (1938) and a doctorate in history from the
                    Catholic University of America. Father McCarthy’s first assignment after
                    ordination was to Villanova College as a professor of history. In June 1946 he
                    went to the Universidad de S. Tomas de Villanueva, Havana, Cuba, as Dean and
                    professor of history. In 1947 he returned to his teaching position at Villanova
                    College and was named first Dean of Arts and Sciences (1948-1950) and then Dean
                    of the Graduate and Extension Schools (1950-1953). In 1953 he returned to the
                    Universidad de Villanueva as Academic Vice President (1953-1957) and remained
                    there until the Augustinians were expelled from Cuba in 1961. Upon his return to
                    the United States, he became the first president of Biscayne College in Miami,
                    Florida, where he remained until 1968. In 1968 he was named prior of Our Mother
                    of Good Counsel Monastery at Merrimack College serving also as chairman of the
                    Department of History (1968-1971). In 1971 he was elected president of Villanova
                    University, a position he held until 1975. From 1975 to 1979 Father took up
                    parochial ministry as pastor of Resurrection Parish in Dania, Florida, and
                    later, from 1977 to 1979, as assistant of Saint Nicholas of Tolentine, Bronx,
                    New York. From 1979-1981 he was Vice President for Academic Affairs at Merrimack
                    College, North Andover, Massachusetts. In 1981 he was called to Villanova to
                    serve on the governing board of the Augustinian Province of Saint Thomas of
                    Villanova and was named Assistant Provincial. He was elected chairman of the
                    Board of Trustees of Villanova University. In 1990 Father was assigned to Saint
                    Augustine Church, Casselberry, Florida. In 1993, at the age of 81, he at the
                    request of Archbishop McCarthy assumed the position of interim President of
                    Saint Thomas University (formerly Biscayne College) serving until the new
                    president was in place; he continued to work as a consultant at Biscayne until
                    his death. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Edward J. McCarthy papers consist of administrative records, correspondence,
                    legal records, news media, and reports. Administrative records include law
                    school budgets and other financial information pertaining to the law school.
                    Correspondence covers various academic and administrative topics, including
                    Catholic education, commencement activities, and collective bargaining with the
                    faculty. The files on collective bargaining include additional materials, such
                    as minutes of a faculty assembly, and copies of handouts distributed at a
                    National Labor Relations Board meeting held on campus in 1973. Legal papers
                    largely relate to agreements and leases, but also include documentation of a
                    patent for a test for Hepatitis developed at Villanova. The collection includes
                    newspaper clippings about Father McCarthy from 1971 to 1996. Finally, the
                    collection contains reports on topics such as the Commission on University
                    Structures and Procedures (CUSP), Phi Beta Kappa, the Student Bill of Rights,
                    tenure, and other University matters.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">McCarthy, E. J. (Edward James), 1912-</persname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">College presidents</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Financial records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>