<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Institutes records <date type="inclusive">1959-1973</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Institutes records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2452</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.32 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1959-1973</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Villanova University's College of Liberal Arts and Sciences is home to a number
                    of academic centers and institutes dedicated to promoting the mission of the
                    College within their area of concentration. In addition to offering courses,
                    centers and institutes in the College host lectures and other special events and
                    may publish a journal. The Augustinian Institute serves the University as an
                    agent and resource to support its efforts to give Augustine's thought a vibrant
                    and integral place within Villanova's academic and community life, and allows
                    that voice of Augustine to continue to speak effectively to today’s world.
                    Between the late 1950s and the mid 1970s, Villanova, supported by grants from
                    the National Science Foundation, conducted an institute offering courses in
                    mathematics and science for secondary school teachers. These courses were
                    conducted in the summer and fall on the University's campus.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of Villanova University's Institutes. Currently,
                    the collection contains materials from two Institutes: the National Science
                    Foundation Institute and the Augustinian Institute. Records of the National
                    Science Foundation Institute include correspondence related to the NSF Summer
                    Institute (1964); brochures for the In-Service Institute (1959-1973) and the
                    Summer Institute (1959, 1962-1966); and reports and participant lists of the NSF
                    In-Service Institute (1959-1973). Records of the Augustinian Institute include
                    correspondence, announcements, and news clippings on the Institute (1962-1971);
                    and brochures for the Patristic, Mediaeval, and Renaissance Studies conference
                    (1997-2000).</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Augustinian Institute.</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>