<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John M. Driscoll, O.S.A. records <date type="inclusive">1964-1988</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1975-1988</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John M. Driscoll, O.S.A. records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2466</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>23.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-1988</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1975-1988</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John M. Driscoll graduated Villanova in 1948. He earned both his master’s degree
                    and his doctorate in philosophy from Catholic University. He was ordained in
                    1951, and began a teaching career at Archbishop Carroll High School in
                    Washington, D.C. In 1956 Father Driscoll was transferred to Merrimack College,
                    where he served as a philosophy teacher and later as vice president and dean. He
                    remained at Merrimack until his assignment to Villanova in the mid-1960s. As
                    vice president, Father Driscoll played a major role in student-university
                    relations. His work eventually resulted in the creation of the University Senate
                    at Villanova. He became the University’s 30th president in 1975, serving in that
                    role until 1988. In 1978 he was elected president of the Pennsylvania
                    Association of Colleges and Universities and became a recognized educational
                    leader in the state. During the 12 years of his presidency, the Connelly Center
                    and the Pavilion were completed, and numerous buildings were renovated. Father
                    Driscoll also instituted the university’s first national fund-raising campaign,
                    the Covenant Campaign, raising more than $34 million over a 10-year period.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The John M. Driscoll papers consist of administrative files, correspondence,
                    legal files, minutes, news media, printed material, personal papers, and
                    reports. Administrative records include information on investment policies and
                    endowment funds, Board of Trustees resolutions and membership information,
                    policy statements, financial and salary information, and insurance information.
                    Correspondence makes up the largest portion of the collection and dates from
                    1974 to 1988. Copies of outgoing correspondence are arranged chronologically,
                    but the bulk of the correspondence is arranged by topic. The subjects cover a
                    wide range of University matters, including academic policies, athletics, Board
                    of Trustees matters, commencements and honorary degrees, public relations,
                    development and capital campaigns, student matters, and faculty matters,
                    including collective bargaining with faculty. The legal series includes records
                    on estates, academic appeals, faculty and student legal matters, and information
                    regarding St. Mary’s Hall and the separate incorporation of St. Thomas
                    Monastery. Minutes, agendas, and related memoranda are present for the Board of
                    Trustees meetings (1975-1988), Vice President’s meetings (1977-1988), as well as
                    for several faculty and administrative committees. News media includes newspaper
                    clippings about Father Driscoll and Villanova activities (1978-1988) and
                    clippings and programs related to the Contemporary Shakespeare Company
                    (1979-1982). Personal papers include addresses given by Father Driscoll
                    (1971-1988); an agenda log (1975-1988); daily calendars (1964-1988); and various
                    invitations and programs. Finally, the collection includes reports from a
                    variety of University offices and committees as well as other associations, on
                    topics such as athletics, academics, student life, development, strategic
                    planning, accreditation, and self-studies and assessments.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Villanova University. Board of Trustees.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">College presidents</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Programs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Speeches.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>