<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Joseph Fedigan, O.S.A. records <date type="inclusive">undated</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Joseph Fedigan, O.S.A. records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2471</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Father John Joseph Fedigan (1842-1908) was born in Rathbran, Ireland. He studied
                    at Saint Mary’s College in Wilmington, Delaware, before entering the Augustinian
                    novitiate at Ghent, Belgium. He was ordained to the priesthood in 1868. During
                    his forty years as a priest, Father Fedigan held many positions in the Province
                    of Saint Thomas of Villanova. In 1874, he was the first Augustinian to serve in
                    Carthage, New York, and became the first Rector there. He was also elected
                    Definitor for American Augustinians at several chapters. Father Fedigan served
                    as president of Villanova College from 1878 to 1880, and in 1887 he was elected
                    Provincial. In this position, he raised more than $275,000 to erect a new
                    college building and Augustinian Monastery at Villanova. These buildings were
                    completed in 1900 and 1901, respectively. From 1902 to 1906, he served as Prior
                    at Our Mother of Good Counsel, Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania, after which he returned
                    to the monastery at Villanova. Fedigan Hall, a residence building at Villanova
                    University, is named in his honor.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The John Joseph Fedigan papers consist of flyers for fundraising campaigns for
                    the Villanova University. One requests funds for the erection of a new college
                    building and Augustinian Monastery. The other flyer requests funds for the
                    erection of a marble statute of St. Augustine and a grotto in honor of the
                    Blessed Mother. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Fedigan, John Joseph.</persname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">College presidents</subject>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>