<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Anthony Flaherty, O.S.A. records <date type="inclusive">1964-1993</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1964-1967</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Anthony Flaherty, O.S.A. records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2474</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-1993</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1964-1967</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Father Joseph Anthony Flaherty (1916-1993) was born in Philadelphia,
                    Pennsylvania. Flaherty attended the Gesu Parochial School, Saint Joseph’s
                    Preparatory School, and in 1938 received an A.B. degree from Saint Joseph’s
                    College in Philadelphia. In 1940 he began his theological studies at Augustinian
                    College, Washington, D.C. During the summer months he took graduate courses at
                    the nearby Catholic University of America. Flaherty was ordained to the
                    priesthood in 1943. In 1946 he was granted a Master’s degree, and in 1949 a
                    Ph.D., in English from Harvard University. In 1947 Father Flaherty was assigned
                    to the newly opened Merrimack College in North Andover, Massachusetts, as a
                    teacher of English. From 1951 to 1964 he held the position of director of the
                    Part-time Division of the College. In 1964 he was transferred to Villanova
                    University and appointed Vice President for Academic Affairs. In the following
                    year, 1965, he was appointed president of the University, serving until 1967.
                    During his tenure as president the entire curriculum of the university was made
                    available to women students; the construction of the first residence hall for
                    women was begun; and salaries for the faculty were raised. In 1967 Father
                    Flaherty returned to Merrimack College as a professor of English and continued
                    to teach until he retired in the mid-1980s.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Father Joseph A. Flaherty. Materials include:
                    correspondence relating to the Master Plan for Higher Education (1967),
                    commencements (1966-1967), a University Library addition (1966-1967), and other
                    topics; clippings on Father Flaherty's appointments as Vice President of
                    Academic Affairs and as President; a report on the Academic Addition to the
                    School of Law; legal materials related to several Villanova estates; and a
                    sermon given at the Baccalaureate Mass in 1966. The collection also includes a
                    small amount of correspondence of Rev. Robert J. Welsh, mostly relating to his
                    inaugural service and a Pontifical Mass, both in September of 1967.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Flaherty, Joseph Anthony.</persname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">College presidents</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Sermons.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>