<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph A. Hickey records <date type="inclusive">1919-1955</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1942-1955</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph A. Hickey records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2473</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1919-1955</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1942-1955</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Father Joseph Hickey (1883-1955) was born in Chicago, Illinois. He went to
                    Villanova, Pennsylvania, in 1898 as an Augustinian postulant and entered the
                    novitiate in 1902. Two years later he was sent to the International College of
                    Saint Monica in Rome, Italy, to continue his studies for the priesthood. He was
                    ordained in Rome in 1906. After ordination, he remained in Rome to do graduate
                    work in Canon Law, for which he was granted a doctorate in 1908. In 1910, he
                    became Rector of Saint Rita’s Hall, the Augustinian preparatory seminary at
                    Villanova and, also, a professor at the College. He was appointed Province
                    Regent of Studies in 1913, Definitor in 1914, and Provincial Socius and
                    Secretary in 1918. Father Hickey became the first Prior of Saint Mary’s Hall at
                    Villanova and from 1925 to 1926 he served as president of Villanova College. At
                    the General Chapter of September 1925, he was named Assistant General for the
                    English-speaking provinces of the Augustinian Order. From that time until 1953,
                    except for the war years, he lived in Rome, Italy. At the General Chapter of
                    1947, Father Hickey was elected Prior-General of the Order of Saint Augustine.
                    During his term of office, Saint Monica’s in Rome was completely remodeled, and
                    the new Curia building was erected. In 1953, after completing his term as Prior
                    General, he retired to Saint Thomas of Villanova Monastery on the Villanova
                    University campus.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Father Joseph A. Hickey. Materials include:
                    reports from 1947 and 1955, in Latin, related to Father Hickey's election as
                    Prior General of the Augustinian Order and to his death; typed lecture notes on
                    education (classroom management), epistemology, ethics, and sociology; and
                    clippings on Hickey receiving his LL.D. from Villanova in 1942 and on his death
                    in 1955. Also included are several printed lectures by others.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Hickey, Joseph, 1883-1955.</persname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">College presidents</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>