<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Library records <date type="inclusive">1838-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Library records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2443</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1838-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Villanova University traces its origins to old Saint Augustine's Church in
                    Philadelphia, which the Augustinians founded in 1796, and to its parish school,
                    Saint Augustine's Academy, established in 1811. Villanova University has been
                    sponsored by the Augustinian Order since its founding in 1842. Today, the
                    University is comprised of five colleges: Liberal Arts and Sciences (Villanova
                    College), Engineering, School of Business (formerly known as the College of
                    Commerce and Finance), Nursing and the School of Law. Over the course of
                    Villanova's history, the University's library had been housed in several
                    buildings. A new library building was erected after World War II, and in 1963 it
                    was named and rededicated in honor of Father Daniel P. Falvey, who was
                    instrumental in the development of the Library and its collections.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Falvey Memorial Library of Villanova
                    University. Administrative records include library policies, receipts for book
                    purchases (1877-1937), forms, and lists of Library staff (1985-1990).
                    Correspondence dates from 1888 to 2000. Topics addressed in the Correspondence
                    files include professional associations, automation, exhibitions, expansion and
                    building issues, installation of a circulation system, and correspondence of
                    Rev. Daniel P. Falvey (1950-1984), James A. Farley (1943-1959), Joseph
                    McGarrrity (1940-1948), Rev. Thomas C. Middleton (1888-1923), Rev. Francis E.
                    Tourscher (1902-1941), and others. Legal records include information regarding
                    appraisals and a 1968 federal loan for the Library. Minutes are present for
                    meetings of the Faculty Library Committee (1954-2000), Library Department Heads
                    (1969-1985), staff meetings, and several other committees and councils. The News
                    Media series includes newspaper clippings and articles on the library, its
                    collections, and several notable members of the Library staff. The Personal
                    Papers series includes articles by and about several Library staff members
                    (including Daniel P. Falvey, Francis Tourscher, Thomas C. Middleton, and Louis
                    A. Rongione), awards, bibliographies, and ephemera. Printed materials and
                    programs include exhibition brochures, invitations, and articles on the Library
                    and its directors. Reports in the collection include building and facilities
                    studies and proposals, annual reports (1962-2000), library manuals, circulation
                    system proposals and agreements, acquisitions, and a 1949 history of the
                    Library. The collection also includes records of the Friends of the Library.
                    These materials consist of correspondence; minutes of the Friends of the Library
                    Executive Committee (1947-1960); newsletters (1954); news clippings and press
                    releases; programs and ephemera; and addresses. Volumes in the collection
                    include: book catalog, 1894; circulation ledger, 1902-1923; library accession
                    books 1898-1908; 1903-1907, 1934-1938; and a printed volume of Augustinus:
                    Civitate Dei, 1838.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Programs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>