<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Middle States records <date type="inclusive">1950-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Middle States records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2446</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1950-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Villanova University was first accredited by the Middle States Commission on
                    Higher Education in 1921. The Commission is the unit of the Middle States
                    Association of Colleges and Schools that accredits degree-granting colleges and
                    universities in the Middle States region, which includes Delaware, the District
                    of Columbia, Maryland, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Puerto Rico, the U.S.
                    Virgin Islands, and several locations internationally. The Commission is a
                    voluntary, non-governmental, membership association that defines, maintains, and
                    promotes educational excellence across institutions with diverse missions,
                    student populations, and resources. It examines each institution as a whole,
                    rather than specific programs within institutions.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Middle States record group consist of the following series: Correspondence,
                    Minutes, Reports, Administrative, Legal, News Media, and Printed. Materials in
                    the collection include correspondence related to Task Forces, an Implementation
                    Team, and a Liaison visit. Minutes include Middle States Periodic Review
                    Committee, 1995-1996, and Middle States Self Study Committee, 1959, 1969-1979,
                    and 1989. The Reports series consists mainly of Middle States Self-Study
                    Questionnaires from a number of University departments. Materials in the
                    Administrative series include financial statements, 1999, 2000 and
                    organizational charts, 1998. Printed materials in the collection include Designs
                    for Excellence: Handbook for Self-Study and a University Senate (Directory),
                    2000-2001.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Middle States Association of Colleges and
                    Schools.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Universities and colleges--Curricula</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>