<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Program Evaluation Committee (PEC) records <date type="inclusive">1979-1988</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Program Evaluation Committee (PEC) records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2484</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1988</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Program Evaluation Committee (PEC) was formed in the fall of 1985 by
                    Villanova University President John M. Driscoll, with the appointment of twelve
                    faculty members and two administrators. Father Dricoll gave the Program
                    Evaluation Committee the charge to evaluate all existing academic and
                    non-academic programs and to make resource allocation recommendations for each
                    program. The Program Evaluation Committee report to the president was issued
                    March 1988. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Program Evaluation Committee records consist mainly of reports. Included in
                    the collection are reports from various task forces including Environmental
                    Opportunities and Constraints, Internal Strengths and Weaknesses, and Personal
                    Values, and internal self studies and departmental reports. Also included are
                    individual responses from members of the university community and departmental
                    responses. The Program Evaluation Committee report submitted to the university
                    president in March 1988 is also included in this series. The PEC report includes
                    a complete set of minutes of the Committee (1986-1988).</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Universities and colleges--Administration.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Universities and colleges--Curricula</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>