<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>School of Business records <date type="inclusive">1929-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">School of Business records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2436</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1929-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Founded in 1922, the Villanova School of Business offers seven undergraduate
                    degrees in the fields of accounting, economics, and business administration;
                    seven graduate programs; and an executive MBA program. Programs are accredited
                    by the Association to Advance Collegiate Schools of Business (AACSB). The school
                    is home to several business research centers including the Center for Marketing
                    and Public Policy Research, the Center for Global Leadership, the Daniel M.
                    DiLella Center for Real Estate, the Center for the Study of Church Management,
                    the Center for Entrepreneurship, and the Institute for Research in Advanced
                    Financial Technology.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The School of Business records include records of the Dean of the School and
                    records of programs and departments within the school. The papers of the Dean of
                    the School of Business are arranged into four series: Correspondence, Minutes,
                    Reports, and Printed Materials. The bulk of the correspondence (1929-1978) is
                    from faculty members or from the Association to Advance Collegiate Schools of
                    Business (AACSB) regarding undergraduate accreditation. Minutes are present for
                    Chairmen’s Meetings (1979-1990); Dean’s Council (1995-2006); and from several
                    departments within the School of Business. The Reports series includes AACSB
                    Undergraduate Accreditation applications and reports; a statement of the
                    philosophy and objectives of the College of Commerce and Finance; annual Dean’s
                    reports (1963-1987); annual reports from the College’s departments; proposals
                    for a Master of Business Administration; and student and alumni surveys;
                    accreditation questionnaires; self-study reports, and reports by consultants.
                    Printed materials in the collection include syllabi for several College
                    programs; and brochures for the Master of Business Administration program. The
                    collection also includes syllabi from the Management Department, for courses
                    given between 1982 and 1995 (with one syllabus from a Statistical Methods course
                    given in 1971), and the Graduate Studies program, for courses given between 1983
                    and 1995.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Annual reports.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>