<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sesquicentennial anniversary records <date type="inclusive">1989-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sesquicentennial anniversary records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2459</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1989-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Villanova University President Edmund J. Dobbin announced in March 1990 the
                    formation of a Steering Committee to begin the planning for Villanova’s
                    Sesquicentennial observance. The 150th anniversary celebration was held during
                    the school year 1992-1993. The committee was charged by Father Dobbin “with the
                    responsibility for providing creative direction and leadership to several
                    committees working on specific aspects of the celebration.” Father Dobbin
                    appointed a Chair and 17-member committee. Subsequently the Sesquicentennial
                    Committee formed 10 subcommittees to oversee events, activities and programs
                    related to Villanova’s 150th anniversary in 1992-1993.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Sesquicentennial collection includes correspondence related to planning,
                    exhibitions, histories, and the Sesquicentennial Pictorial, as well as minutes
                    of the Sesquicentennial Committee, Sesquicentennial Historical dates and
                    Sesquicentennial Historical Minutes. Printed materials consist of publications
                    generated during the Sesquicentennial and include a Belle Air Yearbook, Blue
                    Book Sesquicentennial Exhibit Catalog, University Bulletins, and Villanova
                    Magazine. The Programs series includes brochures and other materials related to
                    various events during the sesquicentennial. Reports are varied and include
                    Sesquicentennial Committee, Sesquicentennial History (Proposal),
                    Sesquicentennial Steering Committee, Sesquicentennial History and others.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Villanova University:
                    College/University Functions records (RG-22)</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>