<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Undergraduate Nursing Program records <date type="inclusive">1965-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Undergraduate Nursing Program records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2482</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1965-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Villanova University first offered a program of study leading to a Bachelor of
                    Sciences in Nursing Education in 1932. This commitment was expanded in 1953 to
                    created a College of Nursing that now offers a generic BSN program, a BSN
                    completion program for registered nurses, an accelerated BSN program for second
                    degree students, and a MSN program, a Ph.D. program and a Continuing Education
                    program. The College of Nursing is approved by the State Board of Nursing of the
                    Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. Upon completion of the undergraduate program,
                    graduates are eligible to take the licensing examination (NCLEX) for
                    professional registered nurses. This license is transferable within the United
                    States nationally by state. The undergraduate and graduate programs are both
                    fully accredited by the Commission on Collegiate Nursing Education. The Nurse
                    Anesthesia concentration in the graduate program is accredited by the Council on
                    Accreditation of Nurse Anesthesia Educational Programs. The Continuing Education
                    Program is accredited as a provider of Continuing Education in Nursing by the
                    American Nurses Credentialing Center, Commission on Accreditation.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Undergraduate Nursing Program Records contain syllabi (faculty and student),
                    examinations, student materials, study guides, course evaluation forms, rotation
                    schedules, and manuals.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>