<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>University Advancement records <date type="inclusive">1875-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">University Advancement records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2435</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1875-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Villanova University traces its origins to old Saint Augustine's Church in
                    Philadelphia, which the Augustinians founded in 1796, and to its parish school,
                    Saint Augustine's Academy, established in 1811. Villanova University has been
                    sponsored by the Augustinian Order since its founding in 1842. Today, the
                    University is comprised of five colleges: Liberal Arts and Sciences (Villanova
                    College), Engineering, School of Business (formerly known as the College of
                    Commerce and Finance), Nursing and the School of Law. Institutional Advancement
                    at Villanova is responsible for a range of activities which provide the
                    framework for building strong support and lasting relationships with a variety
                    of University constituencies, including alumni, parents, friends, and members of
                    the community.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers related to University advancement and includes
                    records from several departments. Records for the Vice President for
                    Institutional Advancement consist of three series: Correspondence, News Media,
                    and Reports. Correspondence makes up the bulk of the materials. This series
                    includes general correspondence (1968-1985) and materials related to the Higher
                    Education Facilities Authority Act (1968-1969); the Master Plan for Higher
                    Education (1966-1969); the Pennsylvania Association of Colleges and Universities
                    (1966-1971); and Citizens for Educational Freedom-Pennsylvania Federation
                    (1969-1970). Other correspondence relates to public relations and public
                    hearings on tax reforms. News Media consists of clippings about the Master Plan
                    for Higher Education (1963-1967). The collection also includes a printed
                    proposal by the Pennsylvania Association of Colleges and Universities (1971).
                    Records related to communications and public affairs include press releases,
                    calendars, fact sheets, visitor’s guides, and campus maps. The series also
                    includes 30 scrapbooks of newspaper clippings on Villanova students, faculty,
                    campus, events, and athletics, 1930-1955 and 1954-1993. Development records
                    include: correspondence, minutes, and reports of the Development Council;
                    correspondence, minutes, charter and by-laws, and brochures of the Development
                    Foundation; Handbook for Faculty and Staff on Foundations, 1968; newspaper
                    clippings; printed brochures, and reports. Materials related to the Alumni
                    Association include: minutes of the Alumni Association Board of Governors;
                    minutes of the Alumni Association Long-Range Planning Committee; annual reports;
                    resource guide; correspondence; and papers related to the Alumni Association
                    Constitution. The collection also includes programs for inaugurations of endowed
                    chairs, 1992-2006.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Fund raising.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>