<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Villanova University photographs collection <date type="inclusive">1855-2008</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1900-2008</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Villanova University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Villanova University photographs collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">VUSp.ACC2488</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Villanova University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>40 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1855-2008</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1900-2008</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Villanova University traces its origins to old Saint Augustine's Church in
                    Philadelphia, which the Augustinians founded in 1796, and to its parish school,
                    Saint Augustine's Academy, established in 1811. Villanova University has been
                    sponsored by the Augustinian Order since its founding in 1842. Today, the
                    University is comprised of five colleges: Liberal Arts and Sciences (Villanova
                    College), Engineering, School of Business (formerly known as the College of
                    Commerce and Finance), Nursing and the School of Law.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of photographs, negatives, and slides related to Villanova
                    University and its campus, students, alumni, and faculty. Images of campus
                    buildings record construction, interiors and exteriors, and documentation of
                    buildings before and after fires. Of note are several images made by
                    photographer James E. McClees in 1856. Events such as awards ceremonies,
                    commencements, centennial celebrations, building dedications, and
                    groundbreakings are also included. There are portraits of Villanova University
                    presidents, as well as proof-books of photos of the inauguration of President
                    Donohue and photographs of inauguration of President Dobbin. Portraits of
                    honorary graduates include John F. Kennedy, Eugene Ormandy, Joseph Biden, James
                    Michener, William Howard Taft, and Cardinal Jozef Glemp of Poland. Portraits of
                    notable visitors include Martin Luther King, Jr., Gerald Ford, and Ronald
                    Reagan. Group portraits, many of them oversized, depict faculty, trustees, and
                    students grouped by academic major and graduating class. Student clubs and
                    societies are also included. Other subjects include student activities, sports,
                    theater productions, and alumni activities. Photographers include Jules Schick,
                    Gilbert and Bacon, Harry D. Richards, William H. Rau, and Drucker and Co.
                    Negatives in the collection include pictures of student clubs, activities,
                    sports, candid shots of students and faculty taken for the yearbook, 1966-1967,
                    and a series of negatives from the Engineering department, some of which
                    appeared in the Villanova Engineer from the 1930s-1950s. The collection also
                    includes photographs of library artwork, photographs used in exhibits and
                    anniversary celebrations; a small number of newspaper clippings of students and
                    faculty; and lithographs and engravings of campus views.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Villanova University--Faculty</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Villanova University--Sports</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Villanova University--Students</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">College presidents--Portraits</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Negatives (Photographic)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photograph albums.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Slides (Photographs)</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>