<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Andrew M. Jones papers <date type="inclusive">1776-1897</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1830-1885</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Andrew M. Jones papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2515</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1776-1897</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1830-1885</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Benjamin Jones (1767-1849), born in Pennsylvania, was the son of Joseph Jones (b.
                    1739) and Hannah Walter, and grandson of Rees Jones and Amy Cock. Benjamin Jones
                    became a merchant, iron manufacturer, and land speculator. He married Rebecca
                    Moore (b. 1778), and together they had William Jones (1798-1798), Walter Moore
                    Jones (1799-1825), and Andrew Moore Jones (1801-1885). After Rebecca's early
                    death in 1802, Benjamin married Mary Howell (1778-1836), and they had eight
                    children: Anne Emlen (1806-1883), William Howell (1808-1819), Margaretta Howell
                    (1809-1874), Richard (1812-1890), Mary Beveridge (1814-1887), Harriet
                    (1816-1855), Samuel Howell (1818-1883), and Benjamin Walter (1821-1883).
                    Following Benjamin Jones's death in 1849, the responsibilities of his estate
                    fell to his son Andrew. In 1840 Andrew married Caroline Bonsall. The couple had
                    no children. Margaretta Howell Jones (1809-1874), daughter of Benjamin, married
                    John Madison Taylor and settled in Maryland. Their daughter Carrie Taylor was
                    married to James Maynard who was marshal to the consular courts in Turkey. Other
                    family members went on to fight in the Civil War, and still others fought in
                    World War I. Although the Joneses were successful merchants, Benjamin and
                    Andrew, with some help from younger son Richard (1812-1890), appear to be the
                    only two that ran the family business. Later members of the family went into
                    different fields of work.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Andrew M. Jones and other members of the Jones
                    and Taylor families. Family correspondence in the collection includes letters to
                    Andrew M. Jones and Caroline B. Jones from family members, including Samuel H.
                    Jones, Richard Jones, Harriet Jones, Anne Emlen, Benjamin Jones Jr., Carrie
                    Taylor (later Carrie Maynard), James Maynard, and J. M. Taylor. Letters discuss
                    activities of family and friends and matters related to the estates of Benjamin
                    Jones Sr. and M. J. Taylor. Business correspondence largely relates to land
                    purchases and sales, with some letters relating to the iron business. The
                    collection also includes; several receipts; bills for tuition; miscellaneous
                    pamphlets; newspaper clippings of recipes, shipping news, and poetry; a list of
                    chateaux in France; a survey of a plot of land in St. Mary's County, Maryland,
                    drawn for Thomas W. Gough; and a printed description of lands owned by Benjamin
                    and A. M Jones in Elk and M'Kean Counties, Pennsylvania.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Jones and Taylor family papers, collection 2037; and Jones family
                    account books, 1810-1874, collection 718.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>