<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Barnett collection of manuscripts <date type="inclusive">1663-1888</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Barnett collection of manuscripts</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2534</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1663-1888</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Andrew Cock (Cox) was a farmer and land owner who lived in Kingsess, in the
                    County of Philadelphia in the 18th century. He was the son of Valentine Cock and
                    brother of Otter Cox. Newesingh, or Navisink, was a piece of marshland near the
                    Schuylkill River. The land was granted in 1669 by the Dutch governor, Peter
                    Stuyvesant of New York to Peter Cock, and confirmed to him in 1681 by Governor
                    Francis Lovelace (1621-1675) of New York, and reconfirmed by William Penn after
                    his arrival.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscript deeds, mortgages, indentures, receipts, and
                    wills dating from the 17th to the 19th century. A number of the items are
                    related to Andrew Cox (or Cock), to his father Valentine Cock and his brother
                    Otter Cox. Of note are an inventory of land, goods, and chattel of Valentine
                    Cock (1725); other Valentine Cock estate papers; a bond between Andrew Cock and
                    Nicholas Scull (1728/9); and the will of Otter Cox (1744). Other materials
                    include a 1663 deed for a parcel of land (Newesingh or Boon's Island) to Maes
                    Hanssen; a 1672 patent, signed by Francis Lovelace; a 1826 fire insurance policy
                    for a house at 208 High Street in the name of Catherine Regli; a fragment of a
                    list of marriages and births of the Springer and Ferré families; three
                    memorandum books of stocks bought and sold, 1863-1888; and small amount of
                    correspondence and miscellaneous manuscripts.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift off Mr. and Mrs. Benjamin H. Barnett, 1974</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>