<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Biddle manuscripts <date type="inclusive">1770-1957</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Biddle manuscripts</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2524</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1770-1957</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Boit was born in Jamaica Plain, Massachusetts in 1858. He was a graduate of
                    Harvard Law School. He studied architecture in New York for several years and
                    built the New York Yacht Clubhouse in Newport. Thereafter he studied painting
                    under John LaFarge, and again in Julien's Studio in Paris. In 1904 he married
                    Louise Horstmann (b. 1869) of Washington, D.C.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscript letters and other documents given to the
                    Athenaeum by Mr. and Mrs. Peyton Biddle. A number of the manuscripts relate to
                    John Boit and his wife Louise Horstmann Boit. Materials include letters to
                    Louise Boit, including a series of letters from Edith Hamilton, 1945-1957, and
                    correspondence between Aubrey Stanhope and Louise Horstmann. One letter from
                    Stanhope, dated 1896, describes the "social side of the Coronation" of the
                    Empress of Russia, with discussion of Europeans and Americans present for the
                    occasion). John Boit's correspondence includes a letter to Stephen Leacock from
                    John Boit, undated, and a letter to John Boit from Chief Justice Edward Douglass
                    White, 1910. Other correspondence in the collection includes: a letter from
                    Josiah Quincy, Jr. (1744-1775) to his father, 1773-1774; a letter from Josiah
                    Quincy III (1772-1864) to Frederick Packard, 1859-1860; a letter from James
                    Madison to James Ogilvie, 1809; a 1770 summons signed by Edward Shippen; an 1863
                    letter to Secretary of War Stanton from Thaddeus Stevens; a letter from Horace
                    Greeley to William D. Kelley related to the movement of troops into Richmond in
                    1862; and several Civil War era passes for W. D. Kelley. The collection also
                    includes one folder of typed transcripts of letters of the King family,
                    1812-1826. The letters between family members in Jamaica and in the United
                    States discuss health and activities of family and friends, and several letters
                    make reference to the family's slaves. The original King family letters are held
                    by the York County Historical Society.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Peyton Biddle, 1973</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>