<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Blanche Pierce Bonaparte scrapbook <date type="inclusive">1899-1944</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Blanche Pierce Bonaparte scrapbook</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2533</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1899-1944</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Blanche Pierce, a noted society figure, was the daughter of Edward Y. and Emily
                    Hill Pierce. She married Harold A. Strebeigh in 1899. The couple had two
                    daughters, Blanche and Barbara. Mr. and Mrs. Strebeigh were divorced in 1914.
                    Shortly after her divorce was final, Blanche Strebeigh married her second
                    husband, Jérôme Napoléon Bonaparte, great grand-nephew of Napoleon, and son of
                    Jérôme Napoléon Bonaparte and Caroline Le Roy Appleton. The couple resided in
                    Washington D.C., Newport, Rhode Island, and Palm Beach, Florida. Blanche
                    Bonaparte died in 1950 in New York.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a scrapbook of newspaper clippings about the life of Blanche Strebeigh
                    Bonaparte. The clippings in the scrapbook document her first and second weddings
                    and her activities as a member of Newport, Boston, Naragansett, and Palm Beach
                    society.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Barbara Strebeigh (granddaughter of Mrs. Jerome
                    Bonaparte?)</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>