<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Burd family papers <date type="inclusive">1757-1932</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Burd family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2512</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1757-1932</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Burd family was a prominent Pennsylvania family active in the social,
                    economic and political affairs of the state. Col. James Burd (1726-1793) was
                    born in Scotland and immigrated to the United States, settling in Lancaster
                    County with his wife Sarah Shippen, a member of the prominent Shippen family of
                    Lancaster and Shippensburg. Edward Shippen Burd (1779-1848) was the grandson of
                    James and Sarah Burd. He was a lawyer in Philadelphia, married to Eliza Howard
                    Simms, daughter of Woodrop and Sarah Sims. Edward Shippen and Eliza Burd's
                    children included Elizabeth (1815-1845/6), Margaret (1819-1844), and Wooddrop
                    (1822-1837), all of whom predeceased both of their parents. Edward Shippen Burd
                    died in 1848; Eliza Burd honored her husband by commissioning the erection of a
                    monument to him at St. Stephen's Church, and several years later conceived the
                    idea of establishing a school for fatherless girls. She died in 1860, but her
                    will provided for the principles and funding of this institution. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Burd family papers. Materials include: letters from
                    Joseph Shippen to Edward Shippen Burd, 1798-1805; a letter from James Burd to
                    Edward Shippen, 1757; two volumes containing copies of the will of Edward
                    Shippen Burd; several deeds, dating from 1813 to 1833. Books belonging to
                    Margaret C. Burd, Elizabeth Shippen Burd, Eliza Howard (Sims) Burd, Woodropp
                    Sims Burd, and Sarah Hopkins. These include commonplace books of poetry and
                    watercolor illustrations; scrapbooks of illustrations; books with addresses of
                    friends in Paris and Philadelphia; volumes of poetry; a copy book; and a volume
                    of manuscript sheet music. A box of calling cards of Mme E.S. Burd, Mlle Burd,
                    and Mlle M.C. Burd. (mother and two daughters). A 1932 newspaper clipping about
                    Elizabeth Shippen Burd. The collection also includes interior and exterior
                    photographs of the Burd School at 63rd and Market Street and photographs of a
                    church. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Edward Shippen Burd papers, 1798-1858, collection # 104.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>