<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>C. Dudley Brown papers <date type="inclusive">1933-1966</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1950s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">C. Dudley Brown papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2510</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.16 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1933-1966</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1950s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>C. Dudley Brown A.I.D. is an interior designer and design consultant. His clients
                    and projects have included The Cosmos Club, the Australian ambassador's
                    residence, Glenview Mansion in Rockville, Capitol Hill Presbyterian Church, Kent
                    Valentine House in Richmond, Virginia, and a number of Chevy Chase residences.
                    In the 1960s, he was retained as a decorator and design consultant to the
                    Cochran Chair Co. He was awarded the 2006 Mayor's Award for Excellence in
                    Historic Preservation, served as the first president of the Washington Chapter
                    of the Victorian Society in America and remains an active member of the board of
                    the Society.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the alphabetical reference files of C. Dudley Brown.
                    The files include newspaper and magazine clippings, product catalogs, and
                    brochures. The bulk of the materials date from the 1950s and early 1960s, with a
                    few items dating back to the mid-1930s. Topics covered by the files include
                    antiques, clocks, display, early American furniture, modern furnishings,
                    hardware, windows, and remodeling. Sources of articles include American Home,
                    House Beautiful, New York Times Magazine, Better Homes and Gardens, and House
                    and Garden. There is some material related to Brown's work for the Cochran Chair
                    Co. including product catalogs, price lists, and a company history. The
                    collection also includes lecture notes, papers, drawings, and reference material
                    from courses taken by C. Dudley Brown on design, display, and professional
                    practice, 1951-1952.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>