<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Clement Biddle letterbooks <date type="inclusive">1795-1800</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Clement Biddle letterbooks</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2525</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.39 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1795-1800</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Clement Biddle (1740-1814) was the second son of John and Sarah Biddle. He was
                    born in Philadelphia and entered his father's shipping and importing business at
                    an early age. Business was interrupted by the onset of the Revolutionary War,
                    when in 1765, Clement and his brother, Owen, signed the non-importation
                    agreement and pursued patriotic activities in Philadelphia. In 1775, Clement
                    Biddle helped to organize a Philadelphia volunteer regiment, the "Quaker
                    Blues." In July 1776, he was appointed deputy quartermaster-general by
                    Congress, holding the rank of colonel. Clement participated in the battles of
                    Trenton, Brandywine, Germantown, and Monmouth, and he served under both
                    Washington and General Greene. After the Revolutionary War, he was the first
                    U.S. Marshal (1789-1793) for Pennsylvania.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of two letterbooks of Clement Biddle, 1795-1797 and
                    1797-1800. The letters discuss business matters, such as stocks, insurance,
                    payments on accounts, and real estate. Some of the letters include statements of
                    accounts. Notable correspondents include George Washington, Col. William
                    Deakins, Robert Morris, Jonathan Dayton, Benjamin Stoddert, and the firms
                    Armstrong &amp; Barnewall and LeRoy, Bayard, &amp; McEvers. Several letters from
                    1797 discuss the effects of the yellow fever epidemic on business affairs.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Peyton Biddle, 1973</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Biddle family papers, 1776-1876, collection # 1792H (includes
                    Clement Biddle business correspondence).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>