<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Curwen family papers <date type="inclusive">1763-1973</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Curwen family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2513</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>14.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1763-1973</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Curwen (1749-1825) was born in England and immigrated to Pennsylvania in
                    1784. His wife was Mary Fisher Curwen (1750-1818). In 1785 Curwen purchased
                    lands in Lower Merion in Montgomery County, calling his new estate Walnut Hill.
                    His son, Joseph Curwen (1778-1848), was an agent for Stephen Girard and was in
                    partnership with William Shippen Willing, selling tea, dry goods, and Madeira
                    wine. Another son, George Fisher Curwen I (1790-1847), spent a year in Stephen
                    Girard's Philadelphia counting house and briefly represented a Baltimore
                    mercantile house. In 1816 he traveled to Port au Prince overseeing cargo sales.
                    Upon his return in 1817 Curwen assumed management of Walnut Hill. He married
                    Elinor Hunter Ewing (1789-1879) in 1819. Their children were John Curwen, MD
                    (1821-1901), Mary Curwen (1823-1903), Maskell Ewing Curwen (1825-1868), and
                    George F. Curwen II (1828-1901). George F Curwen II was an oil tycoon and built
                    the current Walnut Hill house in 1864 near the site of John Curwen's 18th
                    century farmhouse. Edwin Forrest Durang designed the house and the builder was
                    William Danley. The wife of George Curwen II was Emily Moore Beatty Curwen
                    (1829-1907). Their children were: Samuel Moore Curwen (1859-1932), who worked
                    for the Brill Company, and also spent time in the west purchasing land, working
                    as a "cow puncher"; George Fisher Curwen III (1861-1945), John Curwen
                    (1863-1949); Maskell Ewing Curwen (1867-1918); and Christine Curwen (1871-1901).
                    George Fisher Curwen III married Helen Stoddard Osborne (1868-1959) in 1894.
                    Their children were Elinor E. Curwen (b. 1896) and Alice Osborne Curwen McKeen
                    (Mrs. Edward F. McKeen) (b. 1902). Elinor lived at Eltham on the family estate.
                    From 1926 to 1931 she ran the New York office of Masquelier &amp; Fils. From
                    1933 to 1937 she worked at Irving Trust Co., after which she returned home to
                    stay with her parents in Villanova. Other families represented in the collection
                    include Ewing, Beatty, Patterson, Moore, Tanner, Osborne, Stoddard, Leaming,
                    Hunter, and Wynkoop.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of the Curwen family of Villanova, Pennsylvania.
                    Materials include: correspondence; family financial records; diaries,
                    commonplace books, poems, and other writings; notes on family history and family
                    trees; recollections and personal narratives; wills and estate papers; a small
                    number of photographs and cartes de visites; sketches; school papers and report
                    cards; miscellaneous certificates; printed materials, such as newspaper
                    clippings and family and parish histories; family bibles; wedding invitations;
                    and obituaries. Materials related to Walnut Hill, the Curwen family estate,
                    include: farm and house accounts; deeds, mortgages, and legal papers; blueprints
                    of the subdivision of the estate; several sketches of estate buildings and
                    ground plans; interior and exterior photographs; clippings of an Architectural
                    Age article on the estate; and correspondence about subdivision of the property
                    and ownership. There are also inventories made in 1946 of the furnishings of
                    Spring iIll, the home of Mr. and Mrs. George Curwen. Materials related to lands
                    in Western Pennsylvania owned by the Curwen family include: deeds and letters
                    relating to the purchase of lands; a patent for 355 acres in Lycoming County,
                    1789; and additional patents from the 1790s for several parcels of land. The
                    collection also includes letters to Joseph Curwen from Stephen Girard,
                    1810-1811, and business correspondence of Samuel Curwen (1859-1932) with
                    miscellaneous bills related to his work for Brill Co.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Elinor Ewing Curwen and Alice Curwen McKeen, 1970-1972</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>