<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Henry Charles Lea manuscripts <date type="inclusive">1839-1922</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1865-1922</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Henry Charles Lea manuscripts</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2516</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1839-1922</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1865-1922</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henry Charles Lea (1825-1909) was a prominent Philadelphia intellectual and
                    historian writing books on medieval history and the Inquisition. He was involved
                    and recognized as a preeminent historian and philanthropist by the American
                    Philosophical Society, the Historical Society of Pennsylvania, and the
                    University of Pennsylvania. Lea was also a businessman buying and improving
                    stores along 7th and Sansom Streets from 1865 to 1895. The importance of these
                    buildings is that they were built between 1800-1802 and became the stereotypical
                    "Philadelphia row home" copied by other east coast cities. As architects Lea
                    used the firm of Collins and Autenrieth, John Crump (1827-1892), and Rudolph
                    Blankenburg (1843-1918), who was mayor of Philadelphia in 1911 until 1915. Lea
                    relied on several carpenters and builders including Michael Errickson, James H.
                    Errickson, Yarnall and Cooper, and Kister and Orem, all of Philadelphia.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence between H. C. Lea and family and various
                    contractors, architects, and attorneys. Also included are agreements with
                    contractors, fire inspection certificates, receipts for materials suppliers,
                    payments to contractors, property taxes, and water rents for Philadelphia and
                    Cape May properties. Legal notes are also included for sales and settlements of
                    property. The collection also includes an undated building survey for the corner
                    of 5th and Walnut Streets. Among the Philadelphia addresses represented in the
                    collection are: 600 and 700 block of Sansom Street; 11 and 13 Bank Street; 16
                    and 18 Strawberry Street; 900 block of Chestnut; and 428-432 Walnut Street (Penn
                    Building). Cape May addresses include 9 Grant Street, S. Lafayette Street, and 6
                    Windsor Street.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Acquired by purchase from Carmen Valentino.</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>