<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Henry D. Gilpin papers <date type="inclusive">1818-1843</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Henry D. Gilpin papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2537</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1818-1843</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henry Dilworth Gilpin (1801-1860) was an American lawyer and statesman of Quaker
                    extraction who served as Attorney General of the United States. After graduating
                    from the University of Pennsylvania, he studied law with Joseph R. Ingersoll and
                    was admitted to the bar in 1822. He served as U.S. Attorney for the Eastern
                    District of Pennsylvania from 1831 to 1837, and then as Solicitor of the United
                    States Treasury in 1837. During this time he joined the American Philosophical
                    Society and from 1833 to 1835 he was on the board of the Bank of the United
                    States. President Martin Van Buren named him 14th Attorney General of the United
                    States in 1840. He served until 1841, during which time he presented the U.S.
                    government's side of the Amistad case to the U.S. Supreme Court. From 1853 until
                    1858 he was President of the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts and from 1856 to
                    1858 he was a director of Girard College. He was also a secretary and director
                    of the Chesapeake and Delaware Canal. Gilpin died in 1860.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Henry D. Gilpin. Items include: a docket book
                    involving Gilpin and other attorneys, 1818-1843; a scrapbook of clippings on
                    legal cases, 1831-1833; a volume of Gilpin's notes on algebra and analytical
                    geometry taken during his education at University of Pennsylvania, [after 1816];
                    and a letter of introduction to Levi Woodbury, Secretary of the Navy, written by
                    H.D. Gilpin for James M. Broom Jr., dated 1833. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: HIstorical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Gilpin Family papers. Collection 238. </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>