<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Herman Beerman and Thomas Hart collections of Sherlockiana <date type="inclusive">1908-1984</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Herman Beerman and Thomas Hart collections of
                    Sherlockiana</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC951</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1908-1984</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Herman Beerman (1901-1995) was one of the founders of the Society for
                    Investigative Dermatology, which established the Annual Herman Beerman Lecture
                    in 1960. He was also a founder and early president of the American Society of
                    Dermatopathology, and chaired the Department of Dermatology at the University of
                    Pennsylvania from 1949 to 1967. Beerman was an eminent dermatologist and an
                    enthusiastic Sherlockian, and he combined his two worlds by founding The Sir
                    James Saunders Society for dermatologists who shared his enjoyment of the Canon.
                    Sherlock Holmes is a famous fictional detective of the late nineteenth and early
                    twentieth centuries, who first appeared in publication in 1887. He is the
                    creation of Scottish-born author and physician Sir Arthur Conan Doyle.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of Sherlockiana collected by Herman Beerman and Thomas
                    Hart and given to the Athenaeum. The Beerman materials include: a framed thank
                    you note signed by A. Conan Doyle; a color illustration of Sherlock Holmes; a
                    silhouette of Holmes by Ben Wolf; Beerman's membership certificate to the Baker
                    Street Irregulars; a bank check featuring an image of Sherlock Holmes; and a
                    plaque awarded to Herman Beerman as Consultant to the Sir James Saunders
                    Society, 1984. Other items collected by Beerman include: a meerschaum pipe; an
                    audiocassette tape of Dvorak's 8th Symphony; an audiocassette tape of
                    Sherlockian esoterica; swizzle sticks; ballpoint pens; a medal featuring the
                    image of Arthur Conan Doyle; business cards of Sherlock Homes, Mycroft Holmes,
                    and Professor Moriarty; a soap sculpture of Sherlock Holmes; a small pewter
                    silhouette of Holmes; a ceramic plate depicting John Watson; a tin cannister;
                    35mm slides of Sherlockian meetings, movie stills, and illustrations of Holmes
                    tales; and a Sherlock Holmes wooden nutcracker. The collection also includes a
                    framed certificate belonging to Thomas Hart given to him by the Sons of the
                    Copper Beeches, 1958.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 87.5</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>