<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Samuel family papers <date type="inclusive">1830-1962</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Samuel family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2523</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.54 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1830-1962</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Samuels were a noted Jewish family in Philadelphia. David Samuel (1804-1881)
                    and Esther (Hetty) Moss Samuel (1808-1867), were the parents of John Samuel
                    (1829-1913) and Joseph Bunford Samuel (1853-1929). John Samuel was a prominent
                    attorney and member of Congregation Mikveh Israel. His son, John D. Samuel (b.
                    1869) was married to Maria Amilla Robb (b. 1869). Their daughter Lois Samuel (b.
                    1902) donated the family's papers to the Athenaeum. Maria's parents were Maria A
                    Burnett (1835-1903) and James M. Robb (1823-1899). William Moss (1831-1895) was
                    a cousin of John Samuel. Members of the Levy family include Hayman Levy
                    (1795-1865) and his wife, Almeria DeLeon Levy (1798-1882) and their children
                    Rebecca Hendricks Levy Samuel (1832-1915), Julian Levy (c. 1834-1862), and
                    Solomon B. Levy (1823-1865).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of the Samuel family of Philadelphia. There are
                    also some papers of the Levy and Robb families. John Samuel materials include:
                    letters; newspaper obituaries and memorials; published writings; and disbound
                    scrapbooks assembled by Samuel. Scrapbooks include correspondence, published
                    writings, Civil War and antebellum memorabilia, and newspaper clippings of
                    letters to the editor from John Samuel about the inequality of the races and
                    arguments for legal disenfranchisement of African-Americans. John D. and Millie
                    Samuel materials include: correspondence; memorabilia; poetry; school papers;
                    papers on Maria's family background (the Robbs); tintypes of Millie and her
                    brother Harry; and a tintype of the Robb family. Other Millie materials include
                    letters and newspaper clippings related to her political activities as a member
                    of the Women's Democratic Committee and as appointee to a vacant Magistrate's
                    seat by Governor Sproul in the early 1920s. Joseph Bunford Samuel materials
                    include genealogical research and papers related to the publication of Records
                    of the Samuel Family, and documentation related to his acquisition of the statue
                    of Thorfinn Karlsefni in Fairmount Park. David and Esther Samuel materials
                    include wills, stock certificates, cemetery records, and trust papers. Levy
                    family materials include: wills and legal documents; family letters; letters
                    from Julian and Solomon Levy written during their service in the Civil War; and
                    life insurance certificates and receipts for slaves owned by the Levy family.
                </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Donated by Lois Samuel, 1968</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>