<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sarah Josepha Hale papers <date type="inclusive">1827-1869</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sarah Josepha Hale papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2514</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1827-1869</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Sarah Josepha Buell Hale (1788-1879) was an American writer. She is well known as
                    the author of the popular nursery rhyme "Mary Had a Little Lamb." In 1823 Hale
                    published her first book of poems, The Genius of Oblivion, with her late
                    husband's Freemason lodge paying for the publication. Her career was firmly
                    established with her first novel, Northwood, released in 1827. Hale served as
                    editor of Ladies' Magazine from 1827-1836 and Godey's Lady's Book from
                    1837-1877. Hale continued to write poetry, novels, and children's literature,
                    while serving as a major editorial force for the next fifty years. Over her
                    lifetime, Hale produced nearly fifty volumes of work.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence, both incoming and outgoing, of Sarah
                    Josepha Hale, dating from 1827 to 1869. Correspondents include David E. Hale,
                    D.E. Wilson, Emma Willard, L.A. Godey, Mrs. Sigourney, Mrs. Phelps, and assorted
                    others. Correspondence between Sarah and her son, David Hale, 1829-1839, written
                    while David was a cadet at West Point and later a Lieutenant in the Army. In the
                    1830s, David Hale was sent to Florida to fight in the Indian Wars. His letters
                    describe battles with the Seminoles as well as his activities in camp and the
                    progress of his career in the Army. He also mentions his regiment being sent to
                    Baltimore to deal with riots in that city. The collection also includes several
                    newspaper clippings.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>