<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>T. Morris Longstreth papers <date type="inclusive">1901-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">T. Morris Longstreth papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2518</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1901-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas Morris Longstreth (b. 1886) was an author. His works were published in the
                    Christian Science Monitor and other publications. His books include Knowing the
                    Weather, The Silent Force, The Laurentians, The Catskills, and The Lake Superior
                    Country. Charles Wharton Stork (b. 1883) was a poet and teacher who lived in
                    Philadelphia. His published volumes include Hearts and Voices, On Board Old
                    Ironsides, and Sea and Bay. He was also a translator and anthololgist of Swedish
                    poetry. He taught English Literature for 25 years at Harcum College, Bryn Mawr,
                    Pennsylvania, and lectured on poetry around the country and overseas. He was a
                    founder of Contemporary Verse magazine, and served as president of the Poetry
                    Society of America and of the Browning Society in Philadelphia.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence between T. Morris Longstreth and Charles
                    Wharton Stork, from 1901 to 1968. The majority of the letters are from
                    Longstreth to Stork. The letters discuss the writing output and careers of both
                    men, with comments and suggestions passing back and forth. The letters
                    occasionally touch on family matters and events of the day, but their main focus
                    in on the craft of writing. The letters include a number of poems by Stork, and
                    several by Longstreth. There are newspaper clippings of pieces by Longstreth and
                    several clippings of reviews. The collection also includes a small amount of
                    correspondence between Longstreth and Stork's wife Lisl. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Syracuse University:
                    Charles Wharton Stork Papers, Special Collections Research Center, Syracuse
                    University Library </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>