<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas Fletcher papers <date type="inclusive">1774-1949</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1774-1905</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas Fletcher papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2530</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1774-1949</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1774-1905</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas Fletcher (1787-1866) was a Philadelphia silversmith. His partner in
                    business was Sidney Gardiner. In Boston in 1808, he and Sidney Gardiner founded
                    the firm Fletcher &amp; Gardiner. In 1811, they moved the firm to Philadelphia.
                    Between 1811 and 1826, the firm received many important commissions for
                    commemorative or presentation silver pieces. They made several pieces for heroes
                    of the War of 1812, including Isaac Hull, Jacob Jones, James Biddle and Oliver
                    Hazard Perry. Thomas Fletcher was one of the five original founders of the
                    Franklin Institute. After Sidney Gardiner's death in 1827, Fletcher carried on
                    the business. From 1836 to 1839, he was a partner with Calvin Wilder Bennett
                    (operating as Fletcher &amp; Bennett). Thomas Fletcher's brothers Charles and
                    George were also silversmiths and jewelers. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of the Fletcher family of Philadelphia, including
                    Timothy Fletcher and his children Thomas, Charles, Melanie, George, Frank,
                    James, and Levi, as well as his grandson Veron Fletcher. The bulk of the
                    materials relate to the life and business activities of Thomas Fletcher.
                    Business materials include correspondence (of the firms Fletcher &amp; Gardiner,
                    Fletcher &amp; Bennett, and Baldwin &amp; Fletcher); bills of lading; freight
                    lists; indentures and agreements; commissions and orders for vases, swords,
                    necklaces, and communion vessels. Fletcher family papers include correspondence;
                    wills and deeds; estate papers; personal essays and poetry; clippings;
                    genealogical records; marriage certificates; passports; and a small number of
                    records of personal investments. Notable items in the collection include
                    statements of Fletcher family members made upon the laying of the cornerstone of
                    their country house in 1899; and a plan of lots in Delanco, New Jersey belonging
                    to the estate of Thomas Fletcher. The collection also includes some papers of
                    George Dummer.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Marjorie Fletcher Thomson Bowden, 1994</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Thomas Flecther letters (Collection 1343); Winterthur Archives:
                    Thomas Flecther papers (Collection 278).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>