<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Travelers' Club of Philadelphia records <date type="inclusive">1858-1913</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1886-1894</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Athenaeum of Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Travelers' Club of Philadelphia records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoPSp.ACC2536</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Athenaeum of Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.21 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1858-1913</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1886-1894</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Travelers Protective Association is a fraternal organization of traveling
                    salesmen and other traveling businessmen. The Association was founded in Chicago
                    in 1882 to serve as a forum for members to meet and discuss the problems and
                    challenges of their mode of business. Today, the Association conducts monthly
                    meetings, engages in a variety of charitable activities, and provides its
                    members with networking opportunities and experience in public speaking and
                    conducting meetings. The Association's headquarters are in St. Louis, Missouri,
                    and it has chapters in Pennsylvania and Indiana.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of minute books of the Travelers Club of Philadelphia
                    (also called the Pennsylvania Division, Travelers Protective Association),
                    1886-1894. Minutes record the club's routine business conducted at monthly
                    meetings, including reports of committees, changes to the constitution and
                    by-laws, and nominations and resignations of members. The collection also
                    includes a small amount of correspondence, reports, a manuscript list, possibly
                    of dues, written on the back of an tobacco company advertisement illustration,
                    newspaper clippings, and a pamphlet entitled "Manual of the Active Principles
                    of Indigenous and Foreign Medicinal Plants" from B. Keith &amp; Co., New York,
                    1858.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>