<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>A. B. Frost collection <date type="inclusive">1874-1994</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1874-1933</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">A. B. Frost collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2343</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1874-1994</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1874-1933</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Arthur Burdett Frost (1851-1928) was an American illustrator, graphic artist,
                    comics writer, and painter. Born in Philadelphia, Frost's first illustrations
                    were published in 1874. In 1876, Frost joined the art department at the
                    publisher Harper &amp; Brothers, where he worked with such well-known
                    illustrators as Howard Pyle, E. W. Kemble, Frederic Remington, and C. S.
                    Reinhart. In 1877 and 1878, Frost went to London to study with some of the great
                    cartoonists of the time. Later, he returned to Philadelphia and studied under
                    painters Thomas Eakins and William Merritt Chase at the Pennsylvania Academy of
                    the Fine Arts. Soon after returning, he published several stories formed of
                    sequential drawings with captions, pioneering the form that would later develop
                    into comic strips and comic books. In 1884, Frost published Stuff and Nonsense,
                    an anthology of his previous works that advanced the concept of time-stop
                    drawings and contained several other innovations. From 1906 until May of 1914,
                    Frost and his family lived in France, attracted by the impressionist artistic
                    movement. Upon returning to the United States, he continued work as an
                    illustrator and comics artist, mainly for Life magazine.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of drawings and published books illustrated by A. B. Frost.
                    Volumes with illustrations by Frost include the "Uncle Remus" stories of Joel
                    Chandler Harris and Rhyme and Reason by Lewis Carroll. A few of the volumes
                    include additional original sketches by Frost. Drawings in the collection
                    include; 136 originals for Bull Calf and Other Tales; published edition and set
                    of drawings for Stuff and Nonsense, including several unpublished illustrations;
                    drawings for Skating Series; and a collection of Frost's contributions to
                    Scribner's and Harper's magazines, 1880-1928. The collection also includes a
                    catalog from a 1994 exhibition at the Morris Museum entitled "The Best of A.B.
                    Frost"; and a volume about Frost entitled A.B. Frost, the American Sportsman's
                    Artist, by Henry W. Lanier, 1933.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Free Library of
                    Philadelphia: History of the book and Illustration manuscripts (5 letters and 2
                    sketches by Frost); Princeton University: A. B. Frost collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>