<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Aerial photograph collection <date type="inclusive">1928-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Map Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Aerial photograph collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2358</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Map Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1928-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Aero Service Corporation began in 1919 in Philadelphia and was a pioneer and
                    world leader in aerial photography and photogrammetry. Directed by Virgil I.
                    Kauffman, a World War I veteran pilot who joined the company in 1924, the firm
                    obtained lucrative government and private contracts including those with the
                    United States Geological Survey and the Tennessee Valley Authority that involved
                    some of the first aerial surveys of the country. In 1924, pilot J. Victor
                    Dallin, a former member of the Royal Air Force and veteran of the First World
                    War, formed the Dallin Aerial Survey Company. Operating out of the Philadelphia
                    Municipal Airport, his company was one of many during the era searching for
                    business opportunities that utilized the nascent technology of the airplane.
                    Dallin's company took thousands of aerial photographs throughout the
                    Mid-Atlantic region, most in the Philadelphia area. The Delaware Valley Regional
                    Planning Commission (DVRPC) is the metropolitan planning organization for the
                    Delaware Valley. Created in 1965 by an interstate compact, DVRPC is responsible
                    for transportation and regional planning in the greater Philadelphia area.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of aerial photographs of Philadelphia and vicinity from 1928
                    to 2000. Materials in the collection include: 170 aerial photographs of
                    Philadelphia and the surrounding area by the Regional Planning Federation of the
                    Philadelphia Tri-State District, 1928; 33 aerial photographs, as well as 4 boxes
                    of reformatted photographs, of Philadelphia and the surrounding area by Dallin
                    Aerial Surveys, 1930; 5 volumes, reformatted into 23 boxes of aerial photographs
                    of Philadelphia and the vicinity by Aero Service Corporation, 1945; 6 boxes of
                    Philadelphia aerial photographs, which was reflown by the Aero Service
                    Corporation, 1950; aerial photographs of Philadelphia and vicinity by Delaware
                    Valley Regional Planning Commission, with sets for Philadelphia from every 5
                    years, and more sporadic coverage of the surrounding area, 1965-1995; and aerial
                    photographs in digital form of the Delaware Valley region by Delaware Valley
                    Regional Planning Commission, 2000. (Note that all available DVRPC photos from
                    1965-2005 will soon be available in digital format.) The collection also
                    includes real estate atlases by Real Estate Data Inc. for Bucks, Montgomery (2
                    volumes), Chester, and Delaware counties, 1971-1979.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Free Library of
                    Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection: Aerial photographs.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>