<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Aliki papers <date type="inclusive">1962-1975</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature Research
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Aliki papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2402</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature
                    Research Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1962-1975</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Aliki Liacouras Brandenberg (b. 1929) is an author and illustrator of books for
                    children. Aliki graduated from the Philadelphia Museum School of Art in 1951.
                    Before she began writing books for children, Aliki worked as a freelance artist,
                    creating art for advertising and display purposes. She also taught classes in
                    art, worked as a muralist, and started a greeting card company. Her first book,
                    The Story of William Tell, was published in 1960. Over her career, she has
                    written many books and illustrated the books of other authors, including her
                    husband Franz Brandenberg.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of sketches, illustrations, dummies, color separations and
                    pasteups for This is the House Where Jack Lives, My Five Senses, Birds at Night,
                    Averages, and The Story of William Penn.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Minnesota, Children's Literature Research Collections: Aliki Brandenberg
                    papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>