<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Americana collection <date type="inclusive">1787-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Americana collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2378</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1787-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Among the exemplary collections of the Free Library of Philadelphia is the Print
                    and Picture Collection. Spanning the graphic arts from 1493 to the present time,
                    the Free Library's Fine Art Prints and Photographs collection includes thousands
                    of images. Initially representing only Philadelphia artists, the collection has
                    been extended to include early masters as well as renowned modern printmakers
                    and photographers. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Free Library's collection of Americana is composed of over 8,000 prints,
                    photographs, and pictures relating to American military, political, and social
                    history. Of particular interest is a complete Julius Bien chromolithographed
                    elephant folio edition of John James Audubon's Birds of North America,
                    1858-1860. Other notable printmakers represented include J. T. Bowen, Thomas
                    Doughty, John Hill, George Endicott, John Sartain, and Currier and Ives. The
                    collection also includes several hundred trade cards as well as numerous
                    political cartoons and items related to political campaigns. Civil war prints
                    are also well represented. Other items include: bottle labels, baseball cards,
                    stationary, greeting cards, calling calls, newspaper and magazine clippings,
                    postcards, realia, and maps. Subject categories found in the collection include:
                    military, political, and social history; political cartoons; commerce and
                    technology; geographic locations; and decorative arts, fine arts,
                    architecture.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Free Library of
                    Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection: 19th century trade cards
                    collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>