<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>A. P. Hankins collection <date type="inclusive">1945-1957</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">A. P. Hankins collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2373</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.14 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1945-1957</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Abraham Peter Hankins (1904-1963) was born in Gomel, Russia. He was sent to the
                    United States in 1914 to live with his cousins and study at the Pennsylvania
                    Academy of the Fine Arts and the Philadelphia Museum College of Art. Hankins
                    served in the U.S. Army during World War I. After the war, he studied at the
                    Academy Julien and worked privately with M. de Montholon. Returning to
                    Philadelphia, he attended the Philadelphia Museum School of Art, the Barnes
                    Foundation, and the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts. His work is in the
                    collections of the Philadelphia Museum of Art, the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine
                    Arts, the Free Library of Philadelphia and the Barnes Foundation.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of etchings, aquatints, serigraphs, monotypes, woodcuts, and
                    pastels by Abraham P. Hankins. The collection also includes a sketchbook kept by
                    Hankins, several watercolors and a few sketches.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Free Library of
                    Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collections: WPA collection and Fine print
                    collection (both include Hankins); Smithsonian Institution, Archives of American
                    Art: Abraham P. Hankins papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>