<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Augustus Köllner collection <date type="inclusive">1840-1889</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Augustus Köllner collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2370</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1840-1889</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Augustus Köllner (1813-1900) was a lithographer, engraver, and landscape painter
                    in watercolor. He was born in Germany and came to the United States in 1839 or
                    1840. He settled in Philadelphia and soon became associated with the
                    lithographic firm of W. M. Huddy and Peter S. Duval. In 1851 he became a partner
                    for a brief period of Henry Camp. He also made a series of lithographs for the
                    American Sunday School Union. The earliest of these seems to have been produced
                    in the late 1840s, with others following periodically in the 1850s. One of
                    Köllner's favorite subjects was domestic animals.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of watercolors, drawings, etchings, lithographs, American
                    Sunday School prints, and panoramas. Prints depict views of the Schuylkill and
                    Delaware Rivers, Cobb's, Cohocksink, and Pennypack Creeks, Delaware Narrows,
                    Fairmount Park, and bridges, houses, city street scenes, and charitable
                    institutions. Other prints and drawings include a small number of views from
                    outside of Pennsylvania, military uniforms (for U.S. Military Magazine),
                    domestic animals, and lithographs produced for the American Sunday School
                    Union.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Free Library of
                    Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection: Castner scrapbooks and Lewis
                    portrait collection include works by Kollner.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>