<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Beatrice Schenk De Regniers papers <date type="inclusive">1962-1967</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature Research
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Beatrice Schenk De Regniers papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2426</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature
                    Research Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1962-1967</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Beatrice Schenk de Regniers (1914-2000) was a writer of children's books. She was
                    trained in social work and held a Master's in Education from Winnetka Graduate
                    Teachers' College. During the 1950s she began writing for children, and The
                    Giant Story (illustrated by Maurice Sendak) appeared in 1953. In addition, she
                    wrote articles and stories for adults. In 1961, she became the first editor of
                    Scholastic Book's "Lucky Book Club." Twenty years later she retired to write
                    for the theater. Her first production appeared in 1986, based on her book
                    Everyone Is Good for Something. She wrote more than 50 children's books, some
                    using the pseudonym Tamara Kitt, and was the recipient of many awards and
                    honors.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscripts, notes, and correspondence of Beatrice de
                    Regniers. Documentation is present for The Little Girl and Her Mother, Willy
                    O'Dwyer Jumped in the Fire, May I Bring a Friend?, and The Abe Lincoln Joke
                    Book. Materials include production notes and correspondence with editors;
                    annotated manuscripts; galley proofs; dummies; blurb text; and notes by the
                    author on the creation of Willy O'Dwyer.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Minnesota, Children's Literature Research Collections: Beatrice Schenk de
                    Regniers papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>