<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Benton Spruance collection <date type="inclusive">1928-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Benton Spruance collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2366</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1928-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Benton Spruance (1904-1967) was an important American lithographer of the 20th
                    century. He lived and worked in the Philadelphia area, teaching printmaking at
                    the Philadelphia College of Art and Beaver College. His lithographs chronicle
                    the city and the world from the 1930s through the 1960s, and depict scenes of
                    urban life, dramatic images of football players, stories from the Bible, and
                    Moby Dick. During his long career Spruance served for many years on the
                    Philadelphia Art Commission, was the chairman of the Arts Department of Beaver
                    College, Jenkintown, and the chairman of the Printmaking Department of the
                    Philadelphia College of Art. His work is in the collections of the Library of
                    Congress, the National Gallery of Art, the New York Public Library, the Museum
                    of Modern Art and the Whitney Museum in New York, the Philadelphia Museum of
                    Art, the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts and the Carnegie Institute.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of works by Benton Spruance. Works include portraits,
                    landscapes, cityscapes, and allegorical and biblical themes in a variety of
                    media including lithographs, etchings, drypoints, aquatints, woodcuts,
                    monotypes, drawings, and pastels. The collection also includes a copy of Moby
                    Dick, the Passion of Ahab, a set of 26 lithographs by Spruance with excerpts
                    from the novel; sets of proofs of several works by Spruance; architectural plans
                    and six gouaches for a mural installed in the Holmsburg House of Detention,
                    1960; and several photographs of the artist at work.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>