<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Carolyn Haywood papers <date type="inclusive">1940-1982</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature Research
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Carolyn Haywood papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2398</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature
                    Research Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.9 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1940-1982</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Carolyn Haywood (1898-1990) was an author and illustrator of children's books.
                    She attended the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, where she studied with
                    Elizabeth Shippen Green and Jessie Willcox Smith, and where she served as studio
                    assistant for Violet Oakley, the renowned artist and muralist. Haywood herself
                    painted murals in banks and schools throughout Philadelphia, where they can
                    still be viewed today. Her first children's book, When I Grow Up, was published
                    in 1931, and in 1939 she hit her stride with the first of the Betsy and Eddie
                    books, B Is for Betsy. She wrote about the childhood adventures of these two
                    characters for more than fifty years. In her later years, her books were
                    illustrated by other artists. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscripts and illustrations by Haywood. Materials
                    include typescript manuscripts, galley proofs, original and finished art and
                    jacket art. Titles include Away Went the Balloons, B Is for Betsy, Besty and Mr.
                    Kilpatrick, C is for Cupcake, Eddie the Dog Holder, Here Comes the Bus, Merry
                    Christmas from Betsy, Robert Rows the River, A Sundae with Judy, Taffy and
                    Melissa Molasses, and A Valentine Fantasy. The collection also includes
                    illustrations for an edition of Pinocchio which was never published; and a
                    miniature portrait of Haywood by Malthe Hasselriis.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Minnesota, Children's Literature Research Collections: Carolyn Haywood
                    papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>