<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Castner scrapbooks <date type="inclusive">1845-1962</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1880s-1940s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Castner scrapbooks</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2362</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1845-1962</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1880s-1940s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Samuel Castner, Jr. (1843-1929), was born in Philadelphia. He was president of
                    the firm Castner, Curran &amp; Bullitt, coal operators, and was a director of
                    the American Dredging Company. He was a member of the Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania, a president of the Catholic Historical Society, and a member of
                    the Union League. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This richly illustrated collection of scrapbooks was assembled by Samuel Castner,
                    Jr. Most items date to the 19th century, though a few items, dating up to 1962,
                    were added after the scrapbooks were donated to the Free Library. The scrapbooks
                    contain various items of Philadelphiana: photographs, prints, watercolors,
                    drawings, postcards, booklets, newspaper and magazine clippings, and other
                    printed and manuscript materials. The scrapbooks are organized by location,
                    building type, or theme. Artists represented in the collection include William
                    and Thomas Birch, Cephas G. Childs, Augustus Köllner, the Langenheim brothers,
                    and Frank H. Taylor. The collection also includes photographic prints of
                    selected images from volumes 2-22 and negatives of selected images from the
                    entire run of scrapbooks.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>