<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charles Dickens collection <date type="inclusive">1846-1965</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charles Dickens collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2342</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1846-1965</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles Dickens (1812-1870) was one of the most popular English novelists of the
                    Victorian era as well as a vigorous social campaigner. Hablot Knight Browne
                    (1815-1882) was an English artist, famous as Phiz, the illustrator of the
                    best-known books by Charles Dickens, Charles Lever and Harrison Ainsworth in
                    their original editions. Dickens met George Cruikshank (1792-1878) through the
                    publisher John Macrone, who suggested that Dickens should put together a book
                    with illustrations by Cruikshank. The result was Sketches by Boz published in
                    1836. Cruikshank would later illustrate Dickens' Oliver Twist and was an actor
                    in some of the plays done by Dickens' amateur company. George Cattermole
                    (1800-1868), was a Dickens friend and illustrator, collaborating with Browne
                    (Phiz), on Master Humphrey's Clock and the novels The Old Curiosity Shop and
                    Barnaby Rudge. Cattermole's specialty was interior and exterior architectural
                    illustration rather than character drawings.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of original drawings for Dickens by Hablot Knight Browne
                    (Phiz), George Cattermole, and George Cruikshank. The collection contains
                    pencil, charcoal, and several pencil and pen drawings by Browne for David
                    Copperfield, Domby and Son, and Bleak House. The collection also includes pencil
                    sketches by Cruickshank including a study for "Bumble" from Oliver Twist;
                    letters from Kate Perugini, Dickens's daughter, addressed to Mr. Charles
                    Sessler; several issues of The Bookman magazine with presentation plate
                    portraits of Charles Dickens (1910-1912); a set of 12 hand-colored extra
                    illustrations to the Pickwick Papers, by Charles E. Brock, 1921; lithographic
                    portrait of Charles Dickens by H. Blackburn Hart; and two engravings, one by
                    Darley and the other by Cruickshank. The collection also contains greeting
                    cards, Christmas cards, and postcards featuring illustrations from Dickens
                    (1905-1965); and postcards of the Dickens house and other Dickens-related
                    images.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Free Library of
                    Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection: Rutter collection of Dickens
                    illustrations.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>