<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Collection of pictures, albums and newspaper clippings about the
                        real James Bond <date type="inclusive">1927-1991</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Collection of pictures, albums and newspaper clippings
                    about the real James Bond</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2351</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1927-1991</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James Bond (1900-1989) was a leading American ornithologist. Bond was born in
                    Philadelphia and worked at the Academy of Natural Sciences, rising to become
                    curator of birds. He was an expert in Caribbean birds and wrote the definitive
                    book on the subject: Birds of the West Indies, first published in 1936. Bond won
                    the Institute of Jamaica's Musgrave Medal in 1952; the Brewster Medal of the
                    American Ornithologists Union in 1954; and the Leidy Medal of the Academy of
                    Natural Sciences in 1975. Author Ian Fleming appropriated his name for his
                    fictional spy.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials related to the ornithologist James Bond.
                    Scrapbooks in the collection consist of letters, photos, and clippings, from
                    1953 to 1991. Included are items related to the fictional James Bond, James
                    Bond's work as an ornithologist, Mary Bond's published works and her articles in
                    local newspapers and newsletters, the awarding of the Leidy medal to James Bond,
                    and the death of James Bond. The collection also includes: correspondence of
                    Mary W. Bond from editors, publishers and fans; correspondence between Mary Bond
                    and Ian Fleming's secretary; royalty statements; photographs of Bond and his
                    wife, including a photograph of James Bond meeting Ian Fleming; an audio tape of
                    Mary Bond being interviewed by the BBC in 1966; and correspondence with several
                    students, historians, and collectors of Bondiana. Manuscripts by Mary Bond
                    include a published copy and advance proofs of How 007 Got His Name; and
                    publisher's proofs of To James Bond with Love. There is also a typescript of The
                    Private World of James Bond by David Contosta. Personal Bondiana (unrelated to
                    007) includes: gun and collecting permits, lists of awards, a map showing the
                    "Bond Line" in the Caribbean, Bond's curriculum vitae, reviews of Bond's Birds
                    of the West Indies, reprints of ornithological articles by Bond miscellaneous
                    clippings, a photograph of Bond skinning a bird and a small die-cast metal model
                    of an Aston Martin.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences: James Bond papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>