<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>D. Jacques Benoliel collection of the letters of Charles Dickens
                            <date type="inclusive">1832-1993</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1832-1870</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">D. Jacques Benoliel collection of the letters of Charles
                    Dickens</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2341</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1832-1993</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1832-1870</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles Dickens (1812-1870) was one of the most popular English novelists of the
                    Victorian era as well as a vigorous social campaigner.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence, manuscript material, and other items
                    related to Charles Dickens. The bulk of the correspondence consists of autograph
                    letters by Dickens. Significant correspondents include William Harrison
                    Ainsworth, George Cattermole, George Cruikshank, John Leech, Mark Lemon, Daniel
                    Maclise, Clarkson Stanfield, Frank Stone, and Thomas Adolphus Trollope. There
                    are also autograph letters from some of these correspondents and from other
                    members of Dickens's circle of family, friends, and associates. Manuscripts in
                    the collection include: The Life of Our Lord; five leaves of Pickwick Papers; a
                    corrected copy of The Cricket on the Hearth; and fragments of several other
                    stories, plays, and poems. Ephemera and memorabilia include: various printed
                    notices, prospectuses, letters to the editor, and printed commentaries;
                    invitations; announcements of readings; cartes de visites; advertisements; a
                    silk commemorative bookmark; and photographs, cabinet card photographs, and
                    engravings of Dickens, his family, and members of his circle. The collection
                    also contains 20th century Dickens ephemera, 1937-1993, including: postcards;
                    stamps, including a first day of issue; newspaper articles; brochures; a set of
                    playing cards; and a set of cocktail napkins. Additionally the collection
                    includes playbills (several of which are framed) from a variety of London and
                    Philadelphia theaters (1838-1873) for plays based on Dickens's writings (Oliver
                    Twist, Martin Chuzzlewit, Domby and Son, Cricket on the Hearth, A Christmas
                    Carol); and playbills for performances in which Dickens appeared. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>