<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>David N. Carvalho handwriting collection <date type="inclusive">1349-1891</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">David N. Carvalho handwriting collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2350</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1349-1891</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>David Nunes Carvalho (1848-1925) was a scholar of handwriting and ink and a
                    collector of incunabula. He was well known as an expert in handwriting analysis
                    and identification, and in that capacity appeared in many court cases throughout
                    the country. He was the author of 40 Centuries of Ink (1904).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of 4000 items that are representative of ordinary
                    handwriting from the 10th to the 20th centuries, written in English, French,
                    Latin, German, and Dutch. The bulk of the items are from the 17th to the 19th
                    centuries. Samples, on paper and vellum, include indentures, letters, receipts,
                    and pages of accounts. There is also a small set of examples of alphabets from
                    many countries; 19th century examples of engraved death and marriage
                    announcements; engraved portraits of writing masters; examples of minute
                    calligraphy; and volumes containing a catalog of Carvalho's book collection.
                    Although the collection contains a number of unrelated documents, there are
                    several concentrations of related papers. For example, among the French
                    materials are papers of the D'Auxy family; among the British papers are a
                    collection of indentures, primarily from Devon; and among the American materials
                    is a batch of letters, deeds, receipts, and agreements from the Philadelphia
                    area (1731-1922) and correspondence received by the Baltimore merchant house of
                    Robert Clinton Wright. The collection also includes a set of papers related to
                    William Darlington, M.D. (1782-1863). These include letters to and from
                    Darlington and drafts of articles on botany.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>