<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Elizabeth Olds papers <date type="inclusive">1962-1963</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature Research
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Elizabeth Olds papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2428</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature
                    Research Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1962-1963</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Elizabeth Olds (1896-1991) was an artist and a writer and illustrator of
                    children's books. She was born in Minneapolis and studied at the Minneapolis
                    Institute of Art from 1918 to 1921. In that year, she moved to New York, where
                    she continued her studies at the Art Students League of New York. During the
                    Depression, she worked for the WPA Federal Art Project's graphic division, and
                    her work from this time focused on the lives of working people. Olds was the
                    first woman to hold a Guggenheim Fellowship in art. During the fellowship, she
                    studied art in Paris. Her works were exhibited in solo shows and group shows
                    over five decades, and she is represented in several museums. Her children's
                    books include The Big Fire, Little Una, Plop Plop Ploppie, and Feather Mountain,
                    which received a Caldecott Honor in 1952.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials related to two of Elizabeth Olds' books: Little
                    Una and Plop, Plop, Ploppie. Little Una materials include illustration and text
                    proofs, galley proofs, author's proofs with correction notes, dummies, color
                    proofs, and woodcut prints of final art. Plop, Plop, Ploppie materials include
                    final art, galley proofs, a dummy, woodblock prints of Ploppie, and a
                    preliminary wash drawing.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of Texas,
                    Harry Ransom Center: Benjamin O. Rees collection of Elizabeth Olds and Emmett
                    Hudspeth collection of Elizabeth Olds; National Museum of American Art in
                    Washington: Collection of Elizabeth Olds prints; Smithsonian Institution,
                    Archives of American Art: Elizabeth Olds papers; University of Minnesota
                    Children's Literature Research Collection: Elizabeth Olds papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>