<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Frederick R. Gardner collection of Robert Lawson <date type="inclusive">1910-1983</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Frederick R. Gardner collection of Robert
                    Lawson</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2345</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1983</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert Lawson (1892-1957) was an American artist and children's book author. He
                    did some illustrations for The Century Magazine in 1919, and in 1922 he produced
                    illustrations for his first book, Little Prince Too Fat. He won the Taylor Arms
                    Prize of the Society of American Etchers in 1931, and was the first person to
                    receive both the Newbery Medal (Rabbit Hill, 1945) and Caldecott Medal (They
                    Were Strong and Good, 1940).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of drawings, etchings, books, and papers of Robert Lawson
                    collected by Frederick Gardner. Materials include original drawings, book jacket
                    designs, designs for title pages, and chapter heading devices for Ben and Me,
                    The Tough Winter and many other works illustrated (and some written and
                    illustrated) by Robert Lawson. The collection also includes a “dummy” for Munro
                    Leaf’s The Story of Ferdinand and 31 early etchings by Lawson. Papers of Robert
                    Lawson include: correspondence from readers and publishers; newspaper clippings;
                    articles by and about Lawson; typescripts of speeches; biographical sketches;
                    and manuscripts of The Great Wheel, Refugees, Joney, and several shorter works
                    (some unpublished). Other Lawson materials include: greeting and Christmas cards
                    designed by Lawson; advertisements and announcements for books; photographs of
                    Lawson and Marie Abrams Lawson; photo albums of the Lawsons and Rabbit Hill;
                    several copies of Young Wings, a children's book club magazine; and a copy of
                    Frederick Gardner's Robert Lawson on My Shelves. Additional materials in the
                    collection include incoming and some outgoing correspondence of Frederick
                    Gardner, with publishers, collectors, and dealers, related to his collecting of
                    Lawson materials. Margaret G. Otto is a significant correspondent and the
                    collection contains a sales ledger kept by Otto listing sales of Lawson's
                    prints.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Minnesota: Robert Lawson papers; University of Southern Mississippi: Robert
                    Lawson papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>