<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Hampton L. Carson Collection of Napoleonic prints <date type="inclusive">undated</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1800-1850</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Hampton L. Carson Collection of Napoleonic prints </unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2365</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="fre"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.28 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1800-1850</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Hampton Lawrence Carson (1852-1929) was a lawyer and an avid historian and
                    collector of manuscripts, autographs, political cartoons, and portraits. Born in
                    Philadelphia in 1852, he graduated from the University of Pennsylvania Law
                    School in 1874 and taught there from 1895 to 1903. He was also a partner in
                    several private laws firm and dealt primarily in estate law. In 1903 Governor
                    Samuel W. Pennypacker appointed him attorney general of Pennsylvania, a post
                    which he held until 1907. From 1919 to 1921 Carson was both president of the
                    American Bar Association and chairman of a subcommittee of the Pennsylvania
                    Commission on Constitutional Amendment and Revision. He was a member of several
                    historical associations, including the American Historical Association Endowment
                    Fund and the Historical Society of Pennsylvania (HSP). He served as president of
                    HSP from 1921 until his death in 1929. His interest in history is reflected in
                    his major published works, History of the Supreme Court of the United States and
                    History of the Historical Society of Pennsylvania.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of prints (etchings, engravings, aquatints, and lithographs)
                    of Napoleon, his associates, and scenes from his life and military career. The
                    collection is arranged in four sections (portraits, life, associated
                    personalities, and miscellaneous items), and contains some 3,300 pieces.
                    Included in the collection is a framed set of seven hand-colored miniature
                    portraits of Napoleon and his generals, and several books on Napoleon.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>