<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Herbert Pullinger collection <date type="inclusive">1915-1954</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Herbert Pullinger collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2372</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1915-1954</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Herbert Pullinger (1878-1961) was a life long resident of Philadelphia. He was a
                    painter, printmaker, and commercial illustrator, as well as being a teacher at
                    the Philadelphia Museum School of Industrial Arts (now the University of the
                    Arts) from 1923 to 1958. He first studied art at the School of Industrial Arts,
                    followed by the Drexel Institute, and finally enrolled at the Pennsylvania
                    Academy of the Fine Arts for studies with Henry McCarter and Thomas Anshutz.
                    During the 1920s, he emerged as one of America's foremost wood engravers.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of etchings, aquatints, lithographs and lithographic pencil
                    drawings, pen and ink drawings, woodcuts, pencil sketches and drawings, and
                    watercolors by Herbert Pullinger. Most of the lithographs, woodcuts, and
                    drawings in the collection are city views of Philadelphia, landscapes and
                    riverscapes along the Wissahickon Creek, and bridges and historical houses in
                    the Philadelphia area. A number of the watercolors are seaside images. There is
                    a small batch of photomechanical reproductions of Pullinger's prints, including
                    an unbound series of views of Philadelphia which were published in Philadelphia
                    Past and Present in 1915 as well as a copy of the volume. The collection also
                    includes watercolors by his wife, Frances Pullinger.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>