<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Jane Flory papers <date type="inclusive">1960-1979</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature Research
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Jane Flory papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2427</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature
                    Research Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-1979</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Jane Trescott Flory was born in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania in 1917. She was
                    educated at the Philadelphia Museum School of Industrial Art (now Philadelphia
                    College of Art), receiving her degree in 1939. She began working as a freelance
                    writer and illustrator of children’s books soon after college, and married
                    artist and college instructor Arthur Leroy Flory in 1941. Flory’s first
                    children’s book, Snooty, the Pig Who Was Proud, was published in 1944 and her
                    last, The Great Bamboozlement, was published in 1982. In addition to her
                    writing, Flory served as director of the evening division of the Philadelphia
                    College of Art in Philadelphia from 1958-1974.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscripts, illustrations, and notes of Jane Flory.
                    Documentation is present for a number of Flory's books, including The Liberation
                    of Clementine Tipton, We'll Have a Friend for Lunch, Ramshackle Roost, The
                    Unexpected Grandchildren, The Faraway Dream, It Was a Pretty Good Year, and The
                    Golden Venture. Materials include manuscript drafts, notes and sketches, galley
                    proofs, and correspondence with editors. The collection also includes a
                    handwritten and illustrated manuscript of This Is Farmer John, which was never
                    published, and several notebooks containing story outlines, manuscript drafts of
                    stories, and notes on character development and changes to story lines.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>