<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Gibb Smith trolley photographs <date type="inclusive">1889-1946</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Gibb Smith trolley photographs</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2368</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1889-1946</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Gibb Smith, Jr. (d. 1958) was the grandson of Charles E. Smith (1820-1900),
                    a president of the Philadelphia &amp; Reading railroad. John Gibb Smith, Jr.
                    collected images of Philadelphia's transit system, primarily trolleys, and
                    donated his collection to the Free Library in 1946.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The John Gibb Smith Collection consists of over a thousand photographs that give
                    a comprehensive overview of Philadelphia's transit system during the first third
                    of the 20th century. Most of the photographs in the collection are of trolleys;
                    almost every type of car that operated in the city between the 1890s to the
                    early 1940s is represented. Many of the views are street scenes that also
                    feature people, businesses, and homes. Most were taken during the Philadelphia
                    Rapid Transit period (1902-1940), but some show the equipment of its
                    predecessors (including a few horse cars). There are also prints of subway cars
                    and Philadelphia Rapid Transit non-passenger equipment. The transportation
                    portion of the collection is rounded out by pictures of both city and suburban
                    trackage and a series of photographs showing the construction of the Market
                    Street subway-elevated line. There are also some pamphlets, newsletters,
                    newspaper clippings, and loose negatives.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.freelibrary.org/pix/trolleys/index.htm">http://www.freelibrary.org/pix/trolleys/index.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Philadelphia Transportation Collection and Dr. Harold E. Cox
                    Transportation Collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>