<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Frederick Lewis portrait collection <date type="inclusive">1750-1942</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Frederick Lewis portrait collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2364</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>133 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1750-1942</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Among the exemplary collections of the Free Library of Philadelphia is the Print
                    and Picture Collection. Spanning the graphic arts from 1493 to the present time,
                    the Free Library's Fine Art Prints and Photographs collection includes thousands
                    of images. Initially representing only Philadelphia artists, the collection has
                    been extended to include early masters as well as renowned modern printmakers
                    and photographers. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Established in 1928, the John Frederick Lewis Portrait Collection contains more
                    than 200,000 portrait prints in all media. Subjects in the collection include:
                    political, religious, military leaders; royalty and nobility; artists,
                    composers, and writers; scientists and inventors; performers, including film and
                    stage actors; figures from antiquity; and others. Among these prints are
                    numerous works of art by such artists as Van Dyck, Nanteuil and Holbein.
                    Highlights include a photograph of Eleanor and Franklin Roosevelt attending
                    their son Elliott's wedding in Bryn Mawr in 1932, an engraving of Gilbert du
                    Motier, marquis de La Fayette, and dozens of engraved portraits of Benjamin
                    Franklin. Portraits are in a variety of media, including engravings, etchings,
                    lithographs, mezzotints, ink drawings, photographs, half-tone reproductions, and
                    magazine and newspaper clippings.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>