<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Pennell collection <date type="inclusive">1880-1920</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Pennell collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2376</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1880-1920</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Pennell (1857-1926) was born in Philadelphia. Pennell studied at the
                    Philadelphia Industrial Art School and at the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine
                    Arts. After 1883, Pennell spent a great deal of his time traveling and working
                    in Europe, using London as his home base, until in 1917, he returned to the
                    United States to live. He produced numerous books (many of them in collaboration
                    with his wife, Elizabeth Robins Pennell), but his chief distinction is as an
                    original etcher and lithographer, and notably as an illustrator. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of lithographs, etchings, and drawings by Joseph Pennell.
                    Lithographs include views of Philadelphia, including city streets, and interior
                    and exteriors of Cliveden and Stenton. Pen and ink drawings include early
                    studies and sketches; several illustrations for The Century; and the title page
                    for Elizabeth Robins Pennell's Over the Alps on a Bicycle. There are a number of
                    views of industrial work sites, including shipyards, locomotive works, and a
                    munitions factory; there are also several views of airfields. The collection
                    also includes "Views on the Old Germantown Road," a set of 16 etchings
                    published in 1880.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Library of Congress:
                    Joseph and Elizabeth Robins Pennell collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>