<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Jackson collection of American lithographs <date type="inclusive">1819-1887</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Jackson collection of American
                    lithographs</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2379</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1819-1887</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Jackson (1867-1946) was an art historian, writer, and lithographer. He was
                    the author of the Encyclopedia of Philadelphia, Literary Landmarks of
                    Philadelphia and other scholarly works. He was also a collector of lithographs
                    and donated his collection to the Free Library.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Jackson Collection of American Lithographs includes some 275 prints. The
                    collection documents the beginnings of lithography in the United States and
                    includes the first lithograph printed in this country by Bass Otis and published
                    in The Analectic Magazine in July, 1819. Other lithographers and companies whose
                    work is represented include Thomas Doughty, Albert Newsam, C.G. Childs, Childs
                    &amp; Inman, Bowen &amp; Co., Sarony &amp; Co, and P.S. Duval &amp; Co. Subjects
                    of lithographs include portraits, landscapes, historical scenes, illustrations
                    of birds and fish, and illustrations of Perry's expedition to Japan and other
                    expeditions to Asia and South America. Some of the lithographs are hand-colored;
                    there are several chromolithographs, as well. A small number of the prints are
                    from British and French lithographers.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Joseph Jackson manuscripts (collection 314).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>