<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Katherine Milhous and Frances Lichten papers <date type="inclusive">1903-1977</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature Research
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Katherine Milhous and Frances Lichten papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2400</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature
                    Research Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1903-1977</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Katherine Milhous (1894-1977) was a artist and children's book author. She
                    attended art school at the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts and the
                    Pennsylvania Museum of Industrial Art. During the Depression, she served as the
                    head of a Federal Art Project for the Works Progress Administration. Milhous’s
                    first children's book illustrations were for author Alice Dalgliesh. In 1940,
                    her first book, Lovina, was published. Her most famous book was The Egg Tree,
                    which won the 1951 Caldecott Award. Frances Lichten was an artist and decorator.
                    She was a specialist on the rural folk art of Pennsylvania. From 1938 to 1941,
                    she was supervisor of the Index for American Design for Pennsylvania. She
                    collaborated with Katherine Milhous on illustrations for some children's books,
                    including They Live in South America, by Alice Dalgleish. She was the author of
                    The Folk Art of Rural Pennsylvania (1946).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscripts, illustrations, and papers of Katherine
                    Milhous and papers of Frances Lichten. Katherine Milhous manuscript materials
                    include: drafts, dummies, proofs, notes, finished art, color separations, and
                    other production materials for Through These Arches; chalk drawings and notes
                    related to The Egg Tree; art and separations for Appolonia's Valentine, Billy
                    Button's Butter'd Biscuit, Once Upon a Time, and Peter Piper's Pickled Peppers;
                    and drafts and notes on book ideas for other stories. Adult artwork by Milhous
                    includes woodcut prints, watercolors, ink illustrations and cartoons,
                    photographs of sculpture, a scrapbook of pencil sketches from Milhous' trip to
                    South America, a painted placard for the WPA Federal Art Project, and works in
                    various other media. Milhous papers include: correspondence with editors,
                    readers, family, and friends (including Alice Dalgleish and Ruth Gagliardo);
                    itineraries, correspondence, lecture notes, and publicity material related to
                    visits and appearances; scrapbooks of publicity, correspondence, and other items
                    related to the writing and publication of The Egg Tree; a scrapbook of book
                    reviews; a scrapbook on poetry; a brief typed autobiography and other
                    biographical material; diaries and journals kept between 1944-1977 (noting work,
                    expenses, memoranda, lists of gifts and cards sent); several photographs of
                    Milhous, including one from the 1951 Newbery-Caldecott Dinner; a collection of
                    postcards; book announcements and brochures on exhibitions and other events,
                    mostly related to friends and associates of Milhous; various subject files;
                    original art in the form of cards, invitations, and small studies given to
                    Milhous by several other artists; a set of Currier and Ives reproduction prints;
                    and a photograph album from a trip to South America (probably in the early
                    1950s). Frances Lichten materials include: correspondence with editors,
                    publishers, friends, and family; a small amount of family history material on
                    the Lichtens; two albums of photographs and letters written from Milhous and
                    Lichten's 1925-1926 trip to Europe; a duplicate set of the letters written
                    during the Europe trip (mostly written by Lichten); and copies of brochures and
                    small volumes illustrated by Lichten.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Minnesota, Children's Literature Research Collections: Katherine Milhous
                    collection and Frances Lichten papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>