<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Lloyd Alexander papers <date type="inclusive">1948-1990</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature Research
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Lloyd Alexander papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2396</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature
                    Research Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>23 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1948-1990</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Lloyd Chudley Alexander (1924-2007) was the author of more than 40 books, mostly
                    fantasy novels for children and adolescents, as well as several adult books. His
                    most famous contribution to the field of children's literature is the fantasy
                    series The Chronicles of Prydain. The first two books in this series formed the
                    basis of the Disney animated film The Black Cauldron. The concluding book of the
                    series, The High King, was awarded the Newbery Medal in 1969. Alexander also won
                    the National Book Award and the American Book Award for several other
                    titles.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of drafts, proofs, research notes, correspondence, reviews,
                    and other materials related to Alexander's published works and writing projects.
                    The collection also includes miscellaneous agent and editorial correspondence,
                    biographical information, and some information about Alexander's involvement
                    with the National Book Awards. Titles represented in the collection include The
                    Beggar Queen, The Marvelous Misadventures of Sebastian, The El Dorado Adventure,
                    The Philadelphia Adventure, and various installments of The Chronicles of
                    Prydain.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Free Library of
                    Philadelphia, Children's Literature Research Collection: Evaline Ness
                    papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>