<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Lubin Film Company records <date type="inclusive">1881-1984</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Lubin Film Company records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2347</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1984</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Siegmund Lubin came from Germany to set up an optical shop in Philadelphia. He
                    eventually designed improvements for cameras and projectors, and began to market
                    his "Life Motion Pictures" in 1897. The Lubin Film Company became one of the
                    most profitable of the new motion picture industry. In 1912 Lubin built a state
                    of the art glassed in studio and factory at 20th and Indiana Streets. Lubin's
                    logo and motto, "Clear As A Bell," referred to the superior quality of his
                    motion picture images. The company went out of business in 1916.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials related to the the Lubin Film Company.
                    Materials include: copies of printed Lubin Film Company Bulletins, 1913-1916;
                    bound and unbound catalogs of films from 1905 and 1909; and seven scrapbooks
                    (1911-1916) of newspaper and magazine clippings, playbills, advertisements, and
                    flyers related to Lubin. The collection contains numerous photographs and a few
                    negatives. Items include: film stills (8 x 10 and 5 x 7 black and white),
                    candids, and portraits; images of the studio (20th &amp; Indiana and Betzwood);
                    group shots of cast members and crew; pictures of theaters owned by Lubin;
                    several larger format photographs; and photos of Lubin and of his family. There
                    are also a small number of glass lantern slides of titles, stills, and a series
                    of lighting test images. Miscellaneous papers include: color lithograph flyers
                    for Gods of Fate and The Great Divide; posters; clippings and articles about
                    Lubin; a biographical sketch of Lubin by his daughter Emma Lubin Lowry; lists of
                    films; and records related to research done on the collection. Artifacts in the
                    collection include a 1905 projector, the hood ornament from Lubin's car, and a
                    glass paperweight. The collection also includes film slides and negatives made
                    by the Free Library.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>