<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Lucille Wallower papers <date type="inclusive">1932-1970</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature Research
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Lucille Wallower papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2399</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature
                    Research Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.66 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1932-1970</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Lucille Wallower (1910-1999) was born in Waynesboro, Pennsylvania, and studied at
                    Pennsylvania Museum School of Art and the Traphagen School of Fashion. Her first
                    book, Nanka of Old Bohemia, was published in 1937 and her first self-illustrated
                    book, A Conch Shell for Molly, was published in 1940. From the 1930s to the
                    1970s she worked as a children's librarian in Pennsylvania. She continued
                    writing throughout her career as a librarian, and in 1975, she began to work
                    full-time as a writer and illustrator. Wallower published over 40 works, many of
                    which include her own illustrations. Many of her works focus on the history and
                    geography of Pennsylvania.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscripts and illustrations of Lucille Wallower.
                    Materials include typescripts, galley proofs, color separations, and final art
                    for a number of Wallower's books, including A Conch Shell for Molly, The Hippity
                    Hopster, The Morning Star, Old Satan, Your Pennsylvania, and My Book about
                    Abraham Lincoln. Also included in the collection are notes and a series of 36
                    lithographs from A Conch Shell for Molly.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>