<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Norman H. and Charlotte Strouse collection of letters of the
                        Presidents <date type="inclusive">1780-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Norman H. and Charlotte Strouse collection of letters of
                    the Presidents</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2336</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1780-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Norman H. Strouse was born in Olympia, Washington, in 1906. Strouse worked for 40
                    years at the J. Walter Thompson Advertising agency. In 1955 he was promoted to
                    president, and was made chief executive in 1960 and was chairman from 1964 until
                    he retired in 1968. During his tenure in charge of the agency, then the world's
                    largest, billings nearly tripled, and he was credited with modernizing
                    organization and management. He was also chairman of the American Association of
                    Advertising Agencies and the recipient of advertising's Gold Medal Award. After
                    retiring in 1968, Strouse focused on his hobby of collecting rare books, fine
                    printing and bindings. He specialized in books by Thomas Carlyle, works bound by
                    Thomas Bird Moser and 12th- to 16th-century illuminated manuscripts. He and his
                    wife, Charlotte, founded the Silverado Museum in St. Helena, dedicated to Robert
                    Louis Stevenson, with more than 6,000 books and other items. He also wrote four
                    books, including How to Build a Poor Man's Morgan Library.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscript letters of Presidents of the United States.
                    Presidents represented include George Washington, John Adams, Millard Filmore,
                    Ulysses S. Grant, Grover Cleveland, Theodore Roosevelt, William Taft, Herbert
                    Hoover, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Harry S. Truman, and John F. Kennedy. First
                    Ladies represented include Grace Coolidge, Florence Harding, Lou Henry Hoover,
                    Jacqueline B. Kennedy, Patricia Nixon, and Eleanor Roosevelt. The collection
                    also includes published volumes with inscriptions by Theodore Roosevelt, Eleanor
                    Roosevelt, Herbert Hoover, Lyndon B. Johnson, John F. Kennedy, and Richard
                    Nixon. Additional items in the collection include: printed copies of "Report
                    upon Weights and Measures," 1821, and "Eulogy on James Madison," 1836, both
                    signed by John Quincy Adams; an autograph book with signatures of presidents,
                    cabinet secretaries, senators, and other politicians; Bushrod Washington's
                    Supreme Court Commission, signed by John Adams, 1798; a framed photograph of
                    Norman Strouse; and a signed framed photograph of Herbert Hoover. Also included
                    is the Burpee collection of Lincoln documents, primarily letters received by
                    Lincoln which include notes about his intended response and his endorsement on
                    the reverse. Many of the letters concern appointments. There is also a Navy
                    Commission signed by Lincoln. Additional materials include: correspondence and
                    notes related to provenance of autograph collections at the Free Library of
                    Philadelphia; auction catalogs; transcriptions of letters of George Washington
                    (originals not in the collection); and newspapers related to the shooting of
                    James Garfield.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>