<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia and surrounding area atlas collection <date type="inclusive">1858-1984</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Map Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia and surrounding area atlas
                    collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2356</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Map Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>76 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1858-1984</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Map Collection of the Free Library of Philadelphia provides researchers and
                    explorers with more than 130,000 current and historical maps, as well as other
                    geographical resources, covering every part of the world. The collection is
                    especially strong in Philadelphia and Pennsylvania maps and atlases, and an
                    extensive collection of aerial photos of the Delaware Valley provides a
                    fascinating view of the development of our region over the past 70 years.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of atlases of Philadelphia and vicinity. Materials include:
                    Hexamer &amp; Locher Maps of the City of Philadelphia, 1857, 7 vols; Hexamer and
                    Son fire insurance maps, 1873-1920, vols. I-XXXV. (these comprise roughly half
                    of the collection; multiple copies of many volumes); G.M. Hopkins &amp;. Co.
                    fire insurance maps, 7 vols. (1870s-1880s); Atlas of the city of Philadelphia.
                    From actual surveys and official plans of the Survey Department, by Geo. W.
                    &amp; Walter S. Bromley. (1880s-1920s), 13 vols.; and Atlas of properties on
                    Main Line Pennsylvania Railroad: from Overbrook to Paoli, from actual surveys
                    and official plans / by George W. and Walter S. Bromley. G.W. Bromley &amp; Co.,
                    1926. The collection also includes atlases for the Pennsylvania Mainline and the
                    Reading Mainline, Bucks, Chester, Delaware, Lancaster, and Montgomery counties,
                    including volumes for towns and cities; atlases of the Franklin Survey Company
                    (greater Northeast Philadelphia area); and a 1865 map of the Fair Hill Estate of
                    Joseph Parker Norris.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>