<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphiana collection <date type="inclusive">1832-2001</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphiana collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2363</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>32 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1832-2001</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Among the exemplary collections of the Free Library of Philadelphia is the Print
                    and Picture Collection. Spanning the graphic arts from 1493 to the present time,
                    the Free Library's Fine Art Prints and Photographs collection includes thousands
                    of images. Initially representing only Philadelphia artists, the collection has
                    been extended to include early masters as well as renowned modern printmakers
                    and photographers. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection of Philadelphiana consists of some 20,000 prints, drawings,
                    photographs, clippings, and other materials documenting the history of the city
                    of Philadelphia from its founding to the present day. The collection has been
                    supplemented over the years by gifts from citizens of the area including John
                    Eckfeld (pictures of the Haddington area), Douglas Macfarlan (Fairmount Park and
                    West Philadelphia), and Charles Mills (Falls of the Schuylkill). The collection
                    also includes the largest collection of photographs documenting the 1876
                    Centennial Exhibition in Fairmount Park: 1,300 silver albumen mounted prints
                    made by the Centennial Photographic Company in sizes ranging from
                    half-stereoviews to 17 x 21 inch photographs. Other major events documented in
                    the collection include the Sesquicenntennial Exhibition of 1926 (24 volumes of
                    photographs) and the Bicenntennial in 1976. Subjects represented in the
                    collection include buildings (businesses, churches, residences, and public
                    institutions), bridges, fire departments and equipment, forts, parks, streets,
                    strikes, trade cards, and views.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://libwww.freelibrary.org/CenCol/index.htm">http://libwww.freelibrary.org/CenCol/index.htm</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>