<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Postcards collection <date type="inclusive">1909-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Postcards collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2383</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>87.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1909-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Among the exemplary collections of the Free Library of Philadelphia is the Print
                    and Picture Collection. Spanning the graphic arts from 1493 to the present time,
                    the Free Library's Fine Art Prints and Photographs collection includes thousands
                    of images. Initially representing only Philadelphia artists, the collection has
                    been extended to include early masters as well as renowned modern printmakers
                    and photographers. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of over 50,000 postcards from America, Europe, Asia, Africa,
                    and the Near and Middle East. The main portion of the collecton is arranged by
                    geographic location or topic and includes such topics as: heraldry, castles and
                    cathedrals, railroads, butterflies, dance, fishes and fishing, and caves.
                    Additionally, there are postcards depicting painting, sculpture, and
                    architecture from Europe and America, and Asia, mainly arranged by location and
                    medium. There are two boxes of postcards of Philadelphia and one box of
                    postcards of the Free Library of Philadelphia and its branches. There is one box
                    of early twentieth century postcards, mostly from Germany, collected by Carl
                    Gatter, There are also a number of souvenir postcard booklets or sets and eight
                    postcard albums from various collectors.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>