<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rosenthal collection of drawings by American artists <date type="inclusive">1777-1909</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1840-1909</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rosenthal collection of drawings by American
                    artists</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2361</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1777-1909</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1840-1909</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Albert Rosenthal (1863-1939) was a painter, etcher, and lithographer from New
                    Hope, Pennsylvania. Albert was the son of Max Rosenthal with whom he worked and
                    studied from an early age. Formally he also studied at the Pennsylvania Academy
                    of Fine Arts, the Ecole des Beaux-Arts in Paris with Gerome, and later in
                    Munich. The brothers Max, Louis, and Simon Rosenthal were trained as
                    lithographers and lived and worked in Poland. Max Rosenthal emigrated to the
                    United States in the late 1840s. He worked for P.S. Duval in Philadelphia. Later
                    the Rosenthal brothers, now all living in the United States, opened their own
                    business. In 1884, Max Rosenthal retired and his son Albert took control of the
                    company. The firm was noted for their work in the development of
                    chromolithography.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of over 840 drawings by American artists from the late
                    eighteenth to the early twentieth century. Works are in a variety of media,
                    including pencil, ink, charcoal, chalk, crayon, gouache, watercolor, and pastel.
                    Subjects include portraits, landscapes, cityscapes, vignettes, cartoons, and
                    illustrations. The collection is largely made up of the work of illustrators
                    such as C.E.H. Bonwill, F.O.C. Darley. Louis M. Glackens, and Edward H.
                    Potthast. Other artist represented in the collection include John Singleton
                    Copley, Asher B. Durand, Winslow Homer, George Innes, Eastman Johnson, Christian
                    Schuessele, Thomas Sully, John Trumball, and Benjamin West. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>