<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sample writing books <date type="inclusive">1554-1969</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sample writing books</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2349</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>9.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1554-1969</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Free Library of Philadelphia was founded in 1891 as the city's first public
                    library system. Its Rare Book Department, among the largest in American public
                    libraries, exists to serve the people of Philadelphia, as well as the students,
                    scholars, and researchers who use its collections. The Rare Book Department's
                    holding span 5000 years, from cuneiform tablets to 20th century literary
                    manuscripts. Among the many collecting areas of the department are incunabula,
                    American, European, and Oriental manuscripts, art and artist's papers,
                    children's books and manuscripts, manuscripts and correspondence of American and
                    British authors, examples of calligraphy, and Pennsylvania German fraktur. The
                    Rare Book Department has major collections of Oliver Goldsmith, Charles Dickens,
                    Edgar Allan Poe, Horace editions, Beatrix Potter, Arthur Rackham, and Robert
                    Lawson.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains an extensive assortment of books on writing and
                    penmanship, received from Columbia Teacher’s College. Volumes include sample
                    alphabets, penmanship guides for school and business use, exercise books, and
                    books on other topics showing examples of calligraphy. There are both printed
                    and manuscript volumes. Dates range from 1554 to 1969. The bulk of the volumes
                    are American. Among the American volumes are several series of manuals published
                    by Shaylor, Spencer, Perkins &amp; Fairman, and Payson, Dunton &amp; Scribner.
                    There are also volumes from England, France, Germany, Holland, Italy, Spain, and
                    Japan. The collection also includes several framed and unbound samples of ornate
                    calligraphy, several of which are hand-colored; and a display of signature cards
                    mounted on a velvet-covered board.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: started by Elaine Schaeffer; American volumes from Columbia Teacher's
                    College</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>