<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sanborn atlas collection <date type="inclusive">1916-2007</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Map Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sanborn atlas collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2357</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Map Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>77 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-2007</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Sanborn Map Company Insurance Maps of Philadelphia consist of a uniform
                    series of large-scale maps, depicting the commercial, industrial, and
                    residential sections of Philadelphia. The maps were designed to assist fire
                    insurance agents in determining the degree of hazard associated with a
                    particular property and therefore show the size, shape, and construction of
                    dwellings, commercial buildings, and factories as well as fire walls, locations
                    of windows and doors, sprinkler systems, and types of roofs. The maps also
                    indicate widths and names of streets, property boundaries, building use, and
                    house and block numbers. They show the locations of water mains, giving their
                    dimensions, and of fire alarm boxes and hydrants.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Sanborn Map Company Insurance Maps of Philadelphia,
                    Pennsylvania volumes. Volumes include: 1916-2004 set: original Philadelphia
                    volumes, with all updates through 2004; 1958 set for Philadelphia; 1956-1967 set
                    for Philadelphia; and volumes, mostly from the 1960s (1956-1967), for Chester
                    County, Delaware County, Montgomery County, Berwyn, Conshohocken, Willow Grove,
                    Camden (New Jersey). The collection also includes microfilm for several sets
                    held by the Library of Congress and others covering Pennsylvania, Delaware, New
                    Jersey, and Maryland; punch cards with microfilm shots of the changes to pages
                    in the Philadelphia volumes, 1980-2002; and digital updates for 2005/2006 and
                    2007.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>