<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thornton Oakley collection of Howard Pyle and his students <date type="inclusive">1883-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thornton Oakley collection of Howard Pyle and his
                    students</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2346</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Rare Book Department<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1883-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thornton Oakley (1881-1953) was born in Pittsburgh. He studied at the University
                    of Pennsylvania and received B.S. and M.S. degrees in architecture in 1901 and
                    1902. He first studied with Howard Pyle in 1902 at Chadds Ford. Oakley became an
                    illustrator and writer for periodicals, including Scribner's, Century,
                    Collier's, and Harper's Monthly. In the years 1914-1919 and 1921-1936 he was in
                    charge of the Department of Illustration at the Philadelphia Museum School of
                    Industrial Art. In 1914-1915 he also taught drawing at the University of
                    Pennsylvania, and gave lectures at the Art Institute of Chicago, the
                    Metropolitan Museum of Art, and the Curtis Institute. Howard Pyle (1853-1911)
                    was an American illustrator and writer, primarily of books for young audiences.
                    A native of Wilmington, Delaware, he spent the last year of his life in
                    Florence, Italy.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials amassed by Thornton Oakley related to Howard
                    Pyle and his students. Items include: books written and illustrated by Pyle;
                    watercolors, pencil, charcoal, chalk drawings, and prints by Pyle; several
                    sketchbooks of Pyle; tearsheets and proofs; photographs of Howard Pyle and his
                    students; photos of Pyle and his studio; photographs and negatives of Chadd's
                    Ford Mill; artwork by Pyle students including N. C. Wyeth, Maxfield Parrish,
                    Frank Scoonhover, and Jesse Willcox Smith; correspondence; and Pyle ephemera.
                    Other material related to Pyle students includes tearsheets, clippings, magazine
                    covers, color prints, posters, and advertising ephemera. Additionally the
                    collection includes framed paintings and prints by Pyle, Maxfield Parrish,
                    Jessie Willcox Smith, Schoonover, Oakley, Francis Newton, N. C. Wyeth, and
                    others. Thornton Oakley materials in the collection include: correspondence to
                    Oakley regarding exhibitions of his work and his collecting of Pyle material;
                    drawings by Thornton Oakley; copies of a 1951 address at the Free Library:
                    "Howard Pyle, His Art and Personality"; photograph albums from trips to the
                    West Indies, France, and the Pyrenees; bookplates for Thornton Oakley's
                    Collection of Works by Howard Pyle and a printing block for a small bookplate;
                    list of Howard Pyle originals; and lists of desiderata. The collection also
                    contains material related to Maxfield Parrish, such as family correspondence
                    (1920-1953), including letters between Maxfield Parrish, Lydia Austin Parrish,
                    and Dillwyn Parrish, and photographs and negatives of figure drawings. Other
                    individuals represented in the collection include Henry C. Pitz (author of The
                    Brandywine Tradition and 200 Years of American Illustration) and Sydney Gross.
                    Pitz materials include professional correspondence, related to articles, books,
                    and exhibitions and handwritten manuscript and galley proofs of The Brandywine
                    Tradition. Gross materials consist of correspondence related to Maxfield Parrish
                    pictures; photographs of Maxfield Parrish, 1928; a drawing of Maxfield Parrish
                    by Gross; and notes on painting procedures.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Delaware: Thornton Oakley and Amy Oakley Collection, Thornton Oakley diaries,
                    and Frank E. Schoonover - Thornton Oakley correspondence related to Howard Pyle;
                    Delaware Art Museum: Thornton Oakley papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>