<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Valentine, Christmas card, and greeting card collection <date type="inclusive">1830-2006</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1880s-1960s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Valentine, Christmas card, and greeting card
                    collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2371</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1830-2006</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1880s-1960s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Among the exemplary collections of the Free Library of Philadelphia is the Print
                    and Picture Collection. Spanning the graphic arts from 1493 to the present time,
                    the Free Library's Fine Art Prints and Photographs collection includes thousands
                    of images. Initially representing only Philadelphia artists, the collection has
                    been extended to include early masters as well as renowned modern printmakers
                    and photographers. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Christmas cards, Valentines, and greeting cards. The bulk
                    of the items in the collection are Christmas and Valentine cards. Other holidays
                    are only sparsely covered, though there are cards for Thanksgiving, Easter,
                    birthdays, New Years, and Washington's birthday and Sunday school rallies).
                    Valentines include "Comic Valentines" dating from the 1920s to the 1940s.
                    These are single sheet images accompanied by an insulting verse. There are also
                    pop-up and mechanical Valentines, some decorated with ribbons, lace, or fringe.
                    Among the Christmas cards are commercial cards, personal cards with photographs
                    of families and houses, and artist cards featuring woodblock and linoleum prints
                    and other media. The collection also includes a batch of cards printed by Louis
                    Prang &amp; Co. of Boston, a noted printing firm. There is also a 1924 sample
                    album of Christmas cards, seals, tags, and other printed items.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>