<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Virginia Lee Burton papers <date type="inclusive">1962-1962</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature Research
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Virginia Lee Burton papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2403</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Children's Literature
                    Research Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.58 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1962-1962</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Virginia Lee Burton (1909-1968) was an illustrator and author of children's
                    books. Burton's books include Mike Mulligan and His Steam Shovel, Katy and the
                    Big Snow, Choo Choo, Calico the Wonder Horse, Life Story, and The Little House,
                    which won the Caldecott Medal in 1942. Burton lived with her two sons, Aristides
                    and Michael, and her husband George Demetrios, the sculptor, in a section of
                    Gloucester, Massachusetts, called Folly Cove. Here she taught a class in design
                    and from it emerged the Folly Cove Designers, a group of internationally known
                    professional artisans. The last act in her book, Life Story, tells the story of
                    her life in Folly Cove.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of text with captions, separations, sketches and drawings,
                    galley proofs, dummies, finished jacket drawings, and sketchbooks for Burton's
                    book Life Story. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Minnesota, Children's Literature Research Collections: Virginia Lee Burton
                    papers; University of Oregon: Virginia Lee Burton papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>