<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>WPA collection <date type="inclusive">1935-1943</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture
                        Collection</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">WPA collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">FLoSp.ACC2369</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Free Library of Philadelphia, Print and Picture Collection<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1935-1943</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1935, President Franklin Delano Roosevelt established the Works Progress
                    Administration (the name was changed to Work Projects Administration in
                    September of 1939), as part of his New Deal program to put millions of
                    unemployed Americans back to work. In July of 1935, Federal Project Number One
                    (Federal One) was established within the WPA as a central administration for the
                    arts-related projects. Federal One provided funds specifically for artists,
                    musicians, actors, and writers through the Federal Art Project (FAP), the
                    Federal Music Project, the Federal Theatre Project, and the Federal Writer's
                    Project. FAP employed more than five thousand artists in various art projects
                    including the many poster divisions that were created throughout the United
                    States. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The WPA Collection contains about 1,400 prints and drawings created by artists
                    hired by the federal government to work in the Philadelphia Graphic Arts
                    Workshop during the Great Depression. Among the artists represented are Julius
                    Block, Sam Brown, Claude Clark, Mildred Elfman, Michael Gallagher, Hubert
                    Mesibov, Raymond Steth and Roswell Weidner. A variety of printing techniques are
                    included, such as lithography, woodblock, carborundum prints, and etching.
                    Drawing media include graphite, charcoal, conte crayon, and gouache.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: WPA Posters and Prints (collection V. 99); Illinois State Museum:
                    Works Progress Administration collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>