<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Collab records <date type="inclusive">1970-1982</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Collab records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC749</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1982</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Originally known as the Inter-Society Committee for 20th Century Decorative Arts
                    and Design, Collab is a group of design professionals formed under the
                    leadership of Calvin Hathaway in 1970. Its aim is to enrich the collection of
                    20th century decorative arts at the Philadelphia Museum of Art. Collab supports
                    a wide range of educational programming at the Museum, including exhibitions,
                    publications, lectures, symposia, and a citywide, college-level Student Design
                    Competition, as well as a distinguished annual Design Excellence Award. Collab
                    is made up of members representing the American Institute of Architects, the
                    American Society of Interior Designers, the Interior Design Council of
                    Philadelphia,the National Home Fashions League, the Industrial Design Society of
                    America, the Philadelphia Museum of Art, and other organizations. In 1971 the
                    Inter-Society Committee held its first fund raising event, called COLLAB. In
                    1976 the group changed its name officially to Collab 20th Century, Inc. Its
                    headquarters are maintained in the Department of Decorative Arts after 1700, at
                    the Philadelphia Museum of Art.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>These are the minutes and correspondence of Collab, from its creation in 1970 to
                    1982. The minutes include lists of members of the Committee, agendas,
                    treasurer's reports, lists of acquisitions and desiderata, event and fundraising
                    planning, and lists of committee and subcommittee assignments. The collection
                    also includes correspondence of Calvin Hathaway, 1970, related to the group's
                    launch party; Hathaway's list of desiderata for the Museum collection; and
                    photographs taken at Collab events, 1974 and 1975.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art. Collab. </corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Decorative arts.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Design, Industrial.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 27</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=COL">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=COL</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art: Decorative Arts Department Records 1917-1978</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>