<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Danielle Rice records <date type="inclusive">1986-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Danielle Rice records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC787</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Danielle Rice came to the Museum in 1986 as its first Curator of Education. In
                    the previous decades, the title of the department head was Chief of the Division
                    of Education. Rice worked as Curator and then Senior Curator for the next 15
                    years. In Spring 2001, the Museum appointed Rice to a newly created position in
                    the Executive Offices based on her experience and talents and the needs of the
                    institution. As stated in that year's Annual Report, Rice became the Museum's
                    first Associate Director of Program, which charged her with the supervision of
                    the Museum's increasingly complex planning for exhibitions, publications and
                    every form of educational and scholarly material. Rice left the Museum four
                    years later to become Executive Director of the Delaware Art Museum, in
                    Wilmington, DE. Offered every summer, VAST (Visual Arts as Sources for Teaching)
                    is an intensive two-week program for teachers of all grades and subject areas,
                    and designed to encourage 60 participants to immerse themselves in the Museum's
                    collections and explore the use of art as a resource in the classroom. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>These records pertain to Rice's role as Senior Curator of Education, and consist
                    primarily of program materials, workbooks, lecture notes, articles, slide lists,
                    participant lists, and participant journals used in the Museum's teachers'
                    workshop known as VAST, 1988-2003. Also included are Rice's lecture notes, slide
                    lists, and correspondence, 1987-2002; publications, 1987-2003; syllabi; slide
                    lists and lecture notes for PMA courses, 1986-2005; and papers pertaining to
                    other museum projects, such as training for new guides.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art.</corpname>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Rice, Danielle. </persname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Art museums--Educational aspects. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Education--Museums.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Lecture notes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Manuals (Instructional materials)</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 4</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=RIC">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=RIC</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art: Education Division Records, 1939-2004 (ED) </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>