<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edwin Atlee Barber Records <date type="inclusive">1901-1916</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edwin Atlee Barber Records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC2384</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>21.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1901-1916</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Edwin Atlee Barber was Curator/Secretary of the Philadelphia Museum of Art from
                    1901 to 1907, Director/Curator from 1907-1916 and Honorary Curator of American
                    Pottery and Porcelain from 1893 to 1916. His great interest was pottery,
                    porcelain, and ceramics, primarily early American works. A scholar and prolific
                    writer, Barber wrote numerous articles on his specialty, many of which were
                    published. He remains today a pioneer scholar in his field. Born in Baltimore,
                    Maryland in 1851, Barber's family included distinguished heroes of the
                    Revolutionary War, as well as early captains of industry. When he was a child,
                    Barber's family moved to Pennsylvania and then to Iowa, but Barber returned East
                    for his schooling. He graduated from the Williston Seminary in East Hampton,
                    Massachusetts, in 1869, and then attended Lafayette College where he studied
                    English. In 1880, Lafayette College conferred upon Barber a Master of Arts
                    degree, and in 1893, he received from the College a Doctorate of Philosophy. In
                    1874, Barber went west with the United States Geological and Geographical Survey
                    of the Territories. The following year his travels took him to sites of Indian
                    ruins in Utah and Arizona where his pottery interests most likely were
                    stimulated. At this time Barber also was reporting for the New York Herald as a
                    special correspondent. In 1879 Barber returned to the Philadelphia area to
                    become a Post Office Superintendant and later an Officer of the U.S. Civil
                    Service Examining Board. Barber became involved with museum interests in
                    Philadelphia. In 1879 he was appointed Chief of the Department of Archaeology of
                    the Permanent Exhibit in Fairmount Park, and in 1893, was appointed Honorary
                    Curator of Pottery and Porcelain at the then Pennsylvania Museum and School of
                    Industrial Art. In addition, he was the Secretary of the Corporation and Curator
                    from 1901 to 1916. In a letter to Morris Carter of the Boston Museum of Fine
                    Arts, Barber outlined his own tasks: “Secretary of the Corporation and various
                    committees, Acting Curator of all the twelve departments of the Museum; arrange
                    and install all of the collections, prepare all of the labels for printing; edit
                    the Museum Bulletin and Annual Report, and prepare for publication all of the
                    Guides, Handbooks, catalogues and Art Primers; conduct the Bureau of
                    Identification of Art Objects; collect the annual Membership dues; act as
                    Superintendent of the building and have direct charge of the guards and all
                    other employees.” Later in 1907, after Pepper's death, his title was changed
                    from Curator to Director. Barber's tenure at the Museum was during a critical
                    period of growth and self-definition for the Museum. Through Barber's influence
                    the Museum placed a great importance on the decorative arts, a focus which has
                    remained through the years. An avid collector and a recognized authority,
                    especially of Pennsylvania German pottery and early American glassware, Barber
                    also is the author of the acclaimed text, Pottery and Porcelain of the United
                    States. Barber spelled his middle name with a capital L, as Edwin AtLee Barber,
                    whenever the choice was left up to him; but others usually spelled it with a
                    small l, including the Library of Congress. Barber married Nellie Louise Parker
                    in 1880. On December 12, 1916, Barber died of pneumonia, and was survived by his
                    wife and their daughter.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Barber's correspondence is arranged in two alphabets, 1901 to 1911 and 1912 to
                    1916. Some Barber correspondence with Museum people was kept separately.
                    Extensive correspondence with John T. Morris, Board of Trustees Vice President
                    and a collector; John Story Jenks, also a collector and a Vice President of the
                    Board; Leslie W. Miller, Principal of the School; and James L. Allan, Assistant
                    Treasurer make up a series. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial
                    Art.</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Ephemera.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/ead.php?c=BAR&amp;p=tp">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/ead.php?c=BAR&amp;p=tp
                    </extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art: Dalton Dorr Records and Edwin AtLee Barber Papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>