<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Fairmount Park Commissioners records <date type="inclusive">1913-1933</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Fairmount Park Commissioners records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC755</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1913-1933</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Historically, the Philadelphia Museum of Art was a legacy of the great Centennial
                    Exposition of 1876 held in Fairmount Park. In March 1873, an act of the
                    Pennsylvania State Legislature set in motion plans for the construction of
                    Memorial Hall—a permanent building to be designed by Hermann J.
                    Schwarzmann—which was to serve as the art gallery of the exposition. At the
                    conclusion of the Centennial celebrations, Memorial Hall was to remain open as a
                    Museum of Art and Industry "for the improvement and enjoyment of the people of
                    the Commonwealth." By the turn of the century, it became increasingly apparent
                    that larger quarters were needed to house the Museum's growing collections. A
                    vast new building on the site of a former reservoir on the hill of Fairmount was
                    first projected in 1907 as the spectacular terminus for the new parkway being
                    planned as a diagonal link between City Hall and Fairmount Park. The dedicated
                    efforts of Eli Kirk Price, Vice-President of the Fairmount Park Commission (who
                    was later to serve as the Museum's President from 1926 to 1933), helped to set
                    the wheels in motion for the new building. Construction was begun in 1919 by the
                    Commissioners of Fairmount Park, with funds provided by the city. The architects
                    retained by the Park Commission to design the new Museum were Horace Trumbauer
                    and the firm of Zantzinger, Borie, and Medary. Julian Abele, one of the first
                    African American architects to come to prominence in the United States, served
                    as chief designer for Trumbauer during this crucial period. By 1923, the
                    terracing of the granite hill at Fairmount had been completed and the
                    foundations of the building, as well as the broad steps leading up to it from
                    street level, had been laid. Designed as a vast Neoclassical temple with wings
                    embracing an open court, the Museum's two outlying pavilions were constructed
                    first in order to ensure a continued flow of city funds to complete the
                    connecting central structure. The Museum's design echoes the simpler
                    Neoclassicism of the little group of buildings by the Schuylkill River to the
                    northwest, which were built in the 1820s to house the city's waterworks. Even
                    before the shell of the building was finished, temporary galleries had been
                    opened in 1924 on the schedule imposed by the wills of George W. Elkins and his
                    father, William, and that of John H. McFadden. They had bequeathed magnificent
                    painting collections on the condition that suitable galleries in the projected
                    building be prepared within a reasonable period of time following their deaths.
                    On March 26, 1928, the first finished section of the new Museum's interior,
                    devoted to British and American art, was formally opened to the public.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of five scrapbooks documenting the planning,
                    construction, and opening of the Philadelphia Museum of Art building on the
                    Benjamin Franklin Parkway. The majority of the clippings are articles appearing
                    in Philadelphia newspapers (the Philadelphia Inquirer, Public Ledger, Evening
                    Ledger, Evening Bulletin, and Record) between 1913 and 1933. The collection
                    includes a copy of the 1928 Pennsylvania Museum Bulletin for the inaugural
                    exhibition at the new building in 1928. The notations and note within the latest
                    dated scrapbookappear to be in Fiske Kimball's hand.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Fairmount Park Commission (Philadelphia,
                    Pa.)</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Art museum architecture--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia. </subject>
                <geogname encodinganalog="651">Philadelphia (Pa.)--Buildings, structures, etc. </geogname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 28</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=FPC">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=FPC</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>