<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Focus archives <date type="inclusive">1973-1974</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Focus archives</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC758</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1974</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1974, a group of women from the Philadelphia area organized a three-month long
                    festival that was comprised of various events throughout the city, all
                    celebrating women in the arts. Promoted as FOCUS "Philadelphia Focuses on Women
                    in the Visual Arts," this ambitious project included more than 100 exhibitions,
                    lectures and conferences. Among the artists who lectured or exhibited works were
                    Agnes Denes, Yayoi Kusama, Louise Bourgeois, Judy Chicago, Niki de Saint Phalle,
                    Elaine de Kooning, and Edna Andrade. Two of the organizers had ties to the
                    Museum. Penny Balkin Bach, who headed the Museum's Urban Outreach department,
                    was one of the participating artists. A member of the Museum's Library
                    Committee, Nessa Forman was also involved in the event. At the time, Forman was
                    the arts and culture editor for the now defunct Philadelphia Bulletin. Held at
                    the Philadelphia Civic Center, "Women's Work: American Art, 1974," was one of
                    the major exhibitions and featured nearly 100 works of art by contemporary
                    American women artists. "In Her Own Image" examined how women were depicted by
                    major women artists and was held at the Fleisher Art Memorial. The Pennsylvania
                    Academy of Fine Arts presented an exhibition that took an historical look at its
                    women alumni. For its part, the Philadelphia Museum of Art organized three
                    special events during April and May of that year. Bringing together more than 45
                    paintings, prints and drawings from its collection, the Museum exhibited
                    "Images of Women in the Performing Arts." That the artists featured were all
                    men, such as Degas, Eakins, Manet and Sloan, lent an interesting if not ironic
                    commentary to the show. The Division of Education presented a "Femmes Fatales"
                    series of films that starred several of Hollywood's iconic leading women.
                    "Mistress and Muse" was a series of six lectures that examined women's
                    contributions to the arts.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records pertaining to various organizing committees for
                    the festival as well as to planning of the Civic Center exhibition. The records
                    include minutes, memoranda, agendas, and member lists for the Steering, Program,
                    Public Relations, and Finance Committees. Records related to artist invitations
                    and lecture planning include: information on artists, including biographies and
                    resumes, proposals, and photographs of works; proposals for programs and
                    lectures; correspondence with artists, gallery owners, staff of cultural
                    institutions, and lecturers; and exhibition checklists. Publicity material
                    includes: printed materials, such as catalogs, invitations, brochures, and
                    posters; press releases and newspaper and journal clippings; photographs of
                    artworks, slides of artists and speakers, film of public service announcements,
                    and photographic negatives and reel-to-reel audio recordings of panel
                    discussions. Financial records include budgets, fundraising records, and
                    reports. The collection includes some documentation about the exclusion of
                    Judith Bernstein's "Horizontal" from the show, in the form of correspondence
                    and clippings. The work was removed from the exhibition after objections to the
                    painting's subject were made by Philadelphia Civic Center Executive Director
                    John Pierron.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">FOCUS. Philadelphia Focuses on Women in the Visual
                    Arts.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Art--Exhibitions.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Feminism and art. </subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Biographies.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Catalogs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Posters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Sound recordings.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 29.5</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=FOC">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=FOC</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>