<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Henri Gabriel Marceau Director Records <date type="inclusive">1955-1964</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Henri Gabriel Marceau Director Records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC2386</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>56.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1955-1964</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henri Gabriel Marceau, an internationally known scholar, art historian and
                    architect, was the Director of the Museum from 1955 to 1964. In 1926, Henri
                    Marceau was appointed assistant curator of the Johnson Collection. Two years
                    later he was promoted to curator. He also maintained a position as an assistant
                    professor at University of Pennsylvania’s School of Fine Arts from 1925 until
                    1929, when he took on the additional role of Curator of Fine Arts at the
                    Philadelphia Museum of Art. In 1933 his position at the Museum was revised to
                    Curator of Paintings, and then to Chief, Department of Paintings and Sculpture
                    in 1937. At this time Marceau also became Associate Director, handling much of
                    the Director's work when Fiske Kimball was away on acquisition missions or on
                    vacations in Europe during the summers. Marceau worked closely with Kimball at
                    other times, and took on full directorship after Kimball's retirement. Marceau
                    maintained his role as Curator of the Johnson Collection throughout these
                    various appointments, and beyond them, until his death.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Marceau's Records consist mainly of correspondence with individuals,
                    corporations, museums and universities, as well as subjects, and they are
                    arranged chronologically by calendar years. Museums are filed under M (for
                    Museum) and then by name for the larger Museums and, alphabetically by
                    individual name for the smaller ones. There are several folders on the
                    installation of the Japanese Tea House and the Kramrisch Collection of Sculpture
                    (1955), as well as a file of condolences for Fiske Kimball in 1955 and 1956.
                    There is a small Object File.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art.</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/ead.php?c=MAR&amp;p=tp">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/ead.php?c=MAR&amp;p=tp
                    </extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art Fiske Kimball Records, Henri Marceau Curatorial Records, and Johnson
                    Collection Curatorial Records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>