<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Kienbusch European decorative arts records <date type="inclusive">1860-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Kienbusch European decorative arts records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC2330</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>104.23 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1860-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>A lifelong New Yorker, Mr. Carl Otto Kretzschmar von Kienbusch (1884-1976) was a
                    successful businessman who collected armor from about 1914 until his death in
                    1976 . The Museum’s relationship with the famous collector and connoisseur began
                    in the late 1940s, when R. Sturgis Ingersoll, former president of the Museum,
                    visited Mr. von Kienbusch’s residence on East 74th Street in New York City,
                    which at the time was filled with his burgeoning collection. In 1974, Mr. von
                    Kienbusch approved the loan of 165 pieces to create a display in the Museum.
                    Upon his death in 1977, the entire collection with an important library and
                    archive was bequeathed to the Museum where it was installed, as Mr. von
                    Kienbusch had requested, in a series of handsome galleries funded by the City of
                    Philadelphia and arranged in the style of a traditional European armory.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Kienbusch archive provides documentation of the collection of arms and armor
                    assembled over many decades by Mr. von Kienbusch. The papers also offer
                    biographical information about Carl Otto von Kienbusch and the Kienbusch family.
                    Kienbusch’s correspondence and related materials document his interactions with
                    dealers, collectors, museums, and scholars. This portion of the collection
                    includes an estate appraisal, copies of Kienbusch's will, inventories of the
                    Kienbusch collection, receipts and invoices, articles by others on the Kienbusch
                    Collection, drafts of articles by Kienbusch, and some genealogical files on the
                    Kienbusch family. Correspondents include R. Sturgis Ingersoll, W. O. Oldman, and
                    the Metropolitan Museum of Art. The collection includes a number of arms and
                    armor auction catalogs collected and annotated by Kienbusch. A number of the
                    volumes have been bound in sets. Catalogues date from 1860-1976. There is also
                    an index to file, arranged by classification and by auction sale, to arms and
                    armor auctions. In 1963, Princeton published The Kretzchmar von Kienbusch
                    Collection of Armor and Arms. This collection includes copies of the published
                    catalog, as well as photographs and annotated typescript drafts of the
                    catalogue. There is a large quantity of photographic material in the collection:
                    glass negatives, lantern slides, film negatives, and small and large format
                    photographic prints. These include images of objects in the Kienbusch collection
                    of arms and armor; objects in various private collections; photographs and
                    negatives from Kienbusch’s European travels (city views, landscapes, castles,
                    people, rooms containing armor collections); and illustrations to accompany
                    lectures. Personal papers of Kienbusch include appointment books, travel
                    diaries, autobiographies, a family history, and photographs. Appointment books
                    document Kienbusch’s daily activities; they include tickets, receipts, and
                    ephemera pasted in. The travel diaries describe collecting trips Kienbusch made
                    to Europe in 1923, 1937, 1952, 1954, and 1959. There are also travel scrapbooks,
                    from 1937, 1952, and 1953, which contain photographs of landscapes, castles,
                    people, and arms and armor. The 1953 scrapbook also includes a typed narrative
                    description of Kienbusch’s journey. There are typescript autobiographies of
                    Kienbusch, which include photographs, as well as a history of the Kienbusch
                    family, also compiled by Kienbusch. Finally, there are a number of loose
                    photographs of Kienbusch taken throughout his life, and photographs of other
                    family members. Other miscellaneous items in the collection include rolled
                    plates illustrating weapons and uniforms from various periods, published by the
                    Company of Military Historians; several miscellaneous posters depicting arms and
                    armor; and a series of mounted photo reproductions, presumably of Kienbusch and
                    his collection. [it seems more likely that these were created by the museum,
                    rather than by Kienbusch -- also possible that they are part of the Herben
                    materials -- not clear from the items themselves] </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art.</corpname>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Von Kienbusch, Carl Otto Kretzschmar, 1884-1976--Art
                    collections. </persname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Armor--Europe. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Armor--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Art--Collectors and collecting.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Weapons--Europe. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Weapons--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia. </subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Autobiographies.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Catalogs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Diaries.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Estate inventories.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Glass plate negatives.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Lantern slides.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Manuscripts.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Negatives (Photographic)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Wills.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>