<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Pennsylvania Museum of Art 69th Street Branch records <date type="inclusive">1928-1933</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Pennsylvania Museum of Art 69th Street Branch
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC738</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1928-1933</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1931 the 69th Street Branch Museum of the Philadelphia Museum of Art was
                    established, and Philip N. Youtz was hired as Curator. Funded in part by a
                    Carnegie Corporation grant to support modern art, the Branch displayed temporary
                    exhibitions of contemporary and recent artists from the permanent collection.
                    The Branch was an experiment in branch museums, and financial belt-tightening of
                    the Depression forced its closing in 1933.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection documents the establishment, operation, and the closure of the
                    69th Street Branch Museum of the Philadelphia Museum of Art. The records date
                    from 1928 to 1933 and include correspondence, minutes, exhibit files, publicity
                    materials, and photographs. The correspondence includes letters between Youtz
                    and PMA curators and staff, curators at other institutions, and professional
                    associations. There are also copies of Fiske Kimball letters that relate to the
                    operation of the Branch. Minutes of the Committee on Museum, 1931-1932, document
                    the process of establishing the Branch. Exhibit files offer a more detailed look
                    at the selection of works displayed at the Branch. These files include budgets,
                    lists of artworks displayed, loan and insurance records, sketches of exhibit
                    layouts, correspondence with curators and lenders, exhibition schedules,
                    attendance statistics, posters for exhibitions and lectures, and abstracts of
                    lectures and panels. Publicity materials include press releases on the Branch
                    and its programs and exhibits, brochures and announcements, newspaper clippings.
                    There are several black and white photographs of the Branch's galleries and of
                    artworks being considered for exhibit. The collection also includes manuscripts
                    of articles by Youtz , including an article on the 69th Street Branch, given at
                    a meeting of the American Association of Museums in 1932.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Pennsylvania Museum of Art. 69th Street Branch. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Art museums and community.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Art museums--Educational aspects. </subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Manuscripts.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Posters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Press releases.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 26</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=SIX">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=SIX</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art: Fiske Kimball records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>