<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art memorabilia <date type="inclusive">1920</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art memorabilia</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC776</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1920</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Philadelphia Museum of Art, located at the west end of the Benjamin Franklin
                    Parkway in Philadelphia's Fairmount Park, was established in 1876 in conjunction
                    with the Centennial Exposition and is now among the largest art museums in the
                    United States. Originally the Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art,
                    its founding was inspired by the South Kensington Museum (now the Victoria and
                    Albert Museum) in London, which grew out of the Great Exhibition of 1851. The
                    museum opened its doors to the public on May 10, 1877, originally housed in
                    Memorial Hall. Construction of the current building began in 1919 when Mayor
                    Thomas B. Smith laid the cornerstone on the former reservoir land of the
                    decommissioned Fairmount Water Works covering ten acres of ground. The first
                    section was completed in the spring of 1928. The quasi-Greek Revival design was
                    produced by Horace Trumbauer and the firm of Zantzinger, Borie and Medary. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>A metal bucket dating approximately from the early 20th century currently makes
                    up this record group. Sporting a once-bright red surface paint, which is now
                    badly chipped, the bucket also has yellow lettering, which reads "P.M.A.
                    Water," signifying its purpose in case of fire emergencies.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art.</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Artifacts.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 34</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=SFM">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=SFM</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>