<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art Johnson Collection binders <date type="inclusive">1917-2008</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art Johnson Collection
                    binders</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC2313</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>47.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1917-2008</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Corporate lawyer and art collector John G. Johnson amassed a seminal collection
                    of over 1,200 European paintings and sculptures between the early 1880's and his
                    death in 1917. In Johnson's will, he left his art collection and his home at 510
                    South Broad Street to the City of Philadelphia, and named the Pennsylvania
                    Company for Insurances on Lives and Granting Annuities as trustee of his
                    residual estate. A 1917 codicil of Johnson's 1912 will mandated that the
                    collection remain installed in his home unless an extraordinary situation should
                    arise making a move necessary. As early as 1919, only 2 years after Johnson's
                    death, legal proceedings began, and by 1921 an official petition was placed
                    before the Orphans' Court of Philadelphia for permanent relocation of the
                    Collection and the sale of the 510 S. Broad St. property. The plea was grounded
                    in the fact that the cost of renovation that the property would necessitate in
                    order to safely house the Collection would be in excess of the available funds.
                    The petition was dismissed, and the City proceeded with renovation projects to
                    the extent afforded by the limited budget. By 1933, the Depression had added an
                    overwhelming burden to the maintenance of the deteriorating property. An
                    informal proposition to display the Collection at the Philadelphia Museum of Art
                    was then approved by the Court. Subsequently, the property was sold and the
                    Trustee of the Collection entered into a lease agreement with the Museum. The
                    Johnson Collection was to be displayed and stored at the Museum in concordance
                    with Museum hours and operations. The Trustee was responsible for rent payments
                    and providing guardianship for the Collection as well as paying maintenance
                    costs, including contributions to the general Restoration Fund of the Museum.
                    The Trustee would continue its role as custodian and administrator of the
                    Collection. In 1926, Henri Marceau was appointed assistant curator of the
                    Johnson Collection. Two years later he was promoted to curator. He also
                    maintained a position as an assistant professor at University of Pennsylvania's
                    School of Fine Arts from 1925 until 1929, when he took on the additional role of
                    Curator of Fine Arts at the Philadelphia Museum of Art. In 1933 his position at
                    the Museum was revised to Curator of Paintings, and then to Chief, Department of
                    Paintings and Sculpture in 1937. At this time Marceau also became Associate
                    Director, and then took on full directorship of the Museum from 1955 to 1964.
                    Marceau maintained his role as Curator of the Johnson Collection throughout
                    these various appointments, and beyond them, until his death. Under the auspices
                    of the Pennsylvania Company, and with the assistance of Barbara Sweeny, Marceau
                    oversaw the relocation and installation of the Collection in the allocated
                    galleries and storage spaces at the Philadelphia Museum of Art. Marceau and
                    Sweeny organized several exhibitions featuring works from the Johnson Collection
                    including "Flemish Painting," "Vienna Art Treasures" and "Flanders in the
                    15th Century," as well as overseeing reinstallations of the Johnson galleries.
                    The team also oversaw the revision of the original Italian and Dutch and Flemish
                    catalogues, published in 1966 and 1972 respectively, and the production of a
                    Book of Illustrations in 1953. They continued together as the curator and
                    associate curator of the Johnson Collection until Marceau's death in 1969, upon
                    which Sweeny assumed Marceau's position of curator until 1972.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Materials include: photographs, catalog descriptions with curator's notes,
                    exhibitions, publication, and provenance information, correspondence, permission
                    to publish requests, research and reference materials including, offprints,
                    extracts and xeroxes of articles, and conservation and restoration files. One
                    lateral drawer of photos used as proofs in Italian Paintings 1250-1450, in the
                    John G. Johnson Collection and the Philadelphia Museum of Art, by Carl B.
                    Strehlke. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>