<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art Development (transitional) records <date type="inclusive">1960-1996</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1967-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art Development (transitional)
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC353</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>24.9 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-1996</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1967-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In addition to cultivating and soliciting donors and other funding sources, a
                    development office establishes the suitability between such funding and an
                    institution's strategic planning. Over the Museum's history, the responsibility
                    for a development program has fluctuated between corporate officers, committees,
                    and personnel from various offices, departments and divisions of operation. At
                    times, one director or manager has been assigned to administer both a
                    development and membership program. In the 1964-1965 Annual Report, a Museum
                    staff person was listed for the first time in connection with the Fund Office.
                    Madeleine S. de Miège, who was secretary to the Museum President, also served as
                    Fund Office Secretary and Assistant. In 1967, the Museum hired Robert Safrin as
                    its first Manager of the Development and Membership departments. Other than a
                    Membership Secretary, Safrin was the sole staffer of these departments. His
                    position was listed as part of the Museum's Administration division. Both Safrin
                    and de Miège held their positions through 1971. The following year appears to
                    have been a turning point in the way the Museum intended to cultivate its
                    development and membership programs. As noted in the 1970-1971 Annual Report
                    (which included a list of staff as of April 1972), a Development and Membership
                    Department, separate from Administration, was listed. Noble Smith was the
                    department's Acting Manager, overseeing Jane Custer, membership supervisor, and
                    Cathey McClain, annual fund-giving coordinator. A Development Steering Committee
                    was also initiated that year. The next year, Development and Membership became
                    separate departments, each operating with the same staff positions of annual
                    giving coordinator and supervisor, respectively. The management position for
                    development, however, once again became part of Administration, with the
                    appointment of Philip Thompson as Assistant Director for Development, who
                    replaced Noble Smith. Thompson remained in that position through 1977, and in
                    1979 Noble Smith returned to the Museum, replacing his replacement. For 1980 and
                    1981, Smith's responsibilities expanded to include membership and public
                    relations in addition to development. As indicated in the 1980-1981 Annual
                    Report, the Museum revised its overall staff structure, so that each office and
                    department was categorized under one of three divisions: corporate, curatorial,
                    and programs and supporting services. In 1980, Noble Smith's Administration
                    position became a Corporate one. And for the first time, a director was
                    appointed to oversee the Development Department, which was classified within the
                    latter division. Maria Giliotti assumed that position, which put her in charge
                    of staff responsible for annual giving, major gifts, grants, and planned giving.
                    Although the organizational structure of the Museum would continue to fluctuate
                    in the following decade, in 1982 the Development Department, as well as
                    Membership began operating as it does today, independent of any corporate
                    supervision. When Maria Gilliotti assumed the position of Development Director
                    in 1982, the department was categorized under the "Programs and Supporting
                    Services" division within the Museum's organizational structure. ("Corporate"
                    and "Curatorial" were the other divisions). Gilliotti's staff that year
                    included Terry Hoff as annual giving coordinator, Daphne Smith as major gifts
                    coordinator, Susan Stuchlak as grants coordinator, and Carol Maloney as planned
                    giving administrator. In 1989, Elizabeth S. Ketcham temporarily replaced
                    Gilliotti as Acting Development Director, overseeing a smaller staff consisting
                    of coordinators for an Associate Member program and for grants. In 1990 the
                    Museum made a significant change in its organizational structure, bringing
                    Development once again under its corporate division and designating it as an
                    administration office. Developmental activities were now administered by the
                    Office of the Vice President for Development, with Alexandra Q. Aldridge joining
                    the Museum as V.P. (Interestingly, the offices of Membership and Public
                    Relations remained part of the Programs and Supporting Services division. In
                    1995, however, the Museum did establish an Office of Vice President for
                    Marketing and Public Relations.) Aldridge's staff coordinated programs devoted
                    to corporate partners, Associate museum members, grants, and annual giving. Over
                    the next three years, additional personnel were hired to broaden and refine the
                    Museum's development strategies, such as a campaign manager, writer and
                    researcher, a foundation relations coordinator, and a
                    communications/publications and telemarketing manager. By June 1994, the
                    Development office grew to a staff of 17. (As a point of comparison, the Office
                    of President and Director had 7.) That year, in addition to having personnel in
                    charge of corporate, associate, and annual giving programs, a Deputy Director
                    and a Director of Foundation and Grant Relations were added. Katharine Wilson
                    Gotwals, who began in 1991 as a part-time campaign manager in Development,
                    assumed the former position, and Linda Jacobs, who came to the Museum in 1992 to
                    work on government grants, was promoted to the latter. In 1996, both Gotwals and
                    Ketcham were named Deputy Directors. Gotwals left the following year; Ketcham
                    continued through 1999. The Second Century Fund was initiated in 1977 in
                    response to a federal grant challenge. The National Endowment of the Humanities
                    would grant the Museum $900,000 over a three-year period if the Museum could
                    match that amount each of the three years. The title of the campaign referred to
                    the Museum beginning its 101st year (1977). The goal of the Landmark Renewal
                    Fund, was to raise $50 million through private funding over a five-year period,
                    1986-1991. Specifically, the funds were intended to enhance the presentation of
                    the Museum's collections, make necessary restorations and repairs to the
                    "landmark" building, and reinforce the institution's financial basis.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Museum’s Development Department. Materials
                    include: form letters, records of gift funds, office accounts and photographs,
                    as well as an outline of development and membership activities during the 1970s;
                    records related to gifts to the Museum made by trustees and associates through
                    at least 1995; planning documents related to a 1981 symposium on planned giving;
                    fund reports; monthly calendars of special exhibitions and events, and members
                    newsletters. The collection also includes records related to activities and
                    events sponsored by the Museum’s Friends and Young Friends to raise funds for
                    Museum acquisitions. These records document the planning of benefit parties held
                    approximately from 1989 to 1997 at noted Philadelphia venues such as the
                    Horticultural Center and Ritz-Carlton. Photographs of events and members are
                    also included. Materials related to special fundraising initiatives, designed to
                    meet specific goals within a specified period of time include: the Second
                    Century Fund which contains a scrapbook of reports, mailings, press releases and
                    clippings, and ephemera; and documentation of the Landmark Renewal Fund which
                    traces the campaign's progress, and contains pre-campaign proposals and
                    feasibility studies, material from previous programs, drafts of programs and
                    solicitation proposals, minutes of various committee meetings, publicity and
                    reference material, including videotapes, and a campaign summary.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art. Development and
                    Membership Department. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art. Development Department. </corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Fund raising.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Museum finance. </subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Press releases.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Videotapes.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 13</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=DM">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=DM</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art: Development and Membership Department Records (ADV) and Development
                    Department Records (DEV).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>