<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art Information Services Department records
                            <date type="inclusive">2001</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art Information Services Department
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC409</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">2001</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The earliest reference to the Museum's adoption of any type of electronic support
                    was in the 1982-1984 Annual Report. It notes that Susanna D. Roberts worked in
                    the Administrative Services office as the lone word processing operator. In
                    1991, the Museum established an Information Systems department, which consisted
                    of a manager, Robert Leming, and Oscar Gunther, Alexander Ryabin and William
                    Taylor Howard as parti-time computer assistants. Two years later, the
                    department's title was changed to Technical Services and its personnel grew to
                    include audio-visual and telephone technicians. In 1997, William Weinstein
                    joined the Museum to manage its newly created Computer Servcies department.
                    Telephone ("Voice") and audio-visual systems were now a separate office. Two
                    year later, the department began operating as Information Services, and
                    Weinstein was named Director. As of the 2006 Annual Report, Weinstein continues
                    to serve as Director of the department, which now is staffed with Database and
                    Network administrators, a Help Desk supervisor and technician, and a Business
                    Systems coordinator. In addition to this staff is another office, Collections
                    Information System Project. The project was initiated in 1999 and began with an
                    18-member committee comprised of curators, conservators, registrars, educators
                    and librarians coming together to select a centralized database system to
                    manage, catalogue and provide access to the Museum's 300,000+ works of art.
                    Jenny Wilker joined the Museum that first year to manage the project, which
                    resulted in the Museum's implementation of "TMS" (The Museum System) database.
                    Wilker retired at the end of 2006. The office, with a staff of approximatley 10,
                    continues to update and expand on its electronic collection management
                    capabilities.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>These are the records of Jenny Wilker, who was manager of the Collections
                    Information Systems Project until her retirement in 2006. Material includes
                    database proposals; a style guide for entering objects in The Museum System
                    (TMS) database; minutes of the Collections Information Committee, the Steering
                    Committee, and the User Advisory Committee; statistics on the project; and
                    samples of the newsletter Wilker issued for a time as an update of the project's
                    progress. The collection also includes a 1993 report by consultant Margaretta
                    Sander on a collections management database project.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art. Information Services
                    Department. </corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Information storage and retrieval
                    systems--Art.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 18</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=IS">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=IS</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>