<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art Education Division records <date type="inclusive">1932-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art Education Division
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC379</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>21.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1932-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Division of Education was firmly established in 1939. Under several Chiefs
                    during the years, the Division has organized tours, lectures, classes and
                    events, published guides and slides of the collection, and has helped prepare
                    exhibitions. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The "Chief, Division of Education Records" series refers to the title given to
                    the staff member who headed the Museum's educational programs during the 1940s
                    and 1950s. The series consists of subject and correspondence files generated by
                    E.M. Benson and his successor John M. Canaday. A draft folder-level inventory is
                    available in the Archives. The “Exhibition” series consists of files documenting
                    exhibitions hels at the Museum and include correspondence, publicity, and
                    signage The "Photographs" series primarily depict children in a variety of art
                    studio classes. Most appear to date from the 1940s. There are also some
                    photographs of special exhibitions, particularly the puppet program, of works of
                    art produced in the classes, and of lecture groups in various galleries. Some of
                    the photographs are captioned or identified on the verso. While the photographs
                    of this series document some of the department's programs and activities, the
                    photographs in "Teaching Materials," were compiled, as the title suggests, as
                    visual aids in classes and lectures featuring works of art. The photographs,
                    which are mounted, primarily depict paintings, and are grouped by collection
                    name or general genres, such as "sculpture" and "Persian miniatures." Each
                    has an identifying caption. The series also includes oversized reproduction
                    prints of paintings, prints and drawings. The original folder titles identify
                    the prints by artist or by a more general description, such as "Drawings by Old
                    Masters" or "German schools, 15th and 16th century." Some of the folders
                    appear to be misidentified. "Film Programs" (1962-1982), include schedules,
                    budgets, and printed material. "Miscellaneous printed material," consists of a
                    sampling of brochures and other mailers produced by the department that describe
                    the Museum's public programs from approximately 1940 to 1980. Other series focus
                    on the special programs and exhibitions produced by the Education staff. To
                    compliment and expand upon many of the Museum's special exhibitions, the
                    Education department would concurrently run related school and public programs.
                    These efforts are the subject of, "Special Exhibitions," which consists of 7.5
                    linear feet of material. The programs documented in this series were held from
                    1939 to 1988, and cover a wide range of arts, from Pennsylvania folk to African
                    art. "Annual Reports" includes copies of the Museum's Annual reports issued
                    from 1985 to 1995. “Guide Training” contains materials related to Park houses,
                    PMA guides, and School guides. The "Family Programs" (1987-1999) series
                    consists of general teaching materials, brochures, and the files of Julie Rogers
                    (1979-1981) and Any Jared (1987-1989). Materials related to the Department’s
                    "Distance Learning" program (1999-2004, n.d.) include lesson confirmations and
                    evaluations, materials related to distance learning programs at other
                    institutions, and materials on VASTweb. Scrapbooks of printed materials
                    (1932-1969) round out the collection.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art. Division of Education. </corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Art museums--Educational aspects. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Art--Study and teaching.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Annual reports.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Press releases.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 15</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=ED">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=ED</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art: Danielle Rice Records (RIC) and Fiske Kimball Records (FKR).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>