<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art W. P. Wilstach Collection records <date type="inclusive">1893-1922</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art W. P. Wilstach Collection
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC766</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1893-1922</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The W. P. Wilstach Collection of art was bequeathed to the city in 1892 following
                    the probate of Anna H. Wilstach's will. Originally administered by the
                    Commissioners of Fairmount Park and a Wilstach Committee, the PMA acquired
                    custodianship in 1917 when Director Langdon Warner was appointed Curator of the
                    Collection. Currently, the Commissioners continue to administer the collection
                    while custody remains with the Museum.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The records comprise correspondence files (1893-1917), presumably of E.A. Shunk,
                    Custodian of Paintings of the Wilstach Gallery, Memorial Hall. Correspondents
                    include Commissioner John G. Johnson, Superintendent Jesse T. Vogdes,
                    Superintendent Russell Thayer, and conservators G.B. Wilkinson and Pasquale
                    Farina. Some of the letters are addressed to Miss Robbins. Materials includes a
                    letterpress volume of outgoing correspondence of Dalton Dorr, Shunk, and Robbins
                    to the Chairman of Committee and Commissioners of Fairmount Park. Correspondence
                    relates to acquisitions, conservation and cleaning of paintings, hanging of
                    paintings in the gallery, and building maintenance such as heating and humidity.
                    Includes lists of holdings and new acquisitions. The collection also includes
                    Hamilton Bell's correspondence related to the Wilstach Collection, largely with
                    M. Knoedler and Company. These letters relate to the restoration and framing of
                    paintings. (1918). Additional materials include clippings about the purchase of
                    Sargent's "Lady Millicent Hawes" (1922), correspondence about the gift of the
                    Sully portrait of William P.C. Barton, and an 1886 catalogue of paintings and
                    works of art belonging to Mrs. A.H. Wilstach.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Fairmount Park Commission (Philadelphia,
                    Pa.)</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art. Wilstach
                    Collection.</corpname>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Catalogs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 32</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=WIL">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=WIL</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art: Fiske Kimball Records, 1908-1955; R. Sturgis Ingersoll Records,
                    1941-1964</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>