<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art Marketing and Public Relations
                        Department records <date type="inclusive">1952-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art Marketing and Public Relations
                    Department records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC705</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>68.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1952-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>While a Public Relations office has long been part of its organizational
                    structure, the Museum did not designate a formal office of Marketing until 1994.
                    That year's annual report noted for the first time a joint Marketing and Public
                    Relations department operated by a staff of seven. Sandra Horrocks, who joined
                    the Museum as its manager of public relations in 1971, headed the newly formed
                    department. Other staff included Charlotte Biddle as Manager of Special Events,
                    and Kristen B. Batley as Deputy Manager, Group Sales and Tourism. Charles Croce
                    assumed Horrocks's position in 2000. As reported in the 2006 Annual Report, the
                    Museum has greatly expanded the duties and staff of its Marketing and Public
                    Relations Department. Department Director Charles Croce oversees a staff of 16
                    who service four distinct operations; namely, media relations, marketing
                    communications, special events and web development. These four offices are
                    managed, respectively, by Norman Keyes, Director of Media Relations, Marcia L.
                    Birbilis, Marketing Communications Manager, Camille Focarino, Director of
                    Special Events and Bill Ristine, Webmaster.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Approximately 14 linear feet of general files comprise the bulk of this record
                    group. While the earliest files date back to the 1950s, most were generated
                    during the 1990s. Individual artists and special exhibitions organized by the
                    Museum are the most frequent subjects. Attendance and fund raising reports, and
                    materials pertaining to audience studies, proposed programs, committees and
                    special events are also included, as well as a small group of files identified
                    as "media." Almost as extensive are the "Photograph" files, which make a
                    visual record of events from the 1960s to the 1990s. A significant number
                    pertain to special events organized by the Museum and those held in the Museum
                    but hosted by other organizations. Included in the former are exhibition
                    openings and related lectures. Conventions of professional organizations, such
                    as the American Association of Museums, and radio station dance parties are
                    among the latter. There are also approximately 2 linear feet of seemingly
                    similar files, 1980s-1990s, identified as "visual materials." The remaining
                    8.5 linear feet of files are identified as "Clippings, Photos and Files." Most
                    were generated during the 1980s and 1990s and like the "Photographs" files
                    pertain in particular to special Museum exhibitions and events.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art. Marketing and Public
                    Relations Department. </corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Museums--Public relations.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 22</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=MPR">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=MPR</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art: Marketing Department records and Public Relations Department
                    records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>