<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art Volunteer Services Department records
                            <date type="inclusive">1961-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art Volunteer Services Department
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC731</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1961-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Museum has a strong tradition of support from volunteers of all ages.
                    Currently, there are approximately 500 volunteers from all over the community
                    working in nearly every department at the Museum, providing services to visitors
                    and assisting the professional staff behind the scenes. Museum Guides serve as a
                    vital source of information, conducting daily tours of both the collections and
                    selected special exhibitions. Admission to either the Weekday or Weekend Guide
                    Program requires a two-year training commitment. Park House Guides are
                    responsible for conducting tours through Fairmount Park and its fully restored
                    historic houses. Membership Volunteers serve as liaisons between Membership and
                    Visitor Services and Museum members. Duties include selling memberships and
                    renewals and assisting members and visitors with information regarding the
                    Museum, membership programs and events. In addition, Membership Volunteers serve
                    as greeters during special exhibitions.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>These records document the activities and procedures initiated over the last 40
                    years by the Volunteer Services office to develop and guide their interactions
                    with the public. The "Museum guides" series pertains to the weekend, weekday
                    and graduate guides. Documentation includes extensive runs, from the mid-1960s
                    to 2005, of the newsletters published for two of the guide groups; namely,
                    "Guidelines" written for the weekday guides, and "Guideposts" for those who
                    work the weekends. Both are monthly publications. Issues of the "Graduate
                    Guidelines," published approximately six times a year, are also included for
                    the years 1991 to 2003. The series also includes meeting minutes,
                    correspondence, handbooks and training materials. The "Park House guides"
                    series documents in varying degrees each of the seven colonial homes situated in
                    Fairmount Park. There is correspondence and an inventory for each of the homes,
                    except Laurel Hill, as well as folders documenting the special events and tours
                    held in these homes, particularly the Yuletide tours. Materials assembled for
                    reference, slide lectures and training programs, as well as lectures recorded on
                    video and audio tapes, suggest the ongoing education of the guides. Other
                    historic structures, such as Girard College, John Bartram house and garden, and
                    the Waterworks, are also documented. Newsletters published from 1992 to 2006
                    comprise most of the material in the "Membership volunteers" series. There is
                    also material pertaining to training, policies and procedures, and finance, as
                    well as to the Captain's and Executive Committees. The membership volunteer
                    handbook, 2000-2001, is saved on a disk along with other miscellaneous items.
                    Originally housed in scrapbooks, the papers comprising the final series were
                    retained more as memorabilia rather than official records. Yet the service of
                    the Museum's volunteer guides and the breadth of their work is well-recorded.
                    The material consists primarily of letters of appreciation to the Museum's
                    volunteer guides from individuals representing numerous organizations, school
                    groups and institutions, including several City offices. The guides office
                    dubbed the correspondence their "fan mail." A substantial amount of clippings
                    are also included, featuring the work of the guides on behalf of the Museum as
                    well as their personal collections and studies.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Fairmount Park (Philadelphia, Pa.) </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art. Volunteer Services
                    Department. </corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Historic buildings--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Volunteer workers in museums.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Manuals (Instructional materials)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Sound recordings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Video recordings.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 25</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=VOL">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=VOL</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>