<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art Public Relations Department records
                            <date type="inclusive">1922-1986</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art Public Relations Department
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC694</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>22.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1922-1986</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>For many years the Museum hired publicity agents through the Director's Office.
                    In 1950 the first full-time press representative was appointed, and there has
                    been a Public Relations Department ever since.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records related to the Museum's Public Relations
                    department. Records include Museum press releases and newspaper clippings from
                    the 1920's to very recently. Also included are some departmental correspondence,
                    brochures, posters and minutes of the Public Relations Committee (1964-1975).
                    The bulk of the collection consists of 64 scrapbooks (1927-1972) that primarily
                    contain newspaper clippings which feature or simply mention the museum. Magazine
                    articles are also included and, to a lesser extent, ephemera and photographs
                    from newspapers across the country. Includes correspondence related to
                    publications of the museum (correspondence of Frederick King and Calvin
                    Hathaway, both editors of the Museum's publications) and some correspondence
                    related to the publication of the Pennsylvania Museum Bulletin, edited by Paul
                    Vanderbilt; Also correspondence of Sandra Horrocks from the 1970s.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art. Public Relations
                    Department. </corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Museums--Public relations.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Press releases.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 21</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=PR">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=PR</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Smithsonian Institute
                    Archives of American Art; microfilm of PMA's Public Relations Scrapbooks (among
                    Philadelphia Museum of Art selected records, 1874-1954); Philadelphia Museum of
                    Art: Marketing Department records, 1983; Marketing and Public Relations
                    Department records, 1955-1999.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>