<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art Library Department records <date type="inclusive">1940-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art Library Department
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC420</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.58 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1940-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The PMA Library has been an important resource throughout its long history. Gifts
                    of books are recorded as early as 1877, and funds for book purchases came with
                    the Wilstach Collection in 1893. Hired as Librarian in 1928, Paul Vanderbilt
                    built the collection and its organization until leaving in 1942. Marjorie Lyons
                    (later Marjorie Lyons Dixon) then assumed the role, and in 1968 Barbara Sevy
                    became Librarian. By 1989, when Anita Gilden succeeded Sevy as Librarian, the
                    department had grown to a staff of six full-time employees, including an
                    archivist, slide librarian, and research and reference librarian. Gilden oversaw
                    the Library until 1993.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Library Department of the Philadelphia
                    Museum of Art. The records include correspondence generated from 1940 to 1979,
                    primarily of Paul Vanderbilt and Marjorie Lyons, arranged alphabetically, as
                    well as memoranda written by Anita Gilden during her tenure as librarian from
                    1989 to 1993. Reports include one generated by the Librarian for the fiscal year
                    1940-1941, slide library sales reports, 1954-1960, and a copy of the Museum's
                    goals and program for 1977. Clippings document the Library's "Public Days"
                    event of the same year. Other materials pertain to the Library's budget needs
                    from 1967 to 1988. Documentation consists of reports, summaries, proposals,
                    memos and notes regarding purchases, subscriptions, staff salaries, and a
                    revolving fund.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art. Library. </corpname>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Vanderbilt, Paul.</persname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Museum libraries.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 19</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=LIB">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=LIB</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art: Fiske Kimball Records,1908-1955, n.d. (bulk 1925-1954). (FKR)</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>