<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art financial records <date type="inclusive">1875-1976</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art financial records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC311</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1875-1976</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Philadelphia Museum of Art, located at the west end of the Benjamin Franklin
                    Parkway in Philadelphia's Fairmount Park, was established in 1876 in conjunction
                    with the Centennial Exposition and is now among the largest art museums in the
                    United States. Originally the Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art,
                    its founding was inspired by the South Kensington Museum (now the Victoria and
                    Albert Museum) in London, which grew out of the Great Exhibition of 1851. The
                    museum opened its doors to the public on May 10, 1877, originally housed in
                    Memorial Hall. Construction of the current building began in 1919 when Mayor
                    Thomas B. Smith laid the cornerstone on the former reservoir land of the
                    decommissioned Fairmount Water Works covering ten acres of ground. The first
                    section was completed in the spring of 1928. The quasi-Greek Revival design was
                    produced by Horace Trumbauer and the firm of Zantzinger, Borie and Medary. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This group of financial records was collected from various sources. The first
                    series, "Accounting records," probably originated in the Corporate Treasurer
                    and Secretary's offices and consists of several ledgers, journals and registers.
                    It offers the earliest documentation, beginning in 1875 and 1876, when the
                    Museum's original site, Memorial Hall, housed the major art exhibition to the
                    Centennial. While general bookkeeping records track transactions up until the
                    early 1920s, most of the investment and funding material pertains to later
                    years. The Assistant Treasurer appears to have generated most of the material in
                    the second series, "Budgets, proposed and operating." Documentation includes
                    operating expense reports, budget estimates, income forecasts and other reports
                    related to the City's operating budget since the Museum is partially funded
                    through municipal appropriations. Most reports date from the 1960s and 1970s.
                    The final series, "City Planning Commission capital projects," focuses on the
                    Museum's funding through the City of Philadelphia. Much of the material dating
                    approximately from 1940 to 1960 originated in the Director's office,
                    specifically during the tenures of Fiske Kimball and Henri Marceau. There is
                    also documentation of specific capital improvement projects at the Museum that
                    were initiated during the first half of the 1960s. The volumes in the collection
                    include: Journals (1876-1913 and 1876-1921); Ledger (1913-1919); Stockholder
                    registers (1875-1882); Underwriting registers (unbound) (1925-1939); and
                    Registers of accounts (unbound) (1939-1958).</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Museum finance. </subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Financial records.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1</p>
            </acqinfo>





            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=FIN">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=FIN</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art: Fiske Kimball Records,1908-1955; George M. Cheston Records, 1968-1977;
                    Julius Zieget Records, 1892-1964; Secretary of the Corporation Records,
                    1825-1980</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>