<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Museum of Art Development Department records <date type="inclusive">1964-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Philadelphia Museum of Art</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Museum of Art Development Department
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PMoSp.ACC365</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Philadelphia Museum of Art<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>50.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>When Maria Gilliotti assumed the position of Development Director in 1982, the
                    department was categorized under the "Programs and Supporting Services"
                    division within the Museum's organizational structure. ("Corporate" and
                    "Curatorial" were the other divisions). Gilliotti's staff that year included
                    Terry Hoff as annual giving coordinator, Daphne Smith as major gifts
                    coordinator, Susan Stuchlak as grants coordinator, and Carol Maloney as planned
                    giving administrator. In 1989, Elizabeth S. Ketcham temporarily replaced
                    Gilliotti as Acting Development Director, overseeing a smaller staff consisting
                    of coordinators for an Associate Member program and for grants. In 1990 the
                    Museum made a significant change in its organizational structure, bringing
                    Development once again under its corporate division and designating it as an
                    administration office. Developmental activities were now administered by the
                    Office of the Vice President for Development, with Alexandra Q. Aldridge joining
                    the Museum as V.P. (Interestingly, the offices of Membership and Public
                    Relations remained part of the Programs and Supporting Services division. In
                    1995, however, the Museum did establish an Office of Vice President for
                    Marketing and Public Relations.) Aldridge's staff coordinated programs devoted
                    to corporate partners, Associate museum members, grants, and annual giving. Over
                    the next three years, additional personnel were hired to broaden and refine the
                    Museum's development strategies, such as a campaign manager, writer and
                    researcher, a foundation relations coordinator, and a
                    communications/publications and telemarketing manager. By June 1994, the
                    Development office grew to a staff of 17. (As a point of comparison, the Office
                    of President and Director had 7.) That year, in addition to having personnel in
                    charge of corporate, associate, and annual giving programs, a Deputy Director
                    and a Director of Foundation and Grant Relations were added. Katharine Wilson
                    Gotwals, who began in 1991 as a part-time campaign manager in Development,
                    assumed the former position, and Linda Jacobs, who came to the Museum in 1992 to
                    work on government grants, was promoted to the latter. In 1996, both Gotwals and
                    Ketcham were named Deputy Directors. Gotwals left the following year; Ketcham
                    continued through 1999. Also in 1997, Mimi B. Stein became Director of Donor
                    Relations. Stein's tenure at the Museum began in 1991 as the part-time campaign
                    researcher. In 1998, the Museum once again reorganized its organizational
                    structure. Development was once again operating as its own department, separate
                    from Corporate offices, which now were designated as "Executive."
                    "Curatorial" was the only other division, as the divisional title of
                    "Programs and Supporting Services" was dropped. Aldridge continued to oversee
                    the department as its Director, rather than Vice President. Development's
                    necessity within the institution was now well established. The department had
                    grown to a staff of 30, including a number of telemarketers. The following year,
                    the Museum initiated a special development program, "Campaign 2001," naming
                    Aldridge Executive Director of Development and the Campaign. Betty J. Marmon
                    came on board as the department's Director. Aldridge remained at the Museum
                    until 2002. According to the Museum's Annual Report 2006, Betty J. Marmon, who
                    came to the Museum in 1999, continues as the Director of Development. Matthew F.
                    Singer is Senior Communications Officer. The 25-member department conducts four
                    on-going programs; namely, Individual Giving, Corporate Relations,
                    Foundation/Government Grants, and Development Services. There are four
                    additional programs within "Individual Giving," and a director leads each.
                    Kelly M. O'Brien is Director of Individual Giving, Edward H. Mills, Jr. is
                    Director of Planned Giving, Ann Winkowski is Director of Stewardship and Major
                    Gifts Officer, and Mimi B. is Director of Donor Relations. Warwick (Rick) S.
                    Wheeler is Director of Corporate Relations, and the position of Director of
                    Development Services remains open. Since the publication of the 2006 report,
                    Susan Fisher has replaced Kirsten Mattson as Director of Foundation
                    Relations.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The first five series to this record group pertain to some of the department's
                    ongoing programs. Each focuses on a specific donor group; namely corporate
                    partners, Associate museum members, annual contributors, "Friends" and "Young
                    Friends," and planned (estate) giving. Most of the records in each series
                    document special events and activities conducted by the department, such as
                    private tours to special exhibitions, lectures, receptions and galas. The
                    "Associates" series, which is the largest, also includes documentation of
                    committee and annual meetings and member lists. The "Planned giving" series,
                    which like the "Corporate partners" and "Annual contributors" series has
                    limited documentation, consists primarily of published material, such as
                    "Estate Planning Quarterly." Files compiled by Johanna Hynes make up most of
                    the "Miscellany" series [series 6], and include staff and donor photos,
                    ephemera, press releases and other material. The series also includes a small
                    amount of documentation of special projects, such as holiday mailings and the
                    Matching Gifts program. The department's publication "Developments" is the
                    subject of Series 7. Produced seasonally, "Developments" highlights current
                    and upcoming exhibitions, programs and major projects, and spotlights certain
                    special supporters and donors of the Museum. The publication is mailed to all
                    annual and other significant donors, which currently amounts to 15,000
                    recipients. The series consists of nearly 15-years of publishing documentation.
                    Another extensive series is "General department records," which covers a
                    number of subjects, such as special exhibitions, special events policy, external
                    affairs, gifts, collections at other institutions, interdepartmental activities,
                    such as retreats, city reports, and outside publications. Correspondence and
                    invoice transmittals comprise a substantial amount of documentation. There is
                    also research material, 1990-1999, regarding prospective donors. Series 9
                    consists of the records generated by Alexandra Q. Aldridge, who served as Vice
                    President of Development, when the office was under the aegis of Administration
                    and as Director, when the office began operating as a separate department. Most
                    of the material is Aldridge's correspondence with donors and with Museum staff.
                    The last series consist of donor files, arranged alphabetically. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Philadelphia Museum of Art. Development Department. </corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Fund raising.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Museum finance. </subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Press releases.</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 14</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=DEV">http://www.philamuseum.org/pma_archives/search.php?c=DEV</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Philadelphia Museum
                    of Art: Development and Membership Department Records, 1927, 1940-1989 (bulk
                    1967-1981) (ADV); Philadelphia Museum of Art: Development (transitional)
                    Department Records, ca. 1967-1996 (DM)</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>