<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Albert Cook Myers - William Penn Collection <date type="inclusive">1668-1955</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chester County Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Albert Cook Myers - William Penn Collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CCHSp.ACC2406</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chester County Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>81 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1668-1955</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Albert Cook Myers was born in Adams County, PA in 1874. He was a graduate of
                    Swarthmore College, and later received an honorary Doctor of Letters from
                    Franklin and Marshall College in 1932. After graduation from Swarthmore in 1898,
                    Myers became affiliated with THE LITERARY ERA, where he served as editor in the
                    history department. (1898-1900). He served as registrar and a member of the
                    faculty at Swarthmore from 1900-1902. Myers spent his post graduate years of
                    historical study at the Universities of Pennsylvania, Wisconsin, and Harvard,
                    sharpening his skills as an historian. During much of this time, he attended
                    lectures taught by Frederick Jackson Turner. In 1907, he was recommended by
                    Governor Pennypacker as one of the directors of the Pennsylvania Historical
                    Exhibit for the Jamestown Exposition. He was later tapped to become the Director
                    of the Historical Exhibits of the Thirteen Original States. The following year,
                    using many of the same skills, Myers became a member of the Mayor’s Historical
                    Committee, celebrating the founding of Philadelphia. From this position, he
                    became director of the Historic Industries Loan Exhibit, part of the Founders
                    Celebration. In 1910, Myers undertook his life’s work--the assembling of
                    material on the life and writings of William Penn. He proposed to recreate the
                    life and works of Penn, accounting for each day. To this end, he undertook a
                    massive campaign to raise money (amounts needed to complete project were vastly
                    underestimated). He spent most of the years, which coincided with World War I,
                    in England, doing research, attempting to get into many private collections to
                    copy letters of Penn. The entrance of the United States into World War I found
                    Myers in America. He became a member of the War Service Committee and worked
                    without compensation to provide for the servicemen coming to Philadelphia. He
                    organized historical walks through Philadelphia, ending with meals and
                    receptions at the Historical Society of Pennsylvania. He wrote pamphlets for the
                    serviceman, pointing out the history of Philadelphia. According to published
                    reports, about 32,000 servicemen were reached with his activities. Though the
                    editing of the works of Penn took up all of his life, Myers participated in
                    other fields of endeavor. From 1924 to 1936, he served on the board of the
                    Valley Forge Commissioners, a time when the greatest expansion of the park took
                    place. From 1924-27 and again from 1933-36, Myers was part of the Pennsylvania
                    State Historical Commission. During his early tenure, he was the driving force
                    behind erecting 27 large historical markers. During his second tenure on this
                    board, he was active in the research and restoration of Pennsbury, Penn’s home
                    in Pennsylvania. Other activities often took him away from his Penn pursuits. In
                    1918, he helped chair a commemoration of the bicentennial of Penn’s death. In
                    1924-25, he spearheaded a campaign to raise money to buy the original charter of
                    Penn to Pennsylvania, and was in charge of the celebration in 1925 when the
                    charter was formally presented to the State. In 1928, he directed the 150th
                    Anniversary Celebration of the French alliance with America, with a pageant and
                    French officials recalling the Valley Forge Encampment. In 1932, Myers directed
                    the grand celebration of the 250th anniversary of the First Arrival of Penn in
                    America. Because his main focus was Penn, the man and his works, Myers was
                    sought as a lecturer. He was known as the foremost authority on Penn, using
                    lantern slides to illustrate the points in his lecture. He also made himself
                    available to budding historians, helping them find manuscripts and sources to
                    aid in their research. A lifelong Hicksite Quaker, Myers was active in the
                    affairs of the Society of Friends and served on several boards. Myers lived at
                    the family home in Moylan, Delaware County from 1906 until 1955, when it was
                    sold. He moved to West Chester, PA for a short time and lived the rest of his
                    life at Pocopson Home, until his death in 1960. His legacy leaves many written
                    works by Myers, even though his masterpiece on Penn was never completed or
                    published </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Arranged chronologically by Myers, the collection includes Myers's research on
                    William Penn and Penn's writings. Includes editions of Penn's works (including a
                    significant number of first editions), photographs of Penn documents as well as
                    Penn manuscripts. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chester County
                    Historical Society: Albert Cook Myers Collection, ca. 1740-1955 (ms. coll.
                    100).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>