<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Buffington - Marshall family papers <date type="inclusive">1707-1876</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chester County Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Buffington - Marshall family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CCHSp.ACC2418</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chester County Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1707-1876</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Buffington family manuscripts begin with emigrant Richard Buffington (d. 1747/8).
                    He was married three times and his children included Ann, Ruth, Richard (d.
                    1741, married Phebe Grubb), Thomas, William, John, Hannah, Mary, Elizabeth,
                    Lydia, Abigail, Joseph, and Alice. Richard Buffington, Jr. (d. 1741) and his
                    wife, Phebe Grubb (d. 1769), settled in West Bradford, their children were John,
                    Frances, Phebe, Richard, Samuel, Henry, Catherine, Peter, Nathaniel, Jeremiah,
                    Isaac, and Joseph. After Richard’s death in 1741, his widow Phebe married Simon
                    Hadley. Marshall family manuscripts originated from the family of emigrant
                    Abraham Marshall (1669-1767) and his wife, Mary Hunt Marshall (d. 1769). They
                    had nine children, including Humphry Marshall (1722-1801), botanist, and his
                    brother James Marshall (1725-1755), father of Dr. Moses Marshall (1758-1813).
                    Moses Marshall assisted his uncle Humphry in his botanical work, and also served
                    as a Justice of the Peace for West Bradford Township, Chester County, PA. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The manuscripts in the collection cover the years 1707 to 1876. The bulk of the
                    collection is connected to two families, Buffington and Marshall. Buffington
                    papers concern primarily the line of descent from Richard Buffington the
                    emigrant, through his son Richard Buffington, Jr. who married Phebe Grubb.
                    Marshall family papers are primarily those of emigrant Abraham Marshall and his
                    family, including his sons James and Humphry Marshall, and James’ son Dr. Moses
                    Marshall (nephew of Humphry Marshall). The collection includes: letters, deeds,
                    accounts, receipts and other business papers, diary pages, summons, warrants and
                    other legal papers, poetry, zodiac chart, advertisement of a murder, maps and
                    land drafts, genealogy, apprenticeship agreements, tax records, poetry, etc.
                    Topics include: farming, botany, legal system, politics and elections, the poor,
                    education, medicine, crime (includes murder, fornication and bastardy cases,
                    etc.), slavery, etc. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>