<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Col. Richard Thomas papers <date type="inclusive">1741-1919</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1741-1857</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chester County Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Col. Richard Thomas papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CCHSp.ACC2390</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chester County Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1741-1919</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1741-1857</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Richard Thomas was born in West Whiteland Township, Chester County, on October
                    30, 1744, a descendant of Richard Ap Thomas of Whitford Garden, Flintshire,
                    North Wales. A Quaker, Thomas was appointed a colonel of the 5th Battalion of
                    Association in Chester County by John Morton on April 19, 1776. He was disowned
                    from Uwchlan’s Friends Meeting for his military service on August 10, 1775 . His
                    brother George remained in the Society of Friends, but according to a letter in
                    the collection, seems to have aided the Revolutionary cause in other ways. After
                    the war, George was a member of the Commission that planned the
                    “Philadelphia-Lancaster Turnpike.” George died after contracting yellow fever in
                    1793. During the Revolutionary War, Col. Thomas participated in a campaign into
                    New Jersey (as far as Amboy) as part of the military’s efforts to protect
                    Philadelphia. Thomas was appointed Brigadier General of Chester County on April
                    19, 1793, (see Box 2, Folder 4), but declined the promotion. He began his
                    political career in 1786, serving as an assemblyman until his election as a
                    State Senator in 1790. In 1794 he became a member of Congress for the fourth,
                    fifth and sixth sessions (1794, 1796, 1798). Thomas was married to Thomazine
                    Downing on October 20, 1774, at Uwchlan Meeting. They had eight children:
                    Richard, Mary, George, Jacob, Phebe, Thomazine, Samuel and William. Richard
                    married Rebecca Malin. Thomazine married William Ashbridge and Phebe married
                    Samuel Hains. Col. Richard Thomas died January 19, 1832 in his eighty-eighth
                    year. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Documents in the collection give not only a detailed account of Chester County
                    and U.S. history, but also the personal side of the Thomas family. Military
                    records include “Accounts of a Revolutionary War Soldier, Richard Thomas
                    1776-1777,” and “A Size Book of Firelocks 1776/Field Book 1775, Richard Thomas.”
                    These record the activity of the Chester County Militia during Thomas’ service
                    in the Revolutionary War and are a record of supplies. Thomas also wrote
                    numerous letters to friends and loved ones back in Pennsylvania during 1800-1801
                    when he was with the first session of Congress to serve in Washington City.
                    Collection also includes his mill account book along with related receipts and
                    letters. Includes many family letters and poetry. Topics include his trip across
                    New York State in 1819. A report of this trip was later published in the Village
                    Record newspaper. Also includes a 1796 travel journal of a trip to Madeira by
                    Samuel Hains. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Donated by Francis D. Brinton and George Ashbridge, III.</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>