<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Court of Common Pleas, Chester County, PA records <date type="inclusive">1681-1900</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chester County Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Court of Common Pleas, Chester County, PA
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CCHSp.ACC2422</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chester County Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>516 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1681-1900</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Records of the Prothonotary, Civil Records of the Sherriff, Select Civil Records
                    of the Circuit Court of Chester County and the Supreme Court of Pennsylvania.
                    This court was based on English practice and was shaped by the laws passed by
                    Pennsylvania’s General Assembly. The court of common pleas heard and determined
                    a variety of civil and equity cases. Primarily, two types of actions concerned
                    the court: personal and real. Personal actions were brought to recover debt or
                    damages or to enforce an obligation imposed on the defendant by his contract.
                    Suits considered personal actions include debt, trespass on case, assumpsit,
                    attachment, and replevin. Real actions were brought for recovery of lands,
                    tenements or hereditaments. Included in this category are dower, partition,
                    estrepement and ejectment actions. Most of the cases before the Chester County
                    Court of Common Pleas were personal actions, specifically debt and trespass.
                </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Includes papers, dockets and books. Types of records include but are not limited
                    to: original writs, narratives, affidavits, depositions, interrogatories,
                    petitions of insolvent debtors, naturalizations and divorces, inquisitions,
                    assigned estates, mechanics’ liens and sheriffs’ deeds, Topics: economics,
                    labor, law, immigration, agricultural and industrial development, women, and
                    social and local history. Records are housed at Chester County Archives &amp;
                    Records Services, Govt. Services Center, 601 Westtown Road, West Chester, PA,
                    19380, 610-344-6760. The Chester County Archives is administered by the Chester
                    County Historical Society in cooperation with the County of Chester. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>