<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Court of Quarter Sessions, Chester County, PA records <date type="inclusive">1681-1969</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chester County Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Court of Quarter Sessions, Chester County, PA
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CCHSp.ACC2421</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chester County Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>300 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1681-1969</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Includes records of the Clerk of Courts of Quarter Sessions and Oyer and Terminer
                    and General Jail Delivery and Criminal Rcords of the Sheriff. The Chester County
                    Court of Quarter Sessions heard criminal cases and dealt with county
                    administrative matters. This court was based on English practice and was shaped
                    by the laws passed by Pennsylvania’s General Assembly. The early county court
                    held by justices of the peace heard all types of cases (civil, criminal, estate)
                    and dealt with administrative functions such as levying taxes, controlling
                    finances, caring for the poor, overseeing building of roads and bridges, and
                    laying out townships and boroughs. The judicial system of Pennsylvania was
                    reorganized by the “Ordinance for Establishing of Courts” (1707). The ordinance
                    designated the provincial court the “supreme court” and formally divided the
                    county court into criminal and civil courts: the court of quarter sessions and
                    the court of common pleas respectively. The Pennsylvania Constitution of 1969
                    brought about significant changes in the structure of the court of quarter
                    sessions as it abolished the courts of oyer and terminer and general jail
                    delivery, quarter sessions of the peace and orphans’ court: the jurisdiction of
                    these courts was transferred to the court of common pleas. In Chester County,
                    criminal records continue to be maintained by the clerk of courts. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Includes dockets and books, indexes to dockets and book, and papers. Types of
                    records include but are not limited to: indictments, tavern license papers,
                    indentured servant and apprentice records, reports of directors of the poor,
                    licenses for hawkers, peddlers and Indian traders. Topics : economics, labor,
                    law, government, crime, poverty, women, and social and local history. Records
                    are housed at Chester County Archives &amp; Record Services, Govt. Services
                    Center, 601 Westtown Road, West Chester, PA 19380. 610-344-6760. The Chester
                    County Archives is administered by the Chester County Historical Society in
                    cooperation with the County of Chester. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>