<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Trimble Rothrock papers <date type="inclusive">1864-1923</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chester County Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Trimble Rothrock papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CCHSp.ACC2389</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chester County Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1923</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Trimble Rothrock (1839-1922), physician, botanist, forester, was born in
                    McVeytown, Mifflin County, Pa. He graduated from Harvard University in 1864 with
                    a degree in botany, having studied under Asa Gray and Louis Agassiz. He studied
                    medicine with his father, Dr. Abraham Rothrock, later earning his M.D. from U.
                    of Pennsylvania in 1868. In that same year, Rothrock became professor of botany
                    at Pennsylvania State Agricutlrual College. In 1873 he joined the Wheeler survey
                    as botanist and surgeon. From 1877 to 1904, he was professor of botany at the U.
                    of Pennsylvania. An opportunity to study botany at the U. of Strassburg left him
                    much impressed with German forest conservation policies. He was one of the
                    founders of the Pennsylvania Forestry Association and its president by 1886.
                    Govenor Pattison appointed Rothrock to a commission to study the state's forests
                    in 1893, and in 1901 Rothrock was appointed the first commissioner of the newly
                    created state forestry department.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of approximately 3,000 letters as well as other
                    manuscripts of Rothrock's lectures on botany and forestry, published articles,
                    scrapbooks, diaries, newspaper clippings and photographs. Correspondence
                    includes family letters as well as letters related to his involvement in
                    Pennsylvania forestry. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of his granddaughter, Eleanor Cleves Rothrock.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1958</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Various related items
                    located in other collections - see list in finding aid.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>