<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Miller - Dickey family papers <date type="inclusive">1786-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chester County Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Miller - Dickey family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CCHSp.ACC2391</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chester County Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1786-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>This collection consists of papers of the Cross, Dickey, and Miller families of
                    Chester County, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and Baltimore, Maryland. John Miller
                    and his wife, Margaret, emigrated from Scotland to Pennsylvania with their young
                    daughter, Jane, in 1786. Miller, who was trained as a stone cutter in Scotland,
                    developed a thriving marble business in Philadelphia; he also owned a farm in
                    Great Valley, Pennsylvania. John was an early member of the Pennsylvania
                    Abolitionist Society, a supporter of the Magdalene and Missionary Societies.
                    John Miller was an elder of the Scots (Associate Reformed) Presbyterian Church
                    Thier daughter, Jane, married Rev. Ebenezer Dickey in 1805. Jane’s sisters,
                    Helen, Margaret and Julia, eventually all married Presbyterian ministers: Helen
                    married William Finney, Julia married George Junkin, and Margaret married
                    Charles McLean. Ebenezer and Jane Miller Dickey settled in Oxford, Pennsylvania
                    and had six children: John Miller, Mary Jackson (later Cross), Margaret Irvine
                    (later Cross), Helen, Samuel (4th), and Ebenezer Verner. Ebenezer and Jane
                    Miller Dickey were passionate supporters of the Chester County Bible Society. As
                    pastor of the Oxford Presbyterian Church, Reverend Dickey rose to prominence in
                    the area, publishing essays on the importance of educating children and the
                    temperance movement. Dickey, a former slave owner, was a charter member of the
                    local colonization society. Plagued with a chronic stomach ailment, Dickey went
                    to Europe in search of a cure. Although he achieved a modicum of relief at a spa
                    in the Pyrenees, Dickey was uncomfortable with the Catholicism in southern
                    Europe and returned home after eleven months. The letters he wrote to his family
                    and congregation were later published as Travels in Europe for Health, in 1820,
                    by an American Clergyman, in the Christian Advocate, a Philadelphia periodical.
                    In addition to his service as pastor, Dickey owned and operated a farm, and
                    served as a silent partner in his brother Samuel’s cotton factory in Hopewell.
                    After Dickey’s death in 1831, his wife, Jane, was left to raise their five minor
                    children, and care for her mother, Margaret Irvine Miller. Jane Dickey oversaw
                    the formidable operation of the Oxford farm, as well as the Philadelphia
                    property she had inherited after her father’s death. Dickey also continued to
                    support various civic organizations including the Oxford Sewing Society and the
                    Poor Widows’ Society of Baltimore. In 1832, her daughter Mary married Richard I.
                    Cross, a Baltimore lumber merchant, and in 1836, her daughter Margaret married
                    Reverend Andrew B. Cross, a Presbyterian minister, author and publisher. Helen,
                    the youngest daughter, did not marry and lived at home with her mother. After
                    training first at Dickinson, then at Princeton Theological Seminary, John Miller
                    Dickey the eldest son of Ebenezer and Jane took his father’s place as pastor of
                    Oxford Presbyterian Church. He established a private school for girls, the
                    Oxford Female Seminary, and later helped found the Ashmun Institute which became
                    Lincoln University after the Civil War. He married Sarah Emlen Cresson and had
                    four children. Samuel Dickey, the second son of Ebenezer and Jane Miller Dickey
                    became a Presbyterian minister after first attending Lafayette College then
                    enrolling in Princeton Theological Seminary. He later served as the President of
                    the Octoraro Bank. The third Dickey son, Ebenezer Verner, attended Lafayette
                    College and medical school at the University of Pennsylvania. Unable to get by
                    on the proceeds of his medical practice, Ebenezer also owned a large dairy farm,
                    was a member of the faculty of the Oxford Female Seminary and was the president
                    of the Philadelphia and Baltimore Central Railroad and the Octoraro Bank until
                    his early death in 1857. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Includes personal correspondence, business records, genealogical notes, diaries,
                    and family photographs. The collection is particularly strong on the following
                    topics: relationships between women, family health, Presbyterian church, the
                    history of Oxford, Pennsylvania, marble cutting business, and the genealogy of
                    the Miller, Dickey, and Cross families. The Miller-Dickey Family Collection
                    includes four photograph albums, two photographs and a stereograph of members of
                    the Dickey and Cross families which have been transferred to photo archives.
                </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>