<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Painter family papers <date type="inclusive">1837-1922</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chester County Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Painter family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CCHSp.ACC2420</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chester County Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1837-1922</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>This collection includes the letters (ca. 6,000+ items, chiefly 19th c.) of the
                    Quaker family of Samuel M. and Anne Vickers Painter of West Chester, PA. Samuel
                    Marshall Painter (1809-1884) was a successful newspaper publisher, book dealer
                    and local official. Both Painters were active abolitionists. Samuel aided in the
                    escape of freedom seeker Rachel Harris and Anne Vickers Painter (1810-1890) was
                    the daughter of noted Underground Railroad conductor, John Vickers. The
                    collection also includes the correspondence of their children: John Vickers
                    Painter (1835-1903) railroad man and banker; Uriah Hunt Painter (1837-1900),
                    West Chester businessman (railroad, telegraph, ice, lumber), early financial
                    backer of Thomas A. Edison, Civil War correspondent for the Philadelphia
                    Inquirer and possible Union intelligence agent; Gen. William Painter (1838-1884)
                    Civil War soldier, at Gettysburg given responsibility of transportation of Army
                    of Potomac; Capt. Francis James Painter (b.1841) Civil War, served in Navy; Dr.
                    Joseph Elwood Painter (1842-1878) Civil War surgeon in charge of the hospital at
                    Camp Curtin, later served in Japan; Henry Painter (1847-1893) Board of Chester
                    County Prison Inspectors; Howard Painter (1851-1876) mining engineer; Ellen
                    Painter (d.1948), daughter of Uriah Hunt Painter. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Most of the family correspondence is authored by the sons of Samuel M. Painter
                    and Ann (Vickers) Painter of West Chester, PA. The bulk of this series includes
                    letters from William Painter, Francis J. Painter, Albert P. Painter, John
                    Vickers Painter and Uriah Hunt Painter. Series includes a number of letters from
                    Ann (Vickers) Painter to her children [handwriting difficult to decipher] as
                    well as letters from Samuel M. Painter. Includes 58 letters written by the
                    Painter brothers from Eaglewood School with details regarding their experiences
                    as students. Eaglewood, in New Jersey, was operated by the abolitionist Theodore
                    Weld and his wife [collection includes one letter authored by Weld]. Civil War
                    era letters include correspondence from Francis J. Painter while serving in the
                    Navy. His duty included time in New Orleans during the Union occupation and
                    blockade service off the coast of the Carolinas and Texas. Also includes Civil
                    War letters from Albert Painter in the Union Quartermaster’s office in Kentucky
                    and Joseph Ellwood Painter’s service as a Union medical doctor. William
                    Painter’s letters also contain details of his time served which included the
                    position of brevet brigadier general in charge of transportation for the Army of
                    the Potomac. Correspondence of the Painter brothers after the Civil War revolve
                    mainly around business dealings and travel in the United States and abroad. Also
                    includes the letters of Joseph Ellwood Painter from Japan while he served as a
                    doctor in the Navy (approx. 1870-1878) offering detailed impressions of Japanese
                    culture and life as well as details regarding life in the Navy. Group of letters
                    (1889-1897) from Uriah Hunt Painter to his daughter in Europe offers detailed
                    descriptions of day to day operations in his two residences in Washington and
                    West End, NJ. Includes details of his relationship with domestic servants and
                    his photography. Letters from school friends, professional acquaintances and
                    extended family. Letters from Civil War soldiers include letters sent from
                    soldiers who Ann (Vicker) Painter took care of in her home. A group of 10
                    letters from Olive Sprogle sent to Howard Painter offers details of courtship
                    activity [she requested the letters be destroyed upon hearing of William
                    Painter’s death]. Letters from the U.S. consulate in Japan regarding the death
                    of Joseph Ellwood Painter (see Mangum). Approximately 100 letters by Emma S.
                    Hunter sent to Uriah Hunt Painter between 1860 and 1865 discuss details of the
                    Civil War and social/business news from West Chester including updates on
                    Uriah’s telegraph business. Camille Bevill’s 17 letters from Japan to Samuel M.
                    Painter detail life in Japan and updates on Samuel’s son Joseph Ellwood Painter.
                    Includes letter from James Mott sent from Philadelphia in 1850 and a letter from
                    the abolitionist Theodore Dwight Weld written in 1860. Also includes a letter
                    from Horace Mann drafted in 1853 from Antioch College. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>