<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Taylor, Harris, Roman, Frazer and Smith families papers <date type="inclusive">1683-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chester County Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Taylor, Harris, Roman, Frazer and Smith families
                    papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CCHSp.ACC2419</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chester County Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1683-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The families in this collection are all related by the marriage of Marianne Smith
                    to Dr. Stephen Harris on April 14, 1833. Marianne’s father, Joseph Smith, was an
                    iron and shipping merchant in Philadelphia, and her mother was Mary Frazer,
                    daughter of Colonel Persifor Frazer and Mary Worrilow Taylor. Marianne’s brother
                    was Persifor Frazer Smith, the lawyer. For an overview of the relationship
                    between the families in this collection, see the chart on page 4 of this guide.
                    More information on the individuals represented in this collection is included
                    in the introductory material to each family’s papers. Both sides of the lineage
                    represented in this collection immigrated to Pennsylvania because of religious
                    persecution in England and Ireland. As Presbyterians and Quakers, they no longer
                    wished to live under a series of laws which forced non-Anglicans out of public
                    office, schools and the church as well as prohibiting meetings for non-Anglican
                    worship. These newcomers contributed to the establishment of the government and
                    religious expression in early Chester County. The documents provide a broad
                    picture of early Chester County and its residents as they interacted with each
                    other at home and in Philadelphia through business, religious, and social
                    transactions. Included in the collection are letters from James Logan (William
                    Penn’s secretary); a broadside by Andrew Bradford, a Philadelphia printer; and a
                    real estate document signed by David Lloyd, Chief Justice of Pennsylvania. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection spans the years 1683 to 1980 (bulk dates 1683-1851). Included in
                    the collection are letters, land records (draughts, surveys, deeds, warrant,
                    maps, advertisements of sale, etc.), business, legal and financial records,
                    commissions, architectural drawings, receipts, account book, broadsides,
                    genealogy, marriage certificates, wills, oath of allegiance, poetry, photographs
                    (originals transferred to photo archives), etc. . Topics include: surveying,
                    Native Americans, Rev. War (includes prisoners, discharge certificate, receipt
                    for British dead, militia, etc.), estate settlements, astronomy, publishing,
                    iron industry, Sarum Forge (includes labor agreements), East Whiteland
                    Presbyterian Church, St. David’s Church, Harris family homestead, domestic abuse
                    (18th c), English Quakers and religious persecution, etc. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>