<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>United Political Action Committee of Chester County (UPAC) records
                            <date type="inclusive">1958-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chester County Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">United Political Action Committee of Chester County (UPAC)
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CCHSp.ACC2416</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chester County Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1958-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Formed in 1966 by a group of local African American residents as a direct
                    response to continuing segregation and racial discrimination in the county, UPAC
                    worked with other local civil rights groups and activists, including activist
                    and West Chester native Bayard Rustin, the West Chester Branch of the NAACP, and
                    the Human Relations Council in fighting against discrimination and for fair
                    employment. The founders of UPAC included Charles A. Melton, Charles H. Butler,
                    Norman W. Bond, Robert L. Wright, Willie Stokes, James Ward, Alston B. Meade,
                    Dr. W.T.M. Johnson, Ernest Spriggs and Charles V. Hamilton. Charles A. Melton
                    was the first president and Dr. Johnson was secretary. Dr. Johnson succeeded
                    Melton as president and it was he who maintained and later donated UPAC's
                    records to CCHS. UPAC was a plaintiff in the racial discrimination case against
                    Lukens Steel (Goodman vs. Lukens Steel, 1973) and participated in the successful
                    1986 legal challenge to West Chester's use of at-large elections in determining
                    voter representation on Borough Council. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Includes legal documents, correspondence, photographs, news releases, memos,
                    clippings, scrapbooks, biographical information on members, etc..</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="www.chestercohistorical.org">www.chestercohistorical.org</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>