<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Administration of the estate of William Bingham, Esq. <date type="inclusive">1804-1818</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Administration of the estate of William Bingham,
                    Esq.</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC1976</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1804-1818</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Bingham was a wealthy merchant, land speculator, and Federalist. [the
                    following was pasted in from a web site:
                    http://www.enchantedmountains.com/POTTER/Pottercoclippings.html] He was born in
                    Philadelphia on the 8th of March, 1753. He was educated at the academy and
                    college in that city. On the 29th of November, 1768, he received a diploma, as
                    Bachelor of Arts, and on the 28th of June, 1771, a diploma as Master of Arts. In
                    1778, Congress appointed him Consul of the United States for the French West
                    India Islands, resident in Martinique. In the spring of 1780 he returned to
                    Philadelphia, and on the 26th of October of that year he married Ann Willing,
                    the eldest daughter of Thomas Willing, a merchant in that city. The marriage was
                    performed by the Rev. William White, Rector of Christ Church, and afterward the
                    venerable Bishop of the Pennsylvania diocese. Mr. Bingham was, for several
                    years, a member of the legislature of his native state, and was Speaker of both
                    Houses, the House of Representatives and the Senate. From the 4th of March, 1795
                    to the 4th of March, 1801, he was a Senator in the Congress of the United
                    States, and an ardent supporter of the administration of Washington, with whom
                    he was on terms of great personal intimacy. While the election between Jefferson
                    and Burr was the subject of contest, Mr. Jefferson did not take his seat in the
                    Senate, over which body he presided, as Vice-President of the United States. In
                    his absence, Mr. Bingham occupied the Chair as presiding officer. Mr. Bingham
                    was an enterprising and successful merchant; but he did not confine his
                    attention merely to mercantile pursuits. He had valuable property in the city
                    and county of Philadelphia, and large landed estates in Maine, New York, and
                    Pennsylvania. From the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania he purchased over a million
                    acres. His title to those acres, lying chiefly in the northern counties, was
                    founded upon WARRANTS, granted to him by the Commonwealth, in the years 1792 and
                    1793, upon SURVEYS, made by the officers of the Commonwealth, and regularly
                    returned by them into the office of the Surveyor General, and upon PATENTS,
                    issued to him, or to the Trustees appointed in his will, and signed by the
                    Governor or Secretary of the Land Office. The evidence of this title is in the
                    Surveyor’s Office at Harrisburg; and any person who will write to the head of
                    that Department for a copy of any paper in his office, will be sure to get it in
                    a week. The cost for a copy of a warrant and survey is half a dollar each, for
                    that of a patent, seventy five cents. No one, then, need be in ignorance of the
                    BINGHAM TITLE, when he can satisfy himself upon it on terms so easy. Mr. Bingham
                    died on the 6th of February, 1804, in the 51st year of his age, having survived
                    his wife, who died in May, 1801. His will, bearing date of January 31, 1804, was
                    duly proved and filed in the Register’s Office in Philadelphia, and copies of it
                    are upon the records of some of the counties in which the lands lie. He
                    delivered his Estate to five Trustees, for the benefit of his son and two
                    daughters, his only children. The Trustees were his two sons-in-law, Alexander
                    Baring, (afterwards Lord Ashburton) and Henry Baring, and his three friends,
                    Robert Gilmore, of Baltimore, and Thomas Mayne Willing and Charles Willing Hare,
                    both of Philadelphia. These Trustees are dead, and the estate is now represented
                    by five other Trustees, appointed in the manner prescribed in the will. They are
                    Joseph Reed Ingersoll, and John Craig Miller, and three of Mr. Bingham’s
                    grandsons, William Bingham Baring, (Lord Ashburton,) Francis Baring, and Henry
                    Bingham Baring. Lord Ashburton and Francis Baring were born in Philadelphia.
                    They are both in the Parliament of Great Britain, the former in the House of
                    Lords, the latter in the House of commons. Mr. Ingersoll was, for several years,
                    the Representative of Philadelphia in Congress, and last summer the President of
                    the United States appointed him Minister to England. The other gentlemen, from
                    time to time, connected with the trust, were held in high estimation in the
                    communities in which they lived; and no person in Philadelphia has a better
                    reputation than Mr. Miller. Such are the persons who have represented and do
                    represent the large interests of the Bingham estate, as well in Pennsylvania as
                    elsewhere. The daughters of Mr. Bingham are dead. One died December 5, 1848; the
                    other, March 9th following. The son, William Bingham, born in Philadelphia, on
                    December 29, 1800, is living in Paris. (From People’s Journal, December 18,
                    1853) Editorial Comment: We publish on the first page a short sketch of the life
                    and character of the late William Bingham, which we hope will receive the
                    attention of every reader. Most of the lands in this county were originally
                    purchased from the State by Mr. Bingham and the title to them is plain and
                    undoubted. We believe no man of sense in this county has ever had any doubt on
                    this subject, and we shall not waste words in trying those who will not listen
                    to reason. The following fact is too seldom thought of by the inhabitants, and
                    is not appreciated even when mentioned. Look at it: For more than half a
                    century, the Estate has paid taxes on these lands, which went to defray county
                    expenses, to build roads and bridges, to pay interest on the State debt, and to
                    support schools, etc.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p/>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Calling card of "Mr Baring Piccadilly" attached to inside board.
                    Purchased by the Dreer Fund.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1933</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>