<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Albert H. Gerberich papers <date type="inclusive">1929-1952</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Albert H. Gerberich papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2141</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15.38 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1929-1952</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Albert Horwell Gerberich (1898-1965) was a genealogist, academic, and diplomat.
                    He received degrees from Dickinson College, the University of Pennsylvania, and
                    Johns Hopkins University. He served in the Navy during World War I and in the
                    Foreign Service from 1919 to 1925. He taught Latin at Coatsville High School
                    from 1926-1928, then joined the faculty of Dickinson College. He rejoined the
                    Foreign Service in 1943 and later held a number of positions in the Department
                    of State, until his retirement in 1960. He published a number of genealogical
                    writings, and was a member of several societies, including the Genealogical
                    Society of Pennsylvania.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists primarily of genealogical research on various German
                    family names. These files include notes, family charts, printed materials, and
                    correspondence. The collection also includes an extensive collection of
                    notebooks featuring etymologies for various languages, lists of Spanish names,
                    family charts and other research on Spanish families, information from Church
                    records and about churches, and English family charts. Other materials include:
                    some correspondence related to genealogical research, including research on
                    German immigration before 1727; loose notes related to the topics above;
                    professional correspondence, including some related to activities at Dickinson
                    College; historical sketches related to Dickinson College; a scrapbook related
                    to the sesquicentennial of the Sullivan Expedition of 1779 (articles from Geneva
                    Daily Times) (may not be Gerberich's); a scrapbook of newspaper articles and
                    ephemera related to "Scenic America" - sights and landmarks in Pennsylvania,
                    organized by county (may not be Geberich's - possibly Heber Gearhart); a record
                    of tombstone inscriptions in the Old Mennonite Cemetery of the Hereford
                    Congregation of Mennonites in the Borough of Bally, Berks County; clippings
                    (many in German, apparently humorous) and ephemera on various topics, including
                    Cuba; photocopies of original documents (court records relating to
                    naturalization of Germans in 18th century); and indexes to names in various
                    genealogical records, including the German Reformed Church in Philadelphia
                    records in the State Archives and other church records. The materials are in
                    English, German, and Spanish.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>