<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Aubrey Haines Baldwin papers <date type="inclusive">1939-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Aubrey Haines Baldwin papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2098</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1939-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Aubrey Baldwin (1905-1998) was the head of the Philadelphia branch of the Federal
                    Writers' Project and a historian and genealogist.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists primarily of historical research and genealogical
                    research materials on the Baldwin family and allied families. Materials include:
                    copies and some original typescripts of various publications by Baldwin
                    including Pennsylvanians in the West and Pennsylvanians in the South, which
                    include data from the 1850 census; listings of Baldwins in various states; an
                    article from Pennsylvania Genealogical Magazine on the Oxfordshire First
                    Purchasers, with drafts, correspondence, reader's report and research materials;
                    printed materials and bibliographies; Baldwin genealogies and family charts;
                    correspondence with family members and others regarding the research; copies of
                    obituaries (photocopies of material from the 19th and 20th century); and copies
                    of indentures, deeds, and other records. There is a small amount of information
                    on the WPA Federal Writers' Project, including copies of signatures of the
                    participants, a listing of writers, copies of newspaper articles, notes, and a
                    couple items of correspondence.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>