<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>B. Hoff Knight papers <date type="inclusive">1855-1960</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">B. Hoff Knight papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2164</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1855-1960</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>B. Hoff Knight was a professional genealogist. He was also a traffic expert and
                    the former manager of the Port of Philadelphia Ocean Traffic Bureau.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists mainly of client files and research materials on various
                    family names. Research materials include printed materials, family charts,
                    extracts from books and records (in the New Jersey Archives, Dutch New York
                    records and other sources), notes, clippings, and correspondence to and from
                    Knight regarding the research. There are also transcriptions from and notes
                    related to English parish registers for 16th through 18th centuries and a short
                    family history titled History of the Knight Family of Byberry, PA from 1855. A
                    small amount of material related to Knight's professional career includes two
                    issues of The Binnacle (a publication of the Philadelphia Engineers District),
                    copies of maps of the Delaware River and a plan of Fort Mifflin, photocopies of
                    newspaper articles, correspondence related to the Prince Plan for railroad
                    consolidation, 1933, and a brief in opposition to ratification of Great
                    Lakes-St. Lawrence Deep Waterway Treaty, 1932. There are also some Singer sewing
                    machine advertisements depicting various Philadelphia landmarks and some
                    photographs and postcards, mostly depicting Philadelphia and New Jersey
                    landmarks and historical figures.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>