<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Bertram Lippincott O'Neill genealogical research materials <date type="inclusive">1907-1989</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1967-1989</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Bertram Lippincott O'Neill genealogical research
                    materials</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2184</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1907-1989</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1967-1989</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Bertram Lippincott O'Neill (1919-2002) lived in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. He
                    worked in his family's insurance business, W. C. O'Neill Sons, for over 20
                    years, then served as a vice president of Aluminum Biclimatic Corporation. He
                    also owned a retail store called La Boutique. He served on the boards of The
                    Historical Society of Pennsylvania, the Genealogical Society of Pennsylvania,
                    the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, and the U.S. Court Tennis Association.
                    His was married to Jane O'Neill and they had a son, Bertram, Jr.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of genealogical research on the Lippincott family and
                    allied families such as Reeves, Biddle, Selous, Coles, Goodwin, Crawford, and
                    Wharton. Materials include: divorce decrees, marriage announcements, marriage
                    licenses, birth certificates, and other vital and legal records; copies of
                    newspaper clippings; correspondence related to the research; personal and
                    genealogical correspondence with family members; photographs; personal
                    memorabilia and printed materials from organizations and clubs in which family
                    members participated; family charts; and obituaries.Information was compiled
                    from various archives and public records offices, as well as other family
                    members.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Bertram Lippincott O'Neill papers (coll. 3011).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>