<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Bradley family charts and Tanner genealogy <date type="inclusive">1975-1981</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Bradley family charts and Tanner genealogy</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2149</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1981</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains information on the Tanner and Bradley families, though it
                    is unclear whether the materials are related. Tanner material is comprised of a
                    photostat of a genealogy of William Tanner, Sr., of South Kingston, Rhode Island
                    and his descendents by Rev. George C. Tanner, Faribault, Minnesota with name
                    index. Stamped with Genealogical Society of Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day
                    Saints. There is also a photocopy of a handwritten Bradbury ancestry chart
                    compiled by Carl F. Hinderer, March 1981. (The Bradburys and Tanners appear to
                    be related.) Bradley family materials include two binders containing photostats
                    of Bradley genealogical research, including data sheets and typed notes -
                    affiliated families include Streeper, Bane, Caine, Copland, Cope, and Hannum,
                    and the families are mainly from the Midwest, Philadelphia and West Chester,
                    Pennsylvania. Most sources are cited. A third binder contains a photostat of a
                    Bradley Family Genealogy compiled over many years by R. Maude Bradley, which
                    includes ancestor charts, narrative, and datasheets.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>