<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Brisbane-Popovic family papers <date type="inclusive">1939-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Brisbane-Popovic family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2193</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1939-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of materials related to the Brisbane and Popovic
                    families, compiled primarily by Daniel J. Popovic. Family members lived in
                    Philadelphia, Ohio, New York, and New Jersey. A series of wire bound notebooks
                    function as scrapbooks, with personal correspondence and correspondence related
                    to genealogical research, greeting cards, and ephemera. Many items include
                    additional annotations. The collection also includes notes on the genealogy of
                    Captain John Brisbane (1730-1822) of Pennsylvania and his descendants, including
                    narrative and pedigrees, and extensive commentary by the author. Sources are
                    generally indicated and include vital records, obituaries, and newspaper
                    clippings. There is also documentation related to Daniel Popovic's work as a lay
                    minister and cantor in the Catholic Church, including writings on religious
                    topics. There is also a good deal of photographic documentation, including two
                    large photograph albums and a number of smaller albums. The albums mainly
                    contain family photos, but several albums consist of photos of the artwork of
                    Beverly Rae Brisbane Popovic (1925-1999). Most photos are identified.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>