<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Calvin I. Kephart genealogical research materials <date type="inclusive">1911-1969</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Calvin I. Kephart genealogical research
                    materials</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2162</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1911-1969</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Calvin I. Kephart (1883-1969) was a historian and hearing examiner with the
                    Interstate Commerce Commission. He served on the faculty of the National
                    University (now George Washington University) for 12 years. He held six degrees
                    and published four books. He was twice president of the National Genealogical
                    Society and helped found the Maryland State Poetry Society. His wife was Olga
                    Ahlson.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection is comprised mainly of genealogical research materials related to
                    the Kephart family and related families. In addition to the Kepharts, family
                    names researched include Britten, Weisel, Runyan, Heller, Fretz, and
                    Rittenhouse. The bulk of the collection consists of incoming and outgoing
                    correspondence with libraries, archives, and historical societies (many in
                    Germany), relatives, and others doing genealogical research on the family. There
                    are also , notes, pedigrees, copies of wills and vital records, and obituaries.
                    There is also a small amount of information on and personal papers of Calvin I.
                    Kephart, including obituaries, memoirs and articles by and about Kephart,
                    advertisements for his books, copies of membership applications, materials
                    related to Kephart's involvement with the National Genealogical Society, and
                    correspondence with other genealogists, including Edward W. Hocker, Milton
                    Rubincam, and William M. Mervine. Some of the genealogical research was
                    conducted by Rubincam.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Commander Robert D. Kephart and Mrs. William Lee Collier.</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>