<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>David M. Adams collection of Adams Family Research Center holdings
                            <date type="inclusive">1999-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">David M. Adams collection of Adams Family Research Center
                    holdings</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2096</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.96 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Adams Family Research Center was located on 742 Centre Avenue in Reading,
                    Pennsylvania, in a 28-room mansion built in 1882 by Frank Furness. David M.
                    Adams was the director. Adams was a former president of the California
                    Genealogical Society and a director of the Genealogical Society of Pennsylvania.
                    Adams moved to Asheville, North Carolina, in 2006.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists primarily of photocopies of catalog cards for books and
                    records related to Schuylkill, Berks and Northampton counties held by the Adams
                    Family Research Center. Notes on the binder covers indicate that these are
                    "cataloged holdings" as of 1999-2001. Some cards contain information on
                    marriages, births or deaths, or index newspapers or other sources. There are
                    also several copies of newspaper articles about the center and correspondence
                    from Adams. The collection also contains photocopies of an S. K. Loy record
                    book, which contains genealogical research related to the Loy family, including
                    indexes to deeds and other primary sources, and extracts from primary sources.
                    This record book also contains some research by Loy on non-family topics.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>