<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>DeBonsall Hedley collection <date type="inclusive">1834-1977</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">DeBonsall Hedley collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2154</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1834-1977</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>DeBonsall Hedley (1911-1978) was married to Eva L. Hedley. He graduated from
                    Westtown School in 1931. He lived in Wethersfield, Connecticut in the 1970s,
                    then moved to Philadelphia. He had also previously lived in West Chester,
                    Pennsylvania.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains genealogical research materials and other items
                    reflecting Hedley's interests. Genealogical materials include: annual reports,
                    minutes, and membership lists for the Society of the Descendants of the Founders
                    of Hartford; handwritten notes, photostats and other copies related to research
                    on royal and biblical figure genealogies; lists, pedigree charts and other
                    information related to the exchange of ancestral surnames; printed materials
                    related to the Connecticut Society of Genealogists; and some information related
                    to the holdings of the Genealogical Society of Pennsylvania. Other materials
                    include: Hedley's Westtown School yearbook from 1931, which includes felt
                    letters, clippings, and signatures from some classmates; research on "migrant
                    races", including a sample chapter for a proposed book, correspondence,
                    handwritten notes, and a telegram from Dwight D. Eisenhower; newspaper articles
                    on World War I and World War II; issues of Spot Lite, the newsletter of the
                    Riegel Paper Corporation, 1938-1939, which include information on recreational
                    and community activities and drawings; Baedeker's London and Surroundings and
                    some printed materials from the U.S. Department of State about various European
                    countries; and miscellaneous printed materials and artifacts. There are also
                    several albums/commonplace books with illustrations and poems copied in. One is
                    supposedly a diary of Anna Humphreys Garrigues.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>