<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Emergency Aid of Pennsylvania records <date type="inclusive">1914-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Emergency Aid of Pennsylvania records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC1990</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>70 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1914-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Emergency Aid of Pennsylvania was a volunteer organization of women which began
                    in 1914, when World War I made foreign and local relief necessary and at which
                    time there was no Red Cross Chapter in Philadelphia. Its purpose, according to
                    the Charter of Incorporation is "to carry on both at home and abroad, emergency
                    and relief work for the benefit of the military forces and the civilian
                    populations of the United States and of their Allies. In World War I the
                    Emergency was the first organization in Philadelphia to forward relief supplies
                    to the military and civilian forces of the Allies and throughout the War sent
                    millions of dollars in money and supplies for overseas relief, having its own
                    distributing centers in each country. In 1917 branches were organized throughout
                    Pennsylvania. In World War II the Emergency Aid again forwarded relief supplies
                    to the Allies and rendered services for the military personnel of the United
                    States, including distribution of books and magazines to naval and military
                    centers; knitted garments and comforts for service men, furnished and equipped
                    recreation rooms in isolated Army posts, provided thousands of Christmas Kits
                    and Survivor Kits for military men, operated canteens, provided housing and
                    information services for enlisted men and women, arranged home entertainment for
                    officers, supervised Clubs for Service Women, and cooperated with Navy League
                    and Army Officers Club for Men. The Emergency Aid also maintained an Allied Work
                    Room for volunteers for making garments for civilians abroad. The Emergency Aid
                    Aides, a special service group, assigned volunteers to draft boards, O.P.A.,
                    hospitals, and numerous other war relief agencies and sold over $68,060,678
                    worth of war bonds. Throughout the war years and in the periods intervening and
                    following, a concurrent local welfare program was carried on, including
                    follow-up care for infantile paralysis victims, unemployment relief,
                    supplemental meals for school children, emergency help and clothing for
                    individuals and families, and providing help for the disabled, the sick, and the
                    underprivileged.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes monthly bulletins (1928-1960), newsletters/bulletins
                    (1918-1978), bylaws (1943, 1956), World War I printed reports, membership and
                    dues cards (1969-1970), personnel records, financial information (1970s),
                    fundraising (1970s), special events (1970s), and charitable outreach projects
                    (1970s). There are also 2 boxes of published books, most of which are about
                    Philadelphia, and at least one scrapbook from the 1940s about Emergency Aid.
                    Framed photographs and certificates, as well as oversized framed photos, are
                    included. Artifacts include ribbons and wood cutouts, and phonograph
                    records/radio interviews from World War II.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>