<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Engineers Club of Philadelphia records <date type="inclusive">1877-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Engineers Club of Philadelphia records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC1991</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>24 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1877-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>"The Centennial Exposition of 1876 in Philadelphia drew engineers from around
                    the world to view the technical advances of that century. It was apparent to
                    engineers residing in Philadelphia that engineers did not know each other.
                    Charles E. Billin invited twenty or so engineers to his home the following
                    winter for refreshments. This started a series of gatherings at the homes of
                    various engineers. The Club formally organized in December of 1877 and Professor
                    L M. Haupt was its first President. It limited its membership to fifty. The
                    minutes of the first meeting stated: 'Its object shall be the professional
                    improvement of its members, the encouragement of social intercourse among men of
                    practical science, and the advancement of engineering in its several branches.'
                    The Club adopted as its motto a quotation from George Washington s speech to the
                    Federal Convention of 1787 accepting the role of president. It expresses the
                    charge placed upon the Engineers Club's members by its charter. The motto
                    states: 'Let us raise a standard to which the wise and honest can repair.' (The
                    Engineers' Club of Philadelphia website, http://www.engrclub.org/)"</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains minutes, correspondence, financial papers, committee
                    reports, minutes of committee meetings, publications, awards given by the club,
                    records of resignations, 100th anniversary planning documents, invitations,
                    menus, and other general files. There are also planning documents for the U.S.
                    Bicentennial.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>