<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Estate of Henrietta E. Garrett, Deceased records <date type="inclusive">1936-1951</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Estate of Henrietta E. Garrett, Deceased
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2024</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>88 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1951</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>These volumes are the records of Clinton Sowers, Esq., who was appointed an
                    examiner to the proceedings of the claims against the estate of Henrietta E.
                    Garrett, held in the Orphan's Court of Philadelphia County. Garrett died a widow
                    on Nov. 16, 1930. Her will provided for a bequest of $62, 500 to several
                    individual and the surviving legatees were paid. However, the total value of
                    Garrett's estate was more than $17 million. In 1931, the Commonwealth of PA
                    filed a claim alleging that Garrett died without leaving next of kin surviving
                    her and that the estate should pass to the Commonwealth by escheat. Because of
                    the size of the estate the case received world-wide publicity and as a result
                    numerous claims flooded the Master's office. Approximately 25,800 claims were
                    made, coming from people in every state but Arizona and several foreign
                    countries. In 1936, a master and two examiners were appointed to exam and render
                    a decision to these claims. These records document this 15 year proceeding. The
                    Masters and the Examiners held approximately 2,000 hearings, at which the
                    tesimony of more than 1100 witnesses was taken. More than 7700 exhibits were
                    received in evidence. On December 18, 1950, the Master, Robert Brigham, issued
                    his report on the case. He ruled that Henrietta E. Garrett left to survive her
                    no husband, no children, no parents, no grandparents, no siblings, no nieces or
                    nephews, and no aunts or uncles. Her nearest next of kin were Howard S.
                    Kretschmar and Herman A. Kretschmar, maternal first cousins, and Johann Peter
                    Christian Schafer I, a paternal first cousin.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the following volumes: Volume "A"-- bound copies of
                    the hearing transcripts before the Orphans' Court of Philadelphia Co.--322
                    volumes (Vol. #285 is missing); Exhibit Books--67 volumes; Volume "D"--
                    transcripts of depositions--196 volumes (Vol. #71 missing); Volume "I" --
                    Investigations--163 volumes (Vol. #75 missing); Volume "K"--Kohler
                    investigation -- 128 volumes (Vol. #125 missing); Volume "O"--abstracts of
                    testimonies--21 volumes; Index of Exhibits (general and sup.1-11)--30 volumes;
                    Index of Dates (general and sup.1-10) --43 volumes; Index, alphabetical--164
                    volumes; Master's Report--3 volumes; Adjudication--1 volume; Other various
                    volumes, including copy of court record, Sowers deposition/report on Garrett's
                    birthdate--13 volumes</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>