<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Eugene S. Richardson, Jr., genealogical research materials <date type="inclusive">1807-1980</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1965-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Eugene S. Richardson, Jr., genealogical research
                    materials</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2194</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1807-1980</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1965-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Eugene S. Richardson, Jr., was the Curator of Invertebrate Paleontology at the
                    Field Museum of Natural History in Chicago, Illinois.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of genealogical research on the Richardson family and
                    allied families. There is also a significant amount of research on the
                    Netherlands Antilles and family members who settled there. Materials include:
                    photocopies of newspapers articles; correspondence regarding the research (and
                    some personal correspondence); printed materials; family charts; photocopies of
                    18th and 19th century documents; calling cards and invitations from the 19th
                    century; photographs; a and very detailed card file of information on various
                    family members. Two significant older items are "Richardson's journal, 1807,"
                    which has been photocopied and transcribed, and a notebook titled "Records"
                    that describes events in the 18th and 19th centuries. There is a separate card
                    file documenting the chronology of the Netherlands Antilles, as well as
                    information on various St. Maarten and Philadelphia residents associated with
                    the Netherlands Antilles. The collection includes notebooks related to research
                    in Dutch and Netherlands Antilles archives, and contains microfilm of some
                    records in the Algemeen Rijksarchief, records offices in St. Maarten, and
                    American repositories.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>