<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Evangelical Lutheran Ministerium of Pennsylvania and the Adjacent
                        States collection <date type="inclusive">1748-1962</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Lutheran Theological Seminary at Philadelphia</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Evangelical Lutheran Ministerium of Pennsylvania and the
                    Adjacent States collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">TLTSp.ACC2354</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Lutheran Theological Seminary at Philadelphia<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>551 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1748-1962</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1742, Henry [Heinrich] Melchior Muhlenberg (1711-1787) arrived in Philadelphia
                    to assume pastoral duties at the largest German Lutheran parish in colonial
                    America. Under the sponsorship of the Francke Foundations—an educational,
                    missionary, and commercial institution in the Prussian city of Halle—he became
                    the prime organizer of churched Lutheranism in America. Muhlenberg was also an
                    influential cultural leader with contact to colonial dignitaries such as
                    Benjamin Franklin, other religious leaders such as George Whitfield, and the
                    Hanoverian court in London. Married in 1745 to Anna Maria Weiser, a daughter of
                    Pennsylvania’s principal go-between with the Lenape, Muhlenberg was not only a
                    formidable figure in his own right, but was the progenitor of what became in
                    effect a German-American dynasty of high-level public officials. His three sons,
                    all trained to be pastors, won fame in politics science, and academia. Peter
                    rose to major general of the Continental Army (receiving the commendation of
                    George Washington), was elected Vice President of Pennsylvania and for four
                    terms, served in Congress; Friedrich, also a member of Congress, was elected
                    first Speaker of the House; Gotthilf excelled in botany and, as president of
                    Franklin College, vigorously promoted American higher education.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The MOP collection contains approximately 551 linear feet, with material dating
                    from 1748 to 1962. The archives holds 28 volumes of Henry Melchior Muhlenberg’s
                    personal journals, correspondence, financial accounts and family papers. Also in
                    the collection are Friedrich’s diary (25 October 1770 to 8 August 1774) and
                    miscellaneous personal papers, as well as Gotthilf’s sermon outlines,
                    miscellaneous personal correspondence, and an 1815 copper plate portrait. In
                    addition to Henry Muhlenberg’s personal papers, the collection holds the
                    personal papers of several nationally know theologians: the Revs. J. H. C.
                    Helmuth (1745-1825), William J. Mann (1819-1892), Charles Porterfield Krauth
                    (1823-1883), Henry Eyster Jacobs (1844-1932), and Charles Michael Jacobs
                    (1875-1938). Organizational archives in this collection include the following
                    Philadelphia churches and Lutheran entities: St. Michael’s &amp; Zion German
                    Lutheran Church (1730-present); St. Michael’s Lutheran Church, Germantown
                    (1728-present); Old St. John’s English Lutheran Church (1806-2002); Lutheran
                    Home at Germantown Foundation (1859-present); The Evangelical Lutheran
                    Ministerium of Pennsylvania &amp; Adjacent States (1748-1962); The General
                    Council of the Evangelical Lutheran Church in North America (1866-1918); New
                    York and New England Conferences, Augustana Evangelical Lutheran Church
                    (1860-1962).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>