<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Florence Kohn Abrahams genealogical research materials <date type="inclusive">1898-1975</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1950-1975</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Florence Kohn Abrahams genealogical research
                    materials</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2095</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1898-1975</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1950-1975</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Florence Kohn Abrahams (1909-1975) was married to Robert D. Abrahams. They had
                    three children, Richard, Roger, and Marjorie. She lived in Elkins Park,
                    Pennsylvania, for most of her life. She served as an American correspondent for
                    The Jewish Chronicle in London in the 1960s.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of genealogical research conducted and compiled by
                    Florence Kohn Abrahams, with a particular focus on genealogies of Jewish
                    families. Families of note include Abrahams, Benjamin, Cohen, Moss, and Davis.
                    Correspondence and compiled research comes from family members in Australia,
                    Montreal and the United States. There are extensive pedigrees and family charts;
                    some pedigrees and related materials have been grouped by country of origin,
                    with binders pertaining to English-Jewish and Spanish-Jewish, and a folder
                    relating to Mexican Jews. There are articles about, correspondence, charts,
                    ephemera and photographs for the Abrahams family, and a pedigree of the
                    Kohn-Abrahams family. Two card files list hundreds of names, and possibly serve
                    as indexes to other materials. The collection also includes photostats and
                    photocopies from books, newspapers, and family charts, as well as pedigrees for
                    English (aristocracy) and Danish families.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>