<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Franklin Fire Insurance Company records <date type="inclusive">1829-1901</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Franklin Fire Insurance Company records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC1997</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>41 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1829-1901</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Franklin Fire Insurance Company was chartered in 1829 and conducted its
                    business on Chestnut Street until 1873, when it moved to 421 Walnut Street.
                    Richard Willing served as its first president. Franklin Fire specialized in
                    perpetual insurance, as opposed to the earlier "seven-year" polices, and thus
                    the duration of the policy was without limit except by cancellation. Policies
                    were paid for only once, and these deposits were based on the face value of the
                    policy. The interest that accrued on the initial deposits sustained the policy
                    for the duration of the contract. The company served the Philadelphia area as
                    well as other regions. Businesses that specialized in flammable goods were not
                    covered by the company. The company had strong financial backing, which enabled
                    it to meet enormous losses in the Chicago fire and other devastating fires.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the surveys made of the insured buildings, beginning
                    with Survey No. 3 done in 1829 for J.J. Borie's tenant house located on the
                    "west side of Schuylkill about one mile above upper ferry bridge." The series
                    then continues with Survey No. 9, also of 1829. The information noted on the
                    surveys includes floor plans, size and type of structure, materials used in
                    construction, number of windows, type of heating, sizes of rooms, location of
                    staircases, and other significant architectural features such as balconies.
                    Outbuildings are often included in the surveys, and the surveyor usually
                    provided rough appraisals of the building's value. The names of the surveyors
                    are also provided.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>