<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Genealogical Society of Pennsylvania genealogical records
                        collection (Gens) <date type="inclusive">1808-1979</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Genealogical Society of Pennsylvania genealogical records
                    collection (Gens)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2000</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>393 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1808-1979</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This extensive collection originally was compiled and held by the Genealogical
                    Society of Pennsylvania. Most of the records represent the research notes,
                    reports and correspondence of genealogists. Although most of the material is
                    secondary and often uncited to source, there is a small amount of original
                    documents within the volumes, including legal documents such as indentures and
                    wills, correspondence, photographs, newsclippings (mostly of obituaries), and
                    receipts. There are also many Photostats and typed transcripts of such
                    documents. While some volumes include documentation regarding multiple families,
                    usually arranged alphabetically, many volumes are devoted to one family and
                    occasionally follow a scrapbook-like format, filled with newsclippings,
                    photographs and printed ephemera. There are also several multi-volume subseries
                    of special topics, such as the signers of the Declaration of Independence and
                    their descendants, the "old families" of Philadelphia and by regional
                    groupings, including some of the mid-Atlantic states, New England, and the
                    counties of Pennsylvania.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>