<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>J.B. Lippincott Company records <date type="inclusive">1855-1958</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">J.B. Lippincott Company records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC623</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>140 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1855-1958</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>J. B. Lippincott &amp; Co. was an American publishing house founded in
                    Philadelphia, Pennsylvania in 1836 by Joshua B. Lippincott. Joshua Lippincott's
                    company began by selling Biblesand other religious works then successfully
                    expanded into trade books, which became the largest portion of the business. In
                    1849, Lippincott acquired Grigg, Elliot &amp; Co., a major book distribution
                    company. The acquisition helped make the company one of the largest publishers
                    in the United States. In the 1950s the company began producing a successful line
                    of medical and nursing books and journals. The company was sold to Harper &amp;
                    Row in 1978 but Joshua Lippincott's great-grandson Joseph Wharton Lippincott,
                    Jr. remained on the Board of Directors until 1987. In 1990, the company was
                    acquired by Wolters Kluwer, who merged it with Raven Publishers and then with
                    Williams &amp; Wilkins to form Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins in 1998.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of business records documenting over 100 years of the
                    company's history. The largest portion of the collection is a series of
                    letterbooks containing outgoing correspondence related to all aspects of the
                    publishing operation, from soliciting advertising magazines to negotiating
                    author contracts. Several dozen letterbooks contain incoming correspondence from
                    Lippincott's London Agency. Much of the rest of the collection consists of a
                    variety of financial records, including general ledgers, receipt books, cash
                    disbursement books, and payroll records. Publication costs and sales are
                    documented through stock cards, royalty payment records, and order and inventory
                    volumes. The collection includes several manuscripts for publications, and some
                    original artwork and illustrations. There are also boxes of books published by
                    Lippincott, including the Annals of Surgery.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2002.036</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An online finding aid is available at <extref href="http://www.hsp.org/files/3104lippincottinventory.pdf">http://www.hsp.org/files/3104lippincottinventory.pdf</extref>.</p>
            </otherfindaid>




        </archdesc>
    </ead>