<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Fryer papers <date type="inclusive">1950-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Fryer papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC640</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>103.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1950-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Fryer (1938-2003) was a groundbreaking gay psychiatrist who is best-known
                    for appearing in full disguise at the 1972 meeting of the American Psychiatric
                    Association as "Dr. H. Anonymous." This performance is credited with
                    convincing the APA's Board to remove homosexuality from the Diagnostic and
                    Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders in 1973. Dr. Fryer, who was born in
                    Kentucky, moved to Germantown in 1972. He was initially active in the community
                    and continued to play the organ at his Episcopal Church. He loved to travel,
                    especially to London, Switzerland, and St. Lucia. In his professional life,
                    Fryer worked largely with gays, lesbians, people who abused alcohol and drugs,
                    and those who were coping with death and dying.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This large collection is comprised of the personal and professional papers of
                    John Fryer. The papers span from Fryer's teens to the last months of his life.
                    There are personal and professional correspondence files; subject files; patient
                    files; student papers from Transylvania and Vanderbilt Universities, notebooks,
                    and exam books; appointment books; diplomas and certificates; and personal and
                    travel diaries. There are materials related to courses taught by Fryer at Temple
                    University Medical School, including syllabi, student records, and reference
                    materials. Reference materials and manuscripts related to Fryer's research on
                    the connections between religion and health, on death and dying, community
                    mental health, cancer care, and on persons living with AIDS/HIV, including a
                    manuscript of a book co-edited by Fryer on care of persons living with AIDS/HIV.
                    Materials related to Fryer's role as member of and organist for St. Peters,
                    including music, church bulletins and programs, notes for meditations,
                    periodicals, and a collection of old bulletins from St. Peter's (1897-1915).
                    There are many photographs and slides, some ephemera, organ music, and several
                    videos and cassettes featuring Dr. Fryer and other psychiatrists and medical
                    professionals.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2003.081</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>