<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John W. Haines genealogical research files <date type="inclusive">1782-1979</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1931-1979</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John W. Haines genealogical research files</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2152</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1782-1979</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1931-1979</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Wesley Haines was a navy captain and professional genealogist. He lived in
                    Medford Lakes, New Jersey.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of genealogical research related to projects for clients
                    and on the Haines family. A set of surname files for a number of families
                    contains copies of family charts, copies of printed materials, notes from
                    published and primary sources (often cited), postcards, and incoming
                    correspondence related to the research. There are also surname files
                    specifically for Haines family members that include family charts,
                    correspondence (much of it with family members regarding the research), and
                    notes. The collection also includes manuscripts of publications by Haines on the
                    Haines family, and notes, correspondence, and copies of original documents and
                    published materials related to the research. There are a a few issues of the
                    Haynes Eagle and a small number of documents from the 18th and 19th century,
                    including deeds, receipts, and marriage certificates, and a few early 20th
                    century school and birth certificates (mostly non-Haines, mainly Wagners).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>