<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Mary Bartol Theiss collection <date type="inclusive">1909-1925</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Mary Bartol Theiss collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2217</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1909-1925</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Mary Bartol Theiss was the daughter of William Cyrus Bartol, a professor at
                    Bucknell University, and his wife, who was active in the Shikelimo Chapter of
                    the Pennsylvania Daughters of the American Revolution and curator of the Union
                    County Historical Society. She was married to Lewis Edwin Theiss, also a
                    Bucknell faculty member. Theiss and her husband were active in documenting local
                    and Bucknell history.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of documentation related to genealogical and historical
                    research and activities, primarily of Theiss's mother, Mrs. W. C. Bartol. The
                    collection includes correspondence and datasheets related to the Shikelimo
                    Chapter of the Pennsylvania Daughters of the American Revolution. Most notable
                    among these are War Service Records related to World War I service of individual
                    soldiers. There is also DAR correspondence related to historical markers and
                    historical and genealogical topics. The collection also includes: correspondence
                    with the Union County Historical Society on creation of a historical marker for
                    Revolutionary War soldiers killed at that spot in 1780; miscellaneous
                    correspondence on personal and historical topics; notes and correspondence
                    related to various families, including descendents of Elizabeth More Clark;
                    photocopies of information on Lewisburg Cemetery in Williamsport, Pennsylvania,
                    and miscellaneous historical topics; information on marriages and records
                    (including records at Prothonotary's Office in Union County); and correspondence
                    and reports of the Luzerne County War History Committee (related to World War
                    I).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>