<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Max Weiner papers on the Consumer Education and Protective
                        Association (CEPA) <date type="inclusive">1966-1990</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Max Weiner papers on the Consumer Education and Protective
                    Association (CEPA)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC508</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1966-1990</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Papers of Max Weiner, founder and executive director of the Consumer Education
                    and Protective Association (CEPA), founded in 1966. This organization fought
                    utility companies, public transportation companies, automotive companies, and
                    other major parties in order to secure rights for consumers. Weiner and CEPA
                    also spoke out about a number of socio-political issues, including political
                    corruption and police brutality. Included in the collection are newspaper
                    clippings, press releases, leaflets, pamphlets, and other printed materials
                    regarding rallies and activities, newspapers and newsletters, correspondence,
                    speeches, radio program scripts, reports, court documents, cartoons, transcripts
                    of hearings, and information about the groups and companies that CEPA fought.
                    There are also videotapes and audiotapes of Weiner's appearances on TV and radio
                    programs. Weiner ran for office unsuccessfully a number of times on the Consumer
                    Party ticket.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Besse Weiner, 1991.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1991</p>
                <p>Accession number: 1991:43</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>