<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Milton Rubincam papers <date type="inclusive">1934-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Milton Rubincam papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2200</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>36.58 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1934-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains documentation of Rubincam's genealogical research.
                    Materials include: an extensive, 113 volume Rubincam family genealogy, which
                    contains correspondence, photocopies of records, photocopies of clippings, and
                    other research; printed family histories and bibliographies (there are often
                    photocopies of correspondence related to the research as well as the final
                    product of the research); genealogical research on various royal families and
                    non-royal families; manuscripts for articles and papers; articles and reprints
                    by others; printed materials from genealogical societies, including a good deal
                    of research related to the Sutherland family and newsletters from the Clan
                    Sutherland Society in Scotland; and miscellaneous reels of microfilm for various
                    individuals and families, as well as the Sussex County Court Records. Many of
                    the genealogical projects draw on German primary sources. There is also
                    extensive correspondence with fellow genealogists and historians - sometimes on
                    genealogical topics, sometimes related to personal and organizational matters
                    for organizations in which Rubincam was involved, such as the American Society
                    for Genealogy. Some files include obituaries written by Rubincam. Correspondents
                    include Walter Goodwin Davis, Donald Lines Jacobus, John Insley Coddington, and
                    Calvin Kephart.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>