<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Natalie Saxe Randall papers <date type="inclusive">1923-1998</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Natalie Saxe Randall papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC650</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>22.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1923-1998</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Natalie Saxe Randall graduated from the Philadelphia High School for Girls in
                    1941 and the University of Pennsylvania in 1944. At the age of 24, she became
                    Director of the Committee for Philadelphia, which spearheaded the reform
                    movement led by the city's great post-WWII reform Democrats Joseph Clark (Mayor
                    1952-1956) and Richardson Dilworth (Mayor 1956-1962) against the legendarily
                    corrupt Republican machine. Saxe remained head of the Committee until Dilworth
                    took office as mayor in January 1956, served concurrently on the Democratic
                    State Committee 1950-1954, and was the self-labeled "Advance Man" during
                    Dilworth's first unsuccessful campaign for governor (1950). When Dilworth
                    resigned his position as mayor to run again for governor in 1962, she remained
                    his Executive Assistant and served as the chief coordinator of his campaign.
                    When Dilworth was appointed President of the Philadelphia Board of Education in
                    1965 by Mayor James Tate (whose campaign Saxe helped direct), Saxe again served
                    as Dilworth's Executive Assistant until he resigned in 1971 rather than work in
                    any way with Frank Rizzo. Following Dilworth's retirement from pubic life, Saxe
                    worked as a government affairs consultant and lobbyist for a Philadelphia
                    consortium of cultural institutions (including the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine
                    Arts and the Academy of Natural Sciences) and Lincoln University. She also
                    worked to perpetuate the memory of Richardson Dilworth and his reform work by
                    assisting in the attachment of his name to Philadelphia City Hall's Dilworth
                    Plaza and the airport's Dilworth International Terminal.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Natalie Saxe Randall. Materials include:
                    typed incoming and outgoing correspondence (originals and retained copies,
                    respectively); notes and memoranda; drafts; typed and typeset reports; newspaper
                    articles; photographs; address books; daily memoranda; and travel diaries. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2004.058</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>