<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Pemberton family genealogical research materials <date type="inclusive">1888-1929</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Pemberton family genealogical research
                    materials</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2187</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1888-1929</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henry J. Pemberton, Jr. (1855-1913), was an inventor and chemist born in
                    Philadelphia, Pa., Sept. 13, 1855. He was the son of Henry and Caroline Town
                    (Hollingsworth) Pemberton. The first of the family in America was Ralph
                    Pemberton, a native of England who arrived in Maryland in November, 1682, and
                    later settled in Bucks County, Pa. Henry Pemberton graduated A.M. at the
                    University of Pittsburgh in 1876 and then entered the junior class of the
                    University of Pennsylvania as a special student, subsequently receiving a
                    certificate of proficiency from that institution. He married Susan Lovering of
                    Philadelphia on Mar. 28, 1894, and had four children.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of genealogical research related to the Pemberton and
                    associated families. Documentation includes: correspondence to Henry Pemberton,
                    Jr., of Philadelphia related to genealogical research on the Craft and Lovering
                    families (Loverings of Massachusetts and Delaware; letters to/from Susan
                    Lovering; a genealogical chart and pedigree for Henry Pemberton and Caroline
                    Towne Hollingsworth; notes and notebooks on family history, particularly the
                    Lovering and related families of New England; notes on Thomas Heatherd of Kent
                    County, Delaware; and a narrative genealogy "Shallcross of Pennsylvania,
                    U.S.A." by Oliver Hough, 1907 (Leonard and John Shallcross of Philadelphia and
                    Bucks County).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>