<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Penn family papers <date type="inclusive">1629-1834</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Penn family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2410</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>40 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1629-1834</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Sir William Penn, 1621-1670. Papers, 1644-1710: journal of Sir William Penn,
                    1644-1647; letters, 1650-1660; Forbes collection, 1653-1710; "The Duty of the
                    Principal Officers of his Majesties Navy Joyntly Considered," 1646; "The
                    Office of the Admiralty of England," n.d. William Penn, 1644-1718. Papers,
                    1654-1735: correspondence, 1654-1855, includes family letters, official
                    correspondence with Admiral William Penn, Hannah Penn, James Logan, Harbert
                    Springett, Thomas Bishop Vickris, John Barclay, J. Freame, and others; letters
                    to and from John, Thomas, and Richard Penn, on Irish immigration, books,
                    education, epidemics; printing account with Benjamin Franklin; drafts, naval
                    accounts, household accounts, land records. William Penn letter books,
                    1667-1675, 1699-1701, contain conciliatory letter to his father; diary of a
                    journey through Kent, Sussex, and Surrey, 1672; narratives of his trial and
                    committal to the Tower; letters to the King, Friends, governors, Lords of the
                    Admiralty, Lords of Trade and Plantations. Domestic and miscellaneous letters,
                    1682-1794, contains letters of William Penn to Hannah Callowhill, and members of
                    Pennsylvania Council, 1684-1694; letters of James Logan, to William Aubrey,
                    1703-1735. Penn manuscripts, 1680-1715, contains last will and testament of
                    William Penn, with codicil in his hand, 1705, 1706; original draft of grant of
                    Province of Pennsylvania, with corrections in his hand, 1680; William Penn to
                    Archbishop Tillotson, 1691; to Robert Turner, 1693; to Lord Romney, 1701; to
                    Samuel Pepys, 1670; commission to William Markham, 1697; "The Case of William
                    Penn," "State of efforts of Crown to regain control of Pennsylvania in Queen
                    Anne's reign," "Act of Pennsylvania vesting proprietary estates in
                    Commonwealth," and other items. Penn's letter to the Free Society of Traders,
                    1683; Irish journal, 1669-1670; "An account of My Journey into Holland and
                    Germany," 1677, includes letters to the King of Poland, Anna Maria de Horn
                    (Countess of Horn), essay; William Penn receipt book, interest on loans,
                    1710-1728; William and Hannah Penn journal, 1710-1726; Hannah Penn cash book,
                    1712-1720. Records of the proprietary government, 1629-1828: papers on the three
                    lower counties, 1629-1774; Penn's deeds, 1639-1759, 1760-1801; leases and
                    mortgages, 1670-1771; governor's proclamations, 1670-1775; county court records,
                    town and county of Deale, 1681-1709; autograph petitions, 1681-1716; receipts
                    for beaver skins for tenure, 1752-1780; addresses to William Penn by Trade
                    Society; petition to Lord Baltimore; petitions from Berks, Bucks, and Chester
                    counties in favor of proprietary government; Pennsylvania land grants,
                    1681-1806; Assembly of Provincial Council of Pennsylvania, 1682-1874; the laws
                    of Pennsylvania, 1682-1688; Pennsylvania charters, Frame of Government, with
                    revised forms, 1683-1696, and marriage settlement and will of Thomas Penn,
                    1751-1774. Official correspondence, 1683-1817: letters from James Logan to John
                    Penn and Hannah Penn, Lord Baltimore, William Penn, Governor Andrew Hamilton,
                    Isaac Norris, W. Popple, Colonel Benjamin Fletcher, on Pennsylvania boundaries,
                    acts for regulating trade, efforts to make Pennsylvania a crown colony, piracy
                    and smuggling, decline in public morals, copper mine beyond Susquehanna,
                    Keith-Logan controversy, Indian treaties, Conrad Weiser's address to the
                    Germans, factions in politics, paper money, yellow fever, Ohio Company, Nicholas
                    Scull, Edward Shippen, George Croghan, Connecticut intrusion, battle of
                    Lexington. Philadelphia land grants, Episcopal church, Society of Friends,
                    University Island in Delaware, 1684-1772; warrants and surveys, 1684-1776;
                    Connecticut claims, 1684-1799; Planter's Speech to his Neighbors and Countrymen
                    of Pennsylvania, East and West Jersey; Indian affairs, 1687-1801, contain
                    information to Thomas Dongan, governor and vice admiral of New York, on invasion
                    of Indians of the Five Nations, 1787; Governor Logan's speech to Sassoonan,
                    1731; negotiations with Six Nations; data on German Palatines, Conrad Weiser,
                    Richard Peters, Sir William Johnson, Albany Congress, Connecticut purchase,
                    Delaware controversy; George Croghan's account of Indian affairs, 1748-1749, to
                    Braddock's defeat; maps and documents on Indian Walk; Governor John Blackwell
                    manuscripts, 1689-1690; and acts of assembly, 1700-1763. Pennsylvania cash
                    accounts, 1701-1778: Pennsylvania journals, 1701-1779, contain accounts of
                    lands, quitrents; James Logan receipt book, 1702-1709, papers relating to iron,
                    peltries, trade, 1712-1817; bonds and powers of attorney, 1714-1828;
                    "Supplementary Saunders Coates," 1720-1766, chiefly Thomas Penn letters to
                    Richard Peters, on administrative affairs; Pennsylvania Assembly messages,
                    1727-1771; Wyoming controversy papers, 1731-1775, and William Smith and William
                    Moore v. Assembly, 1758-1759; account of quitrents, 1742; accounts of land in
                    Chester County called "William Penn's Manor," 1747-1750; warrants to affix the
                    great seal, 1749-1775; accounts, provincial tax for Philadelphia, 1759-1768;
                    William Baker letter book, 1769-1789; John Mifflin letter book, 1788-1802;
                    receipt book (of Philip Syng), provincial tax, 1759-1770; proprietary manors and
                    lands in Pennsylvania, n.d. Penn family. Papers, 1606-1834: Pennsylvania
                    miscellaneous papers, Penn v. Baltimore, Penn family, 1606-1834; wills of
                    Harbert Springett and Anthony Springett, 1682-1721; letters of the Penn family
                    to James Logan, 1701-1730; additional miscellaneous letters and
                    Penn-Engert-Lewis papers, 1683-1872; letters of the Penn family, 1654-1775;
                    papers relating to Penn family title, 1712-1726; "Family Deeds," 1718-1787,
                    contain items relating to Hannah Penn, agreements of Thomas and Richard Penn;
                    Thomas Penn private letters, 1738-1741; Penn-Hamilton correspondence, 1748-1770;
                    letters from Thomas and Richard Penn to James Hamilton; marriage settlement of
                    Thomas Penn, 1751; account book of money due Thomas Penn from T. Asheton, Joseph
                    Yeates, W. Peters, Sir William Johnson, et al., 1758-1769; Penn-Justice
                    manuscripts, 1769-1804, relate to land warrants, surveys, financial accounts
                    with the Penns, political and domestic affairs; John Penn's commonplace book,
                    ca. 1785-1787; Penn letter books, 1789-1834, proprietaries' correspondence
                    relating to Pennsylvania political and domestic affairs; litigation papers,
                    1672-1764; Penn-Physick papers, 1676-1804; Sir William Penn papers, 1644-1710;
                    and records of the proprietary government. Penn-Baltimore boundary dispute
                    papers, 1606-1775: Penn vs. Baltimore, 1606-1774; New York records, 1664-1679;
                    Kent County records, 1675-1683. "Boundaries Pennsylvania and Maryland,
                    1680-1768, Boundaries Virginia and Pennsylvania," 1773-1775, contains the
                    answer of William Penn to Lord Baltimore, 1683; George Talbot to all persons on
                    West of Delaware between Schuylkill and Whorekill; petition of Lord Baltimore to
                    George II, 1753; letters to Charles Mason and Jeremiah Dixon, 1765; petition of
                    all proprietors concerning southern and western boundaries, 1775; "Lands on
                    Delaware Bay," 1683; controversy between Lord Baltimore and Penn, 1683; address
                    to the King from Penn about Charter, 1693; accounts miscellaneous, 1723-1760;
                    boundaries of Delaware and Maryland, 1732-1733; report of commissioners,
                    1733-1734; "Drafting the new bill," 1735; petition, 1735; decree, 1735, 1750;
                    Lord Baltimore's answer, 1737, 1740; drafts of interrogatories, 1739;
                    depositions, Philadelphia, 1740; "Relating to particular points in case,"
                    1743; brief for the plaintiff, 1747; brief for the amended bill, 1749; brief of
                    the original bill against Frederick, Lord Baltimore, 1754; bill of revivor,
                    brief for plaintiff, 1754; draft of bill of revivor, 1754; acts of assembly,
                    1756, 1759, 1760; drafts of the agreement with Lord Baltimore, 1757-1760; bill
                    of reviver and supplemental bill, 1764. Penn-Physick papers, 1676-1804: land
                    grants and surveys, 1676-1801; extracts from patent books and list of land
                    warrants; bonds, surveys, powers of attorney, 1681-1806; correspondence,
                    1682-1803; Penn accounts, 1683-1770; accounts of quitrents, 1701; accounts,
                    1701-1804; extracts from ledgers and journals, 1701, 1763; returns of warrants
                    and surveys, 1732-1804; journal, 1742-1772; warrants to affix the great seal,
                    1767-1776; account books, 1769-1800; letter book, 1769-1804; journal, 1779-1801;
                    and additional warrants to affix the great seal to certificates of land patents,
                    sheriff's commission, pardons. Miscellaneous litigations and papers, 1672-1764:
                    miscellaneous litigations: Ford vs. Penn accounts, 1672-1694, plea of the
                    defendants, 1682-1727; Ford vs. Penn, Penn vs. Beranger, 1674-1716; Ford vs.
                    Penn, 1705-1707; law suits, 1713-1869; Penn vs. Penn, 1722-1727, contains bill
                    of complaint of Hannah Penn, et al., against Aubrey Thomas and Gulielma Maria,
                    his wife, answer of Springett Penn, interrogations, depositions. Other items:
                    letters of William Penn, 1681-1692; records of Sussex County, 1681-1710; an act
                    of Parliament, 1697; maps and surveys, Mason and Dixon Line, 1701-1705; Eastburn
                    map of Indian Walk, 1757; original warrant signed by William Penn ordering Isaac
                    Taylor and Thomas Pierson to survey line between County of Chester and County of
                    New Castle, 1701; certificate signed by Isaac Taylor and Thomas Pierson, with
                    map, "The Figure of the Circular Line Dividing between the County of New Castle
                    and County of Chester, 1701;" merchants account books (Bristol, Eng.), 1717;
                    map of part of the estate of William Penn in the Barony of Imokilly, 1764;
                    proprietary manors and lands in Pennsylvania of John Penn, Jr., and John Penn,
                    including maps; and other material. Letters of William Penn, 1681-1692
                    manuscript copies by J. Francis Fisher, 1840.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>