<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Transportation collection <date type="inclusive">1903-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Transportation collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC648</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1903-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Prior to 1913 the City of Philadelphia's relations with public transit companies
                    were administered through the offices of the City Surveyor and the Bureau of
                    Highways under the general supervision of Councils' Committee on Street
                    Railroads. In that year, under an Act approved on 9 May 1913, the Department of
                    City Transit was established to coordinate the control of all transit facilities
                    located within the City with especial regard to the contract of 1907 between the
                    City and the Philadelphia Rapid Transit Company formed in that year as an
                    amalgamation of the many transit companies that had existed independently until
                    that time.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists largely of printed materials created by Philadelphia
                    Rapid Transit (PRT), which in 1940 became the Philadelphia Transportation
                    Company (PTC), with some later materials from SEPTA, into which PTC merged in
                    1968. Additionally, there are some original company records, including accident
                    reports, scattered employee records, photographs, and a handful of office files.
                    There is also a small amount of correspondence and several publications of the
                    Metropolitan Philadelphia Railway Association. Materials in the collection
                    include: PTC Annual Reports, 1903-1969 (lacking 1939 and 1968); Rules and
                    Instructions for Transportation employees, 1924, 1925, 1944, 1949, 1953; PTC
                    Agreements with the Transportation Workers Union of America, 1944, 1945, 1947,
                    1950, and with the PRT Employees' Union, 1944; Department of City Transit
                    Contracts, 1924-1931; plans and revised plans of reorganization, 1934-1938;
                    notices to Stockholders relating to reorganizations, 1938 &amp; 1966; PTC
                    Accident Registers for 1952, 1953, and 1954; PRT Traffic Survey of 1923;
                    operations manuals, rules for employees, and other publications and forms for
                    employees. Office files in the collection include reports, notices of fare
                    changes, student exams, employee records, accident reports on the trolley lines,
                    forms, and "spook reports," which documented employee misbehavior as observed
                    by company spies. Other materials include: a copy of an agreement between PTC
                    and SEPTA, 1968; by-laws; agreements and leases; traction programs; reports;
                    programs for the annual company picnic at Willow Grove Park, photographs;
                    telephone directories; public notices (many oversized); some blueprints;
                    promotional publications of the PTC; and 16 binders of transfer coupons from the
                    1920s through the 1960s. Printed materials in the collection include: PTC,
                    "Off-Peak" (1943-1944); PTC, "PTC News" (1949-1957), The PRT Traveler, and
                    numerous brochures published for riders, route schedules, maps, unused books of
                    transfers, and used transpasses other publications. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: donated by David and Barbara Brody</p>
                <p>Accession number: 2004.037</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>