<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia cemetery histories collection <date type="inclusive">1920-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia cemetery histories collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2267</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1920-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of research materials related to various cemeteries,
                    particularly in the Philadelphia area. Cemeteries include Laurel Hill,
                    Lafayette, Woodlands, burial ground of First Reformed Church, Upper Burying
                    Ground in Germantown, Christ Church burial ground, Bensalem cemetery (transfers
                    from Lafayette), Bellevue Cemetery, Fourth Reformed Church in Manyunk, Friends'
                    Burial Ground at Fair Hill, Philanthropic Cemetery, Palmer Street Cemetery, and
                    Ronaldson Cemetery. There is also information on a veterans' cemetery in Bucks
                    County and colonial graves in Independence Mall. Research materials are mainly
                    clippings and photocopies from newspaper articles and books. There is also a
                    typewritten history of Oddfellows Cemetery, a 1974 address by Edwin S. Dunkerley
                    on Philadelphia cemeteries that was given at a meeting of GSP, and photographs
                    and negatives of American Mechanics Cemetery.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>