<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Richardson Dilworth papers <date type="inclusive">1881-1991</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1943-1991</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Richardson Dilworth papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC639</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1991</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1943-1991</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Richardson Dilworth (1898-1974), was an American Democratic Party politician,
                    born in the Pittsburgh area, who served as the 116th Mayor of Philadelphia,
                    Pennsylvania from January 2, 1956 until his resignation in 1962 to run for
                    Governor, a race in which he was defeated by William Scranton. Along with Joseph
                    S. Clark and others, he was at the forefront of a post-World War II reform
                    movement in Philadelphia which led to the adoption of a modern city charter that
                    consolidated city and county offices and introduced civil service examinations
                    on a broad scale to replace much of the existing patronage structure. During
                    their tenures as mayor, Clark and Dilworth introduced a variety of reforms and
                    innovations, including extensive high-rise public housing which, a generation
                    later, was condemned by many as a breeding ground for poverty and crime.
                    However, they also greatly strengthened the city planning function of
                    Philadelphia city government. Both retained Edmund Bacon as Executive Director
                    of the Philadelphia City Planning Commission, and this era is recognized as a
                    high water mark for planning, the era when Center City Philadelphia's future as
                    a commercial and residential center was rescued from decline. Dilworth's
                    Administration made a priority of saving the city's historic and irreplaceable
                    Society Hill district. Following his tenure as Mayor, he served as Partner in
                    the Philadelphia-based law firm of Dilworth Paxson LLP, which bears his name. He
                    also served as president of the Philadelphia school board, and in 1971 was
                    appointed one of two bankruptcy trustees (along with Andrew L. Lewis, Jr.) for
                    the Reading Company, the railroad company headquartered in Philadelphia.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Richardson Dilworth. Materials include:
                    alphabetical subject files; public statements; files related to jury cases, jury
                    charges, and law cases; subject files of Dilworth, mainly from the "Ps" --
                    Prisons, Playgrounds, Police, and the Port of Philadelphia.; subject files
                    including extensive correspondence and files on City planning, housing, the fire
                    department, and "City Issues”. Other materials include: notes and short letters
                    from Richardson Dilworth to his wife, Ann; check stub book from 12/30/1968 to
                    11/7/69; 5"x7" black and white photograph of Richardson with two women just
                    after deplaning (one is probably his wife Ann); photographs of Richardson
                    Dilworth, including 6 originals and about 115 copy prints (some duplicates).
                    There is also a small file of clippings about his daughter Deborah, and several
                    about Dilworth. The collection also includes: several folders of Dilworth's
                    correspondence with friends, 1944-1974, typescripts of speeches by Dilworth,
                    1947-1951; undated negatives; letter and photograph about the Dilworth Memorial
                    in Dilworth Plaza, 1985; papers related to the naming and dedication of the
                    Richardson Dilworth International Terminal at Philadelphia International
                    Airport; a typed copy of a Marine Corps citation given to Dilworth "for
                    gallantry and intrepidity in action" in 1943; and an album of photographs
                    documenting The Philadelphia Award dinner, April 15, 1968. Scrapbooks and photo
                    albums include: a Richardson Dilworth memorial scrapbook (1974), Dilworth's
                    student and war scrapbook (ca. 1915-1926), Lees family photographs, (ca. 1960),
                    Dilworth memorials (1974), social events scrapbook (1881-1946), and "G.S.P.
                    photo album (ca. 1925). </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2003.052; 2003.053; 2003.068; 2003.069; 2003.124; 2004.017;
                    2004.033; 2004.102; 010718.5</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>