<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Shoemaker family papers and genealogical research materials <date type="inclusive">1800-1986</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Shoemaker family papers and genealogical research
                    materials</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2204</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1800-1986</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of original records and genealogical research materials
                    related to the Shoemaker family. There are a number of records related to
                    Benjamin H. Shoemaker's (I and II) glass business, including financial records,
                    legal records, property records, product information and catalogs, publicity
                    materials and letterhead. Other materials include: an 1847 notebook by Benjamin
                    H. Shoemaker, 2nd, on Gummere's surveying; family photographs, as well as
                    photographs of ships and other subjects; property records; some family letters
                    and personal financial records; research materials related to the supplement to
                    Shoemaker Pioneers, a published family history; newspaper clippings about
                    various Shoemakers; genealogical research, including correspondence and a copy
                    of Thomas B. Shoemaker's family history with later research notes;
                    correspondence relating to a family history of the Shoemaker family of
                    Germantown and Philadelphia; and maps of Bermuda, the Netherlands, Belgium and
                    Luxembourg.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>