<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Society collection--miscellaneous <date type="inclusive">1676-1937</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Society collection--miscellaneous</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2019</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>17.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1676-1937</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is an artificial collection created by HSP staff, containing manuscript
                    materials from many sources.The collection contains a range of papers, organized
                    by topic, that document a variety of aspects of American life--from finance to
                    slavery, from music to war. Subjects documented include colonial and early
                    republic Philadelphia government, business, and associations, churches, schools
                    and colleges, libraries, watermarks, sanitation, the Whiskey Rebellion, the
                    Mexican War, the War of 1812 and the Civil War, American Indians, slavery and
                    manumission. Documents include correspondence, military papers such as muster
                    rolls, petitions, transportation-related articles such as tickets and passports,
                    leases and deeds, bonds, stock certificates, receipt books, legal papers,
                    broadsides, and musical scores. Also included are several envelopes of 18th and
                    19th century currency. A few documents are in French and Dutch and there are
                    some photostats, photocopies, and facsimiles in lieu of original documents.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>