<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>The Lighthouse records <date type="inclusive">1908-1947</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">The Lighthouse records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC665</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1908-1947</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>During its century-long history, the Lighthouse, located in the Kensington
                    section of Philadelphia, has served as a settlement house, benevolent
                    organization, library, nursery, restaurant, and recreation center. The origins
                    of the Lighthouse began in 1893 with Esther Kelly using two rooms at Episcopal
                    Hospital in Kensington twice a week to conduct Bible classes. Kelly had more in
                    mind than teaching the Bible, for her primary concern was to provide an
                    alternative to the saloons. The Lighthouse soon focused much of its attention
                    toward social clubs and recreation. By the opening decades of the twentieth
                    century, the Lighthouse was operating successful clubs for boys, girls, men, and
                    women. The boys and girls clubs in particular flourished until the 1990s when
                    enrollment declined. Since its inception, the Lighthouse has adapted to the
                    changing needs of the community it serves and continues to provide recreational
                    and social services for the neighborhood.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains three boxes of membership cards for men, women and
                    couples. Information provided on the cards includes name, date of birth, spouse,
                    children, address, church affiliations, nationality/ethnicity, and trade. Most
                    include case histories that detail a person's interactions with the
                    organization, which provide insight into social and working conditions of the
                    time.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2005.105</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>