<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>USS clubs and rest houses for Merchant Marines scrapbook collection
                            <date type="inclusive">1942-1945</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">USS clubs and rest houses for Merchant Marines scrapbook
                    collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2006</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1942-1945</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of scrapbooks of clubs and other facilities set up for
                    the relief of merchant marines during World War II. Most of the material appears
                    to deal with the Oyster Bay (Long Island) New York area. Two of the scrapbooks
                    were compiled by the Mohannes Girls Volunteer Committee and contain autographed
                    photos of the merchant marines who stayed at their club. Some of the
                    inscriptions note the seamen's favorite memories of their stay. The giant-sized
                    scrapbook is of news clippings, most of which were provided by a news clipping
                    service for the USS (United Seamen's Service), regarding the various clubs and
                    homes established for the seamen, profiling their war service and the activities
                    provided by the clubs. A red leather scrapbook contains snapshots chronicling
                    the everyday life and duties aboard a merchant ship and various candid shots of
                    the men on board and in what appear to be some of the relief clubs on shore.
                    Also in this collection are 11 mounted portraits of merchant seaman, each
                    identified by their first name.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>