<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wannemacher family photo albums <date type="inclusive">1907-1937</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1913-1922</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wannemacher family photo albums</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2032</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1907-1937</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1913-1922</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>These 10 photo albums document the social and political lives of the Wannemacher
                    family and other young Philadelphians in the 1910s and 1920s. At least some of
                    the Wannemachers were Socialists involved with the Socialist Sunday School (24th
                    and 27th wards) and the Young People's Socialist League. Their picnics and other
                    excursions are documented. There is a picture of Eugene V. Debs and another of
                    the Socialist Book Store, 1326 Arch St., Philadelphia. The other major aspect of
                    this collection is the documentation of various family trips to the Jersey
                    Shore, New York City, Niagara, Wisconsin, and New England, where the family
                    visited the homes and graves of Emerson, Thoreau, Alcott, and Hawthorne. They
                    also traveled around Pennsylvania a great deal, to Harrisburg, Delaware Water
                    Gap, Graterford, Wissahickon, Perkiomen, Media, Arden, and other places. Also of
                    note are a handful of pictures of Philadelphia on Armistice Day. Some albums
                    focused on the childhood of Margaret Wannemacher.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>