<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Warren S. Ely collection <date type="inclusive">1895-1958</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Warren S. Ely collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2132</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>26.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1895-1958</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Warren S. Ely lived in Doulestown, Pennsylvania. He was the Librarian of the
                    Bucks County Historical Society.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists primarily of genealogical research conducted by Ely and
                    his wife. There is also documentation related to the Ely’s activities with the
                    Bucks County Historical Society and the Daughters of the American Revolution.
                    Genealogical materials include: research on various families, many in Bucks
                    County, containing family charts, extensive handwritten notes, correspondence,
                    reports and some narrative family histories; research materials related to the
                    descendants of Joshua Ely, consisting of original documents and copies and
                    extracts of original documents, notes, and family charts, as well as one
                    photograph; photocopies of genealogical queries in a Hartford, Connecticut
                    newspaper, 1936-1941. (name of the newspaper is not specified); research done
                    for the DAR on Bucks County Revolutionary War soldiers; notebooks of
                    genealogical research; and extensive correspondence with Gilbert Cope, William
                    Wallace, B. F. Fackenthal, and others related to genealogical topics. There is
                    also correspondence, receipts, reports related to Ely’s work as the Bucks County
                    Historical Society Librarian, as well as research files on local history topics.
                    There is one scrapbook featuring newspaper clippings with illustrations of
                    people, ships, and other topics (many humorous) that includes some extracts from
                    primary sources in the back.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>