<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>World War II collection <date type="inclusive">1938-1949</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">World War II collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2412</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>65 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1938-1949</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Organized in three series. The first section consists of correspondence,
                    pamphlets, press releases, photographs, and posters presented by volunteer and
                    community organizations. Included are: America First Committee, Philadelphia
                    chapter, releases, pamphlets, correspondence, and ephemera, 1939-1941; Committee
                    to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, Conyers Read, Philadelphia chairman,
                    correspondence, 1939-1941; Fight for Freedom Committee, Philadelphia chapter,
                    correspondence, 1939-1941; and a number of smaller groups of materials
                    representing, for example, the Anti-defamation League, the American Palestine
                    Committee, Fellowship House of Philadelphia, the American Friends Service
                    Committee, the Friends of the Spanish Republic, and several Afro-American,
                    German-American, and Italian-American organizations. The second section consists
                    of press releases and speeches prepared or distributed by the Office of War
                    Information, 1942-1944. Much concerns agreements achieved by the Office of Price
                    Administration and is arranged by product groups. The third section contains the
                    records of the United Service Organization of Philadelphia, an organization
                    offering recreation and assistance to members of the armed forces and their
                    families. The Philadelphia United Service Organization was the result of a 1941
                    cooperative agreement among the Jewish Welfare Board, the Y.M.C.A., the
                    Y.W.C.A., the Salvation Army, Travelers' Aid, and the National Catholic
                    Commission Services. The section includes: administrative and financial records
                    of the United Service Organization Council, 1941-1947; Stagedoor Canteen,
                    administrative and operational records, statistical records, programs, and
                    photographs, 1942-1947; Jewish Welfare Board, minutes, correspondence, and
                    financial records, 1941-1948; Labor Plaza, minutes and committee reports for
                    this facility providing outdoor entertainment for servicemen and women,
                    1943-1946; subsidiary organizations operated by the United Service Organization,
                    reports and receipts, 1942-1947; and letters written in answer to those sent by
                    a letter-writing group at St. Mark's Church in Philadelphia, 1943-1945. In late
                    1942 the Historical Society of Pennsylvania solicited materials to form an
                    artificial collection which would document the war effort of a number of
                    community and social service agencies. The result is a miscellaneous and uneven
                    group of papers presented over a number of years by the organizations and their
                    officers.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>