<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>World War II graphics collection <date type="inclusive">1939-1946</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>The Historical Society of Pennsylvania</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">World War II graphics collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">THSSp.ACC2037</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">The Historical Society of Pennsylvania<address>
                        <addressline>1300 Locust Street</addressline>
                        <addressline>Philadelphia, PA 19107</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1939-1946</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p/>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection mostly consists of World War II posters from a variety of
                    governmental and nongovernmental agencies. These include recruiting posters from
                    the U.S. Coast Guard, Coast Guard Women's Reserve ("Spars"), Marine Corps,
                    Marine Corps Women's Reserve, Army, Navy, WAVES, Air Corps, and Seabees; war
                    bond posters from the Victory Fund Committee and other agencies; U.S. Civil
                    Service Commission recruitment posters targeting women and men; Office of War
                    Information warnings against spreading rumors or giving information to the
                    enemy; prints of Norman Rockwell paintings illustrating Franklin Roosevelt's
                    "Four Freedoms"; and wartime posters from the Railroad Manpower Mobilization
                    Committee, War Food Administration, Federal Housing Administration, Social
                    Security Board, U.S. Employment Service, Internal Revenue Service, Veterans of
                    Foreign Wars, Boy Scouts of America, Children's Bureau Commission on Children in
                    Wartime, and private companies such as F. W. Woolworth. Also includes a few
                    British war propaganda posters, posters warning against forest fires, and a
                    series of Esso ads featuring "Famous gremlins you should know." Also include
                    World War II-era Christmas cards, magazine ads for war bonds, booklets from the
                    U.S. Army Ordnance Department, magazine pages explaining U.S. military insignia,
                    Pennsylvania Civil Service Commission circulars, part of a 1943 calendar with
                    illustrations by cartoonist Bill Eddy, and other materials.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>