<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Exhibits Department
                        records <date type="inclusive">1852-2001</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1929-2001</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Exhibits
                    Department records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC093</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>49.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1852-2001</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1929-2001</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia was founded in 1812 "for the
                    encouragement and cultivation of the sciences, and the advancement of useful
                    learning." Its collections, acquired through expeditions, gifts, purchases, and
                    exchanges, contain over 17,000,000 specimens. The Academy opened its doors to
                    the public in 1828, growing so rapidly that it outgrew its building three times
                    in sixty years. In 1876, its present home was built at 19th and Benjamin
                    Franklin Parkway, where its permanent exhibits include Dinosaur Hall, and more
                    than 35 dioramas presenting wildlife from Africa, Asia and North America. The
                    Academy also presents changing exhibits and online exhibits.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records related to exhibits at the Academy of Natural
                    Sciences. The records consists primarily of the working files of members of the
                    Exhibits department, including Sean Duran, Harold T. Green, Hollister Knowlton,
                    and Keith Russell. Materials include: correspondence; minutes; proposals; bids
                    and contracts; schedules and staff time sheets; floor plans; sketches of exhibit
                    spaces, subjects, and backgrounds; panel text; specimen acquisition and loan
                    information; photos, negatives, and slides of construction of exhibits, of
                    finished exhibits, and of living animals in their habitats; subject files on
                    materials, artists, other natural history exhibitions. Much the material in this
                    collection relates to the remodeling of Dinosaur Hall and the Discovering
                    Dinosaurs exhibit. The collection also includes: surveys and assessments of the
                    Academy's dioramas and of natural history museums (1936 and 2001); plans and
                    rolled blueprints for construction of Earth Sciences exhibit 1990-1991; photos
                    from the Earth Science Hall (pre-1975); records and photos relating to the
                    fulgerite specimen that had once been on display (now damaged); materials
                    relating to the Deinonyclus sculpture in front of the Academy; brass wall
                    plaques and exhibit signs and labels; field photos; and drawings of specimens
                    and exhibits. Among the Harold T. Green papers, there is a significant amount of
                    documentation of various expeditions, including the Carpenter African expedition
                    of 1955, and the Carpenter Arabian expedition of 1953, the Vanderbilt Africa
                    expedition of 1930, and others. These materials include photographs, equipment
                    lists, bills and receipts,correspondence, and bullets retrieved from specimens.
                    There are also several artifacts that probably belonged to Green, including a
                    pipe and ashtray and a ceramic box. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 02:18; 02:15; 99:08; 98:10; 95:11; 97:02; 02:13; 93:09; 00:11;
                    01:14; 91:02</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Habitat Groups records (collections 717, 718, 719),
                    ANSP. Exhibits papers (collection 256) and Robert Peck papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>