<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Managing Director
                        records <date type="inclusive">1933-1939</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Managing
                    Director records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC095</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>21.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1933-1939</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles Meigs Biddle Cadwalader (1885-1959) was an important figure at the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences. He was elected a life member of the Academy in
                    1908. He became a trustee in 1927 and remained on the board until his death. In
                    1928 he was named Managing Director, and in 1937 was appointed President,
                    retiring from that position in 1951. During his tenure, the Academy conducted
                    more than 100 scientific expeditions, and visitor attendance at the Academy
                    increased by more than 450 percent. In 1935 he was awarded the Philadelphia
                    (Bok) award.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of incoming and outgoing correspondence of Charles M.B.
                    Cadwalader, dating from 1933 to 1939. Much of the correspondence relates to the
                    acquisition of specimens, donations, estates and annuities, publications, and
                    other Academy business. There is also a significant amount of correspondence
                    with scientists on Academy expeditions, including Brook Dolan, M.A. Carriker,
                    J.A.G. Rehn, Rodolphe Meyer de Schauensee, Harold T. Green, R.R.M. Carpenter,
                    and others. Notable are two letters from Ernest Hemingway, discussing his
                    fishing exploits for Academy ichthyologist Henry Fowler, and other matters. The
                    collection also includes copies of outgoing correspondence from the heads of
                    various Academy departments.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 02:22</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>