<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Vertebrate Biology
                        Department records <date type="inclusive">1936-1972</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Vertebrate
                    Biology Department records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1082</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1972</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia was founded in 1812 "for the
                    encouragement and cultivation of the sciences, and the advancement of useful
                    learning." Its collections, acquired through expeditions, gifts, purchases, and
                    exchanges, contain over 17,000,000 specimens. The Department of Vertebrate
                    Zoology is a section within the Center for Systematic Biology and Evolution.
                    Included among the specimens maintained by the department is the Herpetology
                    Collection, which is one of the most biologically diverse collections of its
                    kind, with more than 500 named forms and many primary types.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a small collection of records related to snake, amphibian, and reptile
                    specimens in the Vertebrate Biology Department of the Academy of Natural
                    Sciences, 1936-1972. Included are: lists of specimens, some with dates,
                    locations, and collectors; and a field catalog of amphibians and reptiles
                    collected by Thomas Uzzell, in 1972 and 1973, in Mexico, Guatemala, and
                    Honduras. The collection also includes two completed internal questionnaires for
                    curators at the Academy dating from 1968.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 93:01</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>