<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Development Office
                        records <date type="inclusive">1967-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Development
                    Office records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1058</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>18 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia was founded in 1812 "for the
                    encouragement and cultivation of the sciences, and the advancement of useful
                    learning." The work of the Academy is funded by grants and contracts, state
                    appropriations, contributions, bequests, endowments, museum admissions and
                    museum shop income. The Development Department works to acquire funding for the
                    Academy through grants, donations, and special events. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records from the Academy's Development Department,
                    including records of Honor Fox, Ray Slater, Louis Sage, and Cynthia Jones
                    Eiseman. Materials include: correspondence, grant proposals and reports, appeal
                    letters, records related to city and state appropriations, Development Committee
                    minutes, strategic planning documents, monthly activity reports (1986-1989), and
                    printed promotional materials for the Academy. Also includes diskettes of files
                    kept by Honor Fox, audio cassettes of radio spots for Discovering Dinosaurs,
                    slides of educational programs, and a video of the 180th Annual Meeting.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 92:04; 96:07; 92:05</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>