<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Malacology Department
                        records <date type="inclusive">1849-1983</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Malacology
                    Department records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC019</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1849-1983</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The collection of recent mollusks at The Academy of Natural Sciences of
                    Philadelphia is the oldest in the country, and the second largest catalogued one
                    in the world. It currently has more than 430,000 catalogued lots containing
                    about 12 million specimens, including 30,000-35,000 lots preserved in ethanol.
                    Type specimens of more than 400 authors are represented in more than 12,000 type
                    lots. The Academy has specimens from all over the world. Greatest strengths are
                    in shallow-water marine mollusks from the tropical Indo-Pacific and the Western
                    Atlantic and worldwide freshwater and land mollusks. The staff of the department
                    maintain this collection and conduct research.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials related to the Malacology Department of the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. Materials include Robert
                    Robertson's correspondence 1953-1983, arranged by correspondent; correspondence,
                    reprints, and bulletins kept by various other members of the Department of
                    Malacology, including George Davis, Horace Richards, Earl A. Shapiro, Robert
                    Robertson, and Gary Rosenberg; miscellaneous correspondence and records related
                    to specimens (1939-1976). The collection also includes catalogs and records of
                    the specimen collections, including materials related to the collections of Olaf
                    Oswald, John H. Redfield, H.A. Pilsbry, E.D. Cope, and R.E. Griffith; a volume
                    listing donations to the Academy's conchological section (1867-1874); Department
                    of Geology and Paleontology reports (1957-1972), a list of the publications of
                    Earl Spamer; and glass plate negatives for the Manual of Conchology, Volumes 1,
                    2, and 7, published between 1879 and 1885. The collection also includes 18
                    rolled wall charts of mollusks, circa 1930s.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 00:23</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Geology
                    and Paleontology Department records, George Davis papers, Robert Robertson
                    papers, Horace G. Richards papers, and Edward G. Vanatta papers (subscription
                    ledger for Conchology publications).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>