<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Education Department
                        records <date type="inclusive">1935-2004</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960s-1990s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Education
                    Department records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1008</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>84 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1935-2004</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960s-1990s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia was founded in 1812 "for the
                    encouragement and cultivation of the sciences, and the advancement of useful
                    learning." The Education Department conducts field trips and workshops, creates
                    teacher resources on natural history topics, and runs special programs for a
                    variety of audiences. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Education Department of the Academy of
                    Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. The bulk of the records in the collection date
                    from the 1960s to the 1990s and include papers from the offices of James
                    McGonigle, Nancy Peter, and Colleen North. Administrative records include:
                    budgets, personnel and hiring records, attendance logs, phone logs, accident
                    reports, internal correspondence, department annual reports, and minutes from
                    various committees. Program and exhibit records include planning documents,
                    publicity, lesson plans, schedules, student enrollment sheets and surveys,
                    accessibility surveys, photographs of member trips, records of traveling
                    exhibits, and slides of several programs. Programs and activities documented by
                    the collection include WINS (Women in Natural Science), SEEC (Science Enrichment
                    Expansion Curriculum), SEUS (Science Enrichment for Underserved Students), Earth
                    Week, EcoShow on the Road, Action/Motivation, Potentials, Expeditions for
                    Everyone, and the Ludwick Lecture series. A smaller selection of papers date
                    from the 1930s to the 1950s; these include departmental annual reports,
                    brochures and announcements, and exhibit information.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 90:10; 97:11; 97:12; 97:13; 97:14; 97:15; 98:03; 02:19;
                    07:11</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>