<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Diatom Herbarium
                        records <date type="inclusive">1987-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Diatom
                    Herbarium records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC094</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1987-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Academy's Diatom Herbarium, one of the two largest in the world, is a primary
                    source of taxonomic and ecological information. It includes approximately
                    220,000 slides (curated and non-curated), of which about 5,000 are types.
                    Materials include both fossil and recent diatoms collected from fresh, brackish,
                    and marine habitats. The herbarium has a long history, with many specimens
                    dating from the 19th century or even earlier.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection relates to the Academy's original Diatom Herbarium database
                    created by consultant Hayden Rochester, and includes printouts of the keys to
                    the codes, abbreviations, geographic headings, collection name headings, and
                    other "database dictionaries" used in the database; printouts of duplicate
                    records and other data irregularities; a copy of a proposal for renewal of the
                    grant to fund the project; and tape backups of the database and SEM images
                    relating to NSF-funded research of curator Edward C. Theriot.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 02:20</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>