<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia buildings records <date type="inclusive">1898-1998</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960s- 1980s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia buildings
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1210</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1898-1998</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960s- 1980s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia was founded in 1812 "for the
                    encouragement and cultivation of the sciences, and the advancement of useful
                    learning." Its collections, acquired through expeditions, gifts, purchases, and
                    exchanges, contain over 17,000,000 specimens. The Academy opened its doors to
                    the public in 1828, growing so rapidly that it outgrew its building three times
                    in sixty years. In 1876, its present home was built at 19th and Benjamin
                    Franklin Parkway.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of architectural plans and papers related to the buildings
                    occupied by the Academy of Natural Sciences. Included are blueprints of the
                    Academy's 19th street complex and renovations, 1970s; schematic diagrams and
                    blueprints of Academy spaces, 1979-1981; files on 19th St. garden and Quarry
                    Street house, 1963; a framed print by Tom Jackson showing the Academy's 19th and
                    Race façade; 1979 plans for a projection booth; study reports for renovations to
                    Research Wing and the new 1990 wing adjacent to it; papers related to the sale
                    of a building on Fairmount; proposals for a biochemical laboratory; evaluations
                    of space; diagrams of the layout for some of the research collections that were
                    moved, circa 1980, to the research facility in the historic insurance building
                    at the other end of the Ben Franklin Parkway; plans for Academy buildings
                    proposed for the Penn's landing site, 1963; an architectural elevation of the
                    north side of the Race Street building showing proposed new roof, 1905; an
                    architectural elevation in watercolor of a low-rise building, possibly one
                    proposed for the Parkway, 1973; and a zoning notice from the City of
                    Philadelphia for the erection of the 1990 wing to house the new library
                    stacks.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 99:14; 00:07</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: ANSP Buildings and Grounds (collection 584 ).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>