<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Ornithology Department
                        records <date type="inclusive">1883-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Ornithology
                    Department records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC983</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11.1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1883-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Academy of Natural Sciences maintains an ornithological collection of nearly
                    200,000 study skins and 15,000 tissue samples. Of great historical importance,
                    specimens in the collection predate the founding of the Academy in 1812 and
                    include important early bird collections from such famous collectors as
                    Alexander Wilson, John Audubon, and John Gould. Staff of the department care for
                    and maintain the ornithology collection and conducts research on the
                    evolutionary biology of birds.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Ornithology Department of the Academy of
                    Natural Sciences. Records related to specimens in the collection include: 18
                    volumes of accession books of ornithological specimens (up to 1997) and eight
                    microfilm reels of the accession books (accession # 000001 to #175726); a record
                    book of specimens in the Maple Avenue collection (1889-1896); card files for
                    skeletons housed in Ornithology; specimen tags removed from specimens; records
                    of South American species, including a card file of specimens collected by M.A.
                    Carriker and Rodolphe Meyer de Schauensee; and field data sheets for specimens
                    collected in Washington, Oregon, California, and Peru during J. Peter Myer's
                    Shorebirds study. The Shorebirds study materials also include instructions for
                    collecting and preserving specimens. Material related to the Delaware Valley
                    Ornithological Club (DVOC) includes: a handwritten inventory of the DVOC
                    Collection donated to the Academy; Delaware Valley Birding Hotline files,
                    including transcripts of the hotline messages (1974-1977 and 1993),
                    correspondence, records of financial contributions to the hotline, and telephone
                    instructions; and correspondence between Frank Gill and the DVOC, 1962-1980,
                    much of it about the relationship between the two organizations. Other records
                    in the collection include news releases about the Pennsylvania Breeding Bird
                    Atlas project 1986-1987; correspondence of John Hawley Foster, 1952-1985, about
                    birding trips and Foster's financial support of Academy ornithology projects;
                    and lab notebooks from Frank Gill and Fred Sheldon, 1975-1992, containing notes
                    on their bird DNA studies.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 89:06; 93:02; 97:19; 99:05; 00:02; 01:15; 07:14</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Melbourne A. Carriker field notes, Delaware Valley
                    Ornithological Club records, Frank B. Gill papers, R. M. de Schauensee papers,
                    and C. Chandler Ross papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>