<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Women's Committee
                        records <date type="inclusive">1977-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Women's
                    Committee records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC303</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Women's Committee of the Academy of Natural Sciences. The purpose of the
                    committee is to further the aims of the Academy by undertaking projects or
                    programs which will stimulate public interest and help the activities of the
                    Academy.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection documents the activities of the Women's Committee of the Academy
                    of Natural Sciences from 1977 to 2004. Materials include: monthly meeting
                    minutes 1977-1987 and 1990-1999; budget information and records of donations;
                    special events planning materials, including schedules, correspondence, and
                    mailing lists; invitations, brochures and pamphlets; newspaper clippings;
                    Academy publications, including copies of the Academy News; and annual reports
                    of the Academy. The collection also includes audio, film (housed with the
                    Academy's A/V materials), photos, slides, and disks related to various special
                    events and development initiatives coordinated by the Women's Committee.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 07:05, 07:15</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Women's Committee records (collection 786) and
                    Development Office records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>