<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia ethnological
                        collections records <date type="inclusive">1976-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia ethnological
                    collections records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1939</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia was founded in 1812 "for the
                    encouragement and cultivation of the sciences, and the advancement of useful
                    learning." Its collections, acquired through expeditions, gifts, purchases, and
                    exchanges, contain over 17,000,000 specimens. In 1876, its present home was
                    built at 19th and Benjamin Franklin Parkway, where its permanent exhibits
                    include Dinosaur Hall, and more than 35 dioramas presenting wildlife from
                    Africa, Asia and North America. The Academy also presents changing exhibits and
                    online exhibits.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of information on mummies owned and exhibited by the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. Materials include typed
                    descriptions and sketches of exhibits; exhibit construction records, including a
                    budget and a description of the process of assembling the exhibit; reports on
                    cleaning and conservation; documents related to the loan of items from the
                    University Museum to the Academy, including insurance records, loan agreements,
                    and correspondence; newspaper clippings and articles (some present as
                    photocopies) about the mummy exhibit and about two unidentified mummies that
                    were found at the Academy in 1977; correspondence about the mystery mummies; a
                    list of mummy holdings of the Academy, including donor name and date; and film
                    negatives of decorations on a sarcophagus.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>