<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Library records <date type="inclusive">1837-2004</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1925-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Library
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1087</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>32.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1837-2004</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1925-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Academy of Natural Sciences Library and Archives were established at the
                    founding meeting of the Academy in 1812 to support the Academy's work. The
                    Academy Library is named in honor of Ewell Sale Stewart (1924-1987), a longtime
                    friend and benefactor. The Library is used by the staff of the Academy of
                    Natural Sciences, Academy members, scientists, historians, artists, graduate
                    students, corporations, and members of the public with advanced interests in the
                    natural world.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Library of the Academy of Natural
                    Sciences. Materials include: library correspondence (1925-1931); catalogues of
                    the Library's holdings, 1837; accession books. 1944-1968; acquisitions lists
                    1967-1995; mid-20th century registers of publication exchanges; minutes of the
                    Library Committee, 1937-1974; correspondence with and invoices from book
                    dealers; documents related to planning, moving the collection to the new stack
                    building, and other library projects; materials related to Library's involvement
                    in projects with the Philadelphia Area Consortium of Special Collections
                    Libraries (PACSCL) and The Associated Natural Science Institutions (TANSI);
                    correspondence and notes related to the guide to manuscript holdings created by
                    Venia Phillips; correspondence related to the publication of the guide to
                    microfilms; administrative records, including procedures, budgets, time sheets,
                    departmental activity reports, interlibrary loans, records of gifts, personnel
                    files, records of a 1966 binding survey; and reprints. This collection includes
                    papers from Carol Spawn, Janet Evans, Earle Spamer, Sylva S. Baker, Karen
                    Stevens, and William J. Fox. The collection also includes materials related to
                    Harold Shalit's survey of ornithology records in the archives.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 93:10; 97:20; 97:23; 00:12; 01:19; 02:02; 02:17; 03:02; </p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Collections 591, 434, 726 (History, Correspondence,
                    Policies), plus a number of other processed collections listed in the Manuscript
                    and Archives Guide.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>