<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia records related to
                        Richard Lamborn estate <date type="inclusive">1885-1929</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia records related
                    to Richard Lamborn estate</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1950</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1885-1929</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert Henry Lamborn (1835-1895) was a civil engineer, railroad magnate, realtor,
                    and financier. He was also an amateur naturalist. His interest in the Academy
                    dated from his childhood association with his uncle Jacob Peirce, who was once
                    its librarian. He was a well-known beekeeper and later a member of the Academy.
                    Lamborn willed his entire estate of more than a million dollars to the Academy
                    to be used for biological and anthropological purposes. The inheritance being
                    questioned by other heirs at law, a long legal battle ensued and eventually the
                    bequest was evenly divided between the Academy and the relatives. The assets
                    consisted, in part, of real property in various sections of the country, namely
                    Colorado, Montana, Minnesota, Michigan, Wisconsin, and Pennsylvania. The lands
                    were held for some years, gradually being sold and the income used for
                    research.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers related to the estate of Robert Henry Lamborn.
                    Papers include: correspondence between representatives of the Academy and realty
                    companies, lawyers, and others (1885-1929); invoices and receipts for rent,
                    maintenance on properties, and legal work; financial statements of the estate,
                    tax statements, and bank statements; indentures, land grants, leases, and copies
                    of wills; and blueprints, plans, and maps. This collection includes some
                    correspondence of George Vaux, Treasurer of the Academy from 1894 to 1927.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Treasurer
                    records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>