<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Mineralogy Department
                        records <date type="inclusive">1915-1988</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1970-1988</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Mineralogy
                    Department records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC090</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1915-1988</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1970-1988</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Not long after it opened in 1812, a cabinet of minerals was established at the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences. Several of the founders and early members of the
                    Academy assembled private mineral collections, some of which were later donated
                    to the Academy. The Mineralogical and Geological Section was established in 1877
                    and dissolved in 1924. One of the department's members was Samuel George Gordon,
                    who joined the Academy as a Jessup scholarship student and, over his career,
                    became one of the noted mineralogists of his day.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Department of Mineralogy of the Academy of
                    Natural Sciences. These records, from the office of Robert Middleton, John
                    Sherman, and others, include correspondence, memos, reports, documents related
                    to fundraising, lists of specimens in various collections, reprints, records of
                    exhibits, records of loans, and materials related to hiring curatorial staff.
                    Catalogs in the collection include those of the Vaux, Seybert, Fiss, Keeley
                    collections. There are also checklists of specimens and discrepancy forms for
                    the mineralogy collections, notes and research materials for a history of the
                    mineralogy collection at the Academy. The collection also includes published
                    volumes (Mineralogy, by Berry &amp; Mason, 1959, and Mineralogy of Pennsylvania,
                    Montgomery, 1969); mineralogical assay tools; awards from the Tuscarora Lapidary
                    Society, sponsors of "Gemarama," 1973, 1978, and 1979; Samuel G. Gordon's
                    collection of glass and film slides of geologic formations, landscapes, and
                    portraits; glass slides of colored photomicrographs of mineral preparations; an
                    oversize map of a mineralogy collection cabinet layout; and a small model of
                    mine tram car.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 02:12; 97:18</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>