<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Geology and
                        Paleontology Department records <date type="inclusive">1867-1992</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1936-1978</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Geology and
                    Paleontology Department records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC018</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1867-1992</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1936-1978</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Department of Geology and Paleontology existed from about 1936 to 1978.
                    Horace G. Richards joined the department in 1940, and was its Chairman from 1960
                    until his retirement in 1974. In 1978 the department and the invertebrate fossil
                    collection were administratively absorbed by the Department of Malacology in
                    that year.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of the Department of Geology and Paleontology
                    of the Academy of Natural Sciences, 1970 to 1980. Materials include:
                    correspondence, annual reports, records related to exhibits, documentation of
                    the move of the department's collections in 1977-1978, and inventory lists of
                    fossil specimens (Pelecypoda, Gastropda, Cephalopoda). Other records include:
                    negatives of fossil specimens; a small collection of old correspondence related
                    to the acquisition of specimens (1894-1920s); index card files of donors of
                    vertebrate paleontology, invertebrate paleontology, and paleobotany specimens in
                    the Academy's collection, including donor name, date, and citations from
                    Proceedings of the ANSP;; one reel of microfilm of the catalog of the Academy's
                    invertebrate paleontology collection, filmed in 1986; and records related to
                    Lewis Woolman's collection of artesian well borings. The collection also
                    includes an inventory of the Academy's "rock" collection (not the Mineral
                    Collection) at the time it was packed for storage in 1978. The collection was
                    deaccessioned and transferred to the Wagner Free Institute of Science in 1993.
                    Staff members with files in this collection include Horace G. Richards, and B.F.
                    Howell.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 00:22; 93:02; 96:08</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: B. F. Howell papers, Horace G. Richards papers, and
                    Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Malacology Department records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>