<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Limnology Department
                        records <date type="inclusive">1948-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Limnology
                    Department records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1035</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>36.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1948-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1947, Dr. Ruth Patrick founded the Limnology Department at the Academy of
                    Natural Sciences in order to implement this approach to studying water
                    pollution. One of the department's first projects was a 1948 biological survey
                    of the Conestoga River basin (near Lancaster, Pennsylvania). Within the next few
                    years, additional stream surveys and other studies were conducted in South
                    Carolina, Louisiana, Tennessee and Texas. Dr. Patrick led the Limnology
                    Department from its founding until 1973. A decade later, it was renamed the
                    Patrick Center of Environmental Research in her honor.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Limnology Department of the Academy of
                    Natural Sciences, 1948 to 1985. Materials include records of contracts and
                    grants, including proposals, budget summaries, official correspondence, and
                    accounting information; summary reports of work performed (1950-1977 and
                    1954-1982); personnel records; biographical information on department staff;
                    meeting minutes from department meetings, 1974-1976; annual reports of the
                    department; photos of various staff members in the field and in the laboratory;
                    reports from the Task Force on the Limnology Department (1964-1969);
                    correspondence of Ruth Patrick, Bill Hart, and John Bodine; microfilm reels of
                    Limnology survey reports (1960-1970); and audio tapes and transcripts,
                    schedules, programs, and an executive summary of a 1986 workshop on incinerator
                    emissions.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 91:10</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Division
                    of Environmental Research records, Patrick Center for Environmental Research
                    records, and Ruth Patrick papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>