<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Treasurer records <date type="inclusive">1890-1919</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Treasurer
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1915</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1890-1919</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>George Vaux, Jr. (d. 1927) was a lawyer and geologist. He was elected a member of
                    the Academy of Natural Sciences in 1892. In 1894 he was appointed as Treasurer
                    of the Academy, a position he held until his death in 1927.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of George Vaux, Jr., Treasurer of the Academy.
                    Materials include correspondence regarding estates and properties held by the
                    Academy, including reports of income from rent and dividends, payments for
                    insurance, interest, and repairs to properties; receipts; legal documents
                    related to mortgages; statements of accounts; a ledger of general and special
                    funds (1890-1899) and a general ledger (1895-1901); a copy of Edward D. Cope’s
                    will; a statement of accounts of Cope’s estate; and a list of subscribers to the
                    Cope Fund. The collection also includes a set of printed annual reports of the
                    Treasurer of the Academy, 1890-1919.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: ANSP accounting ledgers (collection 294) and records
                    related to Richard Lamborn estate.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>