<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia President's Office
                        records <date type="inclusive">1874-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia President's
                    Office records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC927</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>140 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1874-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia was founded in 1812 "for the
                    encouragement and cultivation of the sciences, and the advancement of useful
                    learning." Its collections, acquired through expeditions, gifts, purchases, and
                    exchanges, contain over 17,000,000 specimens. The Academy opened its doors to
                    the public in 1828, growing so rapidly that it outgrew its building three times
                    in sixty years. In 1876, its present home was built at 19th and Benjamin
                    Franklin Parkway. In 1948, with the establishment of the Environmental Research
                    Division, the Academy broadened its research orientation to include applied
                    research in aquatic ecosystems as well as the traditional systematics
                    research--discovering and cataloguing organisms.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of several accessions of materials from the President's
                    office from 1874-2003, with the bulk of the material dating from 1930s to the
                    1990s. The records cover a wide range of topics, and include: correspondence;
                    departmental reports; subject files; minutes of the board of trustees and its
                    committees; minutes and notes from the Academy's participation in professional
                    organizations and programs, such as The Associated Natural Science Institutions
                    (TANSI) and the Wistar Institute; strategic planning, development, and marketing
                    materials; documentation of exhibits; financial records; information on grants;
                    personnel and hiring records; speeches of the president; and facilities and
                    maintenance information. The collection also includes several cartons of data
                    sheets from studies of the water and ecology of the Pawtuxent River (1960s and
                    1970s), as well as some photographs.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 85:?; 91:10; 92:06; 99:06; 95:?; 99:12; 00:08; 00:10; 87:02;
                </p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>