<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia publications <date type="inclusive">1818-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
                    publications</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1165</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>40 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1818-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Academy's scientific publications represent America's longest-running serial
                    publishing program devoted to natural history. Since 1817, much of the research
                    by this institution's scientists, as well as the work of researchers around the
                    world, has been published in its five serial publications: the Journal of the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences, Monographs, Notulae Naturae, Proceedings of the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences, and Special Publications.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of copies of publications of the Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia and of records of the Scientific Publications
                    Department. Scientific publications include: Proceedings of the Academy of
                    Natural Sciences; Notulae Naturae; Journal of the Academy of Natural Sciences;
                    Academy News; Frontiers; and selected monographs and special publications. Other
                    Academy publications included in the collection are: annual reports and
                    president's reports; by-laws and articles of incorporation of the Academy; lists
                    of members and correspondents; FYI Newsletters; museum guides and library
                    brochures; membership brochures; children's brochures; and fundraising
                    brochures. Records of the Scientific Publications Department consist of working
                    files from the 1970s and 1980s of Jan Schmitz, Nancy Katz Colman, and other
                    staff members. These files include correspondence, copies of newspaper and
                    magazine articles, press releases and press kits, drafts of articles and
                    reports, invoices for printing and photo reproduction, reference material for
                    various Academy activities and programs, and monthly activity reports for all
                    Academy departments (1983-1990). The collection also includes printing plates
                    for articles published in the ANSP Journal, octavo and quarto; CD-ROMS
                    containing working and final versions of a 2002 special publication on the Lewis
                    and Clark Herbarium (2002); and photos of Academy events and visitors.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 97:21; 02:07; 97:22; 93:05; 99:15</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: ANS Frontiers Magazine papers (collection 597).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>