<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Ichthyology Department
                        records <date type="inclusive">1958-1991</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Ichthyology
                    Department records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1207</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1958-1991</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Ichthyology has been a part of research at the Academy of Natural Sciences since
                    its beginnings, but its importance has increased dramatically since 1898 when it
                    acquired the entire personal collection of the famous 19th century naturalist
                    Edward Drinker Cope and Henry Weed Fowler became its first full-time curator.
                    The collection has continued to grow in size, scope, and importance; the
                    department is now rated as one of the top five ichthyology centers in North
                    America. It currently houses 1.2 million cataloged specimens representing an
                    estimated 11,000 species and 2,797 primary types. The collection is
                    taxonomically diverse, but it's especially strong among eels, characiforms and
                    catfish. Its geographic scope is world-wide, but its strengths include
                    freshwater species of North and South America and marine species of the Bahamas,
                    Western Atlantic and Indian Oceans. Continued growth results from recent
                    expeditions to the Bahamas, South America and Asia.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection documents the activities of the Ichthyology Department of the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences from 1954 to 1991. Materials include annual reports
                    (1956-1981), a list of the department's employees, histories of the department
                    and its collections; records related to funding; curatorial grant proposals and
                    reports; records of expeditions and special projects; and correspondence of
                    several members of the department's staff, including Eugenia Bohlke, James
                    Bohlke, Phillip Heemstra, William F. Smith-Vaniz, and James C. Tyler. The
                    correspondence relates to grants for expeditions, research projects, and
                    preparation of specimen catalogs. The collection also includes commentary and
                    field notes by Harry Pederson on his underwater films (1958-1976); a handwritten
                    journal of a 1977 Venezuela (Rio Caura) expedition kept by William G. Saul,
                    collection manager; and printouts of database records of specimens collected on
                    expeditions, 1951-1991.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 99:10; 01:12; 97:24; 00:14</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Fish Dept. annual reports (collection 705).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>