<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Alfred E. Schuyler papers <date type="inclusive">1979-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Alfred E. Schuyler papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1208</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Alfred Ernest Schuyler has been a botanist at the Academy of Natural Sciences of
                    Philadelphia since 1962. His research focuses on aquatic and wetland plants,
                    including rare and endangered species, with particular emphasis on plants in the
                    Delaware River Basin. Schuyler received his Ph.D. from the University of
                    Michigan in 1963. He periodically teaches botany at Swarthmore College and
                    occasionally offers short courses at local arboretums or for environmental
                    consulting firms.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of notebooks of original descriptions, names, and types of
                    selected Cyperaceae, compiled by A.E. Schuyler. There are ten notebooks with
                    typed descriptions or excerpts of printed catalog entries and handwritten
                    references. There are several packets of seeds pasted into the notebooks, and at
                    least one photograph. The collection also includes a small batch of
                    correspondence between Schuyler and Baruch Blumberg regarding Blumberg's
                    donation of his herbarium to the Academy of Natural Sciences and Schuyler's
                    identification of plants for Blumberg (1979-1992).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 99:11</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>