<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>A. L. Wolf papers <date type="inclusive">1935-1994</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1970s-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">A. L. Wolf papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1096</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1935-1994</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1970s-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Alfred (Abby) Loeb Wolf was a lawyer and pilot. He was a partner in the law firm
                    of Wolf, Block, Schorr, and Solis-Cohen, specializing in both aviation law and
                    patent, trademark, and copyright law. He was a member of the Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia, and sponsored and participated in a number of the
                    Academy's collecting expeditions, including those to the Great Barrier Reef in
                    1969 and to the Cocos (Keeling) Islands in 1974.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of Wolf's voyages and his involvement in
                    expeditions of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. Destinations of
                    the expeditions and voyages include Ceylon, Australia, and Fiji (1971-1972), the
                    Maldives (1974), Cocos (Keeling) Islands (1974), the Virgin Islands (1979), the
                    Bahamas (1981), and Bermuda (1983). Materials include: incoming and outgoing
                    correspondence; bills and receipts; brochures and travel guides; maps and
                    charts; photographs and slides; newspaper clippings, articles, and reprints;
                    sales brochures for diving and photography equipment; and packing lists for the
                    trips. Among the topics covered in the correspondence are trip planning, books
                    and articles on explorations and sea voyages, and Wolf's financial and practical
                    support of several Academy expeditions. The collection also includes personal
                    items, such as a copy of Wolf's will, a copy of remarks made at his memorial
                    service in 1985, and books from his collection, several of which relate to
                    Cook's Pacific voyage.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Connie Wolf (Mrs. Alfred L. Wolf)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 94:02</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>