<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Birds of North America project records <date type="inclusive">1987-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Birds of North America project records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC020</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>49.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1987-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In two centuries of American ornithology, The Birds of North America (BNA) is
                    only the fourth comprehensive reference covering the life histories of North
                    American birds. Following in the footsteps of Wilson, Audubon, and Bent, BNA
                    makes a quantum leap in information beyond what these historic figures were able
                    to provide. Edited by Drs. Alan Poole and Frank Gill, this series provides
                    detailed scientific information (18 volumes, 18,000 pages in total) for each of
                    the 716 species of birds nesting in the USA and Canada. The print version of BNA
                    was completed in 2002, a joint 10 year project of the American Ornithologists'
                    Union, the Cornell Lab of Ornithology, and the Academy of Natural Sciences.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records from the compilation and publication of The
                    Birds of North America. Materials include: annotated typescript drafts of
                    species entries; correspondence related to text and editorial matters; negatives
                    and mock-ups of illustrations; and printed drafts of species entries. The
                    collection also includes published versions of species entries 1 through 80;
                    several versions of the project's guidelines for authors; and brochures and
                    other promotional material for the project.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 00:24; 93:03; 03:11</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>