<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>C. Mervin Palmer papers <date type="inclusive">1922-1975</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">C. Mervin Palmer papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC034</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1922-1975</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>C. Mervin Palmer was an aquatic biologist for the Biological Treatment Research
                    Activities, Cincinnati Water Research Laboratory, Advanced Waste Treatment
                    Branch. In 1949 Palmer worked as voluntary field scientific officer for UNESCO
                    Science Cooperation Office for South Asia. He was Temporary Advisor to the Pan
                    American Health Organization, Sanitary Bureau, Rio de Janiero, Brazil in
                    1969.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of C. Mervin Palmer. Materials include: notes
                    for courses Palmer took at Pennsylvania State College; course and lecture notes
                    for classes he taught at Butler University; handwritten and typescript drafts
                    for articles and manuals by Palmer, many on the topic of algae and water
                    sanitation; index card files containing bibliographic listings, species
                    information, and professional contacts; algae illustrations by species; reports
                    and correspondence from Palmer's projects as a consultant; articles and theses
                    on algae and other botanical topics by colleagues and students of Palmer;
                    miscellaneous notes, lists, and correspondence.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 01:02</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>