<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Crawford H. Greenewalt papers <date type="inclusive">1946-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Crawford H. Greenewalt papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1098</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>104 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1946-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Crawford H. Greenewalt (1902-1993) received his bachelor's degree in chemical
                    engineering from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in 1922. He began his
                    career as a chemist and worked in four manufacturing and two auxiliary
                    departments of E.I. du Pont de Nemours Co. and later served as a vice president,
                    a director and president from 1948 to 1962. He served as board chairman from
                    1962 to 1967. He played a major role in the development of nylon and in 1941 was
                    assigned to the Manhattan Project to act as a liaison between University of
                    Chicago physicists and DuPont engineering and construction crews. His widely
                    varied interests included birds and high-speed photography; he combined those
                    interests in the book Hummingbirds, published in 1960. In 1968 he published
                    another book on the subject, Bird Song: Acoustics and Physiology.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection documents Greenewalt's work as a photographer of birds and an
                    ornithologist. Materials in the collection include: black and white and color
                    photographic prints, negatives, film and glass slides, transparencies, stereo
                    photographs, and movies of hummingbirds, songbirds, and other bird families;
                    field notebooks (1956-1983), which document the location, equipment, and
                    lighting used for Greenewalt's bird photography; manuscripts and reprints of
                    Greenewalt's works on hummingbirds, and motion and sound studies; graphs,
                    charts, and sound wave printouts related to Greenewalt's study of flight and
                    birdsong; notebooks of data from flight tests and observations; photographs and
                    microscope slides of hummingbird feathers; maps and pencil sketches of birds; a
                    typescript of a talk on John Gould and William Baily given by Greenwalt at the
                    American Philosophical Society in 1980, along with a set of slides of Gould and
                    Baily artwork; camera equipment, manufacturers' equipment manuals, and notes on
                    results of equipment tests performed by Greenewalt; documents related to the
                    Academy's VIREO project include technical and equipment manuals, descriptions of
                    the program, and correspondence between Greenewalt and Academy staff. The
                    collection also includes some personal items including awards, certificates,
                    honorary degrees, slides of family and friends.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 94:12; 94:12(7.)</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences: Visual Resources for Ornithology records; Hagley Museum and Library:
                    Crawford H. Greenewalt personal papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>