<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>David H. Wenrich research materials on Joseph Leidy <date type="inclusive">1857-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">David H. Wenrich research materials on Joseph
                    Leidy</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1942</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1857-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Leidy (1823-1891) was one of the preeminent figures in the development of
                    American science in the nineteenth century. He was a physician, naturalist,
                    anatomist, and scientific illustrator. Following William Wagner's death in 1885,
                    Leidy assumed the role of President of the Faculty of the Wagner Free Institute
                    of Science, with special direction of the Biology Department. Leidy was Chairman
                    of the Board of Curators at the Academy of Natural Sciences in Philadelphia, and
                    is a central figure in that institution's history. He also taught courses at the
                    University of Pennsylvania and at Swarthmore College.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials collected by David H. Wenrich for a proposed
                    biography of Joseph Leidy. Materials include: handwritten and typescript drafts;
                    correspondence with libraries and museums requesting information on Leidy
                    correspondence and other items; notes, transcriptions, and photostats of
                    original Leidy materials; correspondence from Academy staff regarding Wenrich's
                    biography; copy of a memoir by Henry C. Chapman on Leidy; microfilm of Leidy
                    letters in the Smithsonian Institute, the Library of Congress, the University of
                    Rochester, and the National Archives; reprints; and photographs. The collection
                    also includes notes and correspondence from Joseph Leidy II (Leidy's nephew)
                    related to his own biographical project, a few original Leidy drawings of
                    rhizopods (circa 1877), and several indexes related to Leidy's work.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia: Joseph Leidy papers; Wagner Free Institute of Science: various
                    Joseph Leidy collections.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>