<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Delaware Valley Ornithological Club records <date type="inclusive">1915-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Delaware Valley Ornithological Club records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1213</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1915-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Founded January 23, 1890, at 1624 Arch Street by Spencer Trotter, William L.
                    Baily, J. Harris Reed, George S. Morris and Samuel N. Rhoads, the Delaware
                    Valley Ornithological Club has flourished ever since. Through most of its
                    existence its headquarters have been at the Academy of Natural Sciences and its
                    collections eventually were donated to that institution. Its official organ is
                    "Cassinia," where much of historic and biographical interest to ornithologists
                    has been published.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes: Spring roundups (annual bird counts), 1933, 1940-1991;
                    DVOC newsletters (Larus), 1950-1996 (incomplete); minutes of the DVOC,
                    1976-1988; membership list from the 1990s; financial reports, 1990-1994;
                    photographs and slides of DVOC activities and members; video of a 1925 trip to
                    the Pine Barrens; audiocassette with an interview of George Reynard; a copy of
                    the constitution of the DVOC; and a small amount of correspondence. There are
                    also two binders containing correspondence and artwork from the Julian Potter
                    collection: letters to Potter from Witmer Stone (1916-1937), programs and
                    newsletters, and program booklets from the Ludwick Lecture Series (1926-1943,
                    not all years represented); heavily illustrated letters, postcards, and
                    Christmas cards from Conrad Roland (1918-1955); and biographical information and
                    a CD of the two Julian Potter binders.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 99:17; 00:01</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
                    Ornithology Department records, C. Chandler Ross papers, Stephen T. Harty
                    papers, Delaware Valley Ornithological Club papers (collection 74), and Delaware
                    Valley Ornithological Club scrapbook (collection 570).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>