<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edgar Theodore Wherry papers <date type="inclusive">1834-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edgar Theodore Wherry papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1909</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1834-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Edgar T. Wherry (1885-1982) was a geologist, crystallographer, and botanist. As a
                    young man, he attended lectures at the Wagner Free Institute of Science, where
                    he would later also teach courses in mineralogy (his students there included
                    Samuel George Gordon, the noted mineralogist). He received his Ph.D. in geology
                    and mineralogy from the University of Pennsylvania in 1909. Wherry worked at the
                    Smithsonian Institution and the U.S. Department of Agriculture in the field of
                    geology, before becoming interested in the wild plants of North America. He
                    became the nation's leading expert on ferns, native phlox, and native
                    wildflowers. In 1930, Wherry returned to Philadelphia, where he joined the
                    faculty of the University of Pennsylvania as Professor of Plant Ecology and
                    Soils. He retired in 1955, but continued to teach courses in botany and ecology.
                    He was the first editor of The American Mineralogist, and was editor of the
                    Bulletin of the American Rock Garden Society and of Bartonia, the journal of the
                    Philadelphia Botanical Club. Over his career, he published more than 420 papers,
                    books, and monographs on geological and horticultural topics.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection of Edgar T. Wherry papers include: specimen catalogues and type
                    catalogues; collecting, reference, and travel notebooks; correspondence with
                    colleagues and letters of appointment; reprints and articles by Wherry and
                    others; a manuscript of Checklist of the Flora of Chester Co. (PA), by Wherry,
                    Fogg, and Wahl (1979); photographs and negatives of specimens, photographs and
                    negatives of Wherry and his colleagues; newspaper clippings; certificates and
                    awards; and maps.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Wherry correspondence and writings (collection
                    742).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>