<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edwin H. Colbert typescript <date type="inclusive">undated</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edwin H. Colbert typescript</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1875</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.125 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Edwin H. (Ned) Colbert (1905-2001) was a noted paleontologist. He spent 40 years
                    as the curator of fossil reptiles and amphibians at the American Museum of
                    Natural History in New York. Upon retirement, he and his wife moved to
                    Flagstaff, Arizona, where he was named honorary curator of vertebrate
                    paleontology at the Museum of Northern Arizona. During his career, he published
                    more than 425 scientific publications, including 17 books. From 1937 to 1941,
                    Colbert commuted from New York to Philadelphia, spending a day each week working
                    in the paleontology collections of the Academy of Natural Sciences of
                    Philadelphia. During this period, he also participated in the Academy expedition
                    to Nebraska in 1938, and lectured at Bryn Mawr College.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of an annotated photocopy of a typescript of A Catalogue
                    of Fossil Vertebrate Types in the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia,
                    by Edwin H. Colbert and Mary Youngman Ayer, Part III Mammalia, 274 pages.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>