<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Eldridge Reeves Fenimore Johnson papers <date type="inclusive">1929-1975</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Eldridge Reeves Fenimore Johnson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC490</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>38 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1929-1975</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Eldridge R. F. Johnson was a pioneer in the development of underwater
                    photography. He was also an explorer, yachtsman, and researcher. He was vice
                    president of Victor Talking Machine Co. until the business was sold to RCA in
                    1927, at which time he resigned and organized a small research and development
                    firm. During World War II, he enlisted in Naval Research, where he was involved
                    with underwater demolition and underwater photography. After the war, he
                    reorganized his company as Fenjohn Underwater Equipment Co. (in Ardmore,
                    Pennsylvania). He patented several inventions and published scientific papers on
                    the absorption and scattering of light by water, and on the preservation of
                    film. He served on the board of trustees of the Academy of Natural Sciences. He
                    was the principal sponsor of University of Pennsylvania expeditions up the
                    Paraguay River and into the Matto Grosso in Brazil, and participated in a number
                    of other expeditions to Africa, Asia, the Bahamas, and Andros Island.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of photographs, negatives, and lantern slides, and 16 mm
                    films taken by E.R. Fenimore Johnson between 1929 and 1975. Subjects include
                    diving and underwater photography equipment, ships and harbors, landscapes,
                    trees and plants, fishes, animals, birds, and native peoples of Brazil and
                    Africa, and personal photos of Johnson, his family, friends, and colleagues. The
                    bulk of the photos are present either as negatives and contact prints or as
                    prints mounted on cards with labels. The collection also includes six oversized
                    albums of prints and a set of loose prints from the Matto Grosso Expedition,
                    1929.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 1989:05 and/or 86:01</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>