<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Ernst Schäfer papers <date type="inclusive">1986-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Ernst Schäfer papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1902</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Ernst Schäfer (1910-1992) was a famous German hunter and zoologist in the 1930s,
                    specializing in ornithology. He is most famous for his three expeditions to
                    Tibet in 1931, 1934-1935, and 1938-1939, the first two led by the Academy's
                    Brooke Dolan II, and the third led by himself under the patronage of Himmler's
                    Ahnenerbe organization. Schäfer wrote several books, including Berge, Buddhas
                    und Bären (Mountains, Buddhas and Bears), and helped produce the film Geheimnis
                    Tibet (Secret Tibet).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers related to Schäfer's participation in the
                    Academy's expeditions in the 1930s to Tibet. Materials include correspondence
                    between Robert M. Peck and Schäfer, in German with English translations by Mary
                    Dolack. Peck was seeking information about the Dolan expeditions for the
                    Academy's 175 anniversary exhibits. The collection also includes excerpts of
                    writings by Schäfer about the Dolan expedition, translated into English by Mary
                    Dolack, and photocopies of pictures taken by Schäfer during the expedition.
                    Other documents in the collection are several letters regarding Schäfer/Dolan
                    materials in the holdings of the Library of Congress and one about the
                    provenance of the adult giant pandas in the Academy's collection.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Brooke Dolan papers (collection 64) and Robert Peck
                    papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>