<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Eugenia B. Bohlke papers <date type="inclusive">1972-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Eugenia B. Bohlke papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1166</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1972-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Eugenia B. Bohlke (d. 2001) was a Research Associate in Ichthyology at the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences. She entered Stanford University as a pre-med
                    student, but switched from biology to chemistry in graduate school. She married
                    James Bohlke and started a family, returning to the laboratory when her oldest
                    son started college. Instead of working as a chemist, she returned to biology,
                    accepting a position as a technician in the Ichthology Department of the Academy
                    of Natural Sciences. She joined the department in 1954, along with her husband
                    James, who took on the curatorship of the department. During her career at the
                    Academy, Eugenia Bohlke became a recognized expert in the biology of eels.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of publication records for Catalog of Type Specimens,
                    including annotated manuscripts; incoming and outgoing correspondence about
                    identification of types, the exchange and loan of specimens, and editorial
                    matters; reviewer comments. The collection also includes publication records for
                    the Fishes of Western North Atlantic, including correspondence about the
                    identification and exchange of specimens, and a set of illustrations from volume
                    9 of the series.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 97:25; 89:03</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>