<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Francis Whittier Pennell papers <date type="inclusive">1925-1950</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1950s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Francis Whittier Pennell papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1891</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1925-1950</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1950s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Francis Whittier Pennell was born in 1886 on a farm near Wawa, Delaware County,
                    Pennsylvania. He was educated at Westtown School and the University of
                    Pennsylvania, receiving a bachelor's degree in 1911 and a Ph.D. in 1913. From
                    1914 to 1921 he was associate curator of the New York Botanical Garden, and in
                    1928, became Curator of Plants at the Academy of Natural Sciences of
                    Philadelphia. He was an international authority on members of the
                    Scrophulariaceae (snapdragon family). He died in 1952.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of three postcards from Francis Pennell to George W. Bassett
                    at the Academy between 1925 and 1927. discussing collecting trips, and specimens
                    being sent back to the Academy. Postcards were sent from Peru, North Carolina,
                    and Kentucky. the collection also contains a typed and handwritten manuscript of
                    species and location descriptions for plants of the family Scrophulariaceae,
                    including: Scrophularia, Cordylanthus, Castilleja, Mimulus, Collinsia, and
                    Adenostegia.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Pennell identification of plants in the family
                    Scrophulariaceae (collection 223) and Pennell Scrophulariaceae studies
                    (collection 672).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>