<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Frank B. Gill papers <date type="inclusive">1969-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Frank B. Gill papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1162</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Frank Gill (1941- ) joined the Academy of Natural Sciences shortly after
                    receiving his Ph.D. in zoology from the University of Michigan in 1969. He held
                    several positions, including Curator of Ornithology (1969-1995), Chairman of the
                    Department of Ornithology, Chairman of the Department of Vertebrate Biology, and
                    Director of the Division of Systematic and Evolutionary Biology. He was also an
                    Adjunct Associate Professor at the University of Pennsylvania. Gill did
                    fieldwork in several parts of the world, including Costa Rica and Africa, and
                    led Academy member trips. His research interests were avian systematics, DNA
                    sequencing, Allozymes, restriction site analysis of mitochondrial DNA, and
                    DNA-DNA hybridization.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains data and manuscripts for research projects, including:
                    the Hermit Hummingbird flight patterns (1980s); East African Sunbird project
                    (1970s); Physiology and Biology of High Montane Nectar-feeding Birds; and Birds,
                    Bees and Passion Flowers. Documents in the collection include: annotated
                    typescript drafts; reprints; negatives and photo prints of birds, data graphs,
                    and other figures; data and research notes; reviewer comments; equipment lists
                    and expense reports from expeditions; and expedition notebooks. There is
                    correspondence in the collection between Gill and his colleagues, discussing his
                    research projects; and there are letters between Gill and editors discussing the
                    review and publication of the studies. The collection also includes unidentified
                    audio tapes.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 97:09</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
                    Ornithology Department records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>