<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Francis Drouet papers <date type="inclusive">1939-1982</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Francis Drouet papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC032</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1939-1982</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Francis E. Drouet (1907-1982) was an algologist. He received his Ph.D. from the
                    University of Missouri in 1931. From 1931 to 1936 he was in charge of the
                    herbarium of the University of Missouri, and was employed by the U.S. Bureau of
                    Fisheries, the U.S. Department of Agriculture, and the Comisao Technica de
                    Piscicultura at Fortaleza, Brazil. He also worked at the Chicago Natural History
                    Museum, the University of Minnesota, and the University of Arizona. Beginning in
                    1962, he was a research fellow at the Academy of Natural Sciences of
                    Philadelphia.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the correspondence and manuscripts of Francis Drouet.
                    Correspondence relates to Drouet's identification of particular algal specimens;
                    his work on the classification of blue-green algae; his National Science
                    Foundation grants and the progress of those studies; and the publication of
                    monographs and articles. There is a significant quantity of correspondence from
                    Drouet to Bill and Fay Daily, 1939-1982 (Bill Daily was a colleague, co-author,
                    and friend). Manuscripts in the collection include various drafts of the
                    "Revision of the Stigonemataceae," and "Revision of the Classification of the
                    Oscillatoriaceae." The collection also includes bibliographic references on
                    algae, illustrations by Drouet, several glass slides, and botanical specimens.
                    Drouet was the executor of Harold Louderback's estate, and the collection
                    includes some personal correspondence to Louderback and a scrapbook of poems,
                    clippings on Louderback, Drouet, and the actor Fritz Leiber. There is also
                    Drouet's correspondence with Herman S. Forest, a botanist focusing on algae, who
                    studied the developmental morphology of blue-green algae (taught biology at
                    State University of New York, Geneseo); and Forest's introduction to and
                    extracts of that correspondence.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 01:01</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Smthisonian
                    Institution Archives: Philip W. Wolle papers (record unit 7385) includes Drouet
                    and Drouet/Patrick correspondence.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>