<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>George Davis papers <date type="inclusive">1964-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">George Davis papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1212</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>28.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dr. George Davis (b. 1938) was curator of the Department of Malacology at the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences from 1972 until his retirement in 2000. In addition
                    to his work at the Academy, which he joined in 1970, Davis served as an adjunct
                    professor at the Universities of Pennsylvania and Delaware, and visiting
                    professor at three Chinese institutions. Over his career, he has published more
                    than 135 scientific articles, popular pieces, and book chapters on the
                    systematics of freshwater snails. One focus of Davis's research has been the
                    snails that transmit schistosomiasis and other parasitic diseases; this research
                    has taken him to many field sites in Asia, South and Southeast Asia, as well as
                    South and Central America and South Africa. His work has been funded by the
                    National Institutes of Health as well as the National Science Foundation.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of George Davis. Materials include typescript
                    drafts; illustrations (figures and photographs); reprints; manuscript notes,
                    sketches, and tables; computer printouts of data; and incoming and outgoing
                    correspondence between Davis and his colleagues (1964-1991). The collection also
                    includes correspondence related to the financial situation of the Association of
                    Systematics Collections (1983-1984), of which Davis was president; and a
                    cassette recording of a 1986 radio debate between Davis and Luther Sutherland on
                    creationism versus evolution.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 99:16; 94:01; 02:09</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Malacology
                    Department records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>