<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Gordon Townsend Bowles papers <date type="inclusive">1930-1934</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Gordon Townsend Bowles papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC981</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.12 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1930-1934</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Gordon Bowles (1904-1991), the son of Quaker missionaries, was born in Japan, and
                    lived there until he graduated from high school. He attended Earlham College
                    where he studied zoology, after which he took graduate courses in anthropology
                    at the University of Pennsylvania for one year before transferring to Harvard.
                    During his time in Penn, he made the acquaintance of Horace Jayne, the director
                    of the University Museum. Jayne later told Bowles about the expedition to China
                    being planned by Brooke Dolan. Having received a scholarship from the
                    Harvard-Yenching Institute for Chinese Studies, Gordon was able to join the
                    expedition.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence and photocopies of maps and expedition
                    journals of Gordon T. Bowles. The letters include reports to Horace Jayne and
                    Chien Tien Ho (of Academia Sinica), and discussion of the logistics of shipping
                    the specimens collected on the expedition back to the United States. There are
                    also inventories of the ethnological specimens collected in Tibet and items
                    presented to the Metropolitan Museum of Natural History in Nanking. The journals
                    (only volumes three and four are present) are photocopies of Gordon's notebooks
                    kept during the trip.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 89:01</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Haverford College:
                    Bowles family papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>