<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>H. A. Pilsbry papers <date type="inclusive">1890-1970</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1900-1957</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">H. A. Pilsbry papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1163</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>14 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1890-1970</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1900-1957</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henry A. Pilsbry, the Dean of American Malacologists, was associated with the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences for 70 years. Conservator, curator and head of the
                    Department of Shells, he was also the internationally recognized authority in
                    the field of land Mollusca. He wrote and edited many volumes of the Manual of
                    Conchology and from 1889 until his death was an editor of the journal Nautilus,
                    which he founded. A member of many scientific expeditions all over the United
                    States, to the Caribbean, South America, Mexico, Hawaii, and other Pacific
                    Islands, and to Australia. Few scientists have so voluminous a list of
                    publications.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of professional papers of H.A. Pilsbry. Materials include:
                    correspondence, 1890-1957, largely related to specimen identification and
                    exchange and taxonomy; manuscripts and galley proofs of articles and books, with
                    illustrations and photographs; subject files on various species, with extracts
                    from printed sources, illustrations, and photographs; and Pilsbry's index card
                    file of species. The collection also includes audio recordings of Pilsbry and
                    H.G. Richards talks; a film of Strombus goliath crawling, Brazil, 1965; and a
                    small number of photographs of Pilsbry.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 97:10; 01:03</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Pilsbry correspondence (collection 98) and Pilsbry
                    biographical papers (collection 200).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>