<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Henry Weed Fowler index cards and illustrations <date type="inclusive">undated</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Henry Weed Fowler index cards and illustrations</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1880</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>26 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henry Weed Fowler (1878-1965) was an American zoologist born in Holmesburg,
                    Pennsylvania. He studied at Stanford University under David Starr Jordan. He
                    joined the Academy of Natural Sciences in Philadelphia and worked as an
                    assistant from 1903 to 1922, associate curator of vertebrates from 1922 to 1934,
                    curator of fish and reptiles from 1934 to 1940 and curator of fish from 1940 to
                    1965. He published material on numerous topics including crustaceans, birds,
                    reptiles and amphibians, but his most important work was on fish. In 1927 he
                    co-founded the American Society of Ichthyologists and Herpetologists and acted
                    as treasurer until the end of 1927.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes index cards of fish species kept by Henry Fowler. The
                    cards list species name, type localities, and citations. There are also 66
                    miscellaneous pencil, ink, and watercolor illustrations of fishes by Fowler,
                    including drawings of Hyrtl skeletons made for the Catalog of World Fishes;
                    other fish species, such as Hemibrycon dentatus and Chaunacidae; and frogs.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Fowler's Catalog of Hyrtl fish skeletons (collection
                    393) and Fowler's Catalog of World Fishes (collection 712).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>