<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Horace G. Richards papers <date type="inclusive">1928-1978</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Horace G. Richards papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC087</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>82 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1928-1978</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Horace G. Richards (1906-1984) was a geologist at the Academy of Natural Sciences
                    of Philadelphia. He received his Ph.D. in zoology and paleontology from the
                    University of Pennsylvania in 1932. He worked at the Smithsonian Institution and
                    at the New Jersey State Museum before joining the Academy in 1937 as a research
                    fellow. He became Chairman of the Department of Geology and Paleontology in 1960
                    and served in that capacity until his retirement in 1974. He published more than
                    260 scientific papers and was the author of six books on earth science and
                    marine fossils. He was an authority on the geologic formations of the Atlantic
                    coastal plain, and spearheaded the Academy's Atlantic Coastal Plain Project in
                    1947 to collect and study fossils and well samples from the Coastal Plain.
                    Richards was also president of the Shorelines Commission of INQUA (the
                    International Union for Quaternary Research). </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of personal and professional papers of Horace G. Richards.
                    Materials in the collection include: Academy correspondence; trip reports,
                    itineraries, and expense records; records of the Atlantic Coastal Plain Project
                    (grant proposals, correspondence, reports) ; records of his work for the
                    International Union for Quaternary Research; records of his activities as a
                    member of professional societies, including the Philadelphia Geological Society;
                    scrapbooks containing announcements and programs for Richard's lectures and
                    newspaper clippings about his work and that of other Academy staff; publications
                    (books, reprints, magazine articles); interviews and scripts for radio and
                    television science programs; records of courses taught and some papers by his
                    students; maps of Cape Island, Cape May County, NJ.; notebooks; Richards’
                    master's thesis and other student papers; and diplomas. The collection also
                    includes photo albums, film and glass slides, and negatives taken on journeys
                    throughout the world. There are also indexes of travel photos and indexes of
                    photos of specimens. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 02:01</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia Geology and Paleontology Department records, Academy of
                    Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Malacology Department records, and H.G.
                    Richards papers (collection 697).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>