<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>H. Radclyffe Roberts papers <date type="inclusive">1936-1980</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1936-1948</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">H. Radclyffe Roberts papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1896</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.875 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1980</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1936-1948</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>H. Radclyffe Roberts (1906-1982) was an entomologist at the Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia. He served the Academy in various capacities from 1930
                    through his death in 1982: trustee, managing director 1947-1972, and associate
                    curator of the Entomology Department. Roberts held a Ph.D. in biology from the
                    University of Pennsylvania and was an expert in Orthoptera. During World War II
                    he wrote a study on malaria-carrying mosquitoes which was circulated to U.S.
                    soldiers. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of H. Radclyffe Roberts. Materials include:
                    professional correspondence (incoming and outgoing) with colleagues in the
                    United States, Mexico, and South America. Many of the letters discuss the study
                    and exchange of specimens of orthoptera. Other correspondence is related to an
                    atlas of mosquitoes, and other publications. There are a small number of
                    typescript and manuscript notes on collecting and funding policies for the
                    Academy (from circa 1946). The collection also includes one folder of notes and
                    illustrations from 1980 related to a study of the genus propedies.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Entomology
                    Department records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>