<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Ida Langman papers <date type="inclusive">1939-1978</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Ida Langman papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1887</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1939-1978</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Ida Kaplan Langman (1904-1991) was born in the Ukraine. While she was still an
                    infant, the Kaplan family immigrated to the United States and settled in
                    Philadelphia. Kaplan married Oscar Langman in 1928. She received a teaching
                    certificate from the Philadelphia Normal School and taught in the public
                    schools, ending her teaching career as the Board of Education's first museum
                    teacher assigned to the Academy of Natural Sciences. While working as a teacher,
                    she pursued her graduate studies at the University of Pennsylvania, earning a
                    master's degree in botany in 1945. She worked as a botanist, bibliographer, and
                    author. In 1964, she published A Selected Guide to the Literature on the
                    Flowering Plants of Mexico, her best known work. She also worked on a
                    bibliography of worldwide botanical literature for the Hunt Botanical Library at
                    Carnegie-Mellon.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of professional and some personal correspondence, most
                    of it incoming, of Ida Langman. Much of the correspondence relates to Langman's
                    compilation of bibliographies of Mexican flora and of worldwide botanical
                    literature. Some of the correspondence is in Spanish.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Ida Kaplan Langman scrapbook (collection 3038); Carnegie Mellon
                    University, Hunt Institute for Botanical Documentation: Ida Kaplan Langman
                    papers (Collection #179).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>