<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>J. Percy Moore papers <date type="inclusive">1850-1956</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1898-1956</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">J. Percy Moore papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1889</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1850-1956</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1898-1956</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Percy Moore (1869-1965) was a university professor and world recognized
                    authority on leeches. He was educated at the University of Pennsylvania,
                    receiving his bachelor's degree in 1892 and his Ph.D. in 1896. His teaching
                    career began in 1890, when he was appointed Assistant Instructor of Zoology at
                    the University of Pennsylvania. He was promoted to Instructor in 1892, Assistant
                    Professor in 1907, and Professor in 1912. In 1939 he became Emeritus Professor.
                    Moore was also an Assistant Curator and Corresponding Secretary for the Academy
                    of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia from 1902 to 1939 and a member of the Board
                    of Trustees from 1938 to 1957. In 1957 he was made an Honorary Life Trustee of
                    the Academy.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains documentation related to the following topics: general
                    Academy and Academy Library business; the Library Committee; minutes and
                    correspondence from the Academy's Board of Trustees (1950s); visual materials
                    such as illustrations, lantern slides, glass plates negatives, film negatives,
                    16mm film, and photographs; the Ludwick Institute, including correspondence,
                    memoranda, and lecture announcements; professional correspondence from
                    1904-1944; field notes on leeches, mosquitoes, and other subjects; manuscripts;
                    typescripts of articles; reprints of articles by Moore and others; notes for a
                    biography of Leidy; notes and correspondence about S.G. Morton and William
                    Maclure; lecture notes for biology classes at Penn; Moore's notes on Cope's
                    lectures on Vertebrata (1899-99); correspondence on Leidy specimens
                    (1920s-1930s); and a copy of G.H. Parker's biography of Leidy, 1951.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: J. P. Moore papers (collection 505).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>