<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James Bond papers <date type="inclusive">1939-1991</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James Bond papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1870</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1939-1991</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James Bond (1900-1989) was a leading American ornithologist. Bond was born in
                    Philadelphia and worked at the Academy of Natural Sciences, rising to become
                    curator of birds. He was an expert in Caribbean birds and wrote the definitive
                    book on the subject: Birds of the West Indies, first published in 1936. Bond won
                    the Institute of Jamaica's Musgrave Medal in 1952; the Brewster Medal of the
                    American Ornithologists Union in 1954; and the Leidy Medal of the Academy of
                    Natural Sciences in 1975. Author Ian Fleming appropriated his name for his
                    fictional spy.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscripts, correspondence, and professional papers of
                    James Bond and volumes of works by James and Mary Wickham Bond. Manuscripts in
                    the collection include: autographed copies of chapters of Birds of the West
                    Indies; typescript corrections for new editions of the book; a typescript draft
                    of The World of James Bond, a biography by David R. Contosta; and a typescript
                    for "A New Race of Chat Tanager from the Dominican Republic," by Bond and
                    Annabelle Dod, with some related correspondence and notes. Other professional
                    correspondence in the collection (incoming and outgoing), dating from 1939 to
                    1973, relates to the editing and publication of other books and articles,
                    sightings of birds, identification of species, and requests for reprints.
                    Correspondence dating from 1975 to 1979 is largely made up of letters between
                    Bond and the secretary of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. The
                    collection includes copies of books by James and Mary Wickham Bond, reprints,
                    and supplements to the Checklist of Birds of the West Indies. Other materials in
                    the collection include photographic portraits of Bond; a set of printing plates
                    for illustrations in Bond's book on Mt. Desert birds; medals awarded to Bond for
                    his work; and a scrapbook of photographs and articles about Ian Fleming's use of
                    James Bond's name.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Free Library of
                    Pennsylvania: James Bond collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>