<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James A. G. Rehn notes <date type="inclusive">1864-1965</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James A. G. Rehn notes</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1894</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1965</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>J.A.G. Rehn (1881-1965) was an entomologist at the Academy of Natural Sciences of
                    Philadelphia. He first joined the Academy in 1900 as a student. He became
                    curator of the insect collection in 1933 and continued in that role until his
                    death in 1965. He was very active in the American Entomological Society, serving
                    as the organization's president (1942-1946 and 1952-1953) and treasurer
                    (1930-1959) as well as serving on several committees. He published extensively
                    and was an expert on Orthoptera. He also participated in several of the
                    Academy's expeditions, including those to Africa, Costa Rica, and Brazil.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a small collection of correspondence, notes, and photographs of J.A.G.
                    Rehn. Materials include: professional correspondence (1904-1965) related to the
                    exchange of specimens, arrangements for international collecting expeditions,
                    taxonomy, and requests for the return of borrowed specimens; notes, possibly for
                    a talk, entitled "Basic Faunistic Aspects of the Orthoptera of North America,"
                    and handwritten extracts from published materials on geology, and zoogeography;
                    slides of landscapes, insects, and drawings of insects; photographs and
                    negatives; and newspaper clippings about Rehn. The collection also includes
                    African artifacts, including a bow, arrows and a quiver, textiles, and a length
                    of rope. These items were presumably collection by Rehn on the George Vanderbilt
                    Africa Expedition in 1934. The collection also contains records related to
                    Rehn’s father, William J. Rehn, including a discharge from the Grand Army of the
                    Republic (1895), the D.C. Volunteers (1864), and the US Army (1865).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Entomology
                    Department records and J.A.G. Rehn correspondence and papers (collections 682,
                    743, 738, 734).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>