<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John W. Harshberger papers <date type="inclusive">1894-1924</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1911-1916</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John W. Harshberger papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC421</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1894-1924</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1911-1916</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John W. Harshberger (1869-1929) was a Philadelphia botanist, biographer,
                    historian and professor of botany at the University of Pennsylvania. He received
                    his Ph.D. from the University of Pennsylvania in 1893, after which he made an
                    extensive scientific tour of Europe, South America, Mexico, and the United
                    States, collecting specimens as he went. He was the author of more than a dozen
                    books and more than 320 papers on botanical subjects. His book Botanists of
                    Philadelphia and Their Works portrays a history of American botany along with
                    the biographies.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a set of 12 volumes of Illustrations of North American Vegetation,
                    companion volumes to a phytographic Survey of North America (Die Vegetation der
                    Erde); one volume of Illustrations of Foreign Vegetation; and an
                    extra-illustration volume of Vegetation of South Florida (Transactions, Wagner
                    Free Institute of Science, vol VII pt.3, Oct 1914). The volumes illustrate the
                    vegetation and geology of various regions of the United States, Mexico, and the
                    Caribbean, with a small selection of images of vegetation from around the world.
                    Pasted into the volumes are photographs, postcards, images clipped from
                    journals, pamphlets, and magazines, letters, and maps. Photographers whose
                    images are used in the volumes include Harshberger, Henry Troth, and William
                    Rau. The collection also includes a copy of Harshberger's The Vegetation of the
                    New Jersey Pine Barrens, 1916, inscribed by the author.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 19:80</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Harshberger correspondence (collection 444);
                    University of Pennsylvania: John William Harshberger, papers (1886 - 1929)
                    (collection # UPT 50 H313).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>