<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>K. Elaine Hoagland papers related to Oyster Creek. <date type="inclusive">1971-1982</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">K. Elaine Hoagland papers related to Oyster
                    Creek.</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC016</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1982</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>K. Elaine Hoagland is a researcher at the Center for Marine and Environmental
                    Studies at Lehigh University in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania. In the 1970s and 1980s
                    she worked in conjunction with the Wetlands Institute of Stone Harbor, New
                    Jersey to research the boring and fouling organisms in the vicinity of the
                    Oyster Creek Generating Station at Barnegat Bay, New Jersey.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection documents the federally funded research project conducted by
                    Hoagland and the Wetlands Institute at the Oyster Creek Generating Station at
                    Barnegat Bay, New Jersey. Materials include data sheets, reports, field notes,
                    photos, slides, and x-ray photographs of sample panels. Specimens from this
                    project are in the Academy's General Invertebrates Collection, Department of
                    Malacology. The collection also includes records related to Hoagland's testimony
                    as an expert witness in a legal matter involving the Oyster Creek Nuclear
                    Generating Station.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 00:20</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>