<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Melbourne A. Carriker field notes <date type="inclusive">1929-1938</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Melbourne A. Carriker field notes</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1874</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1929-1938</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Melbourne Armstrong Carriker Jr. was a Philadelphian interested in becoming a
                    collector and through the sponsorship of the Academy of Natural Sciences and
                    financial aid of Clement B. Newbold, he went to Peru where he collected birds
                    and mammals. Later, on his Bolivian expeditions he was accompanied by his son M.
                    R. Carriker and the expeditions were sponsored by the American Philosophical
                    Society through grants to aid the collections. It developed that Carriker
                    remained in South America and periodically returned to this area to keep up his
                    contacts with museums and individuals wanting collections of specimens made in
                    Peru and Bolivia.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of field notes and specimen lists from seven expeditions
                    made by Melbourne A. Carriker, Jr. between 1929 and 1938. Entries in the volumes
                    are in chronological order with specimen numbers and descriptions, as well as
                    field notes on travel, camping arrangements, and descriptions of collections
                    stations, geography, and fauna.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Carriker South American Expeditions papers (collection
                    900 ) and Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Ornithology Department
                    records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>