<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Milton Laden research papers on Edgar T. Wherry <date type="inclusive">1905-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Milton Laden research papers on Edgar T. Wherry</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC2094</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1905-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Edgar T. Wherry (1885-1982) was a geologist, crystallographer, and botanist. As a
                    young man, he attended lectures at the Wagner Free Institute of Science, where
                    he would later also teach courses in mineralogy (his students there included
                    Samuel George Gordon, the noted mineralogist). He received his Ph.D. in geology
                    and mineralogy from the University of Pennsylvania in 1909. Wherry worked at the
                    Smithsonian Institution and the U.S. Department of Agriculture in the field of
                    geology, before becoming interested in the wild plants of North America. He
                    became the nation's leading expert on ferns, native phlox, and native
                    wildflowers. In 1930, Wherry returned to Philadelphia, where he joined the
                    faculty of the University of Pennsylvania as Professor of Plant Ecology and
                    Soils. He retired in 1955, but continued to teach courses in botany and ecology.
                    He was the first editor of The American Mineralogist, and was editor of the
                    Bulletin of the American Rock Garden Society and of Bartonia, the journal of the
                    Philadelphia Botanical Club. Over his career, he published more than 420 papers,
                    books, and monographs on geological and horticultural topics.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of research materials related to Edgar T. Wherry,
                    primarily collected by Milton Laden, including: reprints and photocopies of
                    articles by Wherry; memorials to Wherry; copies of and some original letters
                    between Wherry and a variety of his correspondents; photocopies of documents in
                    museum, library, university, and business archives around the country and in
                    Europe; tapes of Wherry giving talks on botany and mineralogy and interviews of
                    Wherry by Laden; records of Laden's research project on Wherry, including
                    correspondence from archival repositories and those who knew Wherry; and a card
                    files of Laden's contacts. William and Marion Flook's Wherry materials include:
                    approximately 1600 slides copied from Wherry's glass slides (which are held at
                    the Morris Arboretum); an index of the slides; photoprints of 15 of the slides;
                    and copies of Green Scene that include an article on the slide collection.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>