<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Patrick Center for Environmental Research records <date type="inclusive">1903-1991</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1952-1991</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Patrick Center for Environmental Research
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1215</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>66.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1903-1991</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1952-1991</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Named in honor of Dr. Ruth Patrick, the Patrick Center for Environmental Research
                    at the Academy of Natural Sciences consists of a multidisciplinary group of
                    environmental scientists and engineers devoted to understanding aquatic and
                    terrestrial ecosystems, including the effects of natural processes and human
                    activities on environmental quality. The Center works with a number of diverse
                    stakeholders, including government, community groups, industry and environmental
                    organizations to improve environmental stewardship. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records from the Patrick Center for Environmental
                    Research. Materials include: general files and surveys kept by Robert G. Grant,
                    Jr. (1988-1999); project data sheets; correspondence and memos; reports; and
                    project schedules and budgets. Projects include studies of environmental impacts
                    of the Savannah River Plant, Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission, Potomac
                    Electric Power Company, and various DuPont facilities. The collection also
                    includes files kept by Tran Noc Loi in the 1980s on Marine polychaetes (annelid
                    worms), including data sheets and reprints and a CD containing the notebooks and
                    papers of Danielle Kreeger.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 99:22; 07:18</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Limnology
                    Department records, Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Division of
                    Environmental Research records, and Ruth Patrick papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>