<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Patrick Center for Environmental Research records related to the
                        Fairmount Park Commission <date type="inclusive">1997-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Patrick Center for Environmental Research records related
                    to the Fairmount Park Commission</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1914</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1997-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Named in honor of Dr. Ruth Patrick, the Patrick Center for Environmental Research
                    at the Academy of Natural Sciences consists of a multidisciplinary group of
                    environmental scientists and engineers devoted to understanding aquatic and
                    terrestrial ecosystems, including the effects of natural processes and human
                    activities on environmental quality. In an effort to restore, renew, and protect
                    one of the largest municipal parks in the U.S. for future generations, the
                    Fairmount Park Commission selected The Academy of Natural Sciences of
                    Philadelphia to work on the Natural Lands Restoration and Environmental
                    Education Program (NLREEP). This five-year special initiative was initially
                    funded by a $26 million grant from the William Penn Foundation. NLREEP is
                    designed to restore portions of the natural landscape in the seven watershed
                    parks of the Fairmount Park system, including the Wissahickon Park, Cobbs Creek
                    Park, East and West Park, FDR Park, Pennypack Park, Poquessing Park, and Tacony
                    Park. The Academy's team involved the Environmental, Systematic Biology and
                    Public Programs groups of the Academy and scientists from the Morris Arboretum
                    and the Natural Lands Trust and was led by the Patrick Center for Environmental
                    Research.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials related to the work done by the Patrick Center
                    for Environmental Research for the Fairmount Park Commission in 1997 and 1998.
                    Materials include original data sheets, CDs of data sets, field notes, maps,
                    photos, slides, and reports (on paper and on CD). The collection also includes a
                    CD of the final proposal for the FPC, and video and audio tapes of activities
                    related to this project, including meetings and a radio call-in show.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
                    Bicentennial Symposium records (includes some records from 1970 ecological
                    survey of the park).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>