<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Richard E. Bishop papers, films, and paintings <date type="inclusive">1937-1981</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Richard E. Bishop papers, films, and paintings</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC036</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1937-1981</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Richard Evett Bishop (1887-1975) was a painter, etcher, and photographer of
                    wildlife subjects, particularly wildfowl. He graduated from Cornell University
                    in 1909 with an M.E. degree and went to work as an electrical engineer for the
                    Cutler-Hammer Manufacturing Company in Milwaukee. In 1915 he married Mary Ellen
                    Harrington. The couple moved to Philadelphia, where Bishop worked at a
                    manufacturing plant as a sales manager until his retirement from business in
                    1933. A number of his etchings and prints are in the collection of the National
                    Gallery of Art in Washington D.C. He lived in Philadelphia and was a member of
                    the Philadelphia Print Club and the Philadelphia Watercolor Society. In 1936, he
                    published Bishop's Birds: Etchings of Water-fowl and Upland Game Birds. In the
                    same year, J.N. "Ding" Darling, the Chief of the U.S. Biological Survey, asked
                    Bishop if his drypoint of Canada geese, entitled "Coming In," could be used on
                    the third Federal Duck Stamp.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of samples of the artwork of Richard Bishop and
                    materials related to his artwork. Included are two framed oil paintings of the
                    Mara River in Kenya, a sheet of pencil sketches of ducks in flight, and a bound
                    souvenir volume related to the U.S. Department of Agriculture "Duck Stamp"
                    designed by Bishop. The volume includes plates of Bishop's stamp, a series of
                    humorous duck stamp drawings signed by friends, and a letter and several
                    telegrams congratulating Bishop on the selection of his design. Included in the
                    collection, but not bound into the volume are a U.S. Department of Agriculture
                    brochure on the history of the duck stamp, and a press release announcing the
                    selection of the winner of the 1982-1983 duck stamp competition. The collection
                    also includes two 16 mm color films of birds, one entitled Prairie Wings. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 01:09</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>