<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>R. M. de Schauensee papers <date type="inclusive">1925-1979</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">R. M. de Schauensee papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1903</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1925-1979</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Rodolphe Meyer de Schauensee (1901-1984) was curator of birds at the Academy of
                    Natural Sciences of Philadelphia for nearly 50 years. He was the Academy's vice
                    president from 1940 to 1949 and was a member of the Board of Trustees from 1934
                    until his death. During his tenure, the Academy's bird collection grew from
                    about 80,000 to over 170,000 specimens, and the scope of the collection was
                    greatly expanded to include many more species not native to North America. De
                    Schauensee was a member of a number of ornithological societies, including the
                    Delaware Valley Ornithological Club. He published over 100 articles and six
                    major books on avian systematics.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence, manuscripts, and photographs of Rodolphe
                    de Schnauensee. Materials include incoming and outgoing correspondence,
                    1937-1977, related to identification of specimens, exchange of specimens with
                    other institutions, expedition planning, work being performed by local
                    collectors in Southeast Asia and South America, and other topics related to his
                    work at the Academy. Correspondents include Ernst Mayr and Sidney Dillon Ripley,
                    at the American Natural History Museum, Herbert Deignan, and Thomas Barbour.
                    Materials related to de Schnauensee publications include: manuscript catalogue
                    of the Birds of Siam, in 2 volumes, listing specimen names, references to the
                    initial description, distribution, and measurements; typescript catalog of
                    Siamese birds, in 3 volumes, giving references to initial descriptions; and
                    correspondence related to the publication of Birds of Venezuela and Birds of
                    China. Other materials in the collection include: specimen collecting notebooks,
                    mostly from his trips to Siam, giving specimen number, date, location (sometimes
                    including elevation), sex; film and glass negatives from Schauensee's trips to
                    Thailand and Burma; a small book prepared by Schauensee on collecting shells;
                    photographs; maps; and reprints of articles written by Schauensee.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
                    Ornithology Department records; George Miksch Sutton drawings (illustrations for
                    de Schauensee's Birds of Columbia); Collection 628, de Schauensee papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>