<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert Robertson papers <date type="inclusive">1954-1976</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert Robertson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1898</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1954-1976</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert Robertson is a malacologist and Emeritus Curator in the Department of
                    Malacology of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. He is a
                    specialist in marine gastropods. Robertson received his Ph.D. in biology from
                    Harvard University in 1960, after which he joined the Academy staff. He was
                    Pilsbry Chair of Malacology from 1969 to 1972. A. Myra Keen (1905-1986) was a
                    professor of paleontology at Stanford University, and curator of malacology at
                    the University. She published 14 books and many scientific papers on malacology.
                    She retired in 1972.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Correspondence between Robert Roberson and A. Myra Keen, 1954-1976. The letters
                    cover a broad range of topics, including their research, teaching and
                    supervision of students, publications, colleagues, and personal matters. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Malacology
                    Department records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>