<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert Peck papers <date type="inclusive">1982-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert Peck papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1890</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert M. Peck studied history and archeology at Princeton University. He is a
                    Fellow of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, a writer, naturalist,
                    and historian who has traveled extensively in North and South America, Africa,
                    Asia and Europe. The author of A Celebration of Birds and Headhunters and
                    Hummingbirds: An Expedition in Ecuador, Peck has written for a wide range of
                    popular and scholarly magazines including Audubon, National Wildlife,
                    International Wildlife, Arts, Antiques, Image, Terra, the Philadelphia Inquirer,
                    and the New York Times. In 1991 he was awarded the Academy of Natural Sciences'
                    Richard Hopper Day Medal for his work interpreting natural history to the
                    public.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Robert M. Peck. Materials include: minutes,
                    memos, planning notes and sketches related to various Academy projects and
                    exhibitions, including diorama enhancement, the Discovering Dinosaurs exhibit,
                    and a Brooke Dolan exhibit; correspondence, drafts, photocopies of Cassin
                    correspondence, and other research materials assembled for his introduction to
                    John Cassin's The Illustrations of the Birds of California, Texas, Oregon,
                    British and Russian America; and correspondence related to various projects,
                    including publication and publicity for Richard Ellis's books on whales, and a
                    proposed Thomas Say postage stamp (1982-1986). The collection also includes
                    correspondence and other papers related to Peck's work on Brooke Dolan and the
                    "Dixie Mission" in Yenan. These papers include correspondence with W.J.
                    Peterkin; an inventory of the Dolan collection; published volumes, including
                    Yenan!: Colonel Wilbur Peterkin and the American military mission to the Chinese
                    Communists, 1944-1945 by William P. Head, Dixie Mission: The United States Army
                    Observer Group in Yenan, 1944 by David D. Barrett, and a copy of Annual
                    Pictorial Magazine, 1991, which features the Dixie Mission story; and a series
                    of photographs of Dolan in Yenan.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences Exhibits Department
                    records and Ernst Schafer papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>