<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>R. Tucker Abbott papers <date type="inclusive">1979-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">R. Tucker Abbott papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC2044</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert Tucker Abbott (1919-1995) was a noted American conchologist and
                    malacologist. He graduated from Harvard University in 1942, where he had studied
                    with William James Clench. After his service in World War II, he worked at the
                    National Museum of Natural History, Smithsonian Institution (1944-1954) in the
                    Department of Mollusks. During this time, he earned his Master's and Ph.D. at
                    George Washington University. He then joined the Academy of Natural Sciences in
                    Philadelphia (1954-1969). He was chair of the Department of Mollusks, and held
                    the Pilsbry Chair of Malacology. During that time he went on a number of
                    shelling expeditions to the Indo-Pacific region. He also started his own
                    journal, "Indo-Pacific Mollusca," and an active editor on "The Nautilus." In
                    1969, Abbott accepted the DuPont Chair of Malacology at the Delaware Museum of
                    Natural History. He also headed the Department of Mollusks, and was Assistant
                    Director. In 1971 he became editor-in-chief of "The Nautilus." He was the
                    author of American Seashells, 1974, Seashells of the World, 1962, and The
                    Kingdom of the Seashell, 1972. He was an active member of the American
                    Malacological Union and Conchologists of America.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of illustrations for and a copy of Monographs of Marine
                    Mollusca, number 3, 1985, edited by R. Tucker Abbott. Illustrations include line
                    drawings, maps, charts, and photographs. The collection also includes one black
                    and white slide of Robert Robertson, dated 1979. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>