<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Rudolf G. Schmieder papers <date type="inclusive">1887-1968</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1929-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Rudolf G. Schmieder papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1904</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.88 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1887-1968</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1929-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Rudolf Gustav Schmieder (1898-1967) was an entomologist, associate professor of
                    biology at the University of Pennsylvania, and a research associate at the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. He received his Ph.D. from the
                    University of Pennsylvania in 1927 and taught there until 1967, retiring shortly
                    before his death. He was active in the American Entomological Society, serving
                    as its recording secretary from 1931 to 1935 and its president from 1936 to
                    1938, and was editor of the Society's journal, Entomological News, from 1945 to
                    1967.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Rudolf Schmieder. Materials include: incoming
                    and outgoing correspondence on general entomology with various colleagues;
                    correspondence as editor of Entomological News; and correspondence related to
                    his role as a member of the Thomas Say Foundation. Papers related to Scmeider's
                    connections with the American Entomological Society, especially regarding those
                    years when he was secretary or president of the Society include correspondence
                    regarding corresponding members, recommendations for honors for life members,
                    and other records of the society, including printed by-laws. Other materials in
                    the collection include: a 1910 travel journal of Schmeider's trip to Europe;
                    school papers; a 1916 yearbook from Central High School, Philadelphia; diplomas,
                    certificates, and honorary memberships; and a family genealogy.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: American Entomological Society records and Academy of
                    Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Entomology Department records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>