<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Ruth Patrick papers <date type="inclusive">1898-1991</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1950s-1980s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Ruth Patrick papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1100</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>186 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1898-1991</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1950s-1980s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dr. Ruth Myrtle Patrick (born November 26, 1907, in Topeka, Kansas) is a botanist
                    and limnologist specializing in diatoms and freshwater ecology, who developed
                    ways to measure the health of freshwater ecosystems and established a number of
                    research facilities. She attended the Sunset Hill School in Kansas City,
                    Missouri, graduating in 1925. She earned her Ph.D. at the University of Virginia
                    in 1934. In 1937, Dr. Patrick became curator of the Academy's Leidy
                    Microscopical Collection and in 1947, she founded the Limnology Department at
                    The Academy of Natural Sciences. From 1973 to 1976 she was the first woman chair
                    of The Academy of Natural Sciences’ Board of Trustees and later held the
                    Academy’s Francis Boyer Chair of Limnology. She formed the Environmental
                    Associates, a group of corporate executives concerned about environmental
                    effects of industrial activities. She taught limnology and botany at the
                    University of Pennsylvania for more than 35 years and wrote more than 200
                    scientific papers and a number of books on the environment, including Power So
                    Great, Colors of Tomorrow, and the series Rivers of the United States. She has
                    received numerous awards for her scientific achievements, including the National
                    Medal of Science in 1996.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Dr. Ruth Patrick. Materials include:
                    incoming and outgoing correspondence (1932-1991); memoranda, minutes, reports,
                    and administrative files pertaining to Academy departments and committees;
                    administrative files of organizations with which Patrick was involved, including
                    the Environmental Associates, Environmental Assessments Council, the National
                    Academy of Sciences, and various local, state, and national commissions;
                    manuscripts of published and unpublished works, reprints, reference materials
                    and data for articles and books, and correspondence with publishers, co-authors,
                    and sponsors; lectures and addresses; reports, data, correspondence, maps,
                    photographs, and other files related to various projects undertaken by Patrick
                    or those under her supervision, including her book Groundwater Contamination in
                    the United States; files of reports, articles, and studies on pollution, acid
                    deposition, groundwater contamination, river basins, and estuaries; and
                    miscellaneous memorabilia and photographs. The collection also includes
                    documents related to the Ruth Patrick Fund, the Ruth Patrick Scholars program,
                    and the celebration of Dr. Patrick's 50th anniversary at the Academy; and
                    artifacts from the dedication of the Ruth Patrick Science Education Center,
                    University of South Carolina, in 1991.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 94:14; 97:17; 98:12; 99:03</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>



            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Limnology
                    Department records, Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia Division of
                    Environmental Research records, and Patrick Center for Environmental Research
                    records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>