<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Samuel Nicholson Rhoads papers <date type="inclusive">1879-1918</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Samuel Nicholson Rhoads papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC011</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1879-1918</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Samuel Rhoads was a naturalist, ornithologist, mammalogist, and book dealer. He
                    collected mammal and bird specimens throughout the United States, Canada, and
                    South America. In 1903, he published a book entitled The Mammals of Pennsylvania
                    and New Jersey, and contributed many papers on mammals, birds, and reptiles to
                    various zoological journals. From 1906 to 1925 he operated the Benjamin Franklin
                    Book Store in Philadelphia, specializing in rare books on natural history. He
                    was a founder of the Delaware Valley Ornithological Club, its Secretary, and
                    later its President.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of manuscripts, notes, and correspondence of Samuel N.
                    Rhoads. Manuscripts include Rhoads's writings on natural history topics such as
                    birds and mammals; descriptions of travel in Pennsylvania, Canada, Tennessee,
                    Florida, Texas, and Virginia; an essay on attending the first Quaker meeting at
                    Bald Summit, an essay on literature in the home, and notes for an article on
                    membership in the Society of Friends; and notes and drafts of his volume on the
                    mammals of Pennsylvania and New Jersey. There is a small amount of
                    correspondence in the collection, which includes letters from the firm that
                    printed his Mammals, letters from colleagues who supplied him with information
                    for that volume, and a description of his bicycle trip from Philadelphia to
                    Bedford Springs in 1894. Other items in the collection include reprints, photos
                    and illustrations for his Mammals volume, a copy of an Abstract of the
                    Proceedings of the Delaware Valley Ornithological Club from 1892, photos of a
                    hunting camp, and miscellaneous catalogs and price lists for shells and
                    taxidermy.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 00:05</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Samuel Nicholson Rhoads papers (collection 421).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>