<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Selwyn S. Roback papers <date type="inclusive">1863-1981</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1922-1981</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Selwyn S. Roback papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1007</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1863-1981</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1922-1981</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dr. Selwyn S. Roback (1924-1988) was an entomologist and curator of limnology at
                    the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. He joined the Academy in 1951
                    as an assistant curator and became a full curator in 1963. He was a specialist
                    in non-biting aquatic midges. In the Department of Limnology, Roback studied the
                    taxonomy and ecology of aquatic insects, particularly in the immature stages,
                    collected as part of the Academy's limnological studies. Roback also
                    participated in several Academy expeditions, including those to Peru in 1955,
                    Colombia in 1955, and Peru and Bolivia in 1977.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Selwyn S. Roback. Materials in the collection
                    include: correspondence with H.Radclyffe Roberts and other colleagues; papers by
                    Roback, including drafts of articles and talks; proposals, reports, and receipts
                    for expeditions; slides and photos of expeditions in Peru, Bolivia, and
                    Columbia; notes from professional meetings; several reprints; photocopied maps;
                    illustrations and photographic mockups; a collection of autographs of
                    scientists; and portraits and prints of entomologists. The collection also
                    includes illustrations of insects, fish, shells, mollusks, and butterflies by
                    various people, including H.A. Pilsbry, Helen Winchester, J.A.G. Rehn, and H.W.
                    Fowler. Illustrations are black and white and handcolored prints and original
                    ink and pencil drawings and watercolors. Additionally the collection contains 11
                    woodcuts (1967-1973) by Roback of various subjects including birds, fish and
                    insects. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 90:03; 99:02; 99:02A; 02:14</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>