<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Sinclair Oil Corporation records <date type="inclusive">1929-1966</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Sinclair Oil Corporation records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1905</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1929-1966</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Sinclair Oil Corporation was founded by Harry F. Sinclair in 1916. In 1930,
                    Sinclair began using the apatosaurus (brontosaurus) in its advertising, sales
                    promotions, and product labels. In 1933 at the Chicago Worlds Fair Sinclair
                    sponsored a dinosaur exhibit which included a two-ton animated model of a
                    apatosaurus. In 1964 at the New York City Worlds Fair, Sinclair displayed an
                    exhibit featuring nine life-sized dinosaurs highlighting its unique association
                    with the age of the dinosaur--an age representative of the beginning of the
                    formation of crude oil.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials from the Sinclair Oil Company, related to its
                    use of dinosaurs in company marketing and also its connection with the Teapot
                    Dome Oil scandal. Materials in the collection include: photographs from the
                    Chicago Century of Progress Exhibition, 1933; Dinoland at the New York World's
                    Fair, 1964-1965; photographs from the American Museum of Natural
                    History/Sinclair Dinosaur Expedition in 1934; and booklets, brochures, stamps,
                    clippings, and ephemera from the Sinclair dinosaur advertising campaign. The
                    collection also includes a series of letters to Bruce Quayle from various
                    natural history museums in response to his queries about dinosaur exhibits
                    (1964-1965). Documents related to the Teapot Dome case include letters to
                    stockholders from Robert W. Stewart, John D. Rockefeller, and Winthrop W.
                    Aldrich and photocopies of newspaper articles about the case.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>