<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Stephen T. Harty papers <date type="inclusive">1918-1999</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1950s-1980s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Stephen T. Harty papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC038</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1918-1999</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1950s-1980s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Stephen T. Harty was an artist-naturalist in the Exhibits Department of the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia from 1956 to 1982. He was
                    responsible for many of the dioramas at the Academy. He was director of the
                    Expeditions for Everyone program from 1972 to 1977, and established the "Rare
                    Bird Branch," a group of people who supported the program. Harty retired from
                    the Academy in 1982. He was interested in ornithology, and was a member and past
                    president of the Delaware Valley Ornithological Club.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of scrapbooks, birding notes, and materials related to
                    Harty's career with the Academy of Natural Sciences. Included are photographs
                    and diagrams of Harty's work on the Academy's dioramas; birding journals,
                    including location information, date, and a description of the circumstances of
                    the observation; correspondence related to work Harty did on Barro Colorado
                    Island; schedules and newsletters from the Expeditions for Everyone program
                    (1973-1978); newsletters and member lists for the "Rare Bird Branch";
                    photographs taken by Harold T. Green in Africa and photos of Green from his
                    military service; photos possibly taken by Charles Mohr of caves and cave fauna;
                    a Delaware Valley Ornithological Club album (1965-1999); original watercolors of
                    birds by Richard Ellis; and an album of plates from Rodolphe Meyer de
                    Schauensee's The Birds of Venezuela.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 01:10</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Delaware Valley Ornithological Club records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>