<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas S. Stewart papers <date type="inclusive">1868-1953</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas S. Stewart papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC302</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1868-1953</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas Summerville Stewart (d. 1949) was curator of the Microscopical Department
                    of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. He graduated from the
                    University of Pennsylvania in 1895 and received his M.D. from the same
                    institution in 1904. In the field of medicine, his main interest was in the
                    x-ray. He was among the first to experiment with its varous uses. In the latter
                    half of his life, he focused on microscopy and photo micrography. He was a
                    member of the American Microscopical Society, a fellow of the Royal
                    Microscopical Society, and vice president and treasurer of the Leidy
                    Microscopical Society. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials related to microscopes and microscopy collected
                    by Thomas S. Stewart. Microscope and lens manufacturers and supplies represented
                    in the collection include Bausch and Lomb, Ernst Leitz, Inc., Arthur H. Thomas
                    Company, Charles Lentz and Sons, and Williams, Brown, and Earle. Materials
                    include: price lists and catalogs for microscopes and lenses; printed matter
                    from the New York Microscopical Society and the Leidy Microscopical Club; a
                    series of microscopic preparations on human anatomy (3 sets of 10); and prints
                    of microphotographs. The collection also includes a handwritten manuscript of an
                    article by Thomas C. Stewart entitled "Photo Micrography," and the text of a
                    talk he gave at the Academy in 1941 on the history and use of the microscope.
                    There is a small batch of correspondence of Thomas C. Stewart, related to the
                    disposition of his father's microscope collection. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 07:04, 04:11</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>