<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Virginia Orr Maes papers <date type="inclusive">1950-1986</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Virginia Orr Maes papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1888</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1950-1986</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Virginia Orr Maes (1920-1986) was a marine malacologist who worked at the Academy
                    of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. She attended Wellesley College from 1938 to
                    1940. Her interest in malacology was sparked by a course in the subject given in
                    the 1950s by John Dyas Parker, who was an assistant to Henry Pilsbry. Maes
                    volunteered at the Academy and later became a Scientific Assistant in the
                    Department of Mollusks (later called the Department of Malacology). She worked
                    with Pilsbry, then with R. Tucker Abbott. Upon her marriage to Robert Maes, she
                    gave up her salary and became a research associate. In 1970, she was appointed
                    Research Fellow, the position she held until her death in 1986. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Virginia Orr Maes. Materials in the
                    collection include: incoming and outgoing correspondence; species notebooks
                    which include bibliographic references, often with photographs, illustrations
                    and extracts from the citation pasted in; notes, sketches and photographs of
                    specimens; notes, tables of dimensions and ratios, illustrations, and
                    manuscripts of articles (1959-1965) often accompanied by a printed version;
                    computer printout of Maes specimens in the collections of the Academy of Natural
                    Sciences; figures, plates, negatives, and a reprint of Littoral Marine Mollusks
                    of Cocos-Keeling Islands (1967) and a species location file for specimens she
                    collected in the Cocos; and photos and journals from a 1950-1951 trip to Africa.
                    The collection also includes obituaries of Maes, letters of condolence to her
                    husband, correspondence related to the Virginia Orr Maes Memorial Fund; and
                    several personal photos. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>