<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Visual Resources for Ornithology (VIREO) records <date type="inclusive">1950-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Visual Resources for Ornithology (VIREO)
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1095</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>25.9 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1950-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>VIREO (Visual Resources for Ornithology) is the most comprehensive bird image
                    bank in the world. Started in 1979 to provide a centralized, well-curated
                    collection of avian photos for scientific and public use. VIREO contains more
                    than 130,000 images representing over 6,650 bird species from around the world.
                    Contributors to the collection include some of the world's most talented
                    wildlife photographers.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of photographic material and correspondence related to the
                    VIREO database. The collection includes photographs by Harvey Fisher, Leslie
                    Brown, and Allan Cruickshank, in a variety of formats, including film and glass
                    negatives, color and black and white transparencies, black and white prints, and
                    motion film (the films are housed with the Academy's A/V materials). Records in
                    the collection consist of correspondence (1982-1987) with photographers;
                    proposals for funding the program; documentation related to structuring
                    information, such as classification of habitats and keyword terms; and nine
                    accession notebooks, listing images sent to VIREO from various
                    photographers.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 94: 12(?) Greenewalt; 03:01</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Crawford H. Greenewalt papers and John S. Dunning
                    papers. </p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>