<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Walter M. Benner field notebooks <date type="inclusive">1882-1951</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Walter M. Benner field notebooks</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1868</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.38 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1882-1951</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Walter M. Benner (b. 1888) was a botanist at the Academy of Natural Sciences of
                    Philadelphia. He received his master's degree and Ph.D. from the University of
                    Pennsylvania and began as a research associate at the Academy in 1928. He was
                    appointed acting chairman of the Botany Department in 1958. He conducted many
                    field trips in Pennsylvania, New Jersey, Maryland, and Delaware, and in 1932 he
                    published The Flora of Bucks County, Pennsylvania.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the field notebooks and collection records of Walter
                    Benner. The volumes include a collection record which lists specimen number,
                    name, date, and location; lists of plants collected or recorded from trips to
                    Pennsylvania, New Jersey, and elsewhere, between 1913 and 1951; a notebook with
                    descriptions of plants, possibly transcribed from a number of botanical
                    reference works; a botany journal possibly transcribed from journals kept by the
                    Ruth brothers (John A. and Harvey F. Ruth, d. 1904?) between 1882 and 1914; and
                    an annotated copy of The Flora of Bucks County, Pennsylvania, 1932.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>