<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wharton Huber papers and photographs <date type="inclusive">1898-1943</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wharton Huber papers and photographs</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC015</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>13.6 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1898-1943</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Wharton Huber (1877-1942) was an ornithologist and a mammalogist. He was
                    assistant, and later associate, curator of the collection of birds and mammals
                    at the Academy of Natural Sciences from 1920 to 1934. In 1934 he became curator
                    of mammals, a post he held until his death in 1942. He was a three-time
                    president of the Delaware Valley Ornithological Club, and also a staff member of
                    the Wistar Institute of Philadelphia, where he assisted in making anatomical
                    preparations. An enthusiastic collector and field man, he excelled in
                    photographing birds and mammals in their native haunts.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of photographs and papers of Wharton Huber. Photographs make
                    up the bulk of the collection and include glass and film negatives, contact
                    sheets, and prints. Subjects Huber photographed include birds, animals, plants,
                    landscapes, Apache Indians, and Huber's home and family. His photographs
                    document his trips to Nicaragua, Cape Cod, the Pacific coast, and New Mexico.
                    Papers in the collection include diaries from his trips to Nicargua (1922) and
                    the Queen Charlotte Islands (1930); correspondence about the collection of skins
                    and specimens; letters of introduction; brochures and announcements; and several
                    pamphlets for the Ludwick Lecture Series.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Papers and diaries from John C. McMichael</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 2005</p>
                <p>Accession number: 00:16 and 07:02</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Wharton Huber correspondence and photographs
                    (collection 755) and Huber-Stone correspondence (collection 186).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>