<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Wilhelm Bock papers and photographs <date type="inclusive">1944-1964</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Wilhelm Bock papers and photographs</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC039</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1944-1964</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Wilhelm Bock (1897-1972) was born in Poland, and served in the German artillery
                    and air force in World War I. In the 1930s, he emigrated to the United States,
                    becoming a citizen sometime after 1946. He was trained in mechanical engineering
                    and owned a small manufacturing firm in North Wales, Pennsylvania. He took up
                    the study of Triassic fossils, and joined the Academy as a research associate in
                    the former Department of Geology and Paleontology. In the early 1960s organized
                    The Geological Research Foundation, apparently in his home, to provide advice to
                    local communities about matters concerning water supply, but the organization
                    never became active. Remnants of Bock's collection of fossils are at the
                    Academy, though a large part of his collection is now lost.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence, photographs, notes and drawings of
                    Wilhelm Bock. Photographs are black and white images of plant and animal
                    fossils. Correspondence relates to his research and his collection of specimens.
                    The collection also includes a list of items in Bock's fossil collection and a
                    map of Stafford County, Virginia.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 01:13</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>