<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William W. Cadbury letters and watercolors <date type="inclusive">1945-1956</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William W. Cadbury letters and watercolors</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1953</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1945-1956</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William W. Cadbury (1877-1959) was a physician, Quaker missionary and botanist
                    who collected and studied orchids and ferns. After interning at the Pennsylvania
                    Hospital, he went, in 1909, to China as a missionary and took as position as
                    Instructor in Materia Medica and Therapeutics at the University Medical School
                    in Canton. He taught at the Hackett Medical College for Women, also in Canton.
                    Later he became chief of internal medicine at Canton Hospital and served as
                    physician to Canton Christian College. He left China in 1949, returning, via New
                    Zealand, to New Jersey, where he spent the remainder of his days.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence of William W. Cadbury and a series of
                    paintings of Chinese orchids. The correspondence consists of letters to Cadbury
                    and carbon copies of letters from him. Correspondents include colleagues in the
                    United States, China, Japan, and New Zealand. Many of the letters discuss the
                    identification of fern specimens. Some of the letters, written while Cadbury
                    lived in China, touch upon the political climate in China. The collection also
                    includes nine watercolor paintings of Chinese orchids signed "Gomez,"
                    commissioned by William Cadbury.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences: William Warder Cadbury papers (collection 732); Haverford College:
                    various William Warder Cadbury biographical materials.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>