<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Witmer Stone papers <date type="inclusive">1869-1939</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Academy of Natural Sciences</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Witmer Stone papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">AoNSp.ACC1907</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Academy of Natural Sciences<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1869-1939</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Naturalist, botanist, zoologist, editor and historian, Witmer Stone came to the
                    Academy of Natural Sciences in 1888 just after graduating from the University of
                    Pennsylvania. His first connection with the Academy was as a Jessup Student, but
                    his long association lasted more than fifty years and while at the Academy he
                    was concerned with scientific observations and administrative work. As an
                    executive he was Assistant Curator, 1891-1908, Curator, 1908-1924, Director,
                    1924-1928, and Director, 1929 on. However, from 1927 to the date of his death he
                    was also a vice president of the Academy. His writings concern birds, mammals,
                    reptiles, plants, butterflies and land mollusks in the scientific field, and
                    historical notes and biographies of scientists in the field of humanities. He
                    was acutely interested in people and the organization of groups for study and
                    discussion. As a boy he and his brother Frederick with their neighbors Amos and
                    Stewardson and other Brown brothers organized a group called the Wilson Natural
                    Science Association. This met weekly in the Stone home and was concerned with an
                    attempt to study all the plants, animals and minerals in the vicinity of their
                    Germantown residences. Later, he helped to organize the Delaware Valley
                    Ornithological Club, the Philadelphia Botanical Society and the Pennsylvania
                    Audubon Club. He was also very active in the American Ornithologists' Union and
                    the American Society of Mammalogists.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Witmer Stone. Materials include: notes,
                    bibliographic references, and handwritten and typed manuscript pages for Stone's
                    history of ornithology and for his biographical articles for the Dictionary of
                    American Biography; photographs of the Stone family and copies of photographs
                    from the Academy's 1890 expedition to Mexico and the Yucatan; Stone's diary from
                    the 1890 expedition, which include pen and ink drawings, maps, photographs, and
                    clippings; a handwritten account of an 1889 expedition to York Furnace, PA,
                    compiled by Stone and other expedition members, which includes photographs and
                    drawings; several books of Stone's drawings in pen, pencil, and watercolor, on
                    various animals and plants; proceedings of the Wilson Natural Science
                    Association of Germantown, which include essays written by members; a volume of
                    testimonial letters to Stone; and awards and certificates.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Academy of Natural
                    Sciences of Philadelphia: Witmer Stone correspondence (collections 450 and 752),
                    Witmer Stone writings (collection 72), and Witmer Stone biographical papers
                    (collection 263).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>