<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Administrative Personnel Association of the Presbyterian Church
                        records <date type="inclusive">1976-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Administrative Personnel Association of the Presbyterian
                    Church records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC097</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1976-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joyce P. Bauer organized the Presbyterian Secretarial Association, PCUS, in 1976.
                    The association changed names in 1984 to the Administrative Personnel
                    Association. Prior to reunion in 1983, the association welcomed the
                    participation of administrative personnel of the UPCUSA.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Scrapbooks document the annual meetings of the Administrative Personnel
                    Association as well as yearly business activities. Scrapbooks include minutes,
                    photographs, regional reports, correspondence, bylaws, budgets and financial
                    reports, pamphlets, and other memorabilia, as well as issues of the association
                    newsletter, called variously: The Girl Friday, The Latest News, and APA News.
                    Scrapbooks cover the following years: 1976-1982, 1978-1986, 1984, 1987-1990,
                    1990-1991, 1992-1994, 1999, 2000, and 2001. The 2001 scrapbook also includes a
                    small amount of material for 2002 and 2003. Additionally, there are national
                    conference scrapbooks for 2002 and 2003.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Bauer, Joyce P., APA (via Lindsay Crosby)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 03 0519, 04 0827i</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>