<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Alexander E. Sharp papers <date type="inclusive">1953-1971</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Alexander E. Sharp papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC841</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953-1971</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Alexander E. Sharp (1903-1989) was Chairman, Policy and Strategy Committee, and
                    Vice Chairman, Division of Home Missions, National Council of the Church of
                    Christ in the U.S.A.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Alexander E. Sharp. Materials include: minutes
                    of the Board of Managers, Central Department of Field Administration, 1954;
                    minutes of the Executive Board of Home Missions, 1953-1957; budgets and
                    treasurer's reports, Division of Home Missions, 1957-1961; a small amount of
                    Central Department of Research and Survey correspondence; and reports and
                    studies. The collection also contains files of John Courtney Smith from
                    1966-1971. Materials include: minutes of various committees, including the
                    Working Group of the Bishop's Committee for Ecumenical and Interreligious
                    Affairs and the NCC; reports of the Study Group of the NCC and the Roman
                    Catholic Church; copies of the constitution and by-laws of the NCC, 1966; policy
                    statements; and memoranda. Additionally there is some correspondence, reports
                    and and other papers of Theophilus M. Taylor, 1968-1970. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 68 0286</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>