<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Waldensian Society records <date type="inclusive">1853-1996</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1900-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Waldensian Society records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC934</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>29.40 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1853-1996</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1900-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1906, through the initiative of church forces in New York City, Waldensian
                    interest groups were invited to coalesce into a new entity, the American
                    Waldensian Aid Society (AWS), organized “to collect funds and apply the same to
                    the aid of the Waldensian Church in Italy and elsewhere…and to arouse and
                    maintain interest throughout the US in the work of said Church…” Today, this
                    organization continues as the American Waldensian Society.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the American Waldensian Society and its local
                    branches. Materials from the offices of directors of the Society include:
                    incoming and outgoing correspondence of Executive Directors Charles W.
                    Arbuthnot, Gilbert Colgate, Frank Gibson, Genevieve Lowry, and Harold B. Noyes;
                    subject files; annual reports; and newsletters and pamphlets. The correspondence
                    discusses financial matters, tours and visits, aid to churches and individuals,
                    and society business. There are also minutes of the Executive Committee of the
                    Board of Directors, including reports, articles of incorporation, and by-laws.
                    Financial records include bequests, bank and investment statements, remittances
                    and transmittals, audit reports, and tax records. Records related to branches of
                    the Society include: correspondence, reports, and lists of contributions, as
                    well as files on visits and tours. There is additional documentation of the
                    Montclair branch of the society, including minutes and scrapbooks of
                    invitations, announcements, and clippings. The collection also includes material
                    (some in French and Italian) relating to publication of the book You Are My
                    Witnesses, including pages of translations, correspondence, and drafts; letters
                    to Mrs. Gilbert Colgate, circa 1908; photographs and photo albums; and pamphlets
                    on the Free Christian Church of Italy and the Evangelical Church of Italy,
                    1853-1890, one in French. These pamphlets predate the formation of the American
                    Waldensian Aid Society; they appear to have belonged to the Evangelical Church
                    of Italy and the Waldensian Society of Germantown.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accession 96 0326, 96 0822, 89 0511, 84 0319, 96 0213b, 96 0322c:
                    Gibson, Frank G., Jr.; accession 96 0522a: American Waldensian Society;
                    accession 86 0625, 90 1221d, 87 0630, 91 0107: American Waldensian Aid Society;
                    accession 92 0924, 97 0731e: Transferred from the library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 86 0625|96 0326|96 0522a|96 0822|92 0924|90 1221d|87 0630|91
                    0107|89 0511|84 0319|97 0731e|96 0213b|96 0322c|95 0321</p>
            </acqinfo>


            <otherfindaid>
                <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" xpointer="http://www.history.pcusa.org/collections/research-tools/guides-archival-collections/rg-487">http://www.history.pcusa.org/collections/research-tools/guides-archival-collections/rg-487</extref>
            </otherfindaid>







        </archdesc>
    </ead>