<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Society of Church History records <date type="inclusive">1908-2005</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Society of Church History records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC962</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.70 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1908-2005</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Founded in 1888, the American Society of Church History (ASCH) is dedicated to
                    the scholarly study of the history of Christianity and its relationship to
                    surrounding cultures in all periods, locations and contexts. The Society aims to
                    promote and stimulate the historical study of the Christian church and faith,
                    its figures and movements, in institutional and non-institutional settings.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection includes correspondence, minutes, lists of registrants, programs,
                    and reports related to annual American Society of Church History meetings
                    between 1942-1978, 1980-84, and 1994-2000; correspondence and related materials
                    for a Centennial volume and special issue of Church History; minutes, memoranda,
                    correspondence, and reports of the Centennial Planning Committee, 1979-1988;
                    applications for the Philip Schaff Centennial Award for Younger Scholars, 1985,
                    which include resumes, letters of references, and proposals; materials related
                    to annual meetings, 1985-1989; bound volumes of papers of the American Society
                    of Church History, 1908-1934, and a program for the ASCH winter meeting in
                    Seattle, January 2005. Other materials include a 1997 Johns Hopkins University
                    Press publishing proposal; correspondence related to setting up editorial
                    offices at Duke University, an autobiographical sketch by Winthrop S. Hudson;
                    and a copy of Henry W. Bowden, ed., A Century of Church History: The Legacy of
                    Philip Schaff (Carbondale and Edwardsville, IL: Southern Illinois University
                    Press, 1988).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: most accessions Miller, William B or ASCH; accession 00 1103b:
                    American Society of Church History (via Henry Bowden); accession Handy, Robert
                    T.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 89 0509a|89 0620|85 1003|00 1103b|04 1130a|90 0503a</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: American Society of Church History records (RG 162).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>