<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Protestant Association records <date type="inclusive">1853-1870</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Protestant Association records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1071</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.02 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1853-1870</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American Protestant Association began on Tuesday the 8th of November, 1842,
                    in the city of Philadelphia to halt the spread of Catholicism in the United
                    States. The constitution of the group begins: "Whereas, we believe the system
                    of Popery to be, in its principles and tendency, subversive of civil and
                    religious liberty, and destructive to the spiritual welfare of men, we unite for
                    the purpose of defending our Protestant interests against the great exertions
                    now making to propagate that system in the United States".</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection comprises two items: 1) a bound constitution and by-laws of the
                    American Protestant Association used by Sarah Wiley as commonplace book which
                    includes clippings of poems and inspirational passages, and mementos (book was
                    published in 1853, but clippings are undated); and 2) a "Resolution of
                    Condolence" given to the family of John C. Wiley, past R.W.G. Secretary and
                    member of the American Protestant Association's New York Lodge No. 3, dated
                    1870.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Transferred from the library; may have been donated by Edna Gibson
                    (along with a larger framed document, 2 x 3 feet) -- per note in collection.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 93 1021</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: American Protestant Association records (RG 323).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>