<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Sunday-School Union records <date type="inclusive">1821-1990</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1821-1940</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Sunday-School Union records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC060</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>21.98 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1821-1990</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1821-1940</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American Sunday School Union was organized in Philadelphia in 1817 as the
                    Sunday and Adult School Union. In 1824 its name was changed to the American
                    Sunday School Union. The Union drew from the Sabbath schools in Great Britain
                    founded by Robert Raikes, Esq. in 1782. Its purpose was two fold - to educate
                    children and adults and teach them to read through the use of booklets published
                    by the Union, and to send missionaries out to remote areas to bring Christ to
                    the frontier.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records and printed material from the American
                    Sunday-School Union. Included are financial records, records of the work of ASSU
                    committees, publications records, and copies of pamphlets and periodicals
                    printed by the Union. Financial and inventory records of the ASSU from the
                    nineteenth century to the early twentieth century include: check and cash books;
                    monthly and quarterly financial reports; sales records; inventories; and cost
                    books for publications. Other record books include: indexes to contents of
                    Sunday School journals and lesson helps; and lists of Sunday School men and
                    those authorized to borrow documents from the ASSU, as well as delegates to the
                    ASSU. The collection also includes assorted ASSU legal documents, including
                    deeds, wills, and copyrights. Minute books of meetings of the ASSU and its
                    committees from the nineteenth century to the mid twentieth century include:
                    minutes of annual meetings, 1825-1914; Board of Managers minutes, 1824-1832 and
                    1854-1910; Board of Officers and Managers minutes, 1845-1930; Accounts Committee
                    minutes, 1826-1829; Building Committee minutes, 1825-1856; Depository Committee
                    minutes, 1832-1860; Executive Committee minutes, 1836-1936; Finance Committee
                    minutes, 1860-1943; Missions Committee minutes, 1829-1962; and Publication
                    Committee minutes, 1825-1949. Other Committee records include: Missions
                    Committee salaries and expenses of agents and missionaries, 1833-1837; Missions
                    Committee schedule of missionaries and their support, 1888-1892; Publication
                    Committee binding records, cost books, letterbooks, registers of cuts, book and
                    manuscript lists, and a scrapbook containing cuts and articles used in
                    publications; and Union Bible and Prayer League Committee records, 1916-1927.
                    The collection includes a large number of books, pamphlets, periodicals, and
                    newsletters published by the ASSU. In addition, there are two copies of The
                    Harvey Boys, an 1837 ASSU publication for the blind, printed in large, embossed
                    English letters (rather than Braille); bound issues of Sunday-School at Home,
                    the ASSU Home Department quarterly; and American Missionary Fellowship
                    newsletters from the 1980s and 1990s. Other ASSU materials include: a lantern
                    slideshow for children; textile maps and a wall chart of the Holy Land;
                    scrapbooks of clippings; a scrapbook of facsimiles of Sunday school tickets (in
                    German); and photographs and engravings of ASSU staff and officers, circa
                    1850-1940.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accession 02 0705a, 02 0705: ASSU accession 05 0812m: ASSU? accession
                    90 1012, 94 0715d, 88 0407a, 98 0911c, 97 0306n, 97 0620, 98 0922, 98 0921, 94
                    1111f, 92 1116a: Transferred from the library accession 99 0105: United
                    Methodist Church, General Commission on Archives and History</p>
                <p>Accession number: 02 0705a|02 0705|90 1012|94 0715d|05 0812m|88 0407a|98 0911c|97
                    0306n|97 0620|98 0922|99 0105|98 0921|94 1111f|92 1116a</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: American Sunday-School Union records (RG 73) and
                    Philadelphia Sunday and Adult School Union records (accession 05 0603i).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>