<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American and Foreign Christian Union records <date type="inclusive">1830-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American and Foreign Christian Union records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC903</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.64 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1830-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American and Foreign Christian Union was formed in 1849. The Union was
                    comprised of three complementary missionary societies: the American Protestant
                    Society, the Foreign Evangelical Society and the Christian Alliance. By 1860 the
                    AFCU supported 73 workers in the U.S. and granted subsidies to help support 212
                    foreign workers. Most AFCU officers were leading members of the clergy who were
                    also active in other interdenominational benevolent societies. By 1884 the AFCU
                    focused solely on the American Church in Paris, which it had founded earlier.
                    The American Church in Berlin traces it roots to about 1865 when an American
                    Chapel was founded. Changing its name to the American Church in Berlin in 1886,
                    it made first contact with the AFCU in 1889. In 1914 the AFCU took on the
                    responsibility for managing a fund to support the American Church in Berlin. The
                    stated mission of the American and Foreign Christian Union is "to support the
                    International, English speaking, ecumenical churches whose ministries bear
                    witness to Jesus Christ. In partnership with our member churches, we will strive
                    to develop and manage a strong financial base to further their programs. We will
                    nurture and strengthen our alumni ties and lend support to the pastors,
                    leadership and members of these churches through our care and prayers."</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Included are minutes of AFCU annual meetings and executive and finance committee
                    meetings, 1974-2006, with some gaps; financial records, 1997-1998; a 1999 report
                    on the American Church in Berlin; budgets; reports; list of Board members; and
                    the constitution, 1983-1996. The collection includes a photocopy of the deed for
                    the 65 Quai d'Orsay property in Paris, dated 1925. Also included are research
                    materials used to write a history of the American Church in Paris, including
                    historical information about AFCU and the American Church in Paris; lists of
                    Pastors of the American church; notes on newspaper articles about the AFCU;
                    lists of materials in the archives of the American Church in Paris; photocopies
                    and photostats of records and articles on the American Church in Paris and its
                    clergy; as well as several bulletins and brochures from the American Church in
                    Paris, 1940s. Additionally, the collection includes a constitution and by-laws;
                    tax exemption forms; records of files at the Presbyterian Historical Society;
                    historical background documents; copies of articles and printed materials on the
                    American Church in Berlin and some about the American Church in Paris; AFCU
                    minutes, 1966-1974; AFCU correspondence, 1974-1983; flyers; newsletters;
                    programs for American Church in Paris events; reports; correspondence related to
                    the American Church in Berlin; a cookbook of the American Church in Berlin; and
                    a calendars of events.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Bumpas, W. M.; accession 01 0618: AFCU (via Richard E. Bright);
                    accession 84 0626: Herman, Stewart W; accession 83 0831: Barnes, Dr. Roswell;
                    accession 89 0907: Dixon, Mrs Roger</p>
                <p>Accession number: 83 0831|96 0806|89 0907|84 0626|99 0727b|01 0618| 94 0707a|95
                    0707b|</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: American and Foreign Christian Union records (RG 118); New
                    York University: Papers of the American and Foreign Christian Union (MC 20).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>