<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Andrew Watson papers <date type="inclusive">1868-1898</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1880-1898</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Andrew Watson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1062</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1868-1898</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1880-1898</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Andrew Watson (1834-1916) emigrated with his parents from Scotland to Waukesha,
                    Wisconsin. He was later educated at both Princeton and Pittsburgh Theological
                    Seminaries and also attended Jefferson Medical College, Philadelphia, for some
                    medical courses. After his ordination in 1861, Andrew Watson applied and was
                    appointed to the UPCNA's Egypt Mission. He served in Alexandria and later
                    Mansurah for the first few years and then was sent to Cairo, where he spent the
                    bulk of his career. During his years of service in Cairo Andrew Watson was
                    professor and later head of the Mission Theological Seminary in Egypt. He also
                    was the Moderator at the General Assembly Meeting in Baltimore in 1890 and in
                    1897 he published "History of the American Mission in Egypt." He was involved
                    in reorganizing the civil and political status and relations of the native
                    Protestant communities in Egypt which led the Sultan of Turkey to officially
                    recognize their legal rights. In 1900 he headed a committee to pioneer the
                    establishment of an American Mission in Sudan and in 1910 he was a delegate to
                    the World Mission Conference at Edinburgh. Andrew Watson died in the field in
                    1916 and was survived by his wife, Margaret McVicker Watson, and his sons,
                    Charles and Frederick.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of nineteen diaries of Andrew Watson, 1880-1898, kept during
                    his time at the American Mission in Cairo, Egypt. Diary entries give brief
                    accounts of daily activities; the 1882 volume provides slightly more detail of
                    daily activities, lessons given, bible and other readings, visitors, and brief
                    descriptions of local events, including movements of English troops. Some of the
                    diaries also include accounts, bible class rolls, and lists of sermons preached.
                    The collection also includes a visa document for S. C. Ewing dated 1868.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Transferred from the library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 93 0208d</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Andrew Watson papers (RG 210).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>