<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Archie R. Crouch papers <date type="inclusive">1936-1982</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Archie R. Crouch papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC945</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1982</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Archibald Roy Crouch (b. 1909) received his B.Th. from Princeton Theological
                    Seminary in 1933. He also received a master's degree from Corness University and
                    a Ph.D. in sociology from the University of Southern California. He was Pastor
                    in churches in California and Minnesota and began Missionary work in China in
                    1936. He taught English in Ningpo and performed emergency war work there, 1938
                    and 1939-1941. He also taught English in Shanghai from 1938 to 1939. In 1946 he
                    returned to the United States, where he helped raise the Restoration Fund of the
                    Presbyterian Church, and organize the National Council of Presbyterian Men along
                    the Pacific Coast. Crouch was also Secretary for Communications of the COEMAR of
                    the UPCUSA. From 1950 to 1952 he was director of the Westminster Foundation at
                    the University of California in Berkeley. He published weekly columns in The
                    Cambrian and The Morro Bay Sun.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection includes labor activity reports written in Crouch's capacity as a
                    missionary. Activity reports include lists of meetings and speaking engagements;
                    summary statistics of meeting attendance; and staff hours and financial
                    statements, 1942-1969. There are reports of the Furlough Fellowship, 1942-1947;
                    the National Council of Presbyterian Men, 1949-1950; Westminster Foundation,
                    1950-1952; the Western Area Office (of which Crouch was Secretary) of the
                    Commission on Ecumenical Mission and Relations (COEMAR), 1952-1960; and from the
                    communications office of COEMAR, 1961-1969. The collection also includes a
                    number of academic articles by Crouch on various topics related to his work in
                    China and Chinese history, philosophy, and religion (1940s-1980s). These include
                    guides to China mission resources in archives and libraries in Pennsylvania and
                    the United States, and "Dragon Scales," a series of Crouch's radio talks on
                    China, aired in 1941-1944. There are also pamphlets and printed materials on
                    Chinese history, politics, and religion; newsletters; a scrapbook related to his
                    work in China, including clippings, correspondence, and photographs; and a
                    scrapbook of clippings of Crouch's "Ricksha Rambles" column, published in The
                    Cambrian (Cambria Pines, California), 1937-1941 and 1944-1946.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Crouch, Archie R.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 87 0915</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Mildred Orr Tanner papers (RG 374) include a scrapbook of
                    Crouch's writings.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>