<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Association of Sunday School Teachers of Philadelphia records <date type="inclusive">1824-1831</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Association of Sunday School Teachers of Philadelphia
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC160</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.04 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1824-1831</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Originally called the Association of Male Sunday School Teachers of Philadelphia,
                    the object of the Association of Sunday School Teachers of Philadelphia was to
                    cultivate union among teachers, to devise and recommend the best methods for
                    conducting Sunday schools, and for extending their influence and efficiency.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection includes minutes of monthly meetings of the Association of Male
                    Sunday School Teachers of Philadelphia, 1824-1831. Minutes record routine
                    business and list topics of discussion and reports from visitations. Includes
                    constitution and by-laws, a list of member churches and superintendents of their
                    Sunday schools, and a list of the discussion questions addressed during the
                    Association's meetings. Questions relate to the structuring of classes,
                    increasing attendance and interest in Sunday schools, and some general matters
                    of curriculum.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: ASSU</p>
                <p>Accession number: 05 0603k</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>