<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Association of Statisticians of American Religious Bodies records
                            <date type="inclusive">1930-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Association of Statisticians of American Religious Bodies
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC045</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.29 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1930-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Association of Statisticians of American Religious Bodies (ASARB) brings
                    together statisticians and researchers who collect and publish information about
                    denominations and other faith groups in the United States. Every ten years,
                    ASARB compiles the Religious Congregations Membership Study, providing the most
                    comprehensive portrait of religious affiliation throughout the United States.
                    The Association was founded in 1935.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection includes minutes of annual meetings and executive committee
                    meetings, 1931-2006; annual meeting programs, agendas, handouts, and copies of
                    presentations; constitution and by-laws; directories of members; correspondence
                    of the secretary/treasurer, 1989-1993; 1990 Church Membership Study materials,
                    newsletters, questionnaires, studies and statistical reports; an audiocassette
                    recording of an interview with Otto K. Finkbeiner; correspondence, 1949-1960;
                    and religious census material, 1931-1960.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accessions 02 0131i, 03 0114: ASARB (via Jack Marcum); accessions 01
                    0502, 01 0810a: ASARB</p>
                <p>Accession number: 02 0131i|01 0502|03 0114|01 0810a</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>