<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Auxiliary Union of Pittsburgh for Promoting the Observance of the
                        Christian Sabbath records <date type="inclusive">1830-1867</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Auxiliary Union of Pittsburgh for Promoting the Observance
                    of the Christian Sabbath records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC140</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.04 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1830-1867</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Auxiliary Union of Pittsburgh and Vicinity of the General Union for Promoting
                    the Observance of the Christian Sabbath held its first meeting on March 2, 1830.
                    "The great means employed by this society to effect their design shall be the
                    influence of personal example, of moral suasion, with arguments drawn from the
                    oracle of God, from the existing laws of the country, appeals to the heart and
                    conscience of men and fervent supplication to the Lord of the Sabbath."</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of a volume of minutes of monthly meetings of the
                    Auxiliary Union of Pittsburgh and Vicinity of the General Union for Promoting
                    the Observance of the Christian Sabbath, 1830-1832. The volume includes the
                    organization's constitution, and receipts, 1835 to 1867, for moneys given by
                    Daniel Elliott and other members of the General Assembly's Board of Education to
                    students at the Western Theological Seminary.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Pittsburgh Theological Seminary</p>
                <p>Accession number: 05 0520d</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>