<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Bernard M. Taylor papers <date type="inclusive">1935-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Bernard M. Taylor papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1152</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1935-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Bernard M. Taylor (1906-2003) was born in Tallapoosa, Georgia. He completed his
                    high school education in West Philadelphia and graduated from Lafayette College
                    in 1928. Taylor entered Union Theological Seminary in New York and completed his
                    studies there in 1931. In that same year he married Anne Justice, of
                    Spartanburg, South Carolina, who was also at Union Seminary. Taylor was ordained
                    in 1931 and was immediately installed as pastor of the Olive Church, Clarion
                    Presbytery, in Oliveburg, Pennsylvania. In 1936, he accepted a call by Christ
                    Church in Alpine, Tennessee. He also served as Stated Clerk of Cumberland
                    Mountain Presbytery, Synod of the Mid-South, from 1942 to 1951. The Taylors took
                    a leave of absence in 1946 and returned to New York City where both earned
                    Master's Degrees in Christian Education from the Union Theological Seminary and
                    Columbia University. They returned to Alpine the following year and served there
                    until 1952 when they were called by Old Rehoboth Church (Maryland). Bernard
                    Taylor served as pastor of that congregation and as the Stated Supply for the
                    Gunby Church in Stockton, Maryland for five years. In 1957, he received a call
                    from the Georgetown and Coolspring Presbyterian Churches, and served as the
                    Moderator of New Castle Presbytery for one year. Bernard Taylor was installed as
                    Associate Pastor of the First and Central Presbyterian Church in Wilmington,
                    Delaware, in 1962 and remained there until his retirement in 1976.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers related to the Alpine Institute, Alpine Rural Life
                    Center, and Christ Church Presbyterian Church in Alpine. Materials include:
                    correspondence; typed histories and memoirs; printed material; newsletters;
                    church bulletins; photographs; slides; newspaper clippings; an audiocassette of
                    a recognition service for Bernard M. Taylor (1976); index cards of "contacts,"
                    including members of the church in Alpine; a video made for Overtown County
                    cable access television about Alpine (1986); Bernard Taylor's diaries,
                    1935-1941; a copy of Taylor's biography The Roadmaker; a photocopy of "A Parson
                    and Partner for All Seasons," a memoir by the Taylors; some materials related
                    to Taylor's pastorate of Old Rehoboth Church, Maryland; Christ Church parish
                    records (1943-1944); a small amount of financial records; leases and contracts
                    related to property of Alpine; and maps.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Taylor, Rev. Bernard</p>
                <p>Accession number: 97 1205|98 0826</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society. Bernard M. Taylor papers (RG 254).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>