<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Brooks family papers <date type="inclusive">1919-1983</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Brooks family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1120</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1919-1983</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Adin Paul Brooks (1892-1987) was a missionary in India from 1923 to 1958. He held
                    a Master's in chemistry from George Washington University and served in the
                    Chemical Warfare Service, Research Division of the U.S. Army before beginning
                    his missionary service. He retired in 1962. Marian Easter (Skinner) Brooks
                    (1893-1924) was the first wife of Adin Brooks. She was a missionary in India
                    from 1923 to 1924. Eleanor Nix-James Brooks (1904-1981), Brooks's second wife,
                    was born in Calcutta, India, and returned to that country in 1950 as a
                    missionary after marrying Brooks. Eleanor Brooks was a registered nurse and
                    midwife. Hattie Estella Brooks (1894-1979) was the sister of Adin Brooks. She
                    held bachelor's degrees from the from University of Illinois (in education and
                    psychology) and the University of Maryland (in home economics). She served as a
                    teacher of Home Economics at Allahabad Agricultural Institute.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of the Brooks family. Materials include:
                    correspondence; photographs and negatives; manuscripts; reminiscences; reports;
                    and clippings of Adin Paul Brooks, Marian Easter (Skinner) Brooks, Eleanor Mary
                    Nix-James Brooks, and Hattie Estella Brooks, relating to mission work at
                    Agricultural Institute of Allahabad, India. The collection also includes: a
                    diary of Hattie Brooks, 1945 and 1947; a 1918 letter written on a thin sheet of
                    aluminum; several scientific articles by A. P. Brooks; recollections of the
                    George P. Skinner family by A. P. Brooks; medical records of A. P. Brooks;
                    information on the Extension Study Project at Allahabad; typescript interview
                    with A. P. Brooks for Menaul Historical Society of Presbyterian Church; notes,
                    presumably made by Brooks after a meeting with Gandhi; and postcards.
                    Additionally the collection contains a number of photographs and negatives
                    including: photos of activities at the Agricultural Institute; one photograph of
                    Agricultural Institute students talking to Gandhi at Wardha in 1939; photos from
                    a trip to Chinaand to Kashmir; and photographs of the Brooks family in India
                    (group shots, landscapes, architecture, animals).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Hodgkinson, Darryl</p>
                <p>Accession number: 96 0116, 96 1105a</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>