<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Cameron P. Hall papers <date type="inclusive">1945-1986</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Cameron P. Hall papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC944</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.02 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1945-1986</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Cameron Parker Hall (1898-1987) was educated at Union Theological Seminary and
                    Edinburgh University. He was student pastor at the University of Wisconsin,
                    after which he was named director of the Department of Church and Society of the
                    United Presbyterian Church, USA. This position led to his selection as head of
                    the Department of Church and Economic Life in the Federal Council of Churches.
                    He remained in this post when the Federal Council was succeeded by the National
                    Council of Churches in 1950, continuing until his retirement in 1968. He was the
                    editor of the 11 volume series on Ethics and Economic Life published in the
                    1950s. Cameron P. Hall called a conference and edited a small volume published
                    by the National Council of Churches in 1963 titled On-the-Job Ethics.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection includes sermons as well as drafts of speeches and articles,
                    written in both his official capacity and out of personal interest, whose topics
                    include industrial labor relations, social and economic change, religion and
                    work, materialism, the People's Peace Movement, the arms race, and McCarthyism.
                    There is a a small quantity of material related to the Division of Church and
                    Economic Life of the National Council of Churches of Christ, including minutes,
                    memoranda, reports, pamphlets and a small number of newspaper clippings. There
                    are also photographs, an invitation to the inauguration of Lyndon Johnson and
                    drafts and copies of wills, 1975. The collection also includes drafts of an
                    autobiographical sketch by Hall from 1980.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accession 87 0727: Barnes, Roswell; accession 91 0306: Espy, R.
                    Edwin</p>
                <p>Accession number: 87 0727|91 0306</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>