<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Cecil Corbett papers <date type="inclusive">1968-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Cecil Corbett papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1151</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1968-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Reverend Cecil Corbett is a Nez Perce Native American, retired pastor, and former
                    president and chancellor at Cook College and Theological School in Tempe,
                    Arizona. He was also a founding member of the Native American Theological
                    Education Consortium, which later became the Native American Consulting
                    Committee (NACC). The NACC is comprised of sixteen Native Americans who
                    represent the synods of Alaska Northwest, Lakes and Prairies, Northeast,
                    Pacific, Rocky Mountains, Southern California and Hawaii, Southwest and Sun. The
                    committee provides representation for Native American members, churches and
                    communities within the Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection is of Cecil Corbett's administrative papers and records relating
                    to his work with the Native American Consulting Committee (NACC), which include
                    NACC minutes, reports, position papers, and proposals; printed copies of the
                    Indian Quest newsletter and records related to its publication; financial
                    records; correspondence and memoranda; subject files, including on topics such
                    as education, scholarships and legal issues; NACC membership lists; and Native
                    American Ministry policy statements of the Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: National Ministries Division, Racial/Ethic Ministries</p>
                <p>Accession number: 97 1110</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>