<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charles Brackbill, Jr., papers <date type="inclusive">1961-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charles Brackbill, Jr., papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC930</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1961-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles Brackbill, Jr. (b. 1921), was a Presbyterian minister who worked in
                    planning for radio and television broadcasting for the Presbyterian Church USA.
                    He was a 1948 graduate of Princeton Theological Seminary and did graduate work
                    at Union Theological Seminary. He was pastor at Madison Avenue Presbyterian
                    Church in Elizabeth, New Jersey, from 1948 to 1954, before becoming Associate
                    Executive and Director of Radio and Television of the Synod of New Jersey. In
                    1964 he was named Associate Chairman for Planning with responsibility for
                    long-range planning for the Division of Radio and Television of the UPCUSA.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Charles Brackbill related to his work for the
                    Division of Radio/TV of the UPCUSA. Materials include policy papers, market
                    analyses, reports, minutes, and planning documents. Specific items in the
                    collection include a 1961 packet on standards for local council broadcasting, a
                    1961 critique of religious radio by Brackbill, a 1961 New Jersey Council of
                    Churches yearbook of religious broadcasting, a 1966 five-year plan for the
                    Division of Radio/TV Audio-Visual of the UPCUSA, and minutes of the Ad Board,
                    1968.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Brackbill, Charles</p>
                <p>Accession number: 86 0116</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>