<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charles Chakerian papers <date type="inclusive">1934-1989</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charles Chakerian papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1108</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.83 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1934-1989</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles Chakerian (1904-1994) was a professor at McCormick Theological Seminary,
                    a sociologist, and an ordained Presbyterian minister. He taught for over 50
                    years and was also involved in children’s welfare and social work. He was a
                    consultant for both the Church World Service and Christian Children’s Fund. He
                    retired from McCormick Seminary in 1971. In 1975, while working with
                    Presbyterian Volunteer Services, Chakerian went to Taiwan to teach at the Tainan
                    Presbyterian College and Seminary. He stayed in that post for eight years, and
                    then worked for two years helping to organize the First Graduate Institute of
                    Social Work in Taiwan at Tunghai University.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes papers related to Chakerian's work with the Christian
                    Children's Fund and the Church World Services, including reports on Korea,
                    Vietnam, Brazil, Mexico, India, Taiwan, Laos, and other locations; material
                    related to CCF's Family Helper Project; reports and articles on inter-country
                    adoption; policy statements; meeting minutes from CCF; printed works by
                    Chakerian on topics related to Church social services; magazine clippings; and a
                    small number of travel notes and lecture notes. Materials from the Hartford
                    Seminary Foundation include articles by Chakerian on Church social work and
                    other topics, bulletins of the Greater Hartford Community Council, Connecticut
                    State Planning Board reports, and reports on Presbyterian Settlement Houses.
                    There is a small amount of correspondence and reports from his time at the
                    McCormick Seminary.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Chacerian, Juanita R.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 95 1011</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>