<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charles L. Tarter papers <date type="inclusive">1925-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charles L. Tarter papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1173</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.50 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1925-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles Lewis Tarter (1907-1997) was an African-American Presbyterian minister.
                    Tarter served at Saint Augustine Presbyterian Church, Paterson, New Jersey, from
                    1939 to 1961. From 1961 he served as supply pastor and visiting minister to
                    churches in New Jersey. During World War II Tarter served in Asia as a Captain
                    in the Chaplain Corps. After retirement in 1964 he worked as a Probation Officer
                    in Passaic County, New Jersey.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Charles L. Tarter. Materials include: notes for
                    sermons; personal notes; church bulletins from the St. Augustine Presbyterian
                    Church and other churches; newspaper clippings about Rev. Tarter and the St.
                    Augustine Church; memorial booklets for Tarter and his wife, Mauretta Veronica
                    Tarter (both from 1997); and Bureau of Vital Statistics forms recording
                    marriages performed by Tarter. The collection also includes a few personal
                    papers, including membership cards and photostatic copies of diplomas and
                    military certificates.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Dr. Ronald H. Watts (via McCloud, J. Oscar)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 98 0204</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>