<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Clifford J. Earle papers <date type="inclusive">1931-1969</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Clifford J. Earle papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC902</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1931-1969</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Clifford J. Earle (1904-1982) received his B.D. from McCormick Theological
                    Seminary in 1934. He was pastor of churches in Wisconsin and Illinois, including
                    the Second Presbyterian Church of Oak Park, Illinois (1943-1947). Additionally,
                    he was Chairman, Committee on Social Education and Action, Chicago Presbytery
                    (1943-1947); Moderator of the Chicago Presbytery, 1947-1948; Secretary for Study
                    and Research in the Office of Church and Society of the Board of Christian
                    Education; Secretary of the Office of International Affairs of the UPCUSA; a
                    consultant to the U.S. Mission to the United Nations; and author of How to Help
                    an Alcoholic (1952), and Alcohol and Christian Responsibility (1953).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Included in this collection are sermons (1934-1961); articles and speeches
                    (typescripts and some manuscripts) on a range of topics including alcohol, race
                    relations, the women's movement, Christianity and international relations,
                    faith, prayer, and the Christian experience; and reports from the Office of
                    International Affairs of the UPCUSA (of which Earle was Secretary), 1963-1966.
                    Additionally, there is a small amount of correspondence about the Church's 1967
                    Statement on China (including a letter from Henry Luce about the statement);
                    materials related to the Special Committee to Study Women in Society and in the
                    Church, including minutes, correspondence, and reports, 1967-1969; a report of a
                    1968 survey of United Presbyterian ministers on civil rights; a survey of
                    "Deliverances of the General Assembly of the Presbyterian Church of the USA
                    with reference to war and peace, 1706-1937"; and a small number of materials
                    related to the Wisconsin Christian Endeavor Union, including brochures,
                    newsletters, and reports, 1931-1939. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Earle, Mrs. J.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 83 0825</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>