<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Clifford Drury and William Pugh collection on World War II <date type="inclusive">1926-1980</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1940-1946</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Clifford Drury and William Pugh collection on World War
                    II</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC838</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1926-1980</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1940-1946</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Clifford M Drury (1897-1894) was an historian and bibliographer of Presbyterian
                    history and history of the Protestant missions of the Pacific Northwest. He was
                    born in Iowa and received his B.D. from San Francisco Theological Seminary in
                    1922 and Ph.D. from the University of Edinburgh in 1932. He was pastor of
                    churches in California, Shanghai, and Idaho, and a professor of church history
                    at San Francisco Theological Seminary, 1938-1963. From 1944-1956 he was the
                    official historian of the U.S. Navy, Chaplain Corps. The Rev. Dr. William Barrow
                    Pugh (1889-1950) was a Stated Clerk of the Northern Presbyterians' General
                    Assembly. He was awarded the U.S. Medal for Merit for his wartime services as
                    chairman of the General Commission on Army and Navy Chaplains.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is an artificial collection compiled by Drury and Pugh which contains
                    publications by the PCUSA on services during World War II, as well as
                    non-Presbyterian material. Materials related to chaplains serving in World War
                    II include: publicity photographs of chaplains in the army and navy; training
                    manuals; and press clippings on Pugh. Materials related to social issues during
                    wartime include: pamphlets on refugees and POWs, housing, food and rationing,
                    and returning service personnel; pamphlets published by the Presbyterian
                    Committee on Camp and Church Activities; newsletters, including The World Over,
                    The Vital Speeches, Spiritual Issues and the War, and The Reporter (later called
                    The Reporter for Conscience's Sake); speeches; press releases from Church World
                    Service and other Presbyterian organizations; reports from the Washington
                    Council of Churches and Christian Education; and WCC reports on wartime
                    activities. There are also pamphlets and news clippings on relief work in the
                    Pacific Islands; war posters; published volumes; a small collection of wartime
                    publicity materials from Standard Oil, photographs from a celebration of the
                    150th anniversary of the Mare Island Naval Shipyard, and several magazines.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Drury, Clifford</p>
                <p>Accession number: 68 0177</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>