<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Clifford Merrill Drury papers <date type="inclusive">1910-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Clifford Merrill Drury papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC900</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Clifford M Drury (1897-1894) was an historian and bibliographer of Presbyterian
                    history and history of the Protestant missions of the Pacific Northwest. He was
                    born in Iowa and received his B.D. from San Francisco Theological Seminary in
                    1922 and Ph.D. from the University of Edinburgh in 1932. He was pastor of
                    churches in California, Shanghai, and Idaho, and a professor of church history
                    at San Francisco Theological Seminary, 1938-1963. From 1944-1956 he was the
                    official historian of the U.S. Navy, Chaplain Corps.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains many volumes of sermons by Drury. There are also
                    published and manuscript copies of Drury's writings, including chapters of his
                    autobiography; diaries with entries from 1938 and 1962-1964, 1968-1979; personal
                    and professional correspondence; some photographs, postcards and artwork from
                    Drury's travels in Asia and other countries and some historical information
                    about the U.S. Navy Chaplain Corps, as well as correspondence and annual reports
                    Drury wrote about his Chaplain activities during World War II. Also included are
                    clippings about Drury and awards; citations; honorary degrees and personal
                    memorabilia (passports, marriage and birth certificates, papers related to his
                    home); tax returns; and one audiocassette from a talk Drury gave in 1981 titled
                    "Following the trail of the Whitman."</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 83 0630</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Eastern Washington
                    State Historical Society/Northwest Museum of Arts &amp; Culture: Clifford M.
                    Drury Collection (Ms 17).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>