<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Clinton Bowman papers <date type="inclusive">1918-1954</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Clinton Bowman papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC919</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11.0 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1918-1954</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Clinton Bowman (b. 1890) was a Presbyterian minister. He was a 1915 graduate of
                    Louisville Theological Seminary, and served as a minister in churches in
                    Oklahoma and Illinois. During World War I, he was a chaplain in the U.S. Army.
                    In 1925 he was called to be pastor of the First Presbyterian in East St. Louis.
                    The congregation was divided for a time in the 1950s, with Rev. Bowman and a
                    minority of the congregation remaining at the church's original site, while the
                    majority of the congregation moved to a new site to the southeast. The group led
                    by Bowman became the Westminster Presbyterian Church of East St. Louis on
                    January 31, 1953. The two congregations merged in 1957.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is collection of papers of Clinton Bowman. Materials include: typed sermons,
                    with some notes, 1925-1954 (9 cubic feet); scrapbook of newspaper clippings,
                    programs, and announcements of marriages performed by Rev. Bowman, 1914-1917;
                    minutes, memoranda, and correspondence related to Bowman's position on the Board
                    of Trustees of Washington College; a small amount of correspondence related to
                    church matters in St. Louis; and photographs of Bowman. The collection also
                    contains materials related to Bowman's service as a chaplain for the 141st
                    Infantry during World War I, including memos, orders, correspondence,
                    photographs, postcards, maps, uniform patches, artifacts, and copies of the
                    Stars and Stripes, the Washington Times, and the East St. Louis Times from 1918
                    and 1919.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 85 0911</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>