<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Culver family papers <date type="inclusive">1845-1971</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Culver family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1046</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1845-1971</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Culver family included Rev. Theodore B. Culver, Annie W. Culver (possibly
                    Mrs. Theodore B. Culver), Rev. Andrew Culver (possibly Theodore's father), and
                    Annie Culver Boyd, wife of Rev. William Boyd and daughter of Andrew Culver and
                    Sarah White.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains correspondence and reports from the 1920s to 1940s. The
                    correspondence to the Culvers, most of which is addressed to Mrs. Culver
                    (Annie), is from various Chinese missions and missionaries, most notably from
                    the North China Presbyterian Mission in Peking. Correspondents include Florence
                    Logan, Mrs. J. P. Leynse, Ruth E. Dean and Helen P. Scott. Also included are
                    photographs and negatives of churches and mission schools, students,
                    missionaries, some general scenes of villages, towns, and people, and family
                    photographs of Culvers and Boyds as well as postcards. There are also notes for
                    sermons; a volume of marriage records (1848-1864); funeral records; letters from
                    Chinese church members; materials related to Culver's time at Grace Presbyterian
                    Church (Philadelphia), including newsletters (1907-1911) and parishioner lists;
                    and a small amount of material related to Ashbourne Church. The collection
                    contains oversize maps and broadsides and one oversize photograph.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Transferred from the library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 92 1119b</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>