<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Daisy Chase Russell papers <date type="inclusive">1920-1958</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Daisy Chase Russell papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC993</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.10 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1920-1958</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Daisy Chase Russell (1895-1990) was a graduate of Whitworth College, Spokane,
                    Washington, and studied at Biblical Seminary in New York before going to
                    Ethiopia as a missionary. Her husband was Fred Lawrence Russell, a graduate of
                    the State College of Washington. The Russells served as missionaries for the
                    Board of Foreign Missions, working primarily in Ethiopia. They were first
                    stationed in Dembi Dollo in the Sayo district, then in Addis Ababa, where Mr.
                    Russell was in charge of the mission office. They returned to the United States
                    between 1936 and 1943, when Ethiopia was occupied by Italy. During part of this
                    time, the Russells worked among American Indians in the Northwest. When they
                    returned to Ethiopia, they were stationed in Addis Ababa and then sent to Maji,
                    where they opened a new station. They retired in 1961.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of approximately 40 black and white glass slides. Subjects
                    include village scenes, patients in a medical clinic, buildings, portraits of
                    individuals and group photographs, and a procession.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Russell, Daisy Chase</p>
                <p>Accession number: 90 1010c</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>