<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Dick Wichman papers <date type="inclusive">1969-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Dick Wichman papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1177</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.17 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dick Wichman was a graduate of the University of California, Santa Barbara,
                    attended San Francisco Theological Seminary, and received a master's from
                    Berkeley's Baptist Divinity School. Wichman was pastor of a rural church in
                    Lakeside, California, and served on the staff of the Chinese branch of the YMCA
                    in San Francisco. Established in 1874, the Donaldina Cameron House serves the
                    Asian community in San Francisco, California. Dick Wichman worked as Executive
                    Director from 1947-1977. He was later revealed to have sexually abused at least
                    18 children while they were residents.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Dick Wichman. Materials include: memorabilia,
                    correspondence (including Christmas letters), publicity and a newspaper
                    clipping, and newsletters (Current) related to Cameron House and Wichman's
                    involvement. The correspondence is addressed to Mr. and Mrs. Roy Garten of
                    Oklahoma.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Garten, Jo W.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 98 0911f</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>