<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Donald Grey Barnhouse papers <date type="inclusive">1850-2000</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1850-1960</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Donald Grey Barnhouse papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC988</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>15.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1850-2000</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1850-1960</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Donald G. Barnhouse (1895-1960) was a Presbyterian minister and one of the
                    pioneers of radio preaching. He was pastor of the Tenth Presbyterian Church in
                    Philadelphia, president of the Evangelical Foundation in Philadelphia, and
                    editor in chief of Eternity Magazine. He began broadcasting radio sermons in the
                    1920s, eventually launching his own network program, "The Bible Study Hour."
                    In 1949 he began his famous study of Romans which continued each week for nearly
                    12 years until his death. This radio program continues to air as "Dr. Barnhouse
                    &amp; the Bible."</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of papers of Donald Barnhouse, including:
                    correspondence; magazine and newspaper clippings; publications, including copies
                    of "Broadcast Notes of the Bible Study Hour"; photographs; minutes, financial
                    and other reports of the Evangelical Foundation; scrapbooks; school notes; reel
                    to reel audio tapes of Barnhouse's addresses and sermons (1960); papers related
                    to several court cases; passports; biographical materials on Barnhouse collected
                    by Paul A. Hopkins; radio sermons; manuscripts for addresses, articles, and
                    books; sympathy letters sent to the "Bible Study Hour" and to Ruth Barnhouse;
                    diaries from Barnhouse's visits to foreign missions; appointment books; and an
                    herbarium. Also included is Barnhouse's personal correspondence, 1913-1927,
                    mainly with relatives, and several publications and other papers relating to his
                    military service during World War I. Images include daguerreotypes and prints of
                    Barnhouse family members; portraits of Barnhouse from 1899 into the 1950s; and
                    other prints documenting Barnhouse's activities and family during the 1920s
                    through 1950s. Post-1960 papers are biographical materials and references to
                    Barnhouse collected by the donor, Paul A. Hopkins. Also within this collection
                    is a bound run of Christian Alliance and Foreign Missionary Advance,
                    1890-1896.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accession 90 0605, 02 0221a: Hopkins, Paul A.; accession 85 1022a, 02
                    0610a: Barnhouse, Mrs. Donald</p>
                <p>Accession number: 90 0605|85 1022a|02 0221a|02 0610a</p>
            </acqinfo>


            <otherfindaid>
                <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" xpointer="http://www.history.pcusa.org/collections/research-tools/guides-archival-collections/rg-480">http://www.history.pcusa.org/collections/research-tools/guides-archival-collections/rg-480</extref>
            </otherfindaid>







        </archdesc>
    </ead>