<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>E. Bradford Davis papers <date type="inclusive">1973-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">E. Bradford Davis papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1133</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.50 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Edward Bradford Davis (b. 1921) received his B.D. from Yale Divinity School in
                    1945 and his Master's and Doctorate from Princeton Seminary 1950 and 1961. He
                    was pastor of churches in New Boston, New Hampshire, and Holmes, Pennsylvania,
                    before becoming pastor of the Presbyterian Church in Absecon, New Jersey from
                    1959 to 1966. He also served as pastor of the First Presbyterian Church, Darby,
                    Pennsylvania, starting in 1967. Rev. Davis served as senior pastor of the
                    Kensington United Presbyterian Larger Parish, the four-church complex in
                    Kensington, which was the first urban larger parish organized.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection includes newsletters (The Lamplighter); bulletins for regular and
                    special services; reports including annual reports, treasurer's reports, and
                    reports of senior pastors; minutes of congregational meetings; memoranda;
                    clippings; correspondence (some to the Presbytery of Philadelphia); and meeting
                    minutes related to the founding of the Kensington Larger Parish. There is also
                    one photograph of Davis and the pastors of Twelfth United Presbyterian, Fairhill
                    United Presbyterian, Beacon United Presbyterian and Wilkey Memorial United
                    Presbyterian.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Davis, E. Bradford</p>
                <p>Accession number: 96 1111b</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>