<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edward B. Paisley papers <date type="inclusive">1893-1961</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1934-1961</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edward B. Paisley papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC845</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1893-1961</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1934-1961</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Edward Bland Paisley (1890-1968), a Presbyterian pastor and educator, studied at
                    Arkansas College, Austin Presbyterian Theological Seminary, University of Texas,
                    and Yale. Paisley was the Educational Secretary of the Executive Committee on
                    Home Missions, Secretary of the Board of Christian Education's Graduate
                    Christian Education department, and a professor and later president of the
                    Assembly’s Training School for Lay Workers among several other positions. He was
                    affiliated with the PCUS and the PCUSA.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of professional and personal papers of Edward Paisley. The
                    collection includes incoming and outgoing correspondence, minutes, and reports
                    related to Paisley's work with the Graduate Christian Education department of
                    the BCE; correspondence, lecture notes, and printed educational materials
                    related to his work with the General Assembly's Training School for Lay Workers;
                    reports, annual meeting programs, and board of trustee minutes (1946-1949) of
                    the International Council of Religious Education; and minutes, proposed lesson
                    plans, and publicity materials from the Commission on Education. The collection
                    also includes general and personal correspondence files, 1932-1943; typescripts
                    of speeches and addresses made by Paisley; manuscripts by Paisley and others;
                    and printed catechisms and Presbytery manuals.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown; 134414 give by Mrs. E. B. Paisley</p>
                <p>Accession number: 68 0291|3:14-G-3 (or 13 4414?)</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Austin Presbyterian
                    Theological Seminary: Paisley (Edward Bland) papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>