<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edward Burgett Welsh papers <date type="inclusive">1850-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edward Burgett Welsh papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1010</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.50 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1850-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Edward Burgett Welsh (1881-1968) was a graduate of Wooster University and
                    attended Princeton Theological Seminary, receiving a D.D. degree. Welsh was the
                    pastor at the First United Presbyterian Church in Toronto, Ohio, where he served
                    from 1926 to 1939. He served in other churches in Ohio and Pennsylvania,
                    including the First Presbyterian Church in Coraopolis, Pennsylvania. A historian
                    of the Presbyterian church, Welsh was the author of Buckeye Presbyterianism.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Edward B. Welsh. Much of the material is
                    research for Welsh's book Buckeye Presbyterianism. Materials include:
                    typescripts and photocopies of drafts of Buckeye Presbyterianism, 1963-1968;
                    correspondence related to Welsh's research on the Free Presbyterian Church,
                    1943-1954; an index file of notes on church history; maps of Ohio showing
                    locations of churches and Presbyteries; floorplans for the library of the
                    College of Wooster, 1960; blueprints of the Welsh Presbyterian Church,
                    Philadelphia, 1926; and typed extracts of minutes of the General Assembly,
                    1793-1861. Church records include: marriage licenses, 1915-1951; Barkersville
                    (Evans Creek) Presbyterian Church Session Minutes (1871-circa 1876), Membership
                    Roll (1870s-1880s) and Baptismal register (c. 1871-1891); Linton Presbyterian
                    Church Session Minutes (1835-1855); Session Minutes of the Presbyterian Church
                    of Frankfort, Ohio (1851-1865); and the minister's license of R. B. Wilson from
                    Cambridge, Ohio, 1902. The collection also includes several scrapbooks: two
                    scrapbooks of "Photographs and Notes Illustrative of Pioneer Presbyterian
                    History in America" compiled by Welsh (many of the photographs and descriptions
                    are of churches in Pennsylvania and Delaware); a scrapbook of clippings
                    (1877-1895) from the United Presbyterian, Wayne County Herald (Wooster, Ohio),
                    and other papers; and a scrapbook of clippings from the Free Presbyterian and
                    the Anti-Slavery Bugle, 1850-1855.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Transferred from the library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 91 0130</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>