<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Eighth Street Wayside Mission records <date type="inclusive">1927-1956</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Eighth Street Wayside Mission records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC960</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1927-1956</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Eighth Street-Wayside Mission was the formed by the union of the Eighth
                    Street M.E. Mission and Wayside Presbyterian Mission in 1927. It was conducted
                    by a joint committee of ten: five Methodists and five Presbyterians. During the
                    summer months, the Mission was supported by the Summer Evangelistic Committee,
                    and during the rest of the year by the Trustees of the Presbytery of
                    Philadelphia. The Mission conducted evangelistic meetings and street meetings, a
                    Sunday school and welfare work for residents of the neighborhood.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains minutes of quarterly meetings, 1927-1946 of the Eighth
                    Street-Wayside Mission Committee, which include reports by members of the
                    committee, including the treasurer, and reports on the activities of the
                    Mission; and legal documents, such as an agreement of union between Eighth
                    Street M.E. Rescue Mission and Wayside Mission, 1927, and leases, 1948 and 1956.
                    There are several printed reports of the Presbytery of Philadelphia, Committee
                    on National Missions, 1936-1943, and also some correspondence about the merger
                    of the two missions, 1927.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Philadelphia Presbytery</p>
                <p>Accession number: 89 0105b</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Summer Evangelistic Committee of Philadelphia Presbytery
                    records (accessions 06 1212b and 05 0429b).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>