<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Elder family papers <date type="inclusive">1913-1986</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Elder family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1040</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.28 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1913-1986</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Elder (1894-1981) and Ruth Roche Elder (b. 1899) were appointed by the Board
                    of Foreign Missions to the East Persia Mission in 1921 and arrived in the field
                    in 1923. Throughout their 42 years of service, they were engaged in evangelistic
                    missionary work, initially in Kermanshah (1923-1934), the Hamadan (1934-1937)
                    and finally in Tehran (1938-1964). Dr. Elder served as the pastor of the
                    Persian-speaking congregations in each city. In 1935, he was Moderator of the
                    newly formed Eastern Presbytery of Iran and was elected Moderator of the Synod
                    of Iran in 1947 and 1960. In addition to numerous other activities, Elder wrote
                    diverse articles, pamphlets and books that were published in both English and
                    Farsi. The Elders retired from missionary service in 1964.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of daily diaries of Ruth Elder from the American
                    Mission, Kermanshah, Persia, 1915-1920 and 1924-1943; correspondence to and from
                    Ruth and John Elder; photographs (family and mission-related); typed articles by
                    Elder on scriptural topics; notes for the memoir "Memories of Life in Persia";
                    Christmas letters, 1950s-1970s; newsletters; church bulletins; sermons; and
                    tracts. The photographs of mission projects include those of a flood relief
                    project and an album of photos of the rebuilding of a school in Ismatabad
                    (rebuilt by the World Council of Churches after the 1962 earthquake).
                    Additionally, there is an audiocassette of the 1962 Easter service conducted by
                    John Elder in Iran.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accession 92 0330b: Transferred from the library; accession 93 0301,
                    94 1111i: Leake, Alice Elder</p>
                <p>Accession number: 92 0330b|93 0301|94 1111i|00 0504f</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Elder family papers (RG 189).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>