<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Elizabeth Vara McMurray Ellyson papers <date type="inclusive">1891-1891</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Elizabeth Vara McMurray Ellyson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC002</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1891-1891</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Elizabeth Vara McMurray Ellyson (1868-1958) was married to John Ellyson
                    (1862-1911). She was the daughter of Rev. John McMurray and Kisia Elizabeth
                    (Clamp) McMurray who died in 1880. Rev. McMurray graduated from Princeton
                    Seminary in 1860 and moved to Texas that same year as a missionary under the
                    charge of the Board of Domestic Missions. He was stated supply at a number of
                    churches and also worked as a schoolmaster. In 1867 he moved to Georgetown,
                    Texas, where he became master of the Georgetown Male and Female Academy and
                    served as stated supply of the Georgetown Presbyterian Church in Austin. He died
                    in 1912.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a scrapbook of newspaper clippings and other memorabilia documenting the
                    103rd General Assembly in Detroit (1891). Rev. McMurray was a delegate
                    representing Trinity Presbytery. The articles describe the addresses given at
                    the Assembly, reports from various boards and committees, activities and day
                    trips taken by attendees, and some biographical information about prominent
                    Presbyterian ministers in attendance. The scrapbook also includes a photograph
                    of W. Henry Green. Some of the clippings appear to be from The Herald and
                    Presbyter and the Detroit Free Press. Elizabeth Vara McMurray accompanied her
                    father to Detroit.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Johnson, John C., Jr.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 00 0914a</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>