<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Elwyn A. Smith papers <date type="inclusive">1919-1975</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960s-1975</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Elwyn A. Smith papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC857</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1919-1975</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960s-1975</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Elwyn Allen Smith (b. 1916) received his B.D. from Yale Divinity School and his
                    Th.M from Princeton Seminary. Smith served as a missionary in Philippines from
                    1945 to 1946. From 1945 to 1949 Smith was the Associate Youth Editor, Board of
                    Christian Education. From 1950-1956, Smith was Dean and Professor of Church
                    History, Dubuque Theological Seminary. He was Professor of Ecclesiastical
                    History and History of Doctrine at Western Theological Seminary in Pittsburgh
                    beginning in 1956. Smith is a former Professor of Theology and Vice-President at
                    Temple University and was the coeditor of the Journal of Ecumenical Studies at
                    Temple. Smith served as chair on the Task Force on the Middle East in the early
                    1970s.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Elwyn A. Smith. Materials include: manuscripts
                    and published versions of articles by Smith, as well as background and research
                    materials (including an Air Force training manual circa 1960); printed materials
                    and newsletters from organizations with which Smith was affiliated or related to
                    the topics of his historical research; reprints of articles by others and
                    several dissertations; correspondence related to writing and professional
                    activities; correspondence, minutes, reports, student papers, teaching notes,
                    and a grade book related to Smith's work at Temple as a faculty member and
                    administrator in the Religion Department, and as Vice President for Student
                    Affairs; meeting minutes, correspondence, and papers related to the American
                    Society of Church History; and family correspondence and photographs, as well as
                    information about his children. The collection also includes correspondence,
                    reports, drafts, policy statements, and printed materials related to the work of
                    the Task Force on the Middle East, 1972-1974. Many newsletters and printed
                    materials are from non-Presbyterian organizations, particularly Jewish
                    organizations.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accessions 72 0326, 99 0210: Unknown; accession 82 1018: Smith, Elwyn
                    A.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 72 0326|82 1018|99 0210</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>