<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Englishton Park United Presbyterian Ministries Inc. records <date type="inclusive">1958-1986</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Englishton Park United Presbyterian Ministries Inc.
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC933</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.04 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1958-1986</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Englishton Park Presbyterian Ministries (EPPM) Incorporated is a non-profit
                    organization, founded by the Presbyterian Church in 1952 to serve the needs of
                    the community. Originally the summer home of several generations of the English
                    family dating back to the mid-1800's, Englishton Park is now a multi-use campus
                    serving the community and the needs of children by providing them academic
                    remediation and education. EPPM is located on more than 300 acres in Lexington,
                    Indiana, approximately thirty miles north and east of Louisville, Kentucky.
                    Englishton Park, the large ancestral estate of William E. English was acquired
                    by the National Missions Committee of the Synod of Indiana in 1958. It was used
                    by the Committee for ministries with children and elderly persons. Programs
                    included the Roe-Seal Memorial Retirement Home, an Academic Remediation Program,
                    a Boys' Club Camp, a foster home, and workcamps and service projects.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection mostly consists of photocopies which are comprised of legal
                    documents related to the sale of a portion of the estate's land; articles of
                    incorporation, amended 1982; minutes of the Synod Assembly relating to
                    Englishton Park and the Presbyterian National Missions Homes, Inc.; and a 1966
                    report of the President of Presbyterian National Missions Homes, Inc. There are
                    also brochures for Englishton Park.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Engliston Park United Presbyterian Ministries</p>
                <p>Accession number: 86 0430</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>