<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Eugene Carson Blake papers <date type="inclusive">1906-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Eugene Carson Blake papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC939</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1906-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Eugene Carson Blake (1906-1985) was born in St. Louis. He graduated from
                    Princeton University in 1928 and spent the following year teaching English in
                    Forman College, Lahore, India (now Pakistan). He returned to his studies in
                    1929, spending a year at New College, Edinburgh, Scotland, and two years at
                    Princeton Theological Seminary, where he received a Th.B. in 1932. Blake married
                    Valina Gillespie in 1929. He served as pastor of churches in New York City,
                    Albany, and Pasadena, California, from 1932-1951. In 1951 he was elected Stated
                    Clerk of the General Assembly (PCUSA), a post he held until 1958. In 1958 the
                    PCUSA became the UPCUSA, and Blake was elected Stated Clerk of the UPCUSA
                    General Assembly; he served until 1966. From 1954-1957 he served as president of
                    the National Council of Churches, and in 1966 he became general secretary to the
                    World Council of Churches, from which he retired in 1972. Dr. Blake is noted for
                    his contributions to the 1967 confessional revision in the Presbyterian Church,
                    to the civil rights movement, to church union efforts, and to the WCC's world
                    development activities, as well as for his leadership in the WCC's Programme to
                    Combat Racism.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Eugene Carson Blake. Materials include:
                    correspondence, subject files, photographs, scrapbooks, and printed matter.
                    Papers including minutes, memoranda, reports, correspondence, press releases,
                    bulletins and other printed matter from Blake's term as president of the
                    National Council of Churches of Christ include materials related to the work of
                    the general board and various committees, 1953-1957. Materials from his post
                    retirement years (1970s and 1980s) include incoming and outgoing correspondence,
                    clippings, printed material (for example, magazines featuring Blake); minutes of
                    the Princeton Theological Seminary Board of Trustees; a copy of Blake's FBI
                    file; and a transcript of an 1982 interview of Blake and Roswell Barnes about
                    their 1956 trip to Russia. The Brackenridge files on Blake consist of articles,
                    copies of Blake's notebooks and correspondence, drafts of manuscripts of his
                    biography of Blake (some with Blake's annotations), reprints, speeches and
                    transcripts of interviews. Other items include: photographs (many portraits of
                    Blake, some with other religious leaders); scrapbooks (1906-1966) with
                    clippings, photographs, bulletins, programs, school records, and some
                    correspondence; scrapbook of citations and diplomas (1941-1966); oversized photo
                    albums of Blake's Christmas visits to North East Air Command (1955) and Alaskan
                    Command (1956); vestments; audiocassettes of sermons by others (including those
                    given at Blake's funeral); an audiocassette of an interview of Blake; and a
                    small number of personal files, including tax records, home insurance, and
                    pension records.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accession 86 0730, 68 0289: Unknown; accession 88 0803: Blake, Mrs.
                    Eugene Carson; accession 77 1001: Brackenridge, R. Douglas; accession 88 0407b,
                    92 0918a: Transferred from the library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 86 0730|88 0803|77 1001|88 0407b|92 0918a|68 0289</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Eugene Carson Blake papers (RG 3 and RG 121).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>