<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>First Day or Sunday-School Society records <date type="inclusive">1790-1964</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">First Day or Sunday-School Society records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC163</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1790-1964</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The First Day Society was formed in 1791. Early members included Rev. William
                    White (chairman), Benjamin Rush, William Currie, Thomas Mendenhall, Peter
                    Thompson, Jr., Mathew Carey (secretary), Thomas Pym Cope, Nathaniel Falconer,
                    and Joseph Sharpless. They felt that establishment of first-day or Sunday
                    schools "would be of essential advantage to the rising generation." The work
                    of the Society for the Institution of First-day, or Sunday Schools, in the City
                    of Philadelphia, and the districts of Southwark, and the Northern Liberties was
                    to aid needy Sunday schools of any denomination in Philadelphia by gifts of
                    library books or "lesson helps." The Board of Visitors included Rush, Currie,
                    Falconer, Samuel Powel, Benjamin Say, George Meade, and Samuel Fisher.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains two volumes of minutes, 1790-1964, and four volumes of
                    Board of Visitors minutes, 1791-1940. Minutes include treasurer's reports,
                    records of grants requested and approved, election of officers, memorial
                    minutes, and reports of visitors to Sunday schools around the Philadelphia area.
                    There are some typed reports and resolutions and printed memorial minutes pasted
                    or tipped in and one volume includes clippings of newspaper accounts of the
                    Society's annual meetings.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: ASSU</p>
                <p>Accession number: 05 0603o</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>