<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Geneva Academy Board of Trustees records <date type="inclusive">1865-1913</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Geneva Academy Board of Trustees records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC166</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1865-1913</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The town of Geneva, Kansas, was founded by free-state men in the summer of 1857.
                    The idea of the settlement began with ambition, but the establishment of and
                    building a large town never came to fruition; less than one fourth of the
                    projected 300 families engaged to settle came. Originally, it had been decided
                    to build a large structure and found a non-sectarian college and academy, but
                    through the lack of money and settlement the college was not built, though an
                    academy later took its place. The school had been established in 1866 under
                    charge of the Neosho Presbytery.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection is of the Geneva Academy Board of Trustees minutes and financial
                    records, 1865-1913. Minutes are from 1865-1913, with gaps. Minutes include the
                    constitution and by-laws of the Board of Trustees; plans for a building for the
                    academy; decisions about tuition, school rules, and leasing of rooms and records
                    of actions brought in court related to the occupancy rights to the building
                    (1873-1875). The volume also includes some financial accounting of the Academy.
                    Accounts from 1858-1860 may belong to L. L. Northrup, G. S. Northrup, or the
                    Union Settlement Company, but provenance is unclear.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Synod of Kansas</p>
                <p>Accession number: 05 0603r</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>