<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Geneva Forum records <date type="inclusive">1971-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Geneva Forum records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1146</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.0 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Geneva Forum was an organization for laity and clergy of the Presbytery of
                    Philadelphia to provide a place for open discussion of issues facing the church
                    within an evangelical context. Formed in 1971 during a period of "cleavage
                    between liberals and evangelicals," the Geneva Forum was spawned from the
                    Geneva Cleric, a group of ministers who met monthly for prayer and fellowship.
                    Once the Geneva Forum was formed, the officers of the Geneva Cleric continued as
                    the leaders of the Forum. The Forum was formally disbanded around 1997.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains minutes of the Geneva Forum, primarily from 1983-1994;
                    meeting announcements and flyers; banquet programs; by-laws; notes on officer
                    duties; lists of board members and officers; meeting agendas; list of programs
                    and speakers; and biographical information on speakers. There are also
                    manuscript notes and handouts from meetings and correspondence, largely of
                    invitations to speakers and logistical matters for meetings. Many of the papers
                    in this collection appear to come from the files of Paul E. Housworth and Robert
                    Bruce Wills.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Housworth, Paul E.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 97 0227a</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>