<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Harriet Nelson papers <date type="inclusive">1984-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Harriet Nelson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC936</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1984-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Harriet Ann Abbott Nelson (b. 1935) was Moderator of the 196th General Assembly
                    of the Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.), 1984-1985. Nelson and her husband John were
                    educators in Napa, California. Before being elected to this position, Mrs.
                    Nelson was active at every governing body level in the church: she served a term
                    as Moderator of the Presbytery of the Redwoods, was a member of the Program
                    Agency Board and United Presbyterian Women Committees, and was church organist
                    in Napa and Stockton. From 1963 to 1966 she and her husband served as
                    missionaries in Cameroon, West Africa, working at the Hope School in Elat.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Harriet Nelson's papers from her time as Moderator of the
                    General Assembly. Materials include: incoming and outgoing correspondence with
                    ministers, church members, and other leaders within the church; appointment and
                    travel schedules; clippings and newsletters about Nelson's election as
                    Moderator; several church bulletins, programs, and postcards; and a photograph
                    of Nelson. The correspondence relates to Nelson's visits to churches and
                    organizations as well as the statements and policies of the General Assembly on
                    matters such as Apartheid, abortion, and homosexuality.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Nelson, Harriet</p>
                <p>Accession number: 86 0626a</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>