<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Henry R. O'Brien papers <date type="inclusive">1926-1929</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Henry R. O'Brien papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1176</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.06 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1926-1929</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Henry Rust O'Brien (1891-1970) served in the U.S. Public Health Service's Bureau
                    of Mines in Pittsburgh, with the International Health Board of the Rockefeller
                    Foundation in Thailand from 1921 to 1924, and with the Board of Foreign Missions
                    of the Presbyterian Church in the USA, serving in Chiang Mai, Thailand, as a
                    member of the staff of the McCormick Hospital. His wife, Mary L. Phillips Carr
                    O'Brien, served in Thailand alongside him. The couple returned to the United
                    States in 1931.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence, reports and photographs from the
                    O'Briens' time serving as missionaries in Chiang Mai, Thailand. Photographs
                    include an image of the Chiang Mai Mission Group, 1929, and an image of the cook
                    at Chiang Mai Mission, 1929. The correspondence dates from 1926 to 1929 and is
                    sent from Mary Lou O'Brien to Mrs. Jones and "Friends" (possibly meaning
                    members of the sponsoring church). One letter of three pages is in the form of a
                    poem, made up of rhyming couplets. The collection also includes two reports
                    written by Mary Lou O'Brien in 1928.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Fenn, Martha</p>
                <p>Accession number: 98 0908</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Henry Rust O'Brien papers (RG 394).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>