<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Herbert Booth Smith papers <date type="inclusive">1864-1975</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1937-1975</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Herbert Booth Smith papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC874</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1975</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1937-1975</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Herbert Booth Smith (1883-1967) was the son of Rev. Joseph Addison Smith. Smith
                    received his arts degree in 1905 from Washington University and his A.M. degree
                    from Princeton in 1908. He graduated from the Princeton Theological Seminary the
                    following year. Smith was ordained as a Presbyterian minister in 1909 and took a
                    pastorate in Rochester, New York, and later Knoxville, Tennessee. In 1916 he
                    moved to Los Angeles to take the pulpit of Immanuel Presbyterian Church. Smith
                    was a past president of the Los Angeles ministerial association and a director
                    of the Los Angeles Board of Church Extension. He was moderator of the Presbytery
                    of Union in 1915 and of the Presbytery of Los Angeles in 1928. In 1913 he was a
                    delegate to the Waldensian Synod which met in Italy. He was also a commissioner
                    to the meetings of the General Assembly of the Presbyterian Church held in St.
                    Louis (1919), Columbus, Ohio, (1925), San Francisco (1927), and Pittsburgh
                    (1931).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Herbert Booth Smith. Materials include: sermons
                    by Smith and others; printed materials and text of speeches given by Smith on
                    alcoholism; and printed materials related to the annual congregational meetings
                    of the Ventura Community Church, 1961-1969. The collection also includes papers
                    related to Smith's coursework at San Francisco Theological Seminary and a
                    chapter of Smith's thesis on Thomas Fraser. The collection also includes
                    originals and transcripts of letters by Thomas Fraser written to his wife in
                    1864. Fraser was the subject of Smith's thesis. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Smith, Mrs. H.B.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 77 1011</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>