<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Hoisington family papers <date type="inclusive">1913-1970</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1930-1960</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Hoisington family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1073</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1913-1970</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1930-1960</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Herbert Alton Hoisington (1882-1943) and Eunice Julia Kingsbury Hoisington
                    (1885-1976) served the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. as lay foreign
                    missionaries in Cameroon, West Africa. Herbert Hoisington was born in Illinois
                    in 1882 and received his B.A. from Wheaton College in 1905. He received
                    additional training in business at the Institute and Training School for
                    Employed Officers of the YMCA and in divinity at the McCormick Theological
                    Seminary. In 1910 he married Eunice Kingsbury, also a native of Illinois.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials related to the Hoisingtons' service in the West
                    Africa Mission in Cameroon, dating primarily from the 1930s to the 1960s.
                    Materials include: missionary reports (including reports of Eunice K.
                    Hoisington); newsletters, including The Drum Call and Mefoe Memvok, the
                    newsletter of the West African Mission; correspondence from the Hoisingtons to
                    family and friends; typescripts and manuscripts of talks on mission work in
                    Africa and talks to African audiences; notes on the culture and language of
                    Cameroon; proof copies of the gospels in Banoko, with some copyediting
                    annotation; and printed gospels, primers, and other educational and religious
                    texts published by Board of World Missions and Board of Foreign Mission. Some of
                    the printed materials are in Bulu and Banoko.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Fabrick, Frances</p>
                <p>Accession number: 93 1228</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Hoisington Family Papers (RG 221).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>