<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Hugh Ivan Evans papers <date type="inclusive">1910-1958</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Hugh Ivan Evans papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC842</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1958</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Rev. Dr. Hugh Ivan Evans (1887-1958) was born in Ohio and was pastor of the
                    Westminster Church in Dayton for 26 years. Evans received his B.D. from
                    Princeton Theological Seminary in 1912 and D.D. from the College of Wooster in
                    1925. He was Moderator of the General Assembly of the Presbyterian Church in the
                    U.S.A., 1950-1951; President of Board of Trustees of Lane Theological Seminary;
                    trustee of the College of Wooster; trustee of McCormick Theological Seminary;
                    and trustee of Ohio Presbyterian Homes.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes sermons, 1921-1953; notebooks from Princeton Theological
                    Seminary, 1910-1912; addresses and articles by Evans as Moderator; 1955-1958;
                    correspondence of Evans related to Westminster Church; and folders on various
                    pastorates, including correspondence. There are also scrapbooks on Evans' career
                    from 1912-1958 that include newspaper and magazine clippings, photographs,
                    bulletins and programs, invitations, and announcements. Specific volumes
                    include: 1950-1951 travel to Cuba, Latin America, and Alaska; 1915 election as
                    Moderator; retirement volume of correspondence; 1934 clippings of writings
                    during trip to Europe and Russia; and a post-war photo album of Germany,
                    Switzerland, and the Netherlands. Other items include correspondence of Mrs.
                    Evans related to Rev. Evans' death; an "in memoriam" volume; a published
                    history of Westminster Church (1949); and a reel to reel audio tape of a 1955
                    tribute program for Evans. Travel-related materials include printed "Letters
                    from Dr. Evans" from a trip to Chile in 1950, a motion picture film of trip to
                    South America, and miscellaneous travel brochures, maps and correspondence
                    related to overseas visits.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown 1.00 cu. ft. received 8/25/77 from W. MacGregor Princeton
                    notebooks given by Wm. Schram (according to note on container in collection)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 68 0287</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>