<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Irwin family papers <date type="inclusive">1927-1965</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Irwin family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1174</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1927-1965</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Reverend John Mark Irwin (1899 -1997) and Ruth Hoffman Irwin (1900-1982) were
                    appointed to the Persia (Iran) Mission in 1932 by the Board of Foreign Missions
                    of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.. Until their retirement in 1965, they
                    served primarily as evangelists at various locations in Iran, including Meshed,
                    Hamadan, Teheran, and Sari, as well as in Kabul, Afghanistan.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records related to the Irwins' missionary work in Iran.
                    Materials include typed notes for sermons, lessons for bible study, and programs
                    for services; manuscript articles by J. Mark Irwin on foreign missions, church
                    leadership in Iran, evangelism in Iran, and other topics; a small amount of
                    correspondence, some of it dealing with financial matters; a photocopy of
                    "Who's who in the Iran Mission" from 1963; and a small volume belonging to L.
                    F. Esselstyn noting names of missionaries working in Iran in the late 19th and
                    early 20th century, along with their dates of arrival in the country and their
                    birth and death dates. Some materials are in Persian.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Lewis, Beth Irwin</p>
                <p>Accession number: 98 0605c</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Irwin Family Papers (RG 205).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>