<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Isaac Snowden daybooks <date type="inclusive">1802-1831</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Isaac Snowden daybooks</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1044</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.50 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1802-1831</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Isaac Snowden, Jr. (1763-1835?), was a Philadelphia merchant and a dedicated
                    churchman. He was treasurer of the Board of Trustees of the General Assembly of
                    the Presbyterian Church in the United States of America (PCUSA) from 1799 until
                    his death and of the Presbytery of Philadelphia. Snowden was also an active
                    member and officer of the Second Presbyterian Church of Philadelphia, serving as
                    secretary of its Board of Trustees from 1802, as its pew agent, and on the
                    Congregational School Committee. In 1818 he was ordained an elder. He also
                    served as secretary or treasurer of some of the voluntary societies of
                    Philadelphia, including the Evangelical Society, the Missionary Society, the
                    Humane Society, and the Magdalen Society.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains daybooks with Snowden's observations on his daily
                    activities, mostly listening to sermons and his notes and responses to them.
                    Many of the sermons were given by Dr. Janeway and Dr. Green. The daybooks
                    include some reporting on business and organizational affairs of the Church.
                    Snowden writes regularly, though not daily. There is one volume consisting of
                    quotations and reflections from his reading.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Transferred from the library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 92 0918b</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Isaac Snowden, Jr. papers (RG 218).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>