<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James A. Gittings papers <date type="inclusive">1961-1969</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James A. Gittings papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC843</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1961-1969</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James Gittings was born in 1927 and graduated from Juniata College in 1949,
                    having interrupted his education to serve in the army during World War II. He
                    obtained a Master's degree in Journalism from Columbia Graduate School of
                    Journalism and also did graduate work at Pittsburgh-Xenia Theological Seminary.
                    Appointed in 1957 by the Board of Foreign Missions of the former United
                    Presbyterian Church of North America to served as a journalist in East Asia, he
                    wrote for Presbyterian Life, United Presbyterian curriculum publications,
                    Kerygma Features, and a variety of other publications. Gittings was the editor
                    of the quarterly An Asian Notebook and director of the Office of Overseas
                    Publicity IBC-COC.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of James A. Gittings. Materials include: subject
                    files, including typed drafts of articles; newspaper and magazine clippings;
                    photographs; programs; and correspondence. Also included are scrapbooks of
                    Gittings' articles and publications (1964-1968) and a 1967 photo album of Japan,
                    including photographs of religious services, street scenes, and individuals. In
                    addition there is a book-length typed draft of "UP is an enemy" by Gittings
                    (possibly unpublished).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 68 0288</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>