<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James H. Smylie papers <date type="inclusive">1964-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James H. Smylie papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1042</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.35 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James H. Smylie (b. 1925) was ordained in 1949 and taught at Princeton from 1950
                    to 1962. He is Ernest T. Thompson Professor of Church History, Emeritus, at
                    Union Theological Seminary and Presbyterian School of Christian Education in
                    Richmond, Virginia. Smylie was the editor of the Journal of Presbyterian History
                    from 1968-1996. He is the author of numerous articles and books on various
                    topics related to religious history, including the history of the Presbyterian
                    Church, Christian experience in American, religion and politics, and the Roman
                    Catholic Church in America. His books include Into All the World and A Cloud of
                    Witnesses.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of James Smylie. Materials include: typescript
                    manuscripts of articles; reprints and clippings of articles; pencil sketches of
                    individuals associated with the Presbyterian Historical Society, 1979-1986;
                    correspondence and manuscripts from Smylie's time as editor of the American
                    Presbyterians Journal; newspaper and magazine clippings; photographs and
                    negatives; and photostats of correspondence of Dr. Brown, from the archives at
                    the Presbyterian Historical Society. Smylie manuscripts include: "Hanover
                    Presbytery: Between Revolution and Civil War," "Lynching, 'The Black Christ,'
                    and the Atonement," "William McGuffey, Eclectic Readers, and Virtuous
                    Citizens," and "Thanks for the Memories," an address given at the General
                    Assembly of the Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.), Richmond, Virginia, 2004.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accessions 92 0617, 96 0806c, 00 0504e, 04 0925: Smylie, James;
                    accessions 96 0419b, 96 1002a, 98 0123c, 98 0220: Transferred from the
                    library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 92 0617|96 0419b|96 0806c|96 1002a|98 0123c|98 0220|00 0504e|04
                    0925</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>