<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James D. Smart papers <date type="inclusive">1930-1981</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James D. Smart papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1126</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1930-1981</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James Dick Smart (b. 1906) was a Canadian Presbyterian minister. He served as
                    editor-in-chief of the New Curriculum for the Presbyterian Church USA from
                    1944-1950. He returned to Canada as minister of Rosedale Presbyterian Church in
                    Toronto, Ontario, where he served until 1957. From 1957 to 1969 he was Jessup
                    Professor of Biblical Interpretation at Union Theological Seminary in New York.
                    He wrote 20 books and many sermons, lectures, and book reviews. At the time of
                    his death, he had completed two volumes of his memoirs (unpublished).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is collection of papers of James D. Smart. Materials include: manuscript
                    lecture notes for courses and notes for articles; 1931 thesis for Ph.D. from the
                    University of Toronto, "The Personal Element in Isaiah 40-66"; syllabi and
                    exam questions from Union Theological Seminary; manuscript and typed notes for
                    sermons; typescript manuscripts and manuscript notes for articles and books by
                    Smart, including Memoirs of a Ministry, volumes 1 and 2; reprints by Smart and
                    others; a small number of personal financial records; and printed booklets of
                    catechisms and confessions. The collection also includes minutes of several
                    councils and committees of interdenominational organizations (Reformed
                    Churches), 1970s and early 1980s; and minutes and reports of the General
                    Assembly's Committee on a Brief Contemporary Statement of Faith (1959-1964).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Smart, Mary Eleanor</p>
                <p>Accession number: 96 0322d</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>