<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>James Woodin Laurie papers <date type="inclusive">1889-1960</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">James Woodin Laurie papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC869</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>35.0 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1889-1960</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>James W. Laurie (1903-1970) was born in Bellingham, Washington. His father and
                    grandfather were Presbyterian ministers, as was his son, James Robertson Laurie.
                    Laurie attended Coe College (1920-1924) and Princeton Theological
                    Seminary(1924-1927), receiving a bachelor of divinity degree. He was ordained by
                    the Presbytery of Elizabeth in 1926. Laurie was a pastor at the Second
                    Presbyterian Church in Rahway, New Jersey from 1927-1936, at the Second
                    Presbyterian Church in Wilkinsburg, Pennsylvania from 1936-1941, and Buffalo
                    Central New York Church from 1941-1951. He was named President of Trinity
                    University in 1951. Thomas J. Wilbanks (b. 1890) was the Stated Clerk of Paris
                    Presbytery, Synod of Texas. He was Pastor of Pine Street Presbyterian Church,
                    Texarkana, Texas, from 1925-1958 and chairman of Synod of Texas Historical
                    Society at Trinity University, 1958-1965.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the personal and working papers of James W. Laurie (prior
                    to 1951), those of his father, James A. Laurie, Jr., and of his grandfather,
                    James A. Laurie. The collection also includes the correspondence of Mrs. James
                    W. Laurie (Sarah B.). Included are addresses, sermons and sermon notes
                    (1915-1960s); papers related to his ministries at Rahway and Buffalo, including
                    minutes, programs, bulletins, correspondence, newsletters, and clippings; pocket
                    diaries (1889-1928); photos and cyanotpyes; postcards; clippings; correspondence
                    (1890s-1950s); Council on Theological Education minutes, financial records, and
                    correspondence (1940s-1950s); and papers related to the General Assembly and
                    General Council (1950s). Items from Laurie's time at Coe College include class
                    notes, yearbooks, student papers, a debating handbook, and copies of the school
                    newspaper, the Coe College Cosmos (1920s). There are also class notes from
                    Princeton Theological Seminary (1926-1927) and typed drafts of a biography of
                    Laurie by R. D. Brackenridge. The papers of James Anderson Laurie Jr. include
                    correspondence and sermons; pocket diaries, and an 1896 commonplace book. The
                    collection also includes: photocopies of 1864-1881 diaries of James A. Laurie; a
                    typescript of boyhood memories, probably written by Laurie Sr.'s brother-in-law;
                    a small collection of correspondence of Sarah B. Fiske Laurie; and some papers
                    of Thomas Wilbanks. Most of the Wilbanks papers (1929-1960) relate to a dispute
                    between the Cumberland Presbyterian Church and the Presbyterian Church U.S.A.
                    over title to a 5 acre tract of land in Texas (1936-1939). Other materials
                    include the T. J. Wilbanks collection of church bulletins and special programs
                    and papers related to the Paris Presbytery.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Trinity University Library, Coiner Archives</p>
                <p>Accession number: 76 1227</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>