<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Japanese Presbyterian Conference records <date type="inclusive">1977-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Japanese Presbyterian Conference records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1069</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.10 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Japanese Presbyterian Conference is an informal organization of Japanese
                    American Presbyterian churches in the United States. Founded in 1905, the
                    Conference engages in activities such as lobbying the General Assembly,
                    supporting social justice campaigns and education, and sponsoring cultural
                    seminars. The Conference also works with churches and denominational agencies to
                    develop specialized curriculum, liturgy, and programs for the Japanese American
                    community.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of anniversary booklets for member churches of the Japanese
                    Presbyterian Conference. The collection includes booklets for the Parkview
                    Presbyterian Church, Sacramento, California; the Ogden Japanese Christian
                    Church, Ogden, Utah; the Cortez Presbyterian Church, in Cortez, California; the
                    Calvary Presbyterian Church, Stockton, California; the Union Church of Los
                    Angeles, California; and the Japanese Church of Christ, Salt Lake City,
                    Utah.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Japanese Presbyterian Conference, Sumio Koge</p>
                <p>Accession number: 93 0929</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>