<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Jean Martin Buche papers <date type="inclusive">1891-1972</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Jean Martin Buche papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC027</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.58 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1891-1972</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Jean Martin Buche (1929-1998) was a missionary in India, teaching at the Avalon
                    School (UPCNA) in Pathankot in the 1950s. She was married to the Reverend Robert
                    H. Buche (1905-1992), a Presbyterian minister who served at the Trinity
                    Presbyterian Church in Manhattan from 1938 to 1970. He was also chaplain of the
                    St. George Society of the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection includes a photograph album documenting a 1972 trip made by the
                    Buches to India mission sites including the Avalon School and Christian Medical
                    Center; various publications documenting the UPCNA's India and Pakistan missions
                    and non-church publications on the Sikhs; and two photo albums from India, one
                    from 1958-1961 and one from 1972, showing church members, schoolchildren,
                    village scenes, architecture, and animals. Also included are personal papers of
                    Jean Martin Buche, which include photographs, slides, photograph albums,
                    publications, and a 1967 manuscript by Buche on the languages of India.
                    Additionally there are some photographs and printed material related to the
                    Avalon Girls' High School in Pathankot, Punjab, India.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Martin, M. Gertrude Trudy)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 01 0511a|96 0725d</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>