<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Jerry Hoytt Boles papers <date type="inclusive">1954-1969</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Jerry Hoytt Boles papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC847</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>9.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1954-1969</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Jerry Hoytt Boles (1907-1986) was a Presbyterian minister who was active in the
                    Synod of Texas. He was a 1932 graduate of McCormick Theological Seminary. He was
                    pastor of several churches in Texas and served as the Moderator of the Synod of
                    Texas from 1950 to 1951. During the same year, he was Chairman of the National
                    Staff of the Board of National Missions. In 1945 he became Executive of Synod of
                    Texas, serving until 1968.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence (incoming and outgoing) and subject files
                    of Jerry Hoytt Boles as Executive of the Synod of Texas. Correspondents include
                    pastors and staff of churches in the Texas Synod, staff of local and national
                    offices of the UPCUSA, church members, and others. Subject files include
                    materials related to the Texas Synod Council of United Presbyterian Men, the
                    Office of New Church Development and Building Aid, Moderator visits, meetings of
                    Executives, and various committees. These subjects files consist of
                    correspondence, agendas, minutes, reports, and memoranda. The collection also
                    includes some personal correspondence with family and friends.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown (appears to have been transferred from Trinity University in
                    1973)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 68 0292</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>