<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John McDowell papers <date type="inclusive">1932-1937</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John McDowell papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC846</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1932-1937</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John McDowell (1870-1937) was Moderator of the General Assembly of the
                    Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. He served as Secretary of the Board of
                    National Missions and Secretary of the Committee on Social and Industrial
                    Relations of the Board of National Missions. He was noted for his Labor Day
                    sermons. Scottish-born, a onetime breaker boy in a Pennsylvania mine (where he
                    lost an arm), McDowell worked his way through Mount Hermon School at East
                    Northfield. Massachusetts, and became a friend of Founder Dwight Lyman
                    Moody.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of John McDowell, including typescripts and
                    printed copies of sermons and addresses; news releases of statements; printed
                    messages of the Board of National Missions and the General Assembly, including a
                    "Labor Day Message"; a small amount of correspondence with the Publicity
                    Department of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.; and a broadside of a report
                    of the Standing Committee on Social Welfare, 1937. Topics of the addresses in
                    the collection include labor and the church, the economic crisis, the church and
                    social and industrial relations, and unemployment.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 68 0291a</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>