<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John William Meister papers <date type="inclusive">1969-1971</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John William Meister papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC896</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1971</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John W. Meister (1916-1974) was a Presbyterian minister. He served as Executive
                    Secretary of the Council of Theological Seminaries of the United Presbyterian
                    Church. He was educated at Ohio University and Princeton Theological Seminary
                    and served in churches in Ohio and Indiana. He was the author of What Baptism
                    Means (1960).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of John William Meister. Materials include:
                    incoming and outgoing correspondence of Jack Meister as Executive Secretary of
                    the Council on Theological Education, 1969-1971; correspondence and reports
                    related to plans for and design of a study on theological education by Doug
                    Trout; progress reports; financial statements and budgets of the study;
                    corrections to the Trout Report; reports and memoranda containing responses to
                    the report from task forces at several seminaries; a copy of Part II of the
                    Theological Education Resources of the United Presbyterian Church for the 1970s;
                    and a working paper from the 1969 annual meeting of Council on Theological
                    Education.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Bauer, Richard</p>
                <p>Accession number: 82 0827</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>