<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Coventry Smith papers <date type="inclusive">1938-1970</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Coventry Smith papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC840</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1938-1970</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Coventry Smith (1903-1984) served as a missionary in Japan from 1929 until
                    the outbreak of World War II. For a ten-year period both before and after the
                    union of the Presbyterian Church in the USA, Smith was secretary for Japan,
                    Korea, Philippines, and Thailand, and then was associate general secretary of
                    what became the Commission on Ecumenical Mission and Relations (COEMAR). He
                    became COEMAR's general secretary in 1959 and retired in 1970. From 1968 to
                    1975, he was president of the World Council of Churches. In 1968, he was elected
                    Moderator of the General Assembly of the United Presbyterian Church USA.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of John Coventry Smith. Papers related to the
                    National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America (NCC)
                    include memoranda, correspondence, reports, and proposals. Many of the papers
                    are from the General Board, the Executive Committee, the Division of Foreign
                    Missions, and the Division of Overseas Ministries of the NCC, 1959-1969.
                    Materials related to the World Council of Churches (WCC) include minutes,
                    memoranda, reports, proposals, summaries, agendas, budgets, directories, a small
                    amount of correspondence, and printed materials. Much of the material is related
                    to the Executive Committee, the Division of World Mission and Evangelism, the
                    Central Committee, and various Assemblies of the World Council of Churches,
                    1949-1969. Papers from the International Missionary Council include reports,
                    memoranda, correspondence, minutes (some printed), and discussion papers.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 68 0284</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>