<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph I. Gulick papers <date type="inclusive">1911-1970</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph I. Gulick papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1143</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.17 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1911-1970</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Joseph Isaac Gulick (1890-1972) graduated from Lafayette College in 1917 and from
                    the Princeton Theological Seminary in 1920. Gulick earned a master's degree at
                    George Washington University in 1933 and a doctorate in 1947. He served as
                    pastor of the Presbyterian Church in Soda Springs, Idaho, from 1920 to 1923, and
                    then accepted a call from the Idaho Falls Presbyterian Church. He remained
                    pastor at Idaho Falls until retirement in 1959. He married Winifred Louise
                    Ferebauer in 1923. He spent his retirement years ministering to the people of
                    Swan Valley, Idaho, and writing his autobiography. He died in 1972.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection is a scrapbook of Joseph Gulick's time at the Wilson Military
                    Academy, Lafayette College, Princeton Seminary, and his ministries in Idaho
                    Falls and Soda Springs, Idaho. It includes photographs, clippings,
                    correspondence, programs, and diplomas. There is also a printed history of
                    Lamington Presbyterian Church (which includes a biographical sketch of Gulick),
                    a family tree, and a typed sermon by Henry M. Mellon.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Transferred from the library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 97 0110b</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Joseph Isaac Gulick papers (RG 96).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>