<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Lois M. Finney papers <date type="inclusive">1865-1951</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Lois M. Finney papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC965</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.50 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1865-1951</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Lois M. Finney was a missionary at the American Mission in Egypt. She collected
                    this material from the mission, though her term of service was later.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of mission meeting photos from the Zagazig School and the
                    American Mission in Egypt. Group photographs include: staff of the American
                    Mission in Cairo, 1910; 1951 annual Missionary Conference, New Wilmington,
                    Pennsylvania; Zagazig class of 1931; 1900 Synod of the Nile; Missionary
                    Association, 1897; Meeting of the Synod of the Nile, 1912; American Mission,
                    1885; Egyptian Pastors of Cairo and six missionaries, 1929; Synod of the Nile,
                    1900; wedding party of Mr. and Mrs. Robert W. Walker; and the last meeting of
                    the Presbytery of Egypt, 1899. There are also shots of street scenes from Cairo,
                    Luxor, and Mataria; photographic portraits and cartes de visites of missionaries
                    and their families; as well as pictures of Theodore Roosevelt visiting the
                    American College for Girls in Cairo. Additionally, there is a letter dated 1873
                    from the Board (possibly the Board of Foreign Missions) regarding the possible
                    complicity of members of the Egyptian Mission in slavery.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Finney, Lois M.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 89 0609b</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Ralph C. McGill papers (accession 99 0920b) include
                    photographs from American Mission in Egypt, 1904-1924.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>