<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Lois Harkrider Stair papers <date type="inclusive">1967-1981</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Lois Harkrider Stair papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC873</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.02 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1981</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Lois Harkrider (1923-1981) was born in Waukesha, Wisconsin. She earned her BA at
                    Smith College in 1944. She married Ralph Martin Stair of Waukesha; they had two
                    sons. In 1957 Stair was ordained a ruling elder of the First Presbyterian Church
                    of Waukesha. She was a commissioner to the 171st General Assembly (UPCUSA)
                    (1959) and was elected secretary to the Standing Committee on Theological
                    Education. She became Vice-Moderator of Milwaukee Presbytery in 1965 and was
                    subsequently the first person to serve two successive terms as moderator of that
                    presbytery. In 1968 she was named vice-moderator of Wisconsin Synod and
                    moderator the year after that. In 1971 Stair became the first woman to be
                    elected Moderator of the General Assembly of the United Presbyterian Church in
                    the U.S.A., in the face of a storm of controversy which had begun only days
                    before. An agency of the Church had set up a $10,000 fund to support the defense
                    of African-American militant Angela Yvonne Davis, who was charged with
                    conspiracy and murder. Over 7,000 church members from across the country
                    protested the fund, but Moderator Stair held firm in defense of it, stating that
                    "Angela Davis may be the symbol of the Black's fight for justice." Stair
                    maintained her involvement with the Presbyterian Church after her term as
                    moderator ended, working with the Council on Church Union until her death in
                    1981.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Lois Harkrider Stair. Materials include:
                    personal and professional correspondence; press coverage; printed materials
                    related to speeches and appearances by Stair during and after her tenure;
                    schedules and itineraries; and awards, citations and memorabilia related to
                    Stair's tenure as moderator. The collection also contains topical files related
                    to Stair’s activities. Subjects include: theological education, Council on
                    Church Union Education Committee Work, Carroll College Trustee papers, United
                    Presbyterian Foundation, General Assembly material prior to and after 1974,
                    various seminaries and presbyteries, Moderators Conference, and the Ghost Ranch
                    Foundation. Additional materials in the collection include: correspondence to
                    her husband, Ralph Stair, from others; one audiocassette, "UPW Area Cons., Aug.
                    1971"; a folder containing legal information, including wills for Ralph Stair
                    and Lois Stair, family trusts, and the estate of Lola B. Harkrider; bills and
                    receipts; and copies of the publication "Presbyterian Laymen."</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accession 77 0729: Stair; accession 96 0923: Roche, Barbara</p>
                <p>Accession number: 77 0729|96 0923</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Lois Harkrider Stair records (RG 97).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>