<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Maggie Kuhn papers <date type="inclusive">1882-1989</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Maggie Kuhn papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC901</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>47.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1882-1989</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Maggie Kuhn (1905-1995) was born in Buffalo, New York. Her childhood was spent in
                    Cleveland, Ohio, as well as Memphis, Tennessee. She was a lifelong American
                    activist. She is most famous for founding the Gray Panthers movement in 1971
                    after being forced into retirement by the Presbyterian Church. The Gray Panthers
                    became known for advocating nursing home reform and fighting ageism, claiming
                    that "old people constitute America's biggest untapped and undervalued human
                    energy source." She also dedicated her life to fighting for human rights,
                    social and economic justice, global peace, integration, and an understanding of
                    mental health issues. She wrote her autobiography, No Stone Unturned, in
                    1991.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of personal and professional papers of Maggie Kuhn. Personal
                    and family papers include: Kuhn's baby book and a pair of baby shoes; an
                    envelope of newspaper clippings from her father's files (1930s-1940s); school
                    papers, notes, and yearbooks (1923-1924); correspondence, 1940s-1960s; wills,
                    birth and marriage certificates; the mortgage for Kuhn's Greene Street
                    residence; medical reports; engagement books; photographs and slides; academic
                    regalia; and citations, awards, and honorary degrees. Gray Panthers papers
                    include correspondence, local chapter information, publicity, subject files,
                    financial records, and printed materials. There are also some photographs and
                    audiocassettes; clippings; telephone logs; and records of Kuhn's speaking
                    engagements and travel schedules. The collection includes papers related to
                    Kuhn's work with several Presbyterian and ecumenical organizations, including
                    the General Alliance of Unitarian and other Liberal Christian Women; the United
                    Presbyterian Church, Office of Church and Society, Department of Social
                    Education and Action; the Board of National Missions; and Council on Church and
                    Society. These papers include correspondence, subject files, minutes and
                    reports, and newsletters. Among these papers are letters and notes related to
                    the beginnings of the Gray Panthers and records of the Corporation of 65. There
                    are also USO program materials from the National Board of the YWCA, possibly
                    from 1941.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Kuhn, Margaret and Estate, Kuhn, Margaret; accession 04 0511:
                    Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 83 0813a|83 0815|83 0831a|83 0920a|84 0628|84 1003a|77 0106a|96
                    1119d|97 0326|01 0829|04 0511</p>
            </acqinfo>


            <otherfindaid>
                <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" xpointer="http://www.history.pcusa.org/collections/research-tools/guides-archival-collections/rg-475">http://www.history.pcusa.org/collections/research-tools/guides-archival-collections/rg-475</extref>
            </otherfindaid>







        </archdesc>
    </ead>