<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Margaret Ellen Towner papers <date type="inclusive">1954-1989</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Margaret Ellen Towner papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC964</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.50 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1954-1989</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Margaret E. Towner (b. 1925) received her B.A. from Carleton College. In 1954
                    Towner received her B.D. degree from Union Theological Seminary. In 1956 she was
                    ordained in the Cayuga-Syracuse Presbytery, the first woman to be ordained in
                    the Presbyterian Church in the USA, and was enrolled as a member of the
                    Presbytery of Lehigh. Before her ordination, she was a commissioned church
                    worker in Allentown, Pennsylvania, serving as minister of Christian education at
                    the First Presbyterian Church. After her ordination Towner went on to pastor
                    churches in Maryland, Pennsylvania, Michigan, Indiana and Wisconsin. She took
                    clinical pastoral training and served as chaplain in an Indianapolis hospital
                    emergency room. She was moderator of the Milwaukee Presbytery, and ran for
                    Moderator of the United Presbyterian Church General Assembly.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Margaret E. Towner related to her ordination in
                    1956. Materials include: programs; magazines and newspaper clippings;
                    photographs from her ordination; and correspondence. The collection also
                    includes several typescripts of sermons, exams from seminary, and congregation
                    newsletters.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Towner, Margaret</p>
                <p>Accession number: 89 0608</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>