<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Mary Cooper Thompson papers <date type="inclusive">1847-1990</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1968-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Mary Cooper Thompson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1092</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.04 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1847-1990</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1968-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Damavand College, named after the mountain which rises out of the Alborz range
                    north of the city of Tehran, was a private institution of higher learning for
                    women, offering a four-year intercultural program in the liberal arts. The
                    program of studies at Damavand was accredited in 1968 and its first class of
                    seniors was graduated in 1972. The school began as the Iran Bethel Educational
                    Project and was transformed under the direction of Dr. Frances M. Gray into a
                    four-year liberal arts college. Damavand moved from central Tehran to a new
                    campus on Lashgarak Road in north Tehran in 1975. Dr. Mary C. Thompson was the
                    academic dean of Damavand College, and was involved in the school from its
                    inception.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers related to Damavand College (Tehran) compiled by
                    Mary C. Thompson. Materials include: newspaper and magazine articles; reprints
                    and papers of Damavand professors; promotional brochures, catalogs, and
                    bulletins; presidents' reports; commencement programs; yearbooks (1968, 1973,
                    1977, 1978); newsletters; correspondence from faculty and others associated with
                    the college (1978-1988); address lists of faculty members and alumnae;
                    photographs and slides of students; material related to commencement ceremonies;
                    and papers related to the dissolution of Damavand College Foundation (includes
                    financial material and minutes), 1990. The collection also includes a memoir by
                    Ruth E. Harman about her time in Iran (1931-1936 and 1955-1971). Daguerreotype
                    portraits of Lizzie Cooper and Mrs. R.D. Thompson are housed in with the
                    daguerreotype collection.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accession 94 0815c: Thompson, Mary C.; accession 98 0107k: Jamison,
                    Paul W.; accession 93 0219: Transferred from the museum</p>
                <p>Accession number: 94 0815c|98 0107k|93 0219</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>