<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Maybell Sammons Hayes papers <date type="inclusive">1925-1959</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Maybell Sammons Hayes papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC956</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1925-1959</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Maybell Sammons Hayes (1895-1981), a medical missionary of the PCUSA, graduated
                    from Grove City College in 1919 and from Woman's Medical College in 1923.
                    Appointed to the India Mission in 1924, Dr. Hayes served at the Fatehgarh
                    Hospital from 1925-1927. From 1927 through 1960, she served as a physician on
                    the staff of the Allahabad Agricultural Institute where her husband, Brewster
                    Hayes, was head of the Institute's Horticulture Department. In 1960, she was
                    sent to the Punjab Synod where she served on the staff of the Ludhiana Christian
                    Medical School until 1962. She was enrolled as a Peace Corps volunteer from 1965
                    through 1967 and served with the Department of Social and Preventative Medicine,
                    SMS, Medical College, Jaipur, Rajasthan. From 1967 until her return to the U.S.
                    in 1970 she served in Naila, a village in the Jaipur District, where she
                    conducted general clinic work and lectured at the Health Center.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection is of a scrapbook of photos related to Maybell Hayes' work in
                    India, 1955-1959, including photographs of rural clinics of Jumna Dispensaries,
                    1944; staff and patients of dispensaries; Hayes working with patients; Nehru
                    visiting Extension Project, 1955; and possibly photos of Hayes' husband in
                    Riverside, California, 1957. The collection also includes several loose
                    photographs, including staff and students of the Allahabad Agricultural
                    Institute, 1951; a 1925 group photograph of staff of the Jumna Dispensaris; 1944
                    photographs of the Jumna Dispensaries at the Agricultural Institute; and a 1933
                    group photo of Allahabad Christian College bible teachers and Jumna Church
                    Sunday school teachers.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Transferred from the library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 88 0407c</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Maybell Sammons Hayes papers (RG 182).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>