<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Nancy B. Davison papers <date type="inclusive">1979-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Nancy B. Davison papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1148</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Presbyterian Women (PW) is the national women's organization of the Presbyterian
                    Church (U.S.A.). Nancy B. Davison worked as a volunteer with Presbyterian Women
                    from 1985 to 1994. She served on the National Executive Committee of
                    Presbyterian Women during the 1985-1988 Triennium as the representative from the
                    Synod of Alaska-Northwest. During the 1991-1994 Triennium, she served on the
                    Churchwide Search Committee as the representative from the Western region of the
                    United States.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of materials compiled by Nancy B. Davis during her
                    association with Presbyterian Women. The materials are related to volunteer
                    services with Presbyterian Women including subject files; photographs;
                    notebooks; filmstrip "In the Image of God" from the 1979 UPW National Meeting;
                    and slides from the 1988 PW Churchwide Gathering, with a list identifying
                    slides. Also included are materials from various meetings between 1985 and 1994,
                    including National Meeting of United Presbyterian Women, Churchwide Gathering of
                    Presbyterian Women, Business Meeting of Presbyterian Women, National Executive
                    Committee Meeting and PW Enabler Training. These materials include agendas,
                    programs, meeting minutes, planning notes, reports, photographs of meetings, and
                    newsletters.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Davison, Nancy B.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 97 0701</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>