<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>North Jersey Presbyterian Ministers' Monthly Society records <date type="inclusive">1802-1826</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">North Jersey Presbyterian Ministers' Monthly Society
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC051</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1802-1826</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>North Jersey Presbyterian Ministers Monthly Society was a group of clergymen who
                    met regularly to hear papers read and to hold discussions on a variety of
                    topics. The object of the Society was the advancement of theological knowledge
                    and ministerial usefulness.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of two volumes of minutes of meetings of the North
                    Jersey Presbyterian Ministers' Monthly Society, 1802 to 1826. The minutes record
                    the Society's routine business, list members assigned to deliver addresses on
                    theological topics, and list discussion questions undertaken at each meeting.
                    The minutes include lists of moderators, secretaries, clerks, presenters, and
                    meetings. One volume includes a docket of discussion questions.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Presbyterian Church on the Gr. (12/18/72)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 02 0613j</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>