<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>O. E. Mirtz papers <date type="inclusive">1931-1935</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">O. E. Mirtz papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1015</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1931-1935</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>O.E. (Orvil Edward) Mirtz (1902-1993) was a 1931 graduate of Princeton Seminary.
                    Following his graduation, he spent several years in Hainan, China as a
                    missionary. After his return to the United States, he was a teacher of
                    mathematics and a house parent at the Mount Hermon School for Boys in
                    Northfield, Massachusetts. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers and photographs from Mirtz's time serving as a
                    missionary in Hainan, China, between 1931 and 1935. Materials include a
                    photograph album with images of village activities, dwellings, weddings,
                    sporting events, students, soldiers, Loi and Miao villagers, rice cultivation,
                    kites, and Mirtz's pony "Baby." The collection also includes correspondence
                    from Mirtz; typed reports and notes on various aspects of culture in Hainan;
                    notices for his sermons (in Chinese); a chart of statistics of the China Mission
                    of the Presbyterian Church in USA, 1933; photographs of students and staff of
                    the Pitkin School and the Lingnan Branch School; poems, songs, and children's
                    rhymes in Chinese (some transliterated into Roman script); sketches of kites; a
                    floor plan of Lingnan Branch School; a broadside depicting Jesus' ministry (in
                    Chinese); prints and ephemera; and newspaper clippings (in English).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Mirtz, Mrs. O.E. (Lillian)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 91 0913</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>