<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Ohio Student Volunteer Union records <date type="inclusive">1921-1940</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Ohio Student Volunteer Union records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC076</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.04 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1921-1940</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Student Volunteer Union of Central and Southern Ohio was formed for the
                    purpose of uniting groups of volunteers so they could provide mutual help and
                    inspiration in their work. Some of the methods through which this was
                    accomplished were conferences, councils for leaders, newsletters, and exchange
                    visits between member groups. Colleges with volunteer groups represented in the
                    Union included Oberlin, Wooster, Muskingum, Ohio State University, Ohio
                    Wesleyan, Wittenberg, and Oxford College for Women. An earlier name of this
                    organization was the Southern Ohio Student Volunteer Union.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a volume of minutes of the Student Volunteer Union of Central and
                    Southern Ohio, 1921-1940. The minutes document fall council meetings, spring
                    conferences, and other meetings held by the group at various colleges in Ohio.
                    The minutes include reports of addresses and discussion groups, information on
                    activities of Christian student organizations, treasurer's reports of dues and
                    expenses, and the election of officers and other routine business. The volume
                    includes a printed copy of the organization's constitution and several
                    conference programs.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 02 1218r</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>