<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Parker family papers <date type="inclusive">1915-1950</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Parker family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1175</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.92 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1915-1950</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Allen Parker was born in Old Fort, Ohio in 1891. After graduating from Ohio
                    University in 1915 he attended Hartfort Seminary until 1918. In 1918 he married
                    Irene Glasgow of Summerfort, Kansas and the next year they were appointed as
                    missionaries to the PCUSA's North India Mission. The Parkers spent two years at
                    Allahabad Agricultural Institute and another two years at the Jumna Boys High
                    School in Allahabad. In 1922 the Parkers were transferred to Landour where Rev.
                    Parker was appointed principal of Woodstock School. He remained there until 1941
                    when he returned to the Jumna Boys High School. In 1943 he married a fellow
                    missionary, Dorothy Dragon, following the death of his first wife two years
                    earlier. Dorothy Dragon Parker was born in Berkeley, California in 1907. After
                    graduating from the University of California in 1929 she attended Biblical
                    Seminary in New York and received a Bachelor in Religious Education in 1931. The
                    following year Dorothy Dragon was appointed to the PCUSA North India Mission.
                    After two years of language studies, she taught for a year at the Isabella
                    Thoburn College. From 1935 until her marriage in 1943 she worked as an
                    evangelist in Kasganj, with a special emphasis on women and adult literacy.
                    After her marriage she taught in Jumna High School until Allen Parker's death in
                    1947. In 1952 she transferred to Kasgunj and Etahwah where she continued her
                    work in adult literacy. She retired from missionary service in 1965.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the correspondence of Allen and Irene Parker, 1918-1941;
                    of Allen Parker 1941-1947; and of Dorothy Parker, 1949-1950. The collection also
                    includes clippings of mission letters written by the Parkers that were published
                    in newspapers. These clippings describe life in India and the Parkers' travels
                    to the Himalayas and China.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Riddle, Katharine Parker</p>
                <p>Accession number: 98 0609|99 0428a</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Parker family photographs (RG 229).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>