<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Paul Burgess papers <date type="inclusive">1912-1960</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Paul Burgess papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1109</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1912-1960</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Paul Burgess (1886-1958) and Dora McLaughlin Burgess (1887-1962) were appointed
                    as missionaries to Guatemala by the PCUSA in 1912 and served there until their
                    retirement in 1956. In 1932, Paul and Dora Burgess resigned their positions and
                    amidst considerable controversy, decided to commence work with the Quiche
                    Indians, a large but generally neglected segment of the Guatemalan population.
                    They reduced the Quiche language to a modern written form, learned it and began
                    producing Christian literature in it. In 1940, against the advice of the
                    Presbyterian Mission, they founded one of the pioneer ecumenical projects in
                    Latin America, the Quiche Bible Institute. This institution was established to
                    provide spiritual training for the more than 300,000 Quiche Indians living in
                    Guatemala. Paul Burgess also founded in 1915 El Noticiero Evangelico, a monthly
                    magazine featuring local and world church news, and edited from 1922-23 El
                    Mensajero Evangelico. The Burgesses also translated a number of materials into
                    the Spanish and Quiche languages, including the New Testament, hymnals and
                    miscellaneous Sunday School literature.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of correspondence of Paul and Dora Burgess, dating from 1912
                    to 1950. The letters, outgoing and some incoming, relate to the Burgesses'
                    missionary work in Guatemala. Correspondents include supporters, fellow
                    missionaries, Guatemala Mission staff, staff of the Board of Foreign Missions,
                    and friends and family members. Some of the correspondence is in Spanish. The
                    collection also includes reports, typed manuscripts of articles by Paul Burgess,
                    and a newspaper clipping about the Burgesses from 1960.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Dahlquist, Anna Marie</p>
                <p>Accession number: 95 1206</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Burgess family papers (RG 201).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>