<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Education Society records <date type="inclusive">1854-1910</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Education Society records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC113</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1854-1910</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The object of the Philadelphia Education Society was to "educate young men for
                    the ministry upon the principles and in conformity with the constitution of the
                    American Education Society." The Philadelphia Education Society was a regional
                    auxiliary of the Presbyterian Education Society (originally the Education
                    Society of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.), itself an auxiliary of the
                    Board of Education of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a volume of minutes of the Board of Directors of the Philadelphia
                    Education Society, 1854-1905. (Records prior to September 1854 were destroyed by
                    fire.) The volume includes the constitution of the Society, records of
                    appropriations to scholars at various colleges and seminaries, records of the
                    election of officers, reports from committees, and brief memorials of deceased
                    members. The volume also includes minutes from a 1910 special meeting related to
                    the dissolution of the Society and the transfer of remaining moneys to the Board
                    of Education of the Presbyterian Church in the USA.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 04 1201m</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>