<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Phillips family papers <date type="inclusive">1919-1984</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Phillips family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1147</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent> linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1919-1984</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Clarence Arthur Phillips (1893-1977) was a graduate of McCormick Theological
                    Seminary and a missionary to Venezuela from 1918 to 1959. Phillips served for
                    many years as director of the Colegio Americano de Caracas, an elementary
                    school. Phillips also served as mission treasurer and manager of the Mission
                    Bookstore and Press. He retired in 1959. His wife, Maude Edith Mason Phillips,
                    was also a missionary in Venezuela. In Caracas, Mrs. Phillips taught Sunday
                    school, trained women in house-to-house evangelism, played the organ in church,
                    and taught music at the Colegio Americano. Clarence’s sister Verna Alice
                    Phillips was a missionary in Venezuela from 1921 to 1954. She served as a
                    teacher, principal and associate director of the Colegio Americano.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Philips family papers. Materials include: daily diary,
                    1925, and pastor's pocket record book; photograph of teachers at the Colegio
                    Americano, 1922; photograph album (Verna A Phillips, Venezuela) with index to
                    pictures; scrapbook (Helen Phillips), circa 1928-1940, which includes programs,
                    school records, correspondence, and plays; box of prints labeled Venezuela,
                    circa 1920s-1970s, documenting the Phillips' missionary work in Venezuela; 1927
                    commemorative booklet on the Venezuela Misison of the Presbyterian Church in the
                    USA; set of slides of the Interchurch Building cornerstone laying, October 12,
                    1958; a printed history of the Presbyterian Church in Venezuela, by Rev. C.
                    Arthur Phillips, 1958; two small rolls of film: "Venezuela, Board of Foreign
                    Missions, Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A” and a teaching film; lyrics and
                    sheet music to the 1947 edition of "Himno Nacional De Venezuela,"; 1966
                    yearbook of the Colegio Americano; watercolor of a mission building (possibly
                    the Colegio Americano de Caracas; scarf with Venezuela motif and box of
                    lacework; printed histories of Venezuela; and certificates of Verna Phillips,
                    1953 and 1967. The collection also includes a copy of "How Many Buttons Has a
                    Missionary," Elizabeth Irene Davenport Eggart's circa 1984 transcription with
                    annotations of her father's (Jay Furber Davenport) diaries, 1926-1937, that
                    document Presbyterian mission work in Venezuela.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Kaltenborn, Helen</p>
                <p>Accession number: 97 0404b|03 0320|03 0916b</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>