<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philadelphia Sunday and Adult School Union records <date type="inclusive">1817-1826</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philadelphia Sunday and Adult School Union
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC158</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1817-1826</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Sunday and Adult School Union was formed in 1817. In that year, a number of
                    Philadelphia-area Sunday school societies met to form a larger union of their
                    societies for the purpose of concentrating their efforts in the support of
                    schools, the publication and dissemination of moral and religious materials, and
                    the formation of new schools. In 1825, the Philadelphia-based Sunday and Adult
                    School Union joined with other regional unions to form the American Sunday
                    School Union (ASSU). In 1939 the ASSU changed its name to the Philadelphia
                    Council of Churches, and in 1969 it again changed names to the Metropolitan
                    Christian Council of Philadelphia.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of two volumes of records of the Sunday and Adult School
                    Union. The first volume is a letter book, 1817-1825, which contains
                    correspondence with other Sunday school unions (including requests for
                    publications from the Union and letters about publication exchanges with other
                    societies), and letters to Sabbath school missionaries, discussing duties and
                    remuneration. The second volume contains the constitution and minutes of monthly
                    and annual meetings of the Philadelphia Sunday and Adult School Union,
                    1817-1824. The minutes discuss collecting books for the Union (including by
                    exchange with other Sunday school societies and unions), fundraising,
                    publication of books, reports from visitations, and additions of members to the
                    Union. The volume also includes a printed copy of a proposed constitution for
                    the American Sunday School Union, 1823, and minutes of the ASSU Missions
                    Committee, 1825-1826.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: ASSU</p>
                <p>Accession number: 05 0603i</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: American Sunday School Union records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>