<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Poynette Presbyterial Academy records <date type="inclusive">1884-1914</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Poynette Presbyterial Academy records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC144</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1884-1914</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Poynette Academy was first conceived in 1884, when a group of trustees formed
                    to raise funds to open a school under the direction of the Presbyterian Church.
                    The school ran into financial difficulties and was dissolved, and its property
                    and buildings sold off, in 1911.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Poynette Presbyterial Academy. Minutes of
                    the Board of Trustees, 1884-1914, discuss election of officers, erecting a new
                    building and setting up the school, Academy expenses and subscriptions, hiring
                    staff, and financial dealings. These minutes also include information on the
                    dissolution of the Academy and the sale of its property. Minutes of the Trustees
                    Executive Committee, 1906-1912, largely focus on financial matters of the
                    Academy. Other materials in the collection include: Articles of incorporation,
                    by-laws, and Articles of Dissolution; file of correspondence from 1903-1911;
                    reports on religious work conducted at the Academy, students, and finances;
                    copies of mortgages and insurance statements; historical information on the
                    Academy; copy of the 1903-1904 Academy catalogue; and extracts of meetings of
                    the Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Synod of Wisconsin Archives</p>
                <p>Accession number: 05 0520p</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>