<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Presbyterian Funds for Pious Uses records <date type="inclusive">1718-1747</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Presbyterian Funds for Pious Uses records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1091</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.10 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1718-1747</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1717 the Synod of Philadelphia created what was known as "The Fund for Pious
                    Uses." This fund was used for various purposes, including the relief of needy
                    ministers and their families. Later, a Widow's Fund was created, providing for
                    the payment of certain fixed annuities to widows and children of subscribers.
                    This fund was eventually incorporated as The Corporation for Relief of Poor and
                    Distressed Presbyterian Ministers and of the Poor and Distressed Widows and
                    Children of Presbyterian Ministers or, more familiarly, the Presbyterian
                    Ministers' Fund. The Presbyterian Ministers' Fund is recognized as the first
                    life insurance company in America. In 1990 the Presbyterian Ministers' Fund
                    changed its name to the Covenant Life Insurance Company.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of a typed transcription of "The Book for the Fund,
                    1718-1747." The volume documents expenses, including interest on bonds,
                    payments to employees, printing costs (some payments were made to Mr. Franklin
                    for printing), rental of meeting facilities, and payments to various
                    congregations. The volume also includes records of moneys received by the fund.
                    The transcription (undated) was made by Martha Faires Grant.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Transferred from the library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 94 0715</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Historical Society of
                    Pennsylvania: Presbyterian Ministers Fund records (includes the original of the
                    "Book for the Fund, 1718-1747").</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>