<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Presbyterian Social Union of Philadelphia and Vicinity records
                            <date type="inclusive">1888-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Presbyterian Social Union of Philadelphia and Vicinity
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1063</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.67 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1888-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The object of the Presbyterian Social Union of Philadelphia and Vicinity was "to
                    encourage among the members of the Presbyterian Churches a more friendly and
                    intimate acquaintance, to secure concert action, and to promote the general
                    interests of Presbyterianism in this vicinity." John Wanamaker was the first
                    president. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Presbyterian Social Union of Philadelphia
                    and Vicinity. Materials include: manuscript page from 1888 describing the first
                    meeting of the Presbyterian Social Union, presided over by John Wanamaker; a
                    volume of minutes, 1890-1915 with treasurer's reports, resolutions, lists of
                    addresses given, nominations, and programs; copies of the constitution and
                    by-laws and a history of the Presbyterian Social Union; lists of members;
                    programs and menus from annual banquets (1901-1944, with gaps); and reports of
                    the Outlook Committee, 1924-1967. The reports present in narrative form the
                    committee's positions on a variety of themes, including evangelism, foreign
                    missions, atheism, Presbyterian projects and programs, problems of the inner
                    city, senior citizens, and the function of the layman in the church.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accession 93 0210b: Transferred from the library; accession 02 0614c:
                    Presbyterian Social Union (8/5/71)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 93 0210b|02 0614c</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>