<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Presbyterian Ministers' Association of Birmingham, Alabama records
                            <date type="inclusive">1936-1971</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Presbyterian Ministers' Association of Birmingham, Alabama
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC137</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1971</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Presbyterian Ministers' Association of Birmingham was a group of clergymen
                    who met regularly for mutual fellowship. At the meetings, the members heard
                    papers read and held discussions on a variety of topics. The Association
                    disbanded in 1971.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of minutes of the Presbyterian Ministers' Association of
                    Birmingham, Alabama. Minutes discuss routine business and record speakers and
                    the topics of their addresses. Earlier minutes include brief summaries of talks.
                    Volumes also include lists of members, treasurer's reports, newspaper clippings,
                    programs, and responses to a 1970 survey of members on the future of the
                    Association. Some of the minutes discuss racial relations, including proposals
                    in 1963 to open membership of the Association to ministers of "members of any
                    other race."</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Melton, Howard</p>
                <p>Accession number: 05 0514y</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>