<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Presbyterians United for Biblical Concerns records <date type="inclusive">1965-1989</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Presbyterians United for Biblical Concerns
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC882</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>28.35 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1965-1989</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Presbyterians United for Biblical Confession (PUBC) was formed in 1965 as a
                    response to concerns over the Confession of 1967. The PUBC proposed changes to
                    effect a clearer affirmation of the inspiration and authority of the Bible. In
                    1966, the 178th General Assembly approved some of the changes suggested. The
                    PUBC later changed its name to Presbyterians United for Biblical Concerns. In
                    the summer of 1989 PUBC merged with Covenant Fellowship to form Presbyterians
                    for Renewal.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of Presbyterians United for Biblical Concerns.
                    Materials include: minutes, correspondence, memoranda, reports, and agendas from
                    meetings of the Board, the Executive Committee, and annual meetings; executive
                    director files, including correspondence, subject files, financial records, and
                    employee records; files on a 1985 tour of the Holy Land; copies of Communique,
                    1978-1984, and New Updates, from the late 1980s; newsletters from the
                    Presbyterians for Biblical Confession (precursor to PUBC), Presbyterians United
                    for Biblical Confession and PUBC brochures; copies of various publications,
                    including Presbyterian Journal, Presbyterian Outlook, and A.D.; newspaper
                    clippings; and photographs of individuals and meetings. The collection also
                    includes: files from task forces and conferences on various issues, which
                    contain reports, memoranda, correspondence, and position statements; files on a
                    dialogue between Presbyterians for Lesbian/Gay Concerns (PLGC) and PUBC
                    sponsored by the Committee on Pluralism and Conflict; planning documents for
                    PUBC participation at the General Assembly; and files related to the 1976
                    Consultation on Homosexuality (including logistical records, correspondence, and
                    a printed report from the Consultation). Topics addressed include homosexuality,
                    church union, women's ordination, youth evangelism, missions, theological
                    education, the sanctuary movement, inclusive language, and prayer in
                    schools.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accession 78 1114, 90 0727: PUBC; accession 93 0816b, 95 0525h:
                    Welde, Matthew; accession 90 1019c: Scott, Mary Ellen</p>
                <p>Accession number: 78 1114|93 0816b|95 0525h|90 0727|90 1019c</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>