<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Presbyterian Education Society records <date type="inclusive">1820-1872</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Presbyterian Education Society records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1017</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.01 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1820-1872</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Education Society of the Presbyterian Church in the United States was formed
                    in the autumn of 1818. In 1820 the name was changed to Presbyterian Education
                    Society. For a number of years it continued its operations as an independent
                    Society, and had under its care about one hundred young men. In 1827, it became
                    connected with the American Education Society, and was known as the Presbyterian
                    Branch. In this capacity, the field of its operations was limited to the states
                    of New York, New Jersey, and Pennsylvania. In 1831, the operations of the
                    Presbyterian Branch were folded into the American Education Society.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Presbyterian Education Society. Materials
                    include: copies of printed addresses by the Board of Directors of the
                    Presbyterian Education Society, 1820-1831; an address given by Edward D. Griffin
                    to the Society, 1824; subscription book listing subscribers and amount paid for
                    annual subscriptions, undated (appears to be for one year); and an invitation to
                    the 1872 annual meeting of the Philadelphia Education Society, signed by the
                    secretary, Charles Brown, addressee unknown.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Transferred from the library</p>
                <p>Accession number: 91 1107e</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>