<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Raymond B. Knudsen papers <date type="inclusive">1927-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Raymond B. Knudsen papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC872</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>29.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1927-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Raymond Barnett Knudsen (1919-2001) was a Presbyterian minister, consultant, and
                    author of a weekly syndicated newspaper column entitled "The Counselor." He
                    was a 1948 graduate of McCormick Theological Seminary. He served in pastorates
                    in Illinois and New York and was Special Assistant General Secretary and
                    Executive Director for the Department of Financial Development of the National
                    Council of the Churches of Christ in the USA. In 1977 he joined the staff of
                    Church Development, Inc., as Director of the National Consultation on Financial
                    Development. In addition to his weekly column, Knudsen published book reviews in
                    the field of psychology and religion.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of personal and professional papers of Raymond B. Knudsen.
                    The collection includes records of Knudsen's time at seminary, his ministry, his
                    work with the National Council of Churches, his publications, and his work as a
                    consultant. Materials include records and correspondence from Knudsen's
                    ministries in Colorado, Iowa, Indiana, Illinois, and New York, from the mid
                    1930s to the 1970s; scrapbooks of clippings and programs, 1934-1946; seminary
                    papers and files, 1943-1947; records from his time as Director for Broadcasting
                    for the Illinois and Springfield Councils of Churches, 1952-1963; issues of
                    "The Counselor," 1955-1994; "Counselor" recording disks; "Counselor"
                    television formats; manuscripts of Developing Dynamic Stewardship and Models for
                    Ministry (both 1978); financial records; sermon notes and outlines; files
                    related to The Counselor's Association's incorporation and its work for the
                    Presbytery of Greenbrier; and papers related to Kundsen's position as Special
                    Assistant General Secretary for the National Council of the Churches of
                    Christ.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Knudsen, Raymond</p>
                <p>Accession number: 77 0321|88 0801|88 0613|86 1126|98 0826a</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>