<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Richard John Owen papers <date type="inclusive">1894-1958</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Richard John Owen papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC866</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1894-1958</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Richard John Owen (1887-1961) was born in Wales. In 1907 he emigrated to the
                    United States, working in Colorado, Pennsylvania, and Vermont. He began
                    preaching in 1912 in Vermont, and served as a pastor in churches in Vermont,
                    Pennsylvania, and New York. In 1935 he moved to Minnesota, where he served in
                    churches in Carmel, Salem, and Jerusalem.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of sermons, clippings, and other papers of Richard John
                    Owen. Materials include a volume of sermons preached between 1912 and 1939;
                    sermons and notes for sermons, 1923 to 1953, some in Welsh; funeral addresses;
                    notes on readings; a scrapbook of newspaper clippings, mostly in Welsh; loose
                    clippings in English and Welsh; a commonplace book of poems; a published edition
                    of the Book of Common Worship; Owen's 1920 passport; and several
                    photographs.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: note in collection says materials received 8-7-75 from Vaughn C.
                    Jones</p>
                <p>Accession number: 75 0817</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>