<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert Pierre Johnson papers <date type="inclusive">1916-1974</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1940-1974</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert Pierre Johnson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC881</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1974</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1940-1974</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert Pierre Johnson (1914-1974) was a Presbyterian minister who in 1967 was
                    elected Executive Presbyter of New York City. He received his B.D. from Union
                    Theological Seminary in 1940 and was ordained in the same year. He served
                    pastorates in Pennsylvania and Washington D.C. and served as a field
                    representative of Negro Work in the North and West for the Interboard Commission
                    of New York and as Assistant Secretary in the Department of City and Industrial
                    Work. In 1971, the United Presbyterian Church's Council on Church and Race
                    (COCAR) authorized the dispersal of $10,000 to the Marin County Black Defense
                    Fund in support of Angela Davis, who was charged with murder and kidnapping in
                    connection a Black Panther prison escape. COCAR's action was criticized by some
                    members of the church, and as a result, 20 black Presbyterians, Robert Pierre
                    Johnson among them, joined together to reimburse the Emergency Legal Aid
                    Fund.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Robert Pierre Johnson. Materials include:
                    correspondence (1954-1967) with fellow ministers, parishioners, and members of
                    various church-related organizations; sermons and notes for sermons; a travel
                    diary from a trip Johnson took to Europe in 1963; a small amount of material
                    relating to the Black Presbyterians United; a copy of Johnson's thesis The
                    Economic Doctrines of John Calvin (1940); and Johnson's files on the
                    Presbyterian Church's donation to Angela Davis's defense, the Church's response
                    to the Black Manifesto, the Black Panthers, and black involvement in the Church.
                    These files include articles, correspondence, press releases, and policy
                    statements. The collection also includes a 1916 bulletin from the Fifteenth
                    Street Presbyterian Church in Washington D.C.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Johnson-Hyman, Elayne</p>
                <p>Accession number: 78 0725</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>

            <otherfindaid>
                <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" xpointer="http://www.history.pcusa.org/collections/research-tools/guides-archival-collections/rg-471">http://www.history.pcusa.org/collections/research-tools/guides-archival-collections/rg-471</extref>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>