<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>R. W. Bauer papers <date type="inclusive">1977-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">R. W. Bauer papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC921</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Richard Bauer (b. 1930) was a Presbyterian minister who was active in the area of
                    national missions. Bauer was a 1955 graduate of McCormick Theological Seminary,
                    and then served as pastor at Springdale Presbyterian Church, Springdale, Ohio,
                    from 1955 to 1963. Beginning in 1963, he served as Field Administrator for
                    National Missions in the Presbyterian Synod of Minnesota, Director of National
                    Missions for Presybyterian Synod of Michigan, and Director for Texas Christian
                    University. The 1982 General Assembly requested the General Assembly Mission
                    Council to undertake a serious inquiry into the ability of the United
                    Presbyterian Church "to deal...with social, political, and economic crises."
                    Richard W. Bauer was appointed the Project Administrator. The final report was
                    authored by Bauer and Donald L. Leonard and titled "An Historical Study of Past
                    Denominational Responses to Social, Political and Economic Crises."</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection relates to the research and writing of Bauer and Leonard's report
                    on the Presbyterian response to crises in society. Included in this collection
                    is a research plan, correspondence, mailing lists, handwritten notes,
                    audiocassettes and notes for interviews, questionnaire responses, and drafts and
                    Bauer's own copies of the final report and agendas for meetings. In addition
                    there are photocopies from Presbyterian published materials, including General
                    Assembly Mission Council minutes related to topics such as hunger, race, and
                    civil rights; copies (some photocopies) of annual reports of the Hunger Program,
                    1976-1981; printed "Historical Overview" publications on various topics in the
                    United Presbyterian Church in the United States of America, including
                    racial-ethnic ministry policies, new church development policies, mission
                    funding policies, Christian education, youth programs; and official memos and
                    reports related to funding.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Bauer, Richard Waldron</p>
                <p>Accession number: 85 0930</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>