<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Speedwell Avenue Chapel Drop-in-the Bucket Union Missionary records
                            <date type="inclusive">1911-1943</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Speedwell Avenue Chapel Drop-in-the Bucket Union Missionary
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC080</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.17 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1911-1943</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Speedwell Avenue Chapel Drop-in-the Bucket Union Missionary Society was
                    organized on May 26, 1911. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Speedwell Avenue Chapel Drop-in-the Bucket
                    Union Missionary Society. Materials include minutes and reports, 1911-1916 and
                    1925-1943 (2 volumes) Minutes discuss routine business including election of
                    officers as well as sewing projects and addresses by visitors. Treasurer's
                    records, 1924-1943 (1 volume), include records of payments of dues, special
                    collections, and work done by members. This volume was also used as a scrapbook
                    with photographs of India and Japan, postcards, newspaper clippings related to
                    Society events and activities, and other inserts.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Presbyterian Church on the Green</p>
                <p>Accession number: 02 1218x</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>