<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Summer Evangelistic Committee of Philadelphia Presbytery records
                            <date type="inclusive">1900-2001</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Summer Evangelistic Committee of Philadelphia Presbytery
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC183</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1900-2001</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Summer Evangelistic Committee (SEC) was organized in 1899 by the Presbytery
                    of Philadelphia and the Presbyterian Social Union to " present the Gospel of
                    the Lord Jesus Christ throughout the metropolitan area of Philadelphia each year
                    during the months of June to September." Members of the Summer Evangelistic
                    Committee represented the PCUSA Presbytery of Philadelphia, the PCUSA Presbytery
                    of Philadelphia North, and the Presbyterian Social Union.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Summer Evangelistic Committee. Materials
                    include: seven volumes of minutes, 1900-1924 (4 volumes) and minutes from
                    1969-1970, 1972-1974, and 1983-1985; printed annual reports, 1917-1988
                    (incomplete); and brochures, early 2000s. Minutes include reports from
                    committees, treasurer's reports, occasional annual reports, lists of committee
                    members and attendance records. Committees include Open Air, Equipment, Wayside
                    Mission, Industrial Area, Radio and TV, Children's Work, and Tents and Places of
                    Worship. Volumes 1 and 2 include copies of the Committee's constitution and
                    by-laws. The collection also includes photographs, probably made and exhibited
                    for the 50th Anniversary of the SEC in 1949, although the photographs may have
                    been made much later.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: accession 06 1212b: Russell, Arthur, past-president of the SEC;
                    accession 05 0429b: Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 06 1212b|05 0429b</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Eighth Street Wayside Mission records (accession 89
                    0105b).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>