<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas Clinton Pears papers <date type="inclusive">1927-1943</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas Clinton Pears papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC871</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1927-1943</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas Clinton Pears, Jr. was educated at Princeton University, graduating in
                    1907, and at Western Theological Seminary, graduating in 1910. He served in
                    pastorates in West Virginia and Pennsylvania before becoming manager of the
                    Department of History of the Presbyterian Church in 1933. He remained in that
                    position until his death in 1943. Dr. Pears' published and lectured on the
                    history of the Presbyterian Church. Francis Alison was born in Ireland in 1705.
                    He studied at the University of Glasgow before traveling to America in 1735. In
                    1737 he became pastor of Pennsylvania's New London Presbyterian Church. Ten
                    years later he opened an academy in New London. Students of the academy included
                    three signers of the Declaration of Independence and the Secretary of the Second
                    Continental Congress. In 1752 Alison moved to Philadelphia to take charge of the
                    Philadelphia Academy. He was later appointed Vice-Provost of the newly
                    established University of Pennsylvania, as well as Professor of Moral
                    Philosophy. He was also assistant minister at the First Presbyterian Church.
                    Alison died in 1779.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of research materials on Francis Alison collected by Thomas
                    Clinton Pears, Jr. Included are typed and manuscript notes and extracts from
                    books, lectures, minutes, diaries, newspapers and other sources; photostatic and
                    photographic reproductions of manuscripts; typescripts of several of Pears'
                    lectures and articles on Alison, including drafts of "Fra. Alison, a Catholic
                    Divine"; and a small amount of correspondence related to Pears' research.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Klett, Guy S.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 77 0106b</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Thomas Clinton Pears papers (RG 30) and Francis Alison
                    papers (RG 294).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>