<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Thomas Guthrie Speers papers <date type="inclusive">1920-1983</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Thomas Guthrie Speers papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC923</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.0 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1920-1983</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Thomas Guthrie Speers (b. 1890) graduated from Princeton University in 1912 and
                    was ordained after three years at Union Seminary and one year touring mission
                    stations in the Far East. He served in the Army as a chaplain in the First World
                    War. Speers was pastor of the Brown Memorial Presbyterian Church of Baltimore,
                    Maryland, from 1928 to 1957. Speers began an outreach program to Baltimore's
                    Jewish community, occasionally exchanging pulpits with local rabbis. He also
                    abolished racial segregation at the church and supported the installation of the
                    church's pipe organ by Ernest M. Skinner in 1931.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of Thomas Guthrie Speers. Materials include: typed
                    and manuscript sermons, 1920s-1983, often with date and location noted; class
                    materials from courses on the Bible and race relations at Gilman, including exam
                    questions, informational booklets on race relations; and notes, pamphlets,
                    articles and reprints, and a small amount of correspondence on such topics as
                    funerals, children's services, race relations, alcohol, bible study, US
                    military, and trips. There is a small collection of letters to Speers from
                    servicemen in the early 1950s and photos of Speers and family members, including
                    his father.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Speers, T.G., Jr.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 85 1031</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>