<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Transylvania University records <date type="inclusive">1783-1850</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Transylvania University records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC057</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1783-1850</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1780 the Virginia legislature set aside land for the establishment of a school
                    in the Kentucky district. In 1783 the school was named Transylvania Seminary.
                    The first classes were held in Danville, Kentucky in 1785. By 1789 the school
                    had moved to Lexington, Kentucky. As a result of dissatisfaction surrounding
                    waning Presbyterian influence at the seminary, Reverend David Rice and others
                    broke with Transylvania and established Kentucky Academy in 1794. The academy
                    was located in Pisgah, Woodford County where it remained until 1799 when it
                    merged with Transylvania Seminary to form Transylvania University. In its early
                    years, the University included a medical school, a law school, a divinity
                    school, and a college of arts and sciences. During this early period many
                    important figures in American history attended the school. Stephen F. Austin,
                    the "Father of Texas", graduated in 1810. In the early 1820s, Jefferson Davis
                    attended as a student, but chose to finish his studies at West Point. Henry Clay
                    taught at the school's college of law from 1805-1807 before returning to
                    politics and founding the Whig Party.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of record books of the "general heads" of the University,
                    and includes synopses of from minutes and reports from the Board of Trustees,
                    library, treasurer, and other departments. Synopses include lists of trustees,
                    officers, lists of meetings, extracts from by-laws, notes on University lands,
                    and attendance records.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown. Information in RG 196 (Box 21, folder 17) may help establish
                    provenance for these volumes. </p>
                <p>Accession number: 02 0626c</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: The Shane Collection (RG 196).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>