<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Tri-State Bible Conference records <date type="inclusive">1929-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Tri-State Bible Conference records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC918</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1929-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Tri-State Bible Conference was founded in 1929 by Dr. Abraham L. Latham, a
                    pastor of the Third Presbyterian Church of Chester (Pennsylvania) and other
                    members of the Chester Presbytery and lay community as a reaction to what they
                    saw as the increasing liberalization of values and standards within the
                    Presbyterian Church. The Conference was concerned with the training and
                    education of young adults and was conceived as an alternative to the existing
                    summer youth programs that the area Presbyteries offered -- one which emphasized
                    fundamentalist teachings and missionary and evangelical work within the context
                    of Presbyterianism. Despite its Presbyterian origins, the corporation was never
                    official connected to or recognized by the Philadelphia Presbytery or the
                    Committee on Christian Education. During the late 1950s and early 1960s, some
                    attempts were made to unite the Tri-State Bible Conference with the Philadelphia
                    Presbytery. These attempts, failed, however, in part due to friction caused by
                    what was seen by some as the Conference's basically fundamentalist/evangelical
                    stance on religion. Since 1970 the Conference has met each summer at Hilltop
                    Ranch in Colora, Maryland.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Tri-State Bible Conference. Materials
                    include: minutes; brochures, conference programs and flyers; slides and
                    photographs; lists of delegates, 1944-1974: correspondence and lists of
                    delegates, 1975-1979; correspondence, by-laws, and certificate of incorporation,
                    1945; correspondence related to the relationship of Tri-State to the camping
                    programs of the Philadelphia Presbytery, 1955-1962; a two volume history of the
                    Tri-State Bible Conference, 1929-1958; a 1969 Tri-State publicity reel to reel
                    audio tape; several reels of 8mm movie film; printing blocks for the Tri-State
                    Bible Conference; and an index card file of addresses of Board of Directors and
                    members. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Sheldon, Ben</p>
                <p>Accession number: 85 0412</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>