<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>United Presbyterian Alcohol Information and Action Network records
                            <date type="inclusive">1975-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">United Presbyterian Alcohol Information and Action Network
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC910</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.50 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The United Presbyterian Alcohol Information and Action Network was formally
                    organized and granted chapter 28 status by the General Assembly in 1978. It was
                    formed to encourage the UPC to educate its membership in the responsible use of
                    alcoholic beverages, to raise awareness about the pressures in society which
                    result in the abuse of alcohol, and to urge groups and individuals within the
                    church to participate in the treatment of alcoholics and their families.
                    Margaret Fuad and William Ailes were elected co-presidents of the
                    organization.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the United Presbyterian Alcohol Information
                    and Action Network. Materials include: correspondence related to the group's
                    formation; newsletters and brochures; materials related to an ecumenical
                    conference on alcohol problems in the church; and the appearance of the Network
                    at the Youth Triennium in 1980. The collection also includes: by-laws;
                    pamphlets; copies of papers and articles from other church organization an
                    alcohol use and abuse; results of a 1979 questionnaire of church members about
                    alcohol usage; and a small number of organizational records, including
                    information on fundraising, treasurer's reports, and agendas for meetings.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: United Presbyterian Alcohol Information and Action Network (given by
                    William B. Ailes)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 84 1003</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>