<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William P. Thompson papers <date type="inclusive">1954-1967</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William P. Thompson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC844</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1954-1967</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Phelps Thompson (b. 1918), was elected Moderator of the General Assembly
                    of the United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. in 1965. The next year, he was
                    elected stated clerk of the General Assembly. He was a key leader in the merger
                    of several Reformed Church groupings into the World Alliance of Reformed
                    Churches, and served as the Alliance's president from 1970 to 1977. From 1975 to
                    1978, he served as president of the National Council of Churches of Christ in
                    the USA. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of materials related to various committees and divisions of
                    the National Council of Churches of Christ, including the General Assembly, the
                    General Policy and Strategy Committee, the Division of International Affairs,
                    the Division of Christian Unity, the General Administration, the Broadcasting
                    and Film Commission, and a number of others. Materials date from 1954 to 1967,
                    and include minutes, reports, policy statements, memoranda, budgets, and
                    newsletters. Reports address various topics within the church and larger social
                    issues, including civil rights, apartheid, the war in Vietnam, and
                    immigration.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 68 0290</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>