<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William Harold Henderson papers <date type="inclusive">1955-1958</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William Harold Henderson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC963</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.00 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1955-1958</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William H. Henderson (b. 1910) was secretary of the Division of Vocation of the
                    Board of Christian Education of the United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.
                    Prior to this appointment he was university pastor and director of the
                    Westminster Foundation at Iowa State University. In 1957, Henderson received a
                    fellowship for a year's study, observation, and participation in student work in
                    Latin America, under joint sponsorship of the Association of Presbyterian
                    University Pastors, the Board of Christian Education, and the Commission on
                    Ecumenical Mission and Relations. He received a B.D. from Yale University.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers and slides from Henderson's trip to Latin America
                    in 1957-1958. Materials include: slides of schools, villages and cities, farms,
                    and people; correspondence between Henderson and missionaries and staff of the
                    Board of Christian Education related to visit planning; itineraries and agendas;
                    reports from Henderson from each country; programs, bulletins from various
                    churches, schools, and hospitals; and travel brochures, informational pamphlets,
                    and maps. There are materials in Spanish, Portuguese, and other languages.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Henderson, William</p>
                <p>Accession number: 89 0518a</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>