<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Winship family papers <date type="inclusive">1909-1967</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Winship family papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC1121</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.92 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1909-1967</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Irwin Everitt Winship (1925-1995) was a missionary in the Philippines. Winship
                    served in Cebu City and the Visayan Islands. Winship conducted in-service
                    training for ministers and lay leaders working with patients in a leprosarium.
                    He was a graduate of Montana State University and the San Francisco Theological
                    Seminary. While on furlough in 1957, he earned a Th.M degree from Princeton
                    Theological Seminary. His wife, Merilyn Strong Winship (b. 1927) was also a
                    missionary in the Philippines and a graduate of Montana State University. She
                    earned a Master's degree from San Francisco Theological Seminary. She worked at
                    Bethany Hospital, conducting a weekly audio-visual program for patients, staff,
                    and visitors.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of papers of the Winship family. Materials include: reports
                    and papers on missionary work in Philippines and East Asia (various authors,
                    including Winship, many of the papers read at Mission Conferences, 1925-1960);
                    Winship's personal statement to the Presbytery of Kalispell as part of his work
                    towards licensure and ordination; articles and background information about
                    Philippines, Cebu City, and Protestantism and evangelical faith in the
                    Philippines; clippings and architectural drawings of Presbyterian Church in
                    Cebu, Philippines, and a plan of Presbyterian Mission property; minutes of
                    meetings of the cabinet of the Visayan Jurisdiction of the UCCP and of the
                    Philippine Mission of the Presbyterian Church of the USA; minutes,
                    correspondence, and other papers related to Winship's work in Cebu, including
                    papers relating to the Cebu Institute and the Kian Kee High School; and
                    pamphlets and magazines, including items printed by Philippine Agency of the
                    American Bible Society, the Board of Foreign Missions, and others. The
                    collection also includes: photographs, including students at Silliman Bible
                    School, mission meetings in Manila, missionary families/mission personnel
                    (pictures are from Presbyterian Mission and United Church of Christ in the
                    Philippines organizations); obituaries and memorial minutes for various
                    missionaries, including Merne Graham; and a small collection of school papers of
                    Marilyn Winship.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Winship, Merilyn S.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 96 0202|96 0327a</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>