<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Witherspoon Society of Presbyterians records <date type="inclusive">1975-1981</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Witherspoon Society of Presbyterians records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC932</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.50 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1981</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Witherspoon Society was organized in 1973 to work for renewal of the church's
                    life and focus, so that it may continue to be biblically and confessionally
                    faithful in the world. The society's goals are to implement the mission
                    priorities of the General Assembly, develop vehicles of communication,
                    reflection, mutual support, and disciplined action within the network, identify
                    emerging priorities in the church and the world, encourage theological inquiry,
                    seek more effective institutional forms, and seek effective ecumenical
                    expressions of mission.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the Witherspoon Society of Presbyterians.
                    Materials include: incoming and outgoing correspondence related to meetings, the
                    publication of Network News (newsletter), membership, and the Society's work on
                    various programs; financial information, including expense reports, financial
                    statements, and budgets; conference materials, including programs and
                    participant lists; proposals for programs and requests for the Society to
                    address social issues; issues of a newsletter titled The Commissioner Memo,
                    1978; and member lists and membership directories. The collection also includes
                    minutes of the steering committee and executive committee, annual meeting
                    minutes, by-laws, and reports, 1976-1979. Many of the papers appear to have come
                    from the files of Andrew and Dorothea Murray, and Elaine Wareham.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Murray, Dr. Andrew</p>
                <p>Accession number: 86 0306</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Presbyterian
                    Historical Society: Witherspoon Society papers (accession 90 0404a), Witherspoon
                    Society papers (accession 82 0818), Witherspoon Society papers (accession 04
                    0827d).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>