<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Woman's Christian Temperance Union of Kaysville, Utah records <date type="inclusive">1893-1899</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Woman's Christian Temperance Union of Kaysville, Utah
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC069</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.04 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1893-1899</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The National Woman's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU) was founded in Cleveland,
                    Ohio, in November 1874. It grew out of the "Woman's Crusade" of the winter of
                    1873-1874. Members advanced their cause by entering saloons, singing, praying,
                    and urging saloonkeepers to stop selling alcohol. Local chapters were called
                    "Unions" and were largely autonomous, but closely linked to the state unions
                    and national headquarters. The Woman's Christian Temperance Union of Kaysville,
                    Utah, was one of these local chapters.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a volume of minutes of the Woman's Christian Temperance Union of
                    Kaysville, 1893-1899. The minutes record the election of officers, papers read
                    at meetings, and planning of events and programs. The volume includes minutes of
                    "mother's meetings," at which works on child rearing were read. The collection
                    also includes a printed copy of the Woman's Christian Temperance Union of
                    Kaysville's constitution, several programs, and a list of members.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Horosz, David (3/10/71)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 02 0726g</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>