<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Women's Presbyterian Missionary Union of Greater Kansas City
                        records <date type="inclusive">1911-1938</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Women's Presbyterian Missionary Union of Greater Kansas
                    City records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC056</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1911-1938</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Woman's Presbyterian Missionary Union of Greater Kansas City, Parkville,
                    Independence, Missouri, and Overland Park was organized to create and increase
                    intelligent interest in worldwide missions, promote acquaintance and sisterhood
                    among its members and to encourage the circulation of missionary literature.
                    Membership consisted of missionary societies of Presbyterian churches in the
                    districts named in the organization's title.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of minutes of the Woman's Presbyterian Missionary Union of
                    Greater Kansas City. Minutes include: routine business, such as election of
                    officers; lists of reports read before the committee; minutes of semi-annual
                    meetings of the Woman's Presbyterian Missionary Union of Greater Kansas City,
                    1918-1938; printed programs of semi-annual meetings; lists of officers
                    (1906-1918); lists of members; constitution and by-laws; places of meeting; and
                    a list of addresses made by foreign missionaries.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Monnett, Hazel (2/2/68)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 02 0614L</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>