<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>World Sunday School Association Committee for Moslem Lands records
                            <date type="inclusive">1915-1928</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Presbyterian Historical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">World Sunday School Association Committee for Moslem Lands
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">PHSSp.ACC149</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Presbyterian Historical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>0.08 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1915-1928</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The World Sunday School Association held its first convention in London in 1889.
                    Renamed the World's Sunday School Association in 1907, it became the World
                    Council of Christian Education in 1947. The association was merged into the
                    World Council of Churches in 1971. The mission of the association was to promote
                    Christian education amongst youth around the world. The Association's Committee
                    for Moslem Lands was formed in 1915 and held meetings in Cairo and Maadi. Dr. S.
                    M. Zwemer was the committee's first chairman.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records of the World Sunday School Association Committee
                    for Moslem Lands. Materials include committee minutes, expense reports and
                    budgets, and related records. Minutes include brief reports from committee
                    members describing conditions abroad and information related to various
                    publications issued by the WSSA. The volume also includes a list of members of
                    the Committee from 1924.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Unknown</p>
                <p>Accession number: 05 0603</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>