<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>A. Lindo Patterson papers <date type="inclusive">1923-1968</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">A. Lindo Patterson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1743</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>54 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1923-1968</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Arthur Lindo Patterson (1902-1966) was a crystallographer who is best known for
                    developing the Patterson function, an application of Fourier methods to X-ray
                    diffraction. Patterson was born in New Zealand and educated at McGill
                    University. He worked in many universities and research institutions, including
                    the Royal Institution in London, the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute at Berlin-Dahlem,
                    and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. From 1940 until 1949 he was an
                    associate professor at Bryn Mawr College. Beginning in 1949 he was senior member
                    and head of the Department of Physics at the Institute for Cancer Research in
                    Philadelphia. Patterson published numerous papers on X-ray analysis of crystal
                    structures and was co-author, with W. C. Michels, of Elements of Modern
                    Physics.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the professional papers of A. Lindo Patterson. Materials
                    include: correspondence; drafts of papers and related computations; newsletters
                    and minutes from professional organizations, such as the American
                    Crystallographic Association and the Crystallographic Society of America;
                    correspondence and articles from symposia, such as meetings of the American
                    Society for X-Ray and Electron Diffraction; computation books, research notes,
                    graphs, technical drawings, and computer printouts of data; glass x-ray plates,
                    x-ray film, and photographs; printing blocks of illustrations for articles; and
                    lecture notes and exam questions from courses Patterson taught at Bryn Mawr
                    College.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Crystallography, Mathematical.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Lecture notes</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Research notes</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>