<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Philosophical Society miscellaneous records <date type="inclusive">1912-1991</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Philosophical Society miscellaneous
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1754</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>6.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1912-1991</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Founded in 1743 by Benjamin Franklin, the American Philosophical Society was the
                    first learned society in the United States. For over 250 years, the Society has
                    played an important role in American cultural and intellectual life. Until the
                    mid-nineteenth century, the Society fulfilled the role of a national academy of
                    science, national library and museum, and even patent office. Early members of
                    the Society included Thomas Jefferson, David Rittenhouse, Benjamin Rush, Stephen
                    Peter Du Ponceau, George Washington, and many other figures prominent in
                    American history.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of miscellaneous records from several offices of the
                    American Philosophical Society. The collection consists of: office files of
                    Randolph S. Klein on various topics, including meetings, public relations and
                    information requests, fundraising, and members (circa 1980-1990); office files
                    of Jean T. Williams (assistant to the Executive Officer), including files on
                    membership, fundraising, committees, and copies of newsletters (circa
                    1986-1991); materials related to the Building and Endowment Fund (1912-1937),
                    including a survey and plan of the campaign, ledger of subscriptions, and
                    statements; information on renovations to the buildings owned by the Society;
                    copies of the Society's pension plan (1957-1969); master copies of various
                    American Philosophical Society forms, including applications and agreements for
                    grant recipients and recommendation forms (circa 1940); an inventory of art and
                    artifacts, including locations and conservation work performed; and records
                    concerning a lawsuit filed by Gail Beckman against the Pennsylvania Historical
                    and Museum Commission and APS, including court records, correspondence, and
                    depositions (1966-1983).</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Fund raising.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Learned institutions and
                    societies--Administration.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>