<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Philosophical Society development records <date type="inclusive">1981-1998</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Philosophical Society development
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1748</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>33 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1981-1998</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Founded in 1743 by Benjamin Franklin, the American Philosophical Society was the
                    first learned society in the United States. The endowment of the Society
                    provides a substantial portion of the operating budget. The Annual Fund, which
                    provides unrestricted operating support, was initiated in 1992 and continues to
                    grow. Foundation grants play an important role, as do the Friends of the
                    Library, in the support of special projects, such as the development of
                    information retrieval systems and the refinement of conservation activities in
                    the Library. Building campaigns have also been a significant source of funds
                    throughout the Society's history. For example, the Benjamin Franklin Hall
                    Campaign, begun in 1981 in conjunction with the purchase of the Farmers' and
                    Mechanics' Bank building and continuing for over a decade, raised funds for that
                    building's renovation to serve as a meeting and collection storage space.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of records related to development activities at the APS. The
                    collection documents major fundraising efforts, including the Annual Fund, the
                    Benjamin Franklin Hall Campaign, and grant proposals to the Mellon Foundation.
                    The Annual Fund records cover the years 1992 to 1996 and include: drafts of
                    appeal letters; monthly reports; and letters of acknowledgment and copies of
                    checks. Records of the Benjamin Franklin Hall Campaign (1981-1992) include:
                    steering committee reports, planning and strategy documents, pledge projections
                    and budgets, copies of appeals to the general membership, foundation and
                    corporate appeals, incoming and outgoing correspondence with donors and
                    prospects, and campaign publications, such as brochures and printed letters.
                    Records of Mellon Foundation grants include drafts and finished copies of grant
                    proposals, projected budgets, and correspondence. The collection also includes
                    correspondence and planning documents from the files of John Callahan and other
                    staff with development responsibilities. These files document fundraising
                    efforts such as the Daland fellowship, the Lincei project, as well as various
                    exhibitions and awards, including the Rhoads medal (1997). These files also
                    document other projects with which Callahan was involved, such as executive
                    searches for the Institute for Nautical Archaeology and the Delaware Theater
                    Company, and the Russian Translation Project.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Fund raising.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Learned institutions and
                    societies--Administration.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Financial records</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>