<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Philosophical Society meetings records <date type="inclusive">1936-1997</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1976-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Philosophical Society meetings records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1750</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>16.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1997</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1976-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Founded in 1743 by Benjamin Franklin, the American Philosophical Society was the
                    first learned society in the United States. Meetings of the Society are held
                    annually in April and November, with attendance averaging several hundred
                    members and distinguished guests. Papers presented at these meetings, and the
                    discussions that follow, explore topics in both the sciences and humanities,
                    from underwater archaeology to nuclear magnetic imaging, from Shakespeare's
                    writings to race relations in modern America. In addition to these regular
                    meetings, the Society holds a number of smaller sessions for specialists to
                    present papers focused on topics of particular interest; biological complexity,
                    the way we choose our Presidents, and the protein as a science laboratory are
                    some of the recent subjects of these sessions.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection documents the planning and activities of annual meetings and
                    special meetings of the American Philosophical Society. Records related to
                    annual meetings include meeting minutes, correspondence with speakers and
                    attendees, abstracts of talks, curricula vitae of speakers, post-meeting summary
                    reports, drafts of programs and printed programs, attendee lists and
                    registrations, logistical documentation of travel and schedules, and audio
                    recordings and transcripts of the Council and Executive sessions of the 1976 and
                    1977 meetings. Records related to meetings conducted jointly by the American
                    Philosophical Society and the Accademia Nazionale dei Lincei (1996) and the
                    Royal Society of London (1991) include correspondence between the Society's
                    staff and their counterparts at the other institutions, correspondence with
                    speakers and attendees, curricula vitae of speakers, abstracts of papers,
                    programs and agendas, documentation of travel logistics, routine budgeting and
                    purchasing records, and a small number of photographs. Records related to the
                    250th anniversary meeting of the American Philosophical Society include minutes
                    of planning committees, publicity and press releases, special invitations,
                    information on the Philadelphia Symphony's commemorative concert series for the
                    anniversary, programs, pamphlets, and newsletters. The collection also includes
                    an A to Z card file of speakers from approximately 1940 to 1984, giving the name
                    of the speaker and the title and year of the talk; printed, collated lists of
                    speakers and talks from 1940 to 1975; and printed programs from annual meetings
                    from 1936 to 1959.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Accademia nazionale dei Lincei.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Royal Society (Great Britain)</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Learned institutions and
                    societies--Membership.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Financial records</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Minutes</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Newsletters</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>