<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Charles Gillispie papers <date type="inclusive">1961-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Charles Gillispie papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1741</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>23.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1961-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Charles C. Gillispie (b. 1918) is a historian of science specializing in France
                    1760-1820. He received his bachelor's degree from Wesleyan University and did
                    graduate work at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and Harvard
                    University. He joined the faculty of Princeton University in 1947, where he
                    founded both the undergraduate and graduate programs in the history of science;
                    he is now professor emeritus. He was awarded the Balzan Prize in history and
                    philosophy of science in 1997. He was the editor of the Dictionary of Scientific
                    Biography, and his publications include The Edge of Objectivity (1960),
                    Pierre-Simon Laplace, 1749-1827: A Life in Exact Science (1997), and Science and
                    Polity in France: The Revolutionary and Napoleonic Years (2004).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of Charles Gillispie's research notes, reprints, and
                    copies of texts and manuscripts related to his work on 18th and 19th century
                    science in France. Many of the texts and manuscripts are in French, and are
                    present here in the form of photocopies and microfilm. The collection also
                    includes some transcriptions by Gillispie, and his manuscript notes on the
                    original works. In addition to the research materials, there are some drafts of
                    articles by Gillispie, lecture notes on the history of science in France and in
                    America, and several dissertations on the history of science by others.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Science--France--History.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Science--History.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Lecture notes</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reprints</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Research notes</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>