<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>D. Carleton Gajdusek papers <date type="inclusive">1876-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">D. Carleton Gajdusek papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1755</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>125 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1876-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>A pediatrician and virologist trained at the University of Rochester and Harvard
                    Medical School, Daniel Carleton Gajdusek became interested in epidemiological
                    issues in "exotic and isolated populations" early in the 1950s, and while
                    working as a visiting investigator at the Walter and Eliza Institute of Medical
                    Research in Melbourne he had his first introduction to a neurological disorder,
                    kuru, that was endemic among the Neolithic Fore of New Guinea. In an exemplary
                    study, Gajudusek determined that kuru was not hereditary, as previously
                    supposed, but was an infectious disease transmitted through the ritualistic
                    consumption of the brains of deceased relatives. He was recognized for his
                    achievements with the 1976 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the professional and personal papers of Carlton Gajdusek.
                    Materials include: incoming and outgoing work-related correspondence, contracts,
                    financial records, and performance appraisals; research materials related to the
                    Middle Eastern Serum Study; family correspondence with his mother, Ottilia
                    Mahtil Dobrosky Gajdusek (1893-1966), brother, Robert Elemer Gajdusek (b. 1925)
                    and his children and grandchildren; school records of his adoptive children;
                    biographical sketches of correspondents; and CVs and supporting materials. The
                    collection also includes journals from 1937-1940 and 1951-1998 documenting his
                    medical and epidemiological research (especially that on Kuru), pediatric
                    studies, and human and population genetics work in Africa, Australia, Colombia,
                    Guam, Indonesia, Libya, Melanesia, New Guinea, New Hebrides, Pacific Islands,
                    Paraguay, Soviet Union, and the Western Caroline Islands; annotated typescripts
                    and photocopies of the journals.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: National Library of
                    Medicine: D. Carleton Gajdusek correspondence (MS C 565).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>