<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Elisabeth Tooker papers <date type="inclusive">1948-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Elisabeth Tooker papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1236</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>38.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1948-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>An anthropologist and student of Native American cultures, Elisabeth Tooker
                    (1927-2005) devoted a long career, much of it as a professor at Temple
                    University, to the study of the culture and ethnohistory of the Iroquois Indians
                    of New York State. Tooker received her bachelor's degree from Radcliffe College
                    and did her graduate work at the University of Arizona and Radcliffe, studying
                    the Indians of the American Southwest. She taught at the State University of New
                    York at Buffalo and Mount Holyoke College before joining the faculty of Temple
                    University, where she remained for the rest of her professional career, in 1965.
                    Her publications include An Ethnography of the Huron Indians, 1615-1649 (1964);
                    The Indians of the Northeast: A Critical Bibliography (1978), and Lewis H.
                    Morgan on Iroquois Material Culture (1994).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the professional papers of Elisabeth Tooker. Materials
                    include: research notes; copies of background articles and manuscripts;
                    bibliographic card files; reprints, journals, and bulletins; lists of books,
                    papers, and artifacts in the Lewis H. Morgan Library; photographs of people,
                    landscapes, artifacts, and ceremonies; microfilm, slides, and sound recordings;
                    and maps. Much of the collection is organized into files by subject, which
                    include Tooker's notes, copies of articles, and relevant correspondence. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Iroquois Indians.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Women anthropologists.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Microforms</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reprints</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Slides (Photographs)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Sound recordings</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Donated by Elisabeth Tooker (from MOLE for earlier accession)</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1994 (from MOLE for earlier accession)</p>
                <p>Accession number: M2005-11</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>