<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Frederick Mosteller papers <date type="inclusive">1943-2001</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Frederick Mosteller papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1242</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>28 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1943-2001</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Frederick Mosteller (1916-2006) was one of the premier statisticians of his
                    generation. He received his master's degree from the Carnegie Institute of
                    Technology (now Carnegie Mellon University) in 1939. In 1946, he received his
                    Ph.D. from Princeton University, where he worked with statisticians Samuel Wilks
                    and John Tukey. The same year, he joined the faculty of Harvard University in
                    the social relations department. He was the first chairman of Harvard's
                    statistics department, remaining in that role until 1971. He retired in 1987 as
                    the chairman of the department of health policy and management. Mosteller
                    applied mathematical theories to the analysis of educational development and
                    assessment, medical practices, sports, and other fields. One notable study was a
                    statistical analysis of the Federalist papers to settle a question of
                    authorship.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the professional papers of Frederick Mosteller. The
                    papers in this collection document Mosteller's statistical inquiry in the areas
                    of educational assessment, bias in social research, authorship analysis,
                    quantitative expressions of probability, sports, coincidence, and variance
                    analysis. Materials include: reprints of Mosteller's articles; memoranda on
                    National Science Foundation-funded projects; notes, correspondence, photocopied
                    reference articles, and drafts for various studies; awards, certificates, and
                    honorary degrees; and a copy of Mosteller's master's thesis on rank correlation.
                    The collection also includes Mosteller's academic gown and regalia.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Education--Evaluation--Methodology.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Mathematical linguistics.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Social sciences--Statistical methods.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Statistics</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reprints</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: M2006-15</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>