<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>George Vaux papers <date type="inclusive">1701-1985</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">George Vaux papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1757</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>97 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1701-1985</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Vaux family were prominent Philadelphia Quakers. The papers center on the
                    family and business concerns of the surgeon George Vaux V (1721-1803) and his
                    lineal descendants, George Vaux VII, and George Vaux VIII (1832-1915). Other,
                    related families represented in the collection include the Warders, Sansoms,
                    Heads, Graffs, Morrises, Cressons, and Mayberrys. George Vaux VIII was the
                    Secretary and Treasurer of the Swatara Coal Company. He was interested in Quaker
                    history and records and served as an unofficial correspondent for the
                    Philadelphia Yearly Meeting with London Yearly Meeting. His brother, William
                    Sansom Vaux (1811-1882) was a mineralogist and member of the Academy of Natural
                    Sciences. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The 18th century material includes the trans-Atlantic correspondence of James,
                    Richard, and George V, along with domestic correspondence relating to family and
                    business affairs. Several letters discuss Philadelphia during the British
                    occupation, and seven discuss yellow fever in 1797-1798, with a particularly
                    fine letter by Ann Warder discussing the epidemic of 1798. The participation of
                    George Vaux VII in a Quaker mission to the Seneca Indians in 1803 is well
                    documented. Later correspondence, almost all personal and familial in nature,
                    documents the interest of George Vaux VIII in mineralogy, his travels abroad,
                    and Vaux genealogy. The collection also includes correspondence of William
                    Sansom Vaux, much of it related to mineralogy. The collection also contains
                    business correspondence and records of William Sansom, James Vaux, and several
                    George Vauxes and includes receipts, vouchers, correspondence, share
                    certificates, tax documents, legal documents (printed transcripts,
                    verdicts/decisions, statements, and filings), receipt books, daybooks, and
                    ledgers. (1792-1825). Records in the collection documenting the Deborah E.
                    Emlen, William Sansom, Robert Morris, John and Sally Norris Dickinson, Michah M.
                    Moore, John Gordon, Mary M. Johnson, and Cassady family estates include deeds,
                    land records, inventories, correspondence, and vouchers (1700s-1870s). Swatara
                    Coal Company records include correspondence and letter books, dividend book, and
                    account books (1794-1870s). There are also pamphlets and reprints related to
                    mineralogy; almanacs, some with annotations; maps and land surveys; newspapers,
                    broadsides, and other ephemera.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Haverford College:
                    Vaux family papers and Vaux collection of correspondence, documents, and
                    graphics; Friends Historical Library, Swarthmore College: George Vaux family
                    papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>