<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>George T. Reynolds papers <date type="inclusive">1952-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">George T. Reynolds papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1239</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1952-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>George T. Reynolds (1917-2005) was a leading research director in the fields of
                    cosmic rays, high energy particle physics, and biophysics. Reynolds graduated
                    from Rutgers University in 1939 and earned his Ph.D. from Princeton in 1943.
                    During World War II, Reynolds worked on the Manhattan Project as a blast effect
                    specialist and was sent to Japan to conduct bomb damage analysis. He returned to
                    Princeton in 1946 as an assistant professor, and by 1959 he was a full
                    professor. He gained emeritus status in 1987. From 1948 to 1970, Reynolds was
                    director of the High Energy Physics Program at Princeton. Reynolds' later
                    research focused on applying image intensification techniques to biological
                    observations, including bioluminescence and X-ray diffraction. This work led to
                    an appointment as a member of the Corporation of the Marine Biological
                    Laboratory in Woods Hole, Massachusetts, where he was a principal investigator
                    during the course of 31 summers. He was also an adjunct scientist at the Woods
                    Hole Oceanographic Institution.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the professional papers of George T. Reynolds, much of it
                    related to his work on image intensification techniques. Materials include:
                    technical reports, research proposals, dissertations, reprints and drafts of
                    articles by Reynolds and others; subject files on topics within physics and
                    other branches of science; proposals, reports, and financial records for grants
                    from the National Science Foundation, the Department of Energy, and other
                    funding organizations; lab notes; notes and programs for conferences and
                    symposia; problem sets and questions for senior comprehensive examinations at
                    Princeton; and photographs, negatives, slides, and technical drawings.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Bioluminescence.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Green flash.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">X-rays--Diffraction.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Clippings</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reprints</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: M2006-12</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>