<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Hans Ris papers <date type="inclusive">1941-1998</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Hans Ris papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1742</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1941-1998</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Hans Ris (1914-2004) was born in Bern, Switzerland. He was a graduate of the
                    University of Bern. In 1939 he was offered a teaching assistantship in Zoology
                    at Columbia University, where he worked with the cytologist Franz Schrader and
                    his wife, Sally Hughes-Schrader. In 1942 Ris became Instructor in Biology at
                    Johns Hopkins University, and in 1944 he joined the lab of Alfred Mirsky at the
                    Rockefeller Institute. In 1949 Ris joined the Zoology Department at the
                    University of Wisconsin at Madison, where he established an electron microscope
                    laboratory to study chromosome and nuclear structure. In 1969 he established the
                    Madison High Voltage Electron Microscope Facility (HVEM). Ris was a founding
                    member of the American Society for Cell Biology (ASCB) in 1960, and served as
                    its first Treasurer and later served on its Council. Ris had an interest in
                    Chinese society and culture, and beginning in 1985, he made several visits to
                    Chinese laboratories; in 1990 he established a formal scientific exchange
                    program between the ASCB and the Chinese Society for Cell Biology. Ris was a
                    Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and member of the National
                    Academy of Sciences.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Hans Ris. Materials include: photographs
                    (transmission electron micrographs and high voltage electron microscope images);
                    drafts and galley proofs of articles; correspondence with colleagues; class
                    notes and lab notebooks; notes from conferences and poster sessions; articles by
                    others; correspondence with and records related to postdoctoral fellows;
                    correspondence related to his visits to Russia and China; and illustrations.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Electron microscopy.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Transmission electron microscopy.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Galley proofs</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Notebooks</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>