<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Jane M. Rosenthal papers <date type="inclusive">1971-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Jane M. Rosenthal papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1234</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Jane M. Rosenthal (1925-2004) was a linguist and teacher. She received her
                    bachelor's degree in journalism from Indiana University, where she also met her
                    husband, Robert Rosenthal. After college, she worked as a reporter for the daily
                    newspaper in Bedford, Indiana. After their marriage, the couple moved to
                    Chicago, where Robert Rosenthal attended the Graduate Library School at the
                    University of Chicago. He later became the head of the University's manuscript
                    and archives collections. Jane Rosenthal taught English and citizenship to
                    immigrant adults for several years, and then began graduate work in linguistics
                    at the University of Chicago, earning her master's degree in 1971. Her
                    specialization was the Aztec language. She then taught English language and
                    linguistics at Chicago State University, Roosevelt University, and the National
                    College of Education, where she was Coordinator of the Language Institute. While
                    she taught, she continued her research in Nahuatl and Uto-Aztecan languages and
                    Mexican history and culture, and pursued additional graduate coursework at the
                    University of Chicago.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the professional papers of Jane M. Rosenthal. Materials
                    include: notes and drafts of Rosenthal's articles; copies of articles and
                    manuscripts by others; conference and lecture handouts and notes; clippings;
                    correspondence, much of it related to conferences; notebooks and index cards
                    containing lexicons and glossaries; transcriptions and copies of classical texts
                    in Spanish; and photographs and negatives. </p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Linguistics.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Nahuatl language.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Uto-Aztecan languages.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Lecture notes</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: M2004-31</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>