<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John Wheeler papers <date type="inclusive">1911-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John Wheeler papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1238</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>13.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1911-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Archibald Wheeler (b. 1911) is a leading figure in the development of
                    general relativity and quantum gravity. He received his doctorate from Johns
                    Hopkins University in 1933. He was professor of physics at Princeton University
                    from 1938 to 1976, then professor of physics at the University of Texas at
                    Austin. Wheeler's graduate students included Richard Feynman, Kip Thorne, and
                    Hugh Everett. He was a pioneer in the theory of nuclear fission, along with
                    Niels Bohr and Enrico Fermi. In 1939 he collaborated with Bohr on the liquid
                    drop model of nuclear fission. Together with other leading physicists during
                    World War II, Wheeler participated in the development of the atomic bomb under
                    the Manhattan Project at Hanford, Washington. He went on to work on the
                    development of the American hydrogen bomb under Project Matterhorn B. After
                    concluding his Project Matterhorn work, Wheeler returned to Princeton to resume
                    his academic career. In 1957, while working on extensions to general relativity,
                    he introduced the word "wormhole" to describe tunnels in space-time. His work
                    in general relativity included the theory of gravitational collapse, and in 1967
                    he coined the term "black hole." Wheeler was awarded the Wolf Prize in Physics
                    in 1997. He maintained an office at Princeton until 2006.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of professional and personal papers of John Wheeler.
                    Professional materials include: correspondence with colleagues related to
                    articles, awards, and talks; calculations, graphs and diagrams, lecture notes
                    and overhead transparencies; reprints and articles by Wheeler and others;
                    dissertations and manuscripts by others, including copies of Crawford H.
                    Greenewalt's diaries; awards and diplomas; and photographs. Personal materials
                    include: letters to and from Wheeler's family, including a series from his
                    mother (1935-1959); greeting cards; newspaper clippings; genealogical
                    information on Reverend John Wheeler; a file of quotations collected by Wheeler;
                    a memoir entitled "It from Bit"; a scrapbook kept by Wheeler; an unidentified
                    1911 travel diary; and family photographs. The collection also includes
                    Wheeler's FBI file, and miscellaneous artifacts, such as drafting tools, pins,
                    and commemorative plates.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Astrophysics.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Awards</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Lecture notes</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Notebooks</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photograph albums</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reprints</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Deposited by Dr. James Wheeler. (from MOLE record for 24 ft.) </p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1976 (from MOLE record for 24 ft)</p>
                <p>Accession number: M2006-05</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>