<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Marshall Clagett papers <date type="inclusive">1937-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Marshall Clagett papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1237</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>18.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1937-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Marshall Clagett (1916-2005) was one of the world's leading historians of
                    medieval science, in particular the work and influence of Archimedes. He
                    received his bachelor's and master's degrees from George Washington University,
                    and his Ph.D. in history from Columbia University. From 1947 to 1964, he was a
                    professor of the History of Science and later Vilas Research Professor at the
                    University of Wisconsin, where he also directed the Institute for Research in
                    the Humanities for six years. From Wisconsin, he went to the Institute for
                    Advanced Study in Princeton, New Jersey, where he was a professor in the School
                    of Historical Studies. He was the author of more than a dozen volumes on the
                    history of science and mathematics. His major work was the five-volume
                    Archimedes in the Middle Ages, published over 20 years starting in 1964. His
                    more recent scholarship focused on science in ancient Egypt. He was a fellow of
                    the Medieval Academy of America, past president of the History of Science
                    Society, and a member and former vice president of the American Philosophical
                    Society.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the professional papers of Marshall Clagett. Materials
                    include: incoming and outgoing correspondence with colleagues and publishers;
                    research notes, including photostats, photographs, and transcriptions of source
                    material; articles and reprints; drafts of Clagett's manuscripts; course
                    handouts; and correspondence and minutes from various professional organizations
                    and societies, including the American Philosophical Society and the History of
                    Science Society. The collection includes a small number of personal papers,
                    including correspondence regarding Clagett's academic appointments and housing
                    arrangements and a few receipts.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Science--Egypt--History.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Science--History.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Science, Medieval.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Reprints</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Research notes</genreform>

            </controlaccess>

            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: M2006-04</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>