<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Houston family papers (series
                        19) <date type="inclusive">1693-1980</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> post-1930s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Houston family papers
                    (series 19)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1796</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1693-1980</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> post-1930s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Houston family came to the Lancaster County area of Pennsylvania in the early
                    eighteenth century from Scotland, by way of Northern Ireland. The family
                    prospered and Henry Howard Houston's grandfather, John Houston, was able to gain
                    a college education. John also earned a medical degree while studying at the
                    University of Pennsylvania and was active as a patriot during the American
                    Revolution. Houston married Susanna Wright, of Wrightsville, Pennsylvania. The
                    Wright's were also a successful and politically powerful family. Susanna's
                    father, John Wright, owned a ferry across the Susquehanna River, and sat in the
                    Pennsylvania Assembly. Samuel Nelson Houston (1790-1878), one of John and
                    Susanna's nine children, was the father of Henry Howard Houston. In 1817 Samuel
                    married Susan Strickler, and the second of five children, Henry Howard, was born
                    October 3, 1820.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Houston family papers contain material in a wide variety of formats including
                    photographs; newspaper and magazine clippings, and other printed material;
                    manuscript items including letters, notes, and lists. This series is primarily
                    concerned with early family history and genealogy, up to and including material
                    about Henry Howard Houston's father, Samuel N. Houston. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>