<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. George Smith papers (series 67)
                            <date type="inclusive">1693-1952</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1820s-1910s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. George Smith papers
                    (series 67)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1814</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>20 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1693-1952</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1820s-1910s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dr. George Smith (1804-1882) was the son of Benjamin H. Smith and the husband of
                    Mary Lewis Smith (1808-1892). Margaretta Smith, George Smith, Jr., and Clement
                    L. Smith were their children. Mary and George Smith were the grandparents of
                    Lawrence M.C. Smith, husband of Eleanor Houston Smith. Although educated at the
                    University of Pennsylvania as a doctor, George Smith gained most fame as a
                    politician and naturalist. In 1831 Smith was elected to the Pennsylvania State
                    Senate representing both Delaware and Chester Counties. In 1833 he, along with
                    John Cassin, George Miller, John Miller and Minshall Painter, founded the
                    Delaware County Institute of Science. Smith used his farm "Collenbrook" as a
                    base of operations for his study of nature and his political career. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection of papers pertains to the life of George Smith as well as some
                    members of his family including his wife Mary and his daughter Rebecca.
                    Materials in the collection include: letters to and from George Smith; diaries;
                    account and receipt books; wills, bonds, leases and mortgages; school notebooks;
                    commonplace books; notes and transcripts used in writing Smith's history of
                    Delaware County; newspapers and clippings; and photographs. Additionally the
                    collection contains material relating to the establishment of the Delaware
                    County Institute of Science. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>