<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Samuel Frederic and Charlotte
                        H.S. Houston family papers (series 16) <date type="inclusive">1895-1983</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Samuel Frederic and
                    Charlotte H.S. Houston family papers (series 16)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1794</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1895-1983</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Samuel Frederic Houston (1866-1952) and Charlotte Harding Shepherd (1867-1940)
                    were married in Philadelphia in 1902. The marriage was the second for both Sam
                    and Charlotte. Sam's first marriage, in 1887, to Edith Atlee Corlies (1864-1895)
                    of Philadelphia, resulted in three children, Edith (1888-1970), Margaret
                    (1891-1970), and Henry Howard II (1895-1918). Edith died from complications
                    developed after the birth of Henry, in 1895. Henry II died while a soldier in
                    World War I. After about seven years of living at Druim Moir with his children
                    and mother, Sallie Sherrerd Bonnell Houston, Sam married Charlotte. Charlotte, a
                    widow and friend of Sam's first wife, brought two children to Druim Moir,
                    Charles Wardell Brown, Jr. (1891-1951) and Charlotte Harding Brown (1895-1973).
                    Sam and Charlotte had one child together, Eleanor, born in the summer of 1910.
                    The Houstons took a number of trips abroad, chief amongst was a 1902-1903 trip
                    to Europe. Sam, Charlotte and the children sailed the eastern Mediterranean and
                    made ports of call at Tunis, Malta, Zante, Delphi, Corinth, Athens,
                    Constantinople, Knossos, Gournia, and Venice. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Samuel Frederic Houston and his wife
                    Charlotte. Materials include; correspondence; clippings; invitation acceptance
                    lists; scrapbooks; photographs documenting the family’s several trips to Europe;
                    and a notebook entitled "Books We Have Read" in which Sam and Charlotte list
                    books read, by author, with a short review of each. The collection also includes
                    correspondence, clippings, invitations, photographs, printed material, a
                    scrapbook, and postcards regarding Henry's military service in France, and his
                    death there in the summer of 1918. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University Archives
                    and Records Center, University of Pennsylvania: Henry Howard Houston estate
                    papers; Pennsylvania State Archives: H.H. Houston estate papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>