<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Eleanor Houston Smith papers
                        (series 73) <date type="inclusive">1918-1987</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Eleanor Houston Smith
                    papers (series 73)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1820</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>60 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1918-1987</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Eleanor Houston Smith (1910-1987) was the daughter of Samuel Frederic Houston and
                    the wife of Lawrence M.C. Smith. She was a Distinguished Daughter of
                    Pennsylvania, served two terms on the Historical Commission of Pennsylvania,
                    founder of the Schuylkill Valley Nature Center, and a longtime member of the
                    Board of Governors of the Nature Conservancy. In 1987 she received the degree of
                    Doctor of Humane Letters from the Philadelphia College of Textiles and
                    Science.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Eleanor Houston Smith. Materials include:
                    correspondence with family and friends; greeting cards; letters of condolence on
                    the death of her husband Lawrence M. C. Smith; Christmas lists; genealogies;
                    invitations; calendars and address books; diaries; scrapbooks; and photographs.
                    Materials in the collection documenting financial matters include bills and
                    receipts, wills, financial statements, account books, and inventories. The
                    collection also contains materials related to the Franklin Broadcasting Company
                    and WFLN. Records related to Smith's involvement with the Schuylkill Valley
                    Nature Center include minutes, annual reports, correspondence and memos. In
                    addition the collection contains correspondence, clippings, articles, reports,
                    and brochures related to clubs and organizations in which Smith was a member or
                    had an interest. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>