<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Henry H. Houston II papers
                        (series 17) <date type="inclusive">1910-1981</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1910-1930s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Henry H. Houston II
                    papers (series 17)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1795</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1981</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1910-1930s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Born in 1895 to Samuel Frederic and Edith Altee Corlies Houston, Henry Howard
                    Houston II (1895-1918), nicknamed "Hennie," was the last of the couple's three
                    children, and their only son. Henry graduated from the University of
                    Pennsylvania in 1916, and in June of that year enlisted in Battery "C" of the
                    1st Pennsylvania Artillery. He went with his unit to the Mexican border when
                    President Wilson called for troops to respond to Pancho Villa's raids into the
                    United States. Along with his cousin, Henry Howard Houston Woodward, Hennie
                    served in France with the American Ambulance Service (later, American Field
                    Service). When the United States entered the hostilities in Europe, Hennie
                    rejoined his fellow Pennsylvanians in the 53rd Field Artillery Brigade of the
                    American Expeditionary Force, and served as aide-de-camp for Brigadier General
                    William G. Price, Jr. Both Henry Houston II and Henry H. H. Woodward were killed
                    in France in 1918. Hennie died in the village of Arcis-le-Ponsart (Department of
                    the Marne) on 18 August, a short time after being struck by fragments from an
                    exploding artillery shell. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains correspondence, diaries, newspaper and magazine
                    clippings, and photographs and prints of Henry H. Houston II. Most of this
                    material has to do with Houston’s time at the University of Pennsylvania, his
                    military service, and death in France during World War I.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: American
                    Philosophical Society: Houston-Brown-Dallett family papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>