<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. A. Lewis Smith papers (series
                        59) <date type="inclusive">1720-1915</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1830s-1890s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. A. Lewis Smith papers
                    (series 59)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1809</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>11 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1720-1915</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1830s-1890s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Abraham Lewis Smith (1831-1913), a respected and much admired lawyer, was born to
                    Dr. George Smith (1804-1882) and Mary Lewis (1808-1892) in Upper Darby Township,
                    Delaware County, Pennsylvania in 1831. Smith graduated from the University of
                    Pennsylvania with a Bachelor of Arts degree in 1850, and a M.A. and Bachelor of
                    Laws in 1853. In 1859, A. Lewis Smith married Rebecca Levis Wood (1837-1925).
                    Together the Smiths raised four children: Henry Clement (1860-1936), Rebecca
                    (1862-1947), Lewis Lawrence (1864-1931) , and Helen Bright (1875-1958). A. Lewis
                    Smith was active in a number of community businesses and organizations; he was
                    director of the Media Title and Trust Company, director of the West End Trust
                    Company, Secretary of the West Chester and Philadelphia Railroad; President of
                    the Delaware County Historical Society; a longtime advisor to the administration
                    of the University of Pennsylvania, and a Vice President of the Alumni Society.
                    He was also a member of the Historical Society of Pennsylvania, Swedish Colonial
                    Society, Genealogical Society, Delaware County Institute of Science, and
                    Pennsylvania Society of the Sons of the American Revolution. Smith also served
                    as a Media Borough councilman representing the West Ward.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of A. Lewis Smith. Materials include: grade
                    school and college notebooks and grade reports; account books, stock
                    certificates, and receipts; letters to Smith from family members; legal
                    documents, including property deeds, for legal cases in which Smith was involved
                    as an attorney or executor; printed material including "paper books" of
                    counsel in legal cases; a few blueprints detailing proposed property development
                    in Media, Pennsylvania; and correspondence, newsletters, and applications
                    relating to A. Lewis Smith's membership in the Philadelphia Lawyer's Club, Sons
                    of the American Revolution, and the Delaware County Historical Society among
                    others.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>