<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Massey family papers (series 38)
                            <date type="inclusive">1748-1986</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1962-1986</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Massey family papers
                    (series 38)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1808</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1748-1986</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1962-1986</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Thomas Massey House is one of the oldest English Quaker homes in the
                    Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. It is on the National Register of Historical
                    Places, and the Historical American Building Survey. The 1696 brick portion was
                    built by Thomas Massey as an addition to the existing log or frame house. In
                    1731 his son, Mordecai, replaced the log or frame house with a stone section.
                    Thomas Massey was born in the village of Marpoole (Marple) in Cheshire, England
                    in 1663. At the age of twenty Massey traveled to Chester as an indentured
                    servant to Francis Stanfield. Massey fulfilled his indenture and received the
                    promised 50 acres of ground from his master and 50 acres from William Penn. By
                    1696 Thomas was able to buy three hundred acres of land from James Stanfield,
                    the son of Francis, and established his “plantation” in Marple Township. At this
                    time he started his fine brick house. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists of documentation related to Thomas Massey House, which
                    Lawrence M.C. Smith donated to Marple Township in Pennsylvania, and its
                    restoration. Materials include meeting minutes, progress reports,
                    correspondence, newspaper clippings, and printed materials about the house. The
                    collection also includes printed materials form the Marple-Newtown Historical
                    Society. There is also a 1748 death notice for Mordecai Massey and a 1749
                    receipt to Rebecca and Thomas Massey from Mordecai Massey's estate.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>