<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Pike, Hooke, and Gove family
                        papers (series 23) <date type="inclusive">1659-1984</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Pike, Hooke, and Gove
                    family papers (series 23)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1797</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1659-1984</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Pike, Hook, and Gove families are related to the Houston Smith family through
                    the marriage of Charlotte Harding Shepherd (Brown) to Samuel Frederick Houston.
                    Benjamin Brown married Sarah Gove. Their daughter, Lydia Brown, married Moses
                    Pike in 1744. Sarah Pike, their daughter, married Josiah Hooke in 1767. Their
                    son, Captain Moses Hooke married Harriet (Butler) Callender. Their son, Charles
                    Moses Shepherd, Jr, married Josephine Kenner; and their daughter Charlotte
                    Harding Shepherd (Brown) married Samuel Frederick Houston after the death of her
                    first husband, Charles Wardell Brown.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Pike-Hooke-Gove Families Papers contain genealogical notes, deeds,
                    affidavits, and clippings of or regarding the Hooke, Pike, Gove, and Pote
                    families. The collection also includes photographs of paintings and magazines
                    that contain photos of the Hooke family home, and an oversized engraving of the
                    York and Cape Neddick Harbors (1854). </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>