<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Bull family papers (series 30)
                            <date type="inclusive">1804-1984</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Bull family papers
                    (series 30)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1801</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1804-1984</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Bull family is allied to the Smith family through the marriage of Gertrude
                    Gouverneur Clemson and Lewis Lawrence Smith. Thomas Bull and Ann Hunter were the
                    parents of Levi Bull. The Rev. Dr. Levi Bull was the founder and lifelong
                    minister of St. Mary's Episcopal Church in Warwick Township. Levi Bull married
                    Ann Jacobs; their daughter Margaretta Jacobs Bull married Rev. John Clemson.
                    Thomas Green Clemson, son of John and Margaretta Clemson, married Sarah Frances
                    Ogden. The daughter of Thomas and Sarah Clemson, Gertrude Gouverneur, married
                    Lewis Lawrence Smith. Gertrude and Lewis Smith were the parents of Lawrence
                    Meredith Clemson Smith, husband of Eleanor Houston Smith.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Bull family papers contain genealogical information on the Bull and Jacobs
                    families; correspondence and photographs related to the Bull family residence in
                    Chester County; manuscript sermons of Levi Bull; and printed materials
                    concerning Levi Bull's life and work.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>