<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Sallie S. B. Houston papers
                        (series 9) <date type="inclusive">1871-1913</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>American Philosophical Society</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Smith-Houston-Ogden family papers. Sallie S. B. Houston
                    papers (series 9)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">APSSp.ACC1792</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">American Philosophical Society<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1871-1913</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Sallie Sherrerd Bonnell Houston was married to Henry Howard Houston. The couple
                    had six children, Cornelia Bonnell, Henry Howard Jr., Eleanor Anna, Sallie
                    Bonnell, Samuel Frederic and Gertrude. Houston gave substantial amounts for the
                    establishment of colored churches and for the education of the underprivileged.
                    The Houstons also gave a gift to the University of Pennsylvania for Howard
                    Houston Hall and its maintenance.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of the papers of Sallie S.B. Houston. Materials in the
                    collection include: correspondence, much of it with her daughters Sallie B.H.
                    Henry and Gertrude H. Woodward; financial records including summaries of stock
                    purchases and dividends, and receipts; and household accounts. The collection
                    also includes materials related to Houston's gift of Howard Houston Hall at the
                    University of Pennsylvania, and subsequent correspondence on the continued
                    maintenance of the building. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University Archives
                    and Records Center, University of Pennsylvania: Henry Howard Houston estate
                    papers; Pennsylvania State Archives: H.H. Houston estate papers.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>