<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Alan G. MacDiarmid papers <date type="inclusive">1944-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Alan G. MacDiarmid papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC177</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>90 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1944-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Alan Graham MacDiarmid ONZ (b.1927) is Blanchard Professor of Chemistry at the
                    University of Pennsylvania and James Von Ehr Chair of Science and Technology at
                    the University of Texas, Dallas. In 2000 he was awarded the Nobel Prize in
                    Chemistry for his work on conductive polymers, more commonly known as
                    "synthetic metals." In 2001 he was awarded the Order of New Zealand. He
                    studied at Victoria University of Wellington (New Zealand), and holds Ph.D.s
                    from the University of Wisconsin and the University of Cambridge. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of MacDiarmid's correspondence, reprints, University of
                    Pennsylvania files and research files. Records include: documentation of
                    lectures, conferences, and honors ceremonies; correspondence (emails, letters,
                    and telephone messages) with colleagues, students, and friends; copies of
                    students' work; committee paperwork; lecture notes, texts, and overhead sheets;
                    research notes, graphs, and diagrams; correspondence, itineraries, letters of
                    congratulation, publicity, and other documents related to the Nobel Prize;
                    reprints of MacDiarmid's articles and those of others; and other miscellaneous
                    papers.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: A.M.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 05:017</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>