<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Alfred J. Johnson papers <date type="inclusive">1937-1951</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Alfred J. Johnson papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1226</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1937-1951</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Alfred J. Johnson (1892-1984) was a researcher on dye chemistry. He received a BS
                    in chemistry at the University of Wisconsin, and before completing his MS,
                    joined the United States Bureau of Chemistry. He served in the army during World
                    War I, and after the war, joined the DuPont Company. He remained at DuPont until
                    his retirement. He was the holder of a number of patents and authored several
                    textbooks.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of two notebooks and a set of loose notes kept by Alfred
                    Johnson. The loose notes were taken by Johnson based on various texts on dye
                    production procedures. One notebook contains a series of abstracts of various
                    chemicals translated from a German encyclopedia of chemical dyes and a list of
                    German, English and American patents for chemical dyes, along with abstracts of
                    how those dyes are derived. The other notebook lists formulas and procedures for
                    obtaining dyes, giving the source of the information. This notebook also
                    includes a few documents related to the DuPont organization. Much of the
                    material is undated, except for the publication dates of the sources Johnson
                    used.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Doris J. Allebach</p>
                <p>Accession number: GB93:29</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>