<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Institute of Chemical Engineers records <date type="inclusive">1925-1998</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Institute of Chemical Engineers
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC928</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1925-1998</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>American Institute of Chemical Engineers (AIChE) was formed in 1908 to foster
                    professional development and encourage communication among members of the
                    chemical engineering profession. The organization has 18 divisions and forums
                    which focus on specific areas of chemical engineering. AIChE publishes various
                    journals, and holds annual meetings at which members and guest experts present
                    papers.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of selected records from the AIChE. The materials fall
                    into four broad groups: local section histories; abstracts of papers given at
                    the 73rd annual meeting; materials gathered from the chemical engineering
                    departments of universities and other institutions for a history project
                    entitled "Beginning of Chemical Engineering in U.S.A."; and a time capsule of
                    materials on the occasion of the organization's diamond jubilee. Also included
                    in the collection are AIChE membership directories, by-laws, brochures on
                    chemical engineering careers, and other miscellaneous AIChE materials.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 85:02</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>