<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Association for Clinical Chemistry Standards Committee
                        records <date type="inclusive">1960-1994</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960s-1980s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Association for Clinical Chemistry Standards
                    Committee records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC042</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-1994</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960s-1980s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American Association for Clinical Chemistry (AACC) is an international
                    scientific/medical society of clinical laboratory professionals, physicians,
                    research scientists and other individuals involved with clinical chemistry and
                    clinical laboratory science disciplines. Founded in 1948, the society has 9,500
                    members and is headquartered in Washington, DC. AACC is subdivided
                    geographically into 22 local sections. Nathan Radin was the past editor of the
                    American Association for Clinical Chemistry newsletter. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of the Standards Committee of the AACC from
                    1960-1981. Materials include summary reports of meetings of the Standards
                    Committee, memoranda and proposals from various study groups and subcommittees,
                    biographical sketches of AACC symposium speakers, meeting agendas, printed
                    reference material from offices such as the National Bureau of Standards, and
                    information about the structure, purpose and membership of the Standards
                    Committee and its subcommittees.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: files from Raymond Vanderlinde</p>
                <p>Accession number: 01:40</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: American Association for Clinical Chemistry records
                    (97:08;01:07;02:02).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>