<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Association for Clinical Chemistry records <date type="inclusive">1948-2001</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Association for Clinical Chemistry
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1197</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1948-2001</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American Association for Clinical Chemistry (AACC) is an international
                    scientific/medical society of clinical laboratory professionals, physicians,
                    research scientists and other individuals involved with clinical chemistry and
                    clinical laboratory science disciplines. Founded in 1948, the society has 9,500
                    members and is headquartered in Washington, DC. AACC is subdivided
                    geographically into 22 local sections. Samuel Meites (b. 1921) was Professor of
                    Pediatrics at the Ohio State University College of Medicine and head of Clinical
                    Chemistry at Children's Hospital of Columbus, Ohio. He was the chair of the
                    History Division of the American Association for Clinical Chemistry (AACC). In
                    1989, his biography of Otto Folin was published by the AACC. Walter J. Frajola
                    was Professor Emeritus in the Department of Physiological Chemistry at Ohio
                    State University. Frajola was a member of the Ohio Valley Section of the AACC
                    and was chairman of the AACC Endowment Fund for Research in Clinical Chemistry.
                    Wendell T. Caraway (1920-2001) was a Clinical Biochemist at McLaren General and
                    St. Joseph Hospitals in Flint, Michigan. He served as AACC president in 1965-66
                    and supported the Caraway Endowment Fund which is used by the History Division
                    to support its activities related to the history of the field.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection includes AACC materials compiled by several individuals. The
                    Walter Frajola materials consist of records of the AACC Endowment Fund for
                    Research in Clinical Chemistry (1977-1995), including: incoming and outgoing
                    correspondence (1979-1989); minutes and records of fundraising committee
                    activities; some records from the Van Slyke Society, AACC's philanthropic
                    branch; records of contributions; and other administrative documents. The
                    Wendell Caraway materials consist of photocopies of Executive Committee minutes
                    (1948-1958) and copies and a few originals of AACC's newsletter, the Clinical
                    Chemist (1949-1954). The Samuel Meites materials include: correspondence,
                    minutes, newsletters, financial reports, and by-laws from the AACC Division of
                    the History of Clinical Chemistry (1990-1998); AACC meeting programs
                    (1980-2001); records from the Folin/Van Slyke postage stamp campaign;
                    photographs, negatives, and proofsheets for Meites's biography of Otto Folin;
                    correspondence and minutes from the Committee on Pediatric Clinical Chemistry;
                    and other miscellaneous AACC records.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Dr. Wendell T. Caraway (accession 1); Dr. Sam Meites (accessions 2);
                    Dr. Walter J. Frajola (accession 3)</p>
                <p>Accession number: 98:15;01:07;02:02</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: American Association for Clinical Chemistry Standards Committee
                    records (01:40); Samuel Meites papers (01:02); Raymond E. Vanderlinde papers
                    (00:31).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>