<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Chemical Society Division of the History of Chemistry
                        records <date type="inclusive">1960-2003</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1970s-1990s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Chemical Society Division of the History of
                    Chemistry records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC905</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>33.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-2003</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1970s-1990s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American Chemical Society (ACS), founded in 1876, is a self-governed
                    individual membership organization that consists of more than 158,000 members at
                    all degree levels and in all fields of chemistry. The Division of the History of
                    Chemistry is one of the 33 technical divisions within the ACS. The division
                    encourages research and scholarship, presents awards for major achievements in
                    the chemical sciences, and interacts with other organizations interested in the
                    history of science.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records gathered from various members of the ACS
                    Division of the History of Chemistry. Records include: Executive Committee
                    minutes and reports; History Division reports; documents from the Nominating
                    Committee; membership directories and cards; program and symposium materials;
                    documents relating to the Outstanding Paper and Dexter Awards; a small set of
                    documents on the CHEM Study project; financial records; 1985 to 1993 National
                    Meeting Cachets (commemorative envelopes with informational cards); documents
                    from the Committee on Divisional Activities; and by-laws and miscellaneous
                    administrative materials.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 83-1</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>