<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Chemical Society Division of Small Chemical Businesses
                        records <date type="inclusive">1979-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Chemical Society Division of Small Chemical
                    Businesses records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1275</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American Chemical Society (ACS), founded in 1876, is a self-governed
                    individual membership organization that consists of more than 158,000 members at
                    all degree levels and in all fields of chemistry. The Division of Small Chemical
                    Businesses is one of the 33 technical divisions within the ACS. Founded in 1978,
                    it seeks to aid in the formation, development and growth of small chemical
                    businesses by helping self-employed chemists and chemists working in small
                    enterprises with the legal, social, educational, legislative, regulatory, and
                    economic aspects of their work.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of the ACS Division of Small Chemical
                    Businesses. Materials include: Executive Committee agendas and minutes
                    (1981-1989); history and by-laws of the division; financial records; copies of
                    the Small Chem Biz Newsletter (1979-1993); programs and audiocassettes of
                    symposia (1980-1990); and membership directories.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>