<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Chemical Society Division of Chemical Health and Safety
                        records <date type="inclusive">1981-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Chemical Society Division of Chemical Health and
                    Safety records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1202</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1981-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American Chemical Society (ACS), founded in 1876, is a self-governed
                    individual membership organization that consists of more than 158,000 members at
                    all degree levels and in all fields of chemistry. The Division of Chemical
                    Health and Safety (CHAS) is one of the 33 technical divisions within the ACS.
                    The division has over 1500 members, including chemists, health and safety
                    professionals and other scientists working to promote the responsible use of
                    hazardous chemicals. The division's main interest is in "technical research
                    about the hazards and management of these chemicals as they are used in the
                    laboratory, the general workplace and the economy as a whole."</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of the ACS Division of Chemical Health and
                    Safety. Records include: financial records (1984-1994); programs from national
                    meetings (1978-1992); loose copies and a bound volume of the CHAS Notes
                    newsletter (1982-1999); copies of the Chemical Health and Safety journal
                    (1994-1999); membership and committee lists; bound "Extended Abstracts" from
                    papers given at national meetings (1992-1994); guidelines for public policy
                    statements and communications; and miscellaneous correspondence. The collection
                    also includes a set of commemorative CHAS wine glasses. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: “CHAS Notes” donated by Ruth Hathaway (see ACS Div. of Health and
                    Safety donor file) . Originally from Malcolm Renfrew.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 99-13</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>