<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Chemical Heritage Foundation historical services and archives
                        projects records <date type="inclusive">1985-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Chemical Heritage Foundation historical services and
                    archives projects records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1290</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>14 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1982, the Center for the History of Chemistry (CHOC) was launched as a pilot
                    project of the University of Pennsylvania and the American Chemical Society
                    (ACS). In 1987 CHOC was incorporated as a not-for-profit organization, now named
                    the National Foundation for the History of Chemistry, by joint action of the ACS
                    and AIChE, the Center's third sponsor. In 1992 the Chemical Heritage Foundation
                    (CHF) assumed its present name to better reflect the interdisciplinary nature of
                    the sciences and industries it serves and the widening public scope of its
                    activities.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of the Chemical Heritage Foundation's
                    historical services and archives projects. These records pertain primarily to
                    CHF's Biomolecular Sciences Initiative (BIMOSI) -- a project designed to
                    document contemporary history of the life sciences by conducting oral histories
                    with molecular biologists, coordinating archival planning, exploring historical
                    questions raised by the development of molecular biology, and encouraging
                    scientists to donate their papers to appropriate repositories. BIMOSI was funded
                    by grants from the Mellon Foundation and the National Historical Publications
                    and Records Commission. Its particular focus was on documenting the Human Genome
                    Project. BIMOSI records (1985-1996) include: correspondence to scientists and
                    institutions urging participation, information on document preservation
                    strategies, articles and reprints on archives and archival methods, lists of
                    scientists in molecular biology, notes from internal meetings on the project,
                    including the Archival Advisory Committee, grant proposals and progress reports.
                    The collection also includes papers (1998-2000) of Leo Slater. Slater is an
                    historian of science who was CHF's Director of Historical Services. These
                    materials include: memos, agendas and other records from meetings revolving
                    around different historical projects, many of them undertaken with divisions of
                    the American Chemical Society.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>