<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Chemical Heritage Foundation president's records (Arnold Thackray)
                            <date type="inclusive">1967-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Chemical Heritage Foundation president's records (Arnold
                    Thackray)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1289</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>35 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1980, a group of scientists and industrialists concluded that the time had
                    come to found a national history center devoted to the chemical and molecular
                    sciences and industries. In 1982 the Center for the History of Chemistry (CHOC)
                    was launched as a pilot project of the University of Pennsylvania and the
                    American Chemical Society (ACS). In 1984 the American Institute of Chemical
                    Engineers (AIChE) became the third sponsor. In 1987 the Center was incorporated
                    as a not-for-profit organization, now named the National Foundation for the
                    History of Chemistry, by joint action of the ACS and AIChE. The Foundation
                    rented space in a new building at the University of Pennsylvania and
                    restructured its activities into those of the Beckman Center for the History of
                    Chemistry (established 1987) and the Othmer Library of Chemical History
                    (established 1988). In 1992 the Chemical Heritage Foundation (CHF) assumed its
                    present name to better reflect the interdisciplinary nature of the sciences and
                    industries it serves and the widening public scope of its activities. In 1995
                    CHF purchased its permanent home, the First National Bank building at the
                    Independence National Historical Park in Philadelphia, and moved into its new
                    location a year later. Arnold Thackray (b. 1939) is the founding president of
                    the Chemical Heritage Foundation. He took both his M.A. (1965) and Ph.D. degrees
                    at Cambridge (1966) in history of science. He was founding chairman of, and
                    Joseph Priestley Professor in, the Department of History and Sociology of
                    Science at the University of Pennsylvania, while serving on the faculty of the
                    University of Pennsylvania for more than a quarter of a century. He is now
                    Professor Emeritus. He has served as editor of Isis (1978-1985) and Osiris
                    (1985-1994), among other publications, and has been a member and an officer of
                    many professional associations.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of Arnold Thackray's professional files from his work at
                    the University of Maryland, University of Pennsylvania, and the Chemical
                    Heritage Foundation, and reprints of his publications (1967-1984). Thackray's
                    CHF working files include: development materials, such as planning documents,
                    reports, appeals, acknowledgment letters and records of scholarships and
                    foundation funding efforts; records of his involvement with professional
                    organizations and societies, such agendas, reports, minutes, and notes from
                    committee meetings; individual correspondence with colleagues; topical files on
                    CHF programs, such as the Biomolecular Sciences Initiative project (BIMOSI) and
                    the Chemical Instrumentation Museum Group (CIMG); plans for 1994 construction
                    work on the CHF building; correspondence with publishers; and general
                    administrative files on exhibits, publications and preparations for meetings of
                    the CHF Board of Directors.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>