<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Chemical Bond Approach Project records <date type="inclusive">1959-1964</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Chemical Bond Approach Project records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC197</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1959-1964</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Chemical Bond Approach (CBA) Project was a new approach for teaching
                    chemistry to secondary students that was first developed in 1959. It emphasized
                    grounding in the theoretical concepts of chemistry rather than simple
                    memorization. Its development came in response to the United States' fear of
                    being eclipsed in the sciences after the launch of Sputnik.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection of materials was donated by H. Anthony Neidig, one of the four
                    directors of the CBA project (1959-1963). The collection consists of trial
                    editions of CBA textbooks and records of the testing of the programs. Materials
                    include: student and teacher versions of textbooks and laboratory manuals;
                    reference articles; documentation of an Educational Testing Service (ETS)
                    evaluation of the CBA materials; records of feedback received from teachers who
                    tested the program; correspondence and other records from the 1961 CBA Summer
                    Institute in Santiago, Chile; reprints of articles about the CBA program; CBA
                    newsletters; information about the Reed College Conference on High School
                    Chemistry, and miscellaneous records relating to the project.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: H. Anthony Neidig</p>
                <p>Accession number: 06:061</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: Chemical Education Material Study and Chemical Bond Approach Project
                    records (97:03); Joseph S. Schmuckler papers (05:073); Laurence E. Strong papers
                    (93:04); Frank Henry Verhoek papers (includes some CBA) (96:03).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>