<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Chemical Heritage Foundation staff files (Ted Benfey) <date type="inclusive">1985-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Chemical Heritage Foundation staff files (Ted
                    Benfey)</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1291</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1982, the Center for the History of Chemistry (CHOC) was launched as a pilot
                    project of the University of Pennsylvania and the American Chemical Society
                    (ACS). In 1987 CHOC was incorporated as a not-for-profit organization, now named
                    the National Foundation for the History of Chemistry (NFHC), by joint action of
                    the ACS and AIChE, the Center's third sponsor. In 1992 the Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation (CHF) assumed its present name to better reflect the
                    interdisciplinary nature of the sciences and industries it serves and the
                    widening public scope of its activities. Ted (Theodor) Benfey is Emeritus
                    Professor of Chemistry and History of Science, Guilford College. In 1988 Benfey
                    became editor of Chemical Heritage newsmagazine.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of Benfey's editorial and reference files. Included are:
                    articles and correspondence related to professional organizations, societies,
                    and individual chemists; drafts of articles and announcements submitted to
                    Chemical Heritage; ideas for future issues; queries about information or
                    photographs from the collections of CHOC/CHF; CHOC newsletters and copies of
                    Chemical Heritage (1983-1996); files on CHF projects and publications; 3-year
                    progress reports for the NFHC; reference materials on chemical education
                    programs; and miscellaneous reprints.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: Ted Benfey papers (02:15; 02:16); Chemical Heritage Foundation
                    publication records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>