<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Chemical Heritage Foundation publication records <date type="inclusive">1989-1999</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Chemical Heritage Foundation publication
                    records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1295</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1989-1999</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1982, the Center for the History of Chemistry (CHOC) was launched as a pilot
                    project of the University of Pennsylvania and the American Chemical Society
                    (ACS). In 1987 CHOC was incorporated as a not-for-profit organization, now named
                    the National Foundation for the History of Chemistry, by joint action of the ACS
                    and AIChE, the Center's third sponsor. In 1992 the Chemical Heritage Foundation
                    (CHF) assumed its present name to better reflect the interdisciplinary nature of
                    the sciences and industries it serves and the widening public scope of its
                    activities. CHF publishes a variety of books and other materials for readers
                    interested in the history of the chemical and molecular sciences and
                    industries.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records relating to the publications of the Chemical
                    Heritage Foundation. The materials fall into three broad categories: records of
                    the Chemical Heritage newsmagazine, administrative files from the publications
                    department, and records of the American Chemical Society/Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation book series from the files of series editor of Jeffrey L. Sturchio.
                    Chemical Heritage records include: notes on layout and design; drafts of
                    articles, reviews, and announcements; correspondence with authors; letters to
                    the editor; requests for review copies of books; background reference articles;
                    research on images for articles; and planning documents for future issues of the
                    magazine. Publications department files include: monthly reports and
                    inventories; guides to archives and corporate histories; publication information
                    on CHF brochures, catalogues, and books; requests for back issues of magazines
                    and brochures; slide requests; research material for possible use in future
                    publications; and general office administrative files. ACS/CHF book series
                    records include: Advisory and Editorial Board meeting minutes; series marketing
                    materials; correspondence regarding publication and marketing; rejected
                    proposals, and accepted proposals including drafts and correspondence; and an
                    annotated proof copy of an ACS-CHF book on Nobel Laureates.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: Chemical Heritage Foundation staff files (Ted Benfey); Chemical
                    Heritage Foundation printed materials.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>