<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Chemical Heritage Foundation printed materials <date type="inclusive">1982-2004</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Chemical Heritage Foundation printed materials</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1294</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-2004</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1982, the Center for the History of Chemistry (CHOC) was launched as a pilot
                    project of the University of Pennsylvania and the American Chemical Society
                    (ACS). In 1987 CHOC was incorporated as a not-for-profit organization, now named
                    the National Foundation for the History of Chemistry, by joint action of the ACS
                    and AIChE, the Center's third sponsor. In 1992 the Chemical Heritage Foundation
                    (CHF) assumed its present name to better reflect the interdisciplinary nature of
                    the sciences and industries it serves and the widening public scope of its
                    activities. CHF publishes a variety of books and other materials for readers
                    interested in the history of the chemical and molecular sciences and industries.
                </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of many of the Chemical Heritage Foundation's
                    publications. Materials include: newsletters (1985-1992), CHOC news and Chemical
                    Heritage newsmagazine (1982-2004); programs for awards ceremonies; lecture and
                    luncheon announcements; wall charts (timelines); annual reports (2002-2004); CHF
                    directory and Heritage Council reports; a catalog of archival holdings; and
                    various brochures and booklets. The collection also includes documents related
                    to several of the books published by CHF, mounted photographs from exhibits, and
                    a transcript of the WHYY radio program entitled The Emergence of Biotechnology:
                    DNA to Genentech.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: Chemical Heritage Foundation publication records.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>