<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Edward M. Rosen collection of FLOWTRAN documentation <date type="inclusive">1969-1992</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960s-1970s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Edward M. Rosen collection of FLOWTRAN
                    documentation</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC195</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1992</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960s-1970s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>FLOWTRAN is a system of digital computer programs for the mathematical solution
                    of steady-state chemical engineering problems. The purpose of FLOWTRAN is to
                    enable design, process and production engineers to make use of powerful,
                    up-to-date, chemical engineering calculating tools in their day-to-day work.
                    FLOWTRAN was released within Monsanto in 1966. Edward M. Rosen joined Monsanto
                    in 1959, where he worked with an early IBM computer and a FORTRAN compiler on a
                    material balance program, and then in the field of computerized simulation of
                    chemical processes. Alvin Larsen (d. 2004) joined Monsanto in 1969, and was a
                    co-worker of Rosen's. He carefully collected manuals and other documentation
                    about FLOWTRAN. This collection is made up of his records, those of Rosen, and
                    those of a few others. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of manuals, reports, internal Monsanto memos and
                    correspondence relating to Monsanto's FLOWTRAN system. Records include: FORTRAN
                    listings of the internal and external FLOWTRAN building blocks; internal
                    training and workshop documents; published papers about FLOWTRAN; articles about
                    the history of the system; marketing documents; internal and external user's
                    documentation; records of educational outreach projects in which the FLOWTRAN
                    system were made available to universities; and miscellaneous memos and
                    correspondence.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: E.R.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 06:044</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>