<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Fisher Collection of Alchemical and Historical Pictures Louis
                        Pasteur materials <date type="inclusive">1872-1936</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Fisher Collection of Alchemical and Historical Pictures
                    Louis Pasteur materials</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1278</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent> linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1872-1936</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Chester Garfield Fisher founded Fisher Scientific in 1900 at the age of 20. C. G.
                    Fisher was first drawn to alchemical artworks because they included beautifully
                    rendered depictions of laboratory apparatuses. He began acquiring alchemical
                    paintings in the 1920s and continued to collect alchemical artworks throughout
                    his lifetime. In the 1920s Fisher began collecting paintings and artifacts that
                    depict the history of chemistry. Fisher was fascinated by the work of Louis
                    Pasteur, and he constructed a special Pasteur room, dedicated to the great
                    French biologist that contained apparatus, instruments, and other original
                    documents.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection contains 43 of the images and documents from the Fisher
                    Collection's Pasteur room, including sketches, framed letters, photographs and
                    prints.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            










        </archdesc>
    </ead>