<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Heinz Heinemann papers <date type="inclusive">1954-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Heinz Heinemann papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC199</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1954-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Heinz Heinemann (d. 2005) was a lecturer at the College of Chemistry at the
                    University of California, Berkeley and a chemistry researcher at Lawrence
                    Berkeley National Laboratory. Following World War II, as manager of catalysis
                    research for the Mobil Research and Development Co., he developed the process
                    for converting methanol into gasoline. Heinemann contributed to the invention
                    and development of 14 commercial fossil fuel processes, received 75 patents and
                    was the author of more than a hundred publications. He was a long-time member of
                    the International Congress on Catalysis, and from 2001 to 2004, he served as a
                    manager of the Washington Chemical Society (a section of the American Chemical
                    Society) and as president of its Retired Chemists Group.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the papers of Heinz Heinemann. Materials include:
                    drafts and reprints of articles; conference-related documents, such as minutes,
                    agendas, bills and receipts; a binder of Heinemann's patents; legal documents
                    from a lawsuit between Mobil and W.R. Grace Co.; bylaws and other documents from
                    the International Congress on Catalysis; articles relating to catalysis,
                    houdriforming, and other petroleum refining processes.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Barbara Heinemann</p>
                <p>Accession number: 06:071</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>