<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Herman Skolnik papers <date type="inclusive">1948-1994</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1960s-1980s</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Herman Skolnik papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC107</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1948-1994</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1960s-1980s</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Herman Skolnik (Ph.D. University of Pennsylvania) was a research chemist at
                    Hercules, Inc. Research Center. He was editor of the American Chemical Society's
                    Journal of Chemical Information and Computer Science for its first 22 years, and
                    was the editor of the terpene chemistry section of Chemical Abstracts for more
                    than 30 years. He was interested in chemical documentation, history of science,
                    terpenes, heterocyclics, and azeotropy. Skolnik was the historian/archivist of
                    the Delaware Section of the American Chemical Society, and lectured and
                    published on the history and teaching of science.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection includes reprints of Skolnik's publications, company newsletters,
                    clippings of journal articles, copies of the Del-Chem Bulletin (newsletter of
                    the Delaware Section of the ACS), chemistry reference books, a company history
                    of Hercules, Inc., audiocassettes of Skolnik's 1986 interview of Paul W. Morgan
                    for the Chemical Heritage Foundation's Oral Histories project, slides to
                    accompany lectures on chemistry and chemistry education, materials relating to
                    the Scientists in Residence Program in the Delaware public school system, notes
                    from meetings of ChemVets (a group of retired ACS members working to promote
                    science education), and a wooden plaque of the Hercules Powder Company logo.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Susan Skolnik</p>
                <p>Accession number: 03:621</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: University of
                    Delaware: Delaware Chemical Bulletins collection.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>