<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry Commission on
                        Atomic Weights and Isotopic Abundances records <date type="inclusive">1920-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry
                    Commission on Atomic Weights and Isotopic Abundances records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC985</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>10.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1920-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry (IUPAC) was formed in 1919
                    by chemists from industry and academia. Over nearly eight decades, the Union has
                    succeeded in fostering worldwide communications in the chemical sciences and in
                    uniting academic, industrial and public sector chemistry in a common language.
                    IUPAC has long been recognized as the world authority on chemical nomenclature,
                    terminology, standardized methods for measurement, atomic weights and many other
                    critically evaluated data. An International Commission on Atomic Weights (under
                    varying names) has been a central feature of IUPAC since its inception.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of the records of the Commission on Atomic Weights and
                    Isotopic Abundances (CAWIA), donated by several members of the commission and
                    its various subcommittees. Materials include: correspondence (1920-1993);
                    membership lists and bibliographical data; agendas, minutes, and reports of
                    meetings; published and unpublished papers; isotopic abundances tables and
                    reference materials; and atomic weight reports (1820-1992).</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Dr. H. Steffan Peiser for IUPAC</p>
                <p>Accession number: 89:21</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry (IUPAC) Records
                    (2003.600.001).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>