<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John M. Weiss papers <date type="inclusive">1918-1961</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John M. Weiss papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC913</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1918-1961</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John M. Weiss was born in Pennsylvania on March 11, 1885. After receiving his
                    Bachelor of Science degree at the University of Pennsylvania, he became a
                    chemical engineer. In 1905, Weiss began his career with the Barrett Company as a
                    research chemist. By 1921, he was the Director of Development for the company.
                    In 1923, Weiss began a 19-year stint as the president and treasurer of Weiss and
                    Downs, Inc., a chemical engineering consulting firm. In 1943, he established
                    John M. Weiss and Company. He was a senior partner of this company until his
                    death in 1963. His primary interests included acids, maleic anhydride, and
                    synthetic phenol. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The Weiss Collection is divided into six series based on subject. They are as
                    follows: Acids, (1918-46), 1958; Maleic Anhydride, (1932-47), 1958 + [n.d.];
                    Patents, 1925-53; Phthalic Anhydride, 1936-61 + [n.d.]; Synthetic Phenol,
                    1925-56 + [n.d.]; and Addendum - John Weiss Notebooks, [n.d.]. Information on
                    several companies for which Weiss consulted, such as the Pittsburgh Plate Glass
                    Company and Reichhold Chemicals, Inc. is included. The addendum of notebooks,
                    which was donated by Francis B. White independently of the rest of the
                    collection, contains notes compiled by Weiss on chemical subjects of interest to
                    him. The majority of the collection consists of progress reports and case
                    studies, which Weiss generated as a result of his consulting practice. Working
                    notes, data, correspondence, and patents are also present. His interests in
                    Maleic Acid, Maleic Anhydride, Phthalic Anhydride, and Synthetic Phenol are well
                    represented.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: J.M.W.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 84-4</p>
            </acqinfo>



            <otherfindaid>
                <p>A paper finding aid is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>






        </archdesc>
    </ead>