<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John H. Wotiz papers <date type="inclusive">1943-1990</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John H. Wotiz papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC673</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>21.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1943-1990</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>John Wotiz (1919-2001) was born in Czechoslovakia, and emigrated to the United
                    States in 1939. He received his BS in chemistry from Furman University in 1941,
                    his master's degree (on polyhydroxy amines) from the University of Richmond in
                    1943, and his Ph.D. (on rearrangements of acetylene compounds) from Ohio State
                    University in 1948. Wotiz worked as a chemistry professor at the University of
                    Pittsburgh, and then, after a period working in private industry, he went to
                    Marshall University and finally to Southern Illinois University, where he
                    remained until the end of his career. Wotiz had a long standing interest in the
                    history of chemistry. He wrote a directory of international chemistry museums,
                    and conducted chemical history tours throughout Europe (beginning in 1971).
                    Wotiz was a long-time member of the Division of the History of Chemistry (HIST)
                    of the American Chemical Society (ACS) and served as its chairman in 1980. He
                    was an expert on the work and life of F. August August Kekulé, and edited The
                    Kekulé Riddle: A Challenge for Chemists and Psychologists (1993). This work
                    occasioned much controversy, and prior to and following its publication, Wotiz
                    participated in several debates and panel discussions on the topic.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of Wotiz's papers relating to his work on Kekule, his
                    European chemical history tours and museum directory, his involvement in the
                    Center for the History of Chemistry (CHOC), and other personal and professional
                    papers. Kekule materials include: research files, lecture notes and slides,
                    drafts of chapters, correspondence with authors and publishers, documents from a
                    1990 ACS Symposium on Kekule, and records of the professional disagreements on
                    the thesis of his Kekule work. European chemical history tour materials include
                    museum catalogs, brochures, itineraries, narrative reports of tour participants,
                    and photographs. CHOC materials include correspondence, memoranda, clippings,
                    and meeting minutes. Other papers include his master's and doctoral theses,
                    school notes, dissertations written by his students, lecture notes for chemical
                    history courses, and reprints of his articles.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Herbert T. Pratt</p>
                <p>Accession number: 2006:085</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>