<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>John A. Pople papers <date type="inclusive">1931-2003</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">John A. Pople papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC121</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>26.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1931-2003</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Sir John Anthony Pople (1925-2004) was a theoretical chemist. Born in Burnham on
                    Sea, Somerset, England, he attended Bristol Grammar School. He received his B.
                    A. (in 1946) and doctorate (in 1951) degrees in mathematics from Cambridge
                    University in the United Kingdom. He moved to the United States of America in
                    the early 1960s, where he lived the rest of his life, though he retained British
                    citizenship. In 1993 he moved from Carnegie Mellon University , where his
                    earlier accomplishments were made, to Northwestern University. He received the
                    Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 1998. He was made a fellow of the Royal Society in
                    1961, and was knighted in 2003. His first major contribution was a theory of
                    approximate molecular orbital (MO) calculations on pi electron systems in 1953,
                    identical to the one developed by Rudolph Pariser and Robert G. Parr in the same
                    year, and now called the Pariser-Parr-Pople method. Subsequently, he developed
                    the methods of Complete Neglect of Differential Overlap (CNDO) (in 1965) and
                    Intermediate Neglect of Differential Overlap (INDO) for approximate MO
                    calculations on three-dimensional molecules, and other developments in
                    computational chemistry. He pioneered the development of more sophisticated
                    computational methods, so called ab initio methods, that used basis sets of
                    either Slater type orbitals or Gaussian orbitals to model the wave function. He
                    was instrumental in the development of one of the most widely used computational
                    chemistry packages, the "GAUSSIAN" suite of programs. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection includes papers from Pople's days as a student, from his time at
                    Carnegie Mellon University, and some from his time at Northwestern University.
                    Also included are records of some of his many awards and honors, and drafts and
                    correspondence regarding many of his papers. Papers relating to Pople's early
                    academic career include school reports from grammar school, grades, exams,
                    lecture notes from Cambridge (including notebooks for astronomy, mathematics,
                    physics and chemistry), a copy of his dissertation, and correspondence about job
                    offers. His Carnegie Mellon records (1964-1996) consist largely of files
                    regarding students, post-doctoral fellows, and colleagues. These materials
                    include nomination and recommendation letters, administrative records, such as
                    budgets and travel expenses, comments on articles by students, and
                    correspondence regarding jointly published papers. The materials form Pople's
                    time at Northwestern University include reprints, nomination and recommendation
                    letters, administrative and personnel files and correspondence regarding his
                    receipt of the Nobel Prize. The collection also includes Pople's computational
                    notes (1948-1950s), drafts of his original PPP work (1952-1953), drafts of many
                    of his published papers, along with copies of articles on related topics and
                    correspondence with co-authors and publishers, files on various conferences and
                    meetings in which Pople participated, a packet of information for laureates
                    attending the 1991 Nobel Jubilee, and some of the awards and certificates Pople
                    received throughout his career.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: J.P.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 04:028</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>