<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Joseph Corse papers <date type="inclusive">1944-1949</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Joseph Corse papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC106</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1944-1949</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The United States Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD) was
                    established in the Office for Emergency Management (OEM) by Executive Order in
                    1941. Its functions were to advise the President on the status of scientific and
                    medical research relating to national defense, coordinate federal government
                    research relating to national defense, and compile defense mobilization lists of
                    scientific personnel and resources. The Office was abolished December 31, 1947.
                    The bulk of the records of the Office and its Committees are held in the
                    National Archives.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>One of the committees working within the OSRD was the Committee on Medical
                    Research, which worked on medical issues of concern to the military during World
                    War II. Among the projects this committee worked on was the biosynthesis of
                    penicillin. Some of the research for this project was conducted at Eli Lilly and
                    Company laboratories. Joseph Corse was one of Eli Lily's researchers, and this
                    collection consists of his copies of the progress reports issued by the
                    committee, as well as memos, reprints of related journal articles and a copy of
                    the main patent that resulted from the project. The collection also includes a
                    copy of R.B. Woodward's second report to the Committee on Medical Research on
                    the structure of penicillin.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: J.C.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 03:620</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: College of Physicians
                    of Philadelphia: United States Office of Scientific Research and Development
                    Committee on Medical Research Minutes, 1944-1946 (MSS 1/0003-01)</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>