<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Kir G. Karouna collection of paint and resin industry literature
                            <date type="inclusive">1950-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Kir G. Karouna collection of paint and resin industry
                    literature</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1279</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1950-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Kir G. Karouna was the founder of an organization called E.A.O. New York
                    (Electric Age of New York). He was a member of the Société de Chimie
                    Industrielle (American Section).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of a large number of handbooks and product specification
                    brochures from chemical and chemical apparatus manufacturing companies assembled
                    by Kir Karouna. Many of the industry documents are from companies that sell
                    paints and resins, although some other sectors are represented as well. The
                    collection contains a few clippings from newspapers and magazines on diverse
                    topics related to the paint and resin industries. There are several folders of
                    materials from meetings of the Société de Chemie Industrielle. These documents
                    consist largely of lists of speakers and photocopies and listings of attendees
                    of the conferences.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Kir G. Karouna</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 2000?</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>