<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Laurence E. Strong papers <date type="inclusive">1941-1967</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Laurence E. Strong papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1083</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1941-1967</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Laurence E. Strong was Professor of Chemistry at Kalamazoo College and Earlham
                    College, and Director of the Chemical Bond Approach Project. The Chemical Bond
                    Approach (CBA) was one of the major revisions to teaching of high school
                    chemistry which emerged from the curriculum reform movement of the 1950s. The
                    CBA Project's goal was to develop a high school chemistry curriculum that
                    combined experimentation with theory.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains editions of CBA texts, revision notes, correspondence
                    about revisions, a notebook from and correspondence about a Reed College
                    conference on the teaching of high school chemistry, and correspondence with M.
                    Kent Wilson. The collection also includes two boxes of bound reports from the
                    Harvard Blood Plasma studies. These were directed by Edwin J. Cohn of the
                    Department of Physical Chemistry, Harvard Medical School, and the National
                    Research Council during World War II.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: L.S.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 93:04</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: Chemical Bond Approach Project records (06:061); Chemical Education
                    Material Study and Chemical Bond Approach Project records (97:03); Joseph S.
                    Schmuckler papers (05:073); Frank Henry Verhoek papers (includes some CBA)
                    (96:03).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>