<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Louis A. Kazal papers <date type="inclusive">1950-1978</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Louis A. Kazal papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC123</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.75 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1950-1978</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Louis A. Kazal (Ph.D. in Biochemistry, Rutgers University) joined the Department
                    of Physiology at Jefferson Medical College in 1957. He headed the Plasma
                    Fractionation Unit of Jefferson's Cardeza Foundation for Hematological Research.
                    Prior to that he was a research biochemist at the Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme
                    Pharmaceutical Corporation. His research involved the chemistry and biophysics
                    of blood coagulation and erythropoiesis. At Jefferson he presented lectures on
                    the physiology of coagulation, developed laboratory exercises in coagulation,
                    and engaged in and supervised graduate student research in coagulation and
                    erythropoiesis. He retired from Jefferson in 1978.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of Kazal's work at Jefferson Medical College
                    (1956-1978). Materials include: reports and correspondence relating to research
                    on plasma fractionation, coagulation inhibitor studies, anticoagulent activity
                    of gastric juices, and fibrinogen precipitation. The collection also includes
                    binders of experiment data sheets and charts, reprints of Kazal's articles,
                    copies of student papers, and administrative documents and correspondence.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: L.K.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 04:033</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>