<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Ned Heindel collection relating to the establishment of American
                        Chemical Society certification in Chemical Hygiene and Environmental
                        Analytical Chemistry <date type="inclusive">1992-1996</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Ned Heindel collection relating to the establishment of
                    American Chemical Society certification in Chemical Hygiene and Environmental
                    Analytical Chemistry</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC108</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1992-1996</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Ned D. Heindel (b. 1937) is Howard S. Bunn Professor of Chemistry at Lehigh
                    University and is a Visiting Professor of Nuclear Medicine at Hahnemann
                    University. He received his Ph.D. in organic chemistry from the University of
                    Delaware in 1963. He was President of the American Chemical Society in 1994, and
                    from 1985 to 1996 was a Director of the ACS. Between 1980 and 1987, Heindel was
                    Director of Lehigh University's Center for Health Sciences. He has been a
                    Trustee of the Chemical Heritage Foundation since 1986.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains, according to correspondence with the donor, "the paper
                    trail of studies, endorsements, persuasions, and interactions which led -- in
                    December 1995 -- to the ACS Board committing the funds to create two new
                    certifications in Environmental Analytical Chemistry and in Chemical Hygiene.
                    Panels of practitioners in both areas wrote, field-tested, and launched those
                    certifications in 1996-1997. These programs are managed by NRCC [the National
                    Registry in Clinical Chemistry, a multi-society sponsored management
                    organization]." Records include correspondence, reports on certification
                    guidelines, sample examination questions, and background reference materials.
                    Also included in the collection are documents about discussions between the
                    Society for Applied Spectroscopy and the Chemical Heritage Foundation about a
                    spectroscopy museum.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: N.H.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 03:622</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>