<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>New England Nuclear Corporation annual reports and product catalogs
                            <date type="inclusive">1959-2003</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1959-1981</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">New England Nuclear Corporation annual reports and product
                    catalogs</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC124</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1959-2003</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1959-1981</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Paul McNulty was the Vice President of Marketing at New England Nuclear
                    Corporation (NEN). Boston-based New England Nuclear Corporation, incorporated in
                    1956, produced radioactive chemicals and supplies for use in scientific research
                    and for application in the medical, biological, and physical sciences. In a bid
                    to expand its business into medical research, DuPont purchased New England
                    Nuclear in 1981. DuPont sold NEN's medical diagnostic business in 1996 and the
                    remainder of the company (then called NEN Life Sciences Products) in 1997.
                    PerkinElmer, a drug research and development company, bought NEN in 2000. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of marketing materials and company business reports from
                    New England Nuclear Corporation. The marketing materials include all of the
                    sales and product brochures in use by the company in 1981, with publication
                    dates ranging from 1976 to 1981. Reports include annual reports from 1963 to
                    1981, and interim reports from 1977 to 1980, notices of annual stockholder
                    meetings, and stock prospectuses. The collection also includes a 2003 memorial
                    booklet for Edward Shapiro, co-founder of NEN, an annual report from Tracerlab
                    (where NEN's cofounders worked prior to launching the company), and
                    miscellaneous brochures, advertisements, and clippings.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: P.A.M.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 04:040</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>