<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Norbert M. Bikales papers <date type="inclusive">1971-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Norbert M. Bikales papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC120</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Norbert M. Bikales was the head of the Europe Office of the National Science
                    Foundation (NSF) from 1995 to 1998. Prior to assuming this position he was
                    Director of the NSF Polymers Program for 19 years. He had previously been
                    Professor of Chemistry and Director of Continuing Education in the Sciences at
                    Rutgers University. He served as chairman of the American Chemical Society's
                    Polymer Division in 1983. For over 15 years, he was a member of the
                    International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry (IUPAC) Commission on
                    Macromolecular Nomenclature, serving as the Commission Secretary from 1977 to
                    1987.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of Bikales's service with the American
                    Chemical Society Division of Polymer Chemistry and IUPAC, particularly the
                    Commission on Macromolecular Nomenclature. Materials include: American Chemical
                    Society administrative records and correspondence from the period preceding,
                    during, and following Bikales's chairmanship of the Division of Polymer
                    Chemistry; minutes of meetings and other administrative documents of the IUPAC
                    Commission on Macromolecular Nomenclature; and files relating to the preparation
                    of reports of the Commission on Macromolecular Nomenclature. The collection also
                    includes records of the Working Party on Recycling of Polymers, of which Bikales
                    was chairman from 1993 to 1997.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: N.B.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 04:025</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>