<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Philip Siekevitz papers <date type="inclusive">1941-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Philip Siekevitz papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1059</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1941-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Phil Siekevitz (b. 1918) was a biochemist who received his Ph.D. from the
                    University of California,Berkeley. He worked for many years at the Rockefeller
                    Institute. In 1966 he was President of the American Society of Cell Biology. He
                    was elected to the National Academy of Sciences in 1975 and President of the New
                    York Academy of Sciences in 1976. The Enzyme Club was founded in 1942 as a way
                    for researchers in the developing field of biochemistry to share information.
                    The group met in the facilities of the Rockefeller Institute for 50 years before
                    it was disbanded in 1992. Philip Siekevitz was the group's treasurer and its
                    "prime mover" for over 30 years. The Enzyme Club hosted talks on biochemistry,
                    molecular biology, genetics; their speakers included many Nobel laureates.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of the Enzyme Club and papers of Philip
                    Siekevitz. Materials include: a printed history of the club; articles on the
                    club; financial sponsorship documentation; records relating to anniversary
                    celebrations; a list of speakers (1941-1992); and reprints of articles written
                    by Siekevitz and others.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: P.S.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 92:07</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>