<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Ray F. Dawson collection relating to Percy Julian and the Empresa
                        Agroquimica Guatemalteca project <date type="inclusive">1934-1990</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1957-1960</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Ray F. Dawson collection relating to Percy Julian and the
                    Empresa Agroquimica Guatemalteca project</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1081</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1934-1990</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1957-1960</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Ray F. Dawson (b. 1911) was a professor of Botany on the Graduate Faculty of
                    Columbia University. He studied organic chemistry at DePauw University under
                    Percy Lavon Julian (1899-1975).</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of correspondence between Ray Dawson, Percy Julian, and
                    others, in connection with Julian's Empresa Agroquimica Guatemalteca, S.A.
                    Julian and Dawson worked together during the late 1950s and 1960s to establish a
                    facility in Guatemala for the production of raw materials for the extraction of
                    diosgenin, a steroid intermediate. In addition to the correspondence, the
                    collection includes reports, budgets, and permit applications. This collection
                    is a virtually complete record of the first years of the project up to its sale
                    to the Fine Chemicals Division of the Upjohn Company of Kalamazoo, Michigan.
                    Also included in this collection are a typed summary of the project with a
                    information on the correspondents, a photocopy of an article entitled
                    "Diosgenin Production in North America" (HortTechnology, 1991), and additional
                    letters between Julian and Dawson written in the 1960s.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: R.D.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1993; additional material received in 1994</p>
                <p>Accession number: 93:01</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>