<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Raymond E. Vanderlinde papers <date type="inclusive">1947-1990</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Raymond E. Vanderlinde papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC022</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>4 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1947-1990</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Raymond Vanderlinde is Emeritus Professor of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine at
                    Hahnemann University of Philadelphia. Prior to working at Hahnemann, Vanderlinde
                    was a chemist with the State of New York Department of Health Division of
                    Laboratories and Research. He is a member of the American Association for
                    Clinical Chemistry (AACC), Upstate New York and Philadelphia divisions, and
                    served as a member of the Board of Directors of AACC from 1979 to 1981, and was
                    a member of various AACC committees. Dr. Vanderlinde is the author or co-author
                    of more than 80 publications, principally in the areas of enzyme measurement and
                    standardization, enzyme reference materials, laboratory evaluation, and quality
                    control. AACC is an international scientific/medical society of clinical
                    laboratory professionals, physicians, research scientists and other individuals
                    involved with clinical chemistry and clinical laboratory science disciplines.
                    Founded in 1948, the society has 9,500 members and is headquartered in
                    Washington, DC. AACC is subdivided geographically into 22 local sections. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of records of Vanderlinde's work for the NY State
                    Department of Health and of his work on various AACC committees. The collection
                    includes: Vanderlinde's master's and doctoral theses from Syracuse University; a
                    scrapbook of letters to Vanderlinde; records from Vanderlinde's time as a
                    chemist at the State of New York Department of Health Division of Laboratories
                    and Research; legal documents about the College of American Pathologists (CAP)
                    consent decree; grant applications; articles by Vanderlinde and others on
                    screening procedures, along with supporting research materials (articles,
                    brochures) and correspondence; slides on drugs of abuse; reprints; reference
                    manuals for equipment and clinical practices; documents about quality control
                    and proficiency testing; AACC bylaws, section membership lists, histories,
                    newsletters, programs for and correspondence about meetings of the Upstate NY
                    and Philadelphia sections of AACC and committees thereof.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: R.V.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 00:31</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: American Association for Clinical Chemistry records
                    (97:08;01:07;02:02).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>