<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Robert J. Baptista papers <date type="inclusive">1920-2006</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Robert J. Baptista papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC122</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>8 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1920-2006</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Robert J. Baptista was Vice President of Manufacturing in the Fibers, Additives
                    and Rubber Division of the Bayer Corporation until his retirement in 2000. He
                    began his career at the company as a research chemist at the Verona Dyestuff
                    Division in 1972, and between 1977 and 1985 was Plant Manager for two of the
                    company's Bayonne facilities. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of scrapbooks and company manuals Baptista compiled on
                    various plants and companies in the dye industry. Many of these companies
                    eventually merged with Bayer Corporation. Included are histories of Verona
                    Dyestuffs, Harmon Colors, Pharma Chemical, Mobay Chemical Corporation, General
                    Analine and Film Corporation (GAF), Beaver Chemical Works, as well as Bayer
                    Corporation itself. The scrapbooks contain histories compiled by Baptista and
                    others, aerial photographs, photos of employees, management and facilities,
                    company documents, such as articles of incorporation and patents, newspaper
                    clippings, and plant location maps. These scrapbooks are the basis for many of
                    the articles on the website colorantshistory.org, a site founded and maintained
                    by Baptista and dedicated to history of the synthetic organic chemical dye
                    industry. Also included in this collection are miscellaneous printed materials,
                    books of paint and yarn samples, Bayer annual reports, copies of Bayer Research
                    magazine, and materials relating to the decommissioning of the Haledon, NJ plant
                    (owned by Miles, a predecessor of Mobay), and company's plan for environmental
                    remediation at the site.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Robert Baptista</p>
                <p>Accession number: 04:029;06:036;06:060; 06:084</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>