<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Samuel Meites papers <date type="inclusive">1976-1989</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Samuel Meites papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC033</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.66 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1989</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Samuel Meites was Professor of Pediatrics at the Ohio State University College of
                    Medicine and head of Clinical Chemistry at Children's Hospital of Columbus,
                    Ohio. He was the chair of the History Division of the American Association for
                    Clinical Chemistry (AACC). In 1989, his biography of Otto Folin was published by
                    the AACC. Otto Folin (1867-1934) was a biochemist and professor. He was Hamilton
                    Kuhn Professor of Biological Chemistry at Harvard. More than any individual, he
                    provided the modern practical approach to the microanalysis of blood and other
                    body fluids by introducing new or improved quantitative methods and using them
                    to make systematic studies of metabolism, health, and disease.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of typed manuscript and published copies of Meites's
                    biography of Folin and materials relating to the AACC. The AACC records include:
                    several editions of Clinical Chemistry News (the AACC newsletter); profiles of
                    AACC members written by Louise Simonson and correspondence with Simonson;
                    letters responding to a request for testimonials and biographical sketches of
                    AACC members; and AACC press releases.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of Dr. Sam Meites</p>
                <p>Accession number: 01:02</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: American Association for Clinical Chemistry records
                    (97:08;01:07;02:02).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>