<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Science in American Life exhibition records <date type="inclusive">1989-1997</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Science in American Life exhibition records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1164</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1989-1997</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>In 1991, the American Chemical Society agreed to consult on and contribute funds
                    to an exhibit entitled Science in American Life (SAL) at the Smithsonian
                    Institution's National Museum of American History (NMAH). The exhibit opened in
                    1994 and remained on view until 2006. The NMAH had control over the exhibit's
                    content, and in the end, the ACS felt that the portrayal of chemistry was very
                    negative. Ned D. Heindel (b. 1937) is a professor of Chemistry at Lehigh
                    University. He was President of the American Chemical Society (ACS) in 1994, and
                    from 1985 to 1996 was a Director of the ACS. In this latter role, he collected
                    materials about the SAL exhibit's development and about the fallout that
                    resulted from the differing views on the presentation of chemistry in the
                    exhibit.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of documents relating to the Science in American Life
                    exhibit. Materials include: the Smithsonian's initial feasibility study for the
                    exhibit; draft scripts of the exhibit; public relations plans; a copy of a study
                    conducted by the Smithsonian on visitors' responses to the exhibit;
                    correspondence files from the director and one of the members of the ACS
                    advisory committee; publicity materials and other documents on the Hand-On
                    Science Center; and sample activity books. The collection also includes a
                    comprehensive "briefing book" on ACS's response to the exhibit assembled by
                    Heindel, which includes minutes from meetings of the advisory committee, press
                    coverage of the exhibit, a copy of the advisory agreement between the ACS and
                    the Smithsonian.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Ned Heindel</p>
                <p>Accession number: 97:12</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: other Science in American life exhibition records (06:066).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>