<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Science in American Life exhibition records <date type="inclusive">1992-2006</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1992-1993</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Science in American Life exhibition records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC198</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1992-2006</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1992-1993</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>C. Marvin Lang is Professor Emeritus of Chemistry at University of Wisconsin,
                    Stevens Point. Lang has long been active in the affairs of the American Chemical
                    Society (ACS) at the local, regional, and national level including six years
                    service as an elected member of its Board of Directors (1989-1994). He has also
                    served on the Board of Directors of the Chemical Heritage Foundation from 1991
                    to 1997. In 1991, the ACS agreed to consult on and contribute funds to an
                    exhibit entitled Science in American Life at the Smithsonian Institution's
                    National Museum of American History (NMAH). Lang was a member of the ACS
                    advisory committee for the Science in American Life exhibit from 1992 to 1993.
                    The exhibit opened in 1994 and remained on view until 2006. The NMAH had control
                    over the exhibit's content, and in the end, the ACS felt that the exhibit's
                    portrayal of chemistry was very negative. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of documents relating to the Science in American Life
                    exhibit. Materials include: correspondence about meetings of a task force on a
                    proposal to create a traveling portion of the Science in American Life exhibit;
                    preliminary outlines of the "hands-on" aspects of the exhibit; draft scripts
                    of the exhibit; and public relations plans.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: C.M.L.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 06:066</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: other Science in American Life exhibition records (97:12)</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>