<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Solvay Process Company records [microform] <date type="inclusive">1986-1994</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Solvay Process Company records [microform]</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1296</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1994</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Solvay Process Company was formed in 1881 by two Belgian brothers, Ernest and
                    Alfred Solvay, who had perfected a new procedure for producing soda ash, which
                    became known as the Solvay Process. The Solvay Process Company was absorbed in
                    1921 by the Allied Chemical &amp; Dye Corporation. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of a set of microfilm reels of the Solvay Process
                    Company's technical documents, patents, reports, scrapbooks, and photographs.
                    The collection also includes correspondence and newsletter articles about the
                    preservation of the collection at the Solvay Public Library in Solvay, New York,
                    and the distribution of microfilm sets to the Chemical Heritage Foundation and
                    the Sidney M. Edelstein Center at The Hebrew University of Jerusalem.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>





            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: The Solvay Public
                    Library in Solvay, New York holds the originals from which these microfilm reels
                    were made.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>