<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Ted Benfey papers <date type="inclusive">1944-1980</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Ted Benfey papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC092</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1944-1980</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>O. Theodor (Ted) Benfey (b. 1925) is Emeritus Professor of Chemistry and History
                    of Science, Guilford College, and Editor-at-Large of Chemical Heritage
                    newsmagazine. In 1966, he was chair of the American Chemical Society Division of
                    the History of Chemistry. From 1963-1988 he was Editor of the ACS chemical
                    education journal Chemistry. Benfey is the author of many publications,
                    including Classics in the Theory of Chemical Combination (Dover, 1963), Kekulé
                    Centennial (ACS, 1966), and Introduction to Organic Reaction Mechanisms
                    (McGraw-Hill, 1970). </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of a selection of Benfey's academic and professional
                    papers. Materials include: notes from lectures that Benfey attended while on
                    sabbatical at Harvard from 1955-1956 (Frank Westheimer on Physical Organic
                    Chemistry and Peter Debye on Chemical Physics, among others); photostats of
                    French, German, and English articles on chemistry used by Benfey for his book
                    Classics in the Theory of Chemical Combination; information on mercury poisoning
                    and antidotes; background information for biographies on Lothar Meyer, Johannes
                    Thiele, and Edward W. Washburn; and notebooks from chemistry courses Benfey took
                    at University College London and Columbia University.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: O.T.B.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 02:15; 02:16</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Chemical Heritage
                    Foundation: Chemical Heritage Foundation staff files (Ted Benfey).</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>