<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Union Carbide Corporation history <date type="inclusive">1921-2000</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Union Carbide Corporation history</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC006</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>7 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1921-2000</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Union Carbide Company was formed in 1898, to manufacture carbon products for
                    electric arc street lights and electric furnaces and calcium carbide for
                    acetylene lighting. In 1920, with the commercial production of ethylene, Union
                    Carbide became a principal founder and major force in the petrochemical
                    industry. In 2001 Union Carbide merged with Dow Chemical Company and now exists
                    as a wholly owned subsidiary of Dow Chemical.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of a corporate history of Union Carbide Corporation from
                    the 1890s to the 1990s. This history was compiled (with the consent of the
                    company) by the Carbide Retirees Corps, an organization of retired Union Carbide
                    employees. The collection is made up of 17 sections, each related to a product
                    group or program at Union Carbide. Histories were compiled from personal
                    recollections and files, patents, published accounts, and company files and
                    annual reports. Materials in the collection include the printed histories and
                    supporting documentation, in the form of photocopied records and some original
                    materials.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to this collection is restricted; please contact the holding institution
                    for details.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 00-30</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>