<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Walter Slavin papers <date type="inclusive">1966-2001</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Walter Slavin papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC103</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>37.5 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1966-2001</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Walter Slavin was Senior Scientist at Perkin-Elmer and the co-editor of
                    Spectrochimica Acta Part B: Atomic Spectroscopy (SAB) until 2001. He was a
                    graduate in 1949 of the University of Maryland in Physics and Mathematics. In
                    1962 he began a technical journal, the Atomic Absorption Newsletter (now called
                    Atomic Spectroscopy), for communicating new information in the field. Slavin
                    worked with and corresponded extensively with Alan Walsh, who developed the
                    technique of atomic absorption spectroscopy to replace the older method of flame
                    emission for quantitative analysis. Walsh worked at CSIRO (Commonwealth
                    Scientific and Industrial Research Organization), Australia's national science
                    agency.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection contains records of Slavin's time as editor of SAB and of his
                    work at Perkin-Elmer and at Bonaire Technologies. The collection includes:
                    incoming and outgoing correspondence; general files on the history of atomic
                    absorption spectroscopy, and other chemical instrumentation; clippings of
                    articles on the corporate history of Perkin-Elmer; slides, papers, and handouts
                    from various workshops and talks given by Slavin; printed reports from CSIRO,
                    the Marine Analytical Chemistry Studies Program of the National Research Council
                    of Canada, and other research groups; correspondence with Walsh; and records of
                    Perkin-Elmer projects.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: W.S.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 03:010</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>