<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>William D. Williams papers <date type="inclusive">1880-1990</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">William D. Williams papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1194</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1880-1990</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>William Donald Williams was a professor of Chemistry at Harding University from
                    1954 to 1993. He is the author of many articles on chemical history and
                    biography, and wrote the "Old Chemistries" articles in the Bulletin for the
                    History of Chemistry. He and Wyndam Davies Miles together assembled a collection
                    of books, which they gave to Harding University in Searcy, Arkansas.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of additional materials ("duplicates and discards")
                    from the Miles-Williams collection at Harding University; they were donated to
                    the Chemical Heritage Foundation in 1998. The collection consists mainly of
                    reprints of articles on a wide range of topics related to the history of
                    science, primarily chemistry, and individual scientists. A number of the
                    articles were written by Miles. There are a number of reprints pertaining to
                    Western and East Asian alchemy. There are also a number of chemical society
                    membership lists, programs, and histories and chemistry magazines. The
                    collection also contains non-published items, including: a World War I-era
                    notebook from the Chemical Corps; a binder of typed and manuscript letters;
                    loose letters and receipts from chemical, pharmaceutical, and apparatus
                    manufacturing companies and university professors; correspondence related to
                    public lectures given by Miles; and some correspondence between Miles and
                    WIlliams about items in the collection; and correspondence between Wyndham Miles
                    and Denis Duveen, a chemist, chemical historian, and noted collector of books on
                    alchemy and early chemistry.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Gift of W.D.W.</p>
                <p>Accession number: 98:09</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>