<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Winslow H. Hartford collection of materials related to Mutual
                        Chemical Company of America and chromium chemistry <date type="inclusive">1948-1995</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Chemical Heritage Foundation</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Winslow H. Hartford collection of materials related to
                    Mutual Chemical Company of America and chromium chemistry</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">CHFSp.ACC1196</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Chemical Heritage Foundation<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>.25 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1948-1995</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Winslow H. Hartford (b. 1910) received his bachelors degree from Boston
                    University in 1928, and his Ph.D. in inorganic chemistry from the Massachusetts
                    Institute of Technology in 1933. He worked as a research supervisor with the
                    Mutual Chemical Company of America from 1934-58. He later worked at Allied's
                    Syracuse Technical Center as a senior scientist, and then took a position as
                    associate professor of chemistry at Belmont Abbey College. From 1979 until his
                    death in 1997, he was Professor Emeritus at Belmont. He specialized in the
                    chemistry and technology of chromium, and in wood preservation.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection consists of documents related to the history of Mutual Chemical
                    Company, and chromium chemistry. Mutual Chemical Company of America operated
                    from 1845 to 1954 and was at one time the largest chrome manufacturer in the
                    world. In 1954, Mutual was purchased by Allied Chemical. Included are a
                    chronology of the history of the company, a brief history of the company written
                    in 1945, a printed copy of "A Course in Chromium Chemistry" given by Hartford
                    at Mutual in 1948, a 1984 manuscript copy of a report by Hartford entitled "A
                    Systems Analysis of the Baltimore Chromium Chemicals Plant," a brief history of
                    the Baltimore plant entitled "An Introduction to Baltimore Works," and
                    correspondence regarding his work on the environmental considerations of the
                    Mutual chromium production plants.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Mary H. Hartford</p>
                <p>Accession number: 98:12</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>