<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>American Women's Hospital Service <date type="inclusive">1917-1982</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Drexel University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">American Women's Hospital Service</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">DUSp.ACC369</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Drexel University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>12 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1917-1982</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The American Women's Hospitals (AWH) developed from the War Service Committee of
                    the Medical Women's National Association (later AMWA) in 1917 to provide,
                    register, and finance American women physicians for war work; to offer medical
                    and emergency relief to refugees; and later to provide international public
                    health service. In 1959, AWH became an independent agency and remained such
                    until 1982 when it re-merged with AMWA.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Fifteen boxes (approximately 6,000 photographic prints and copper plates) make up
                    the photograph component of this collection. The photographs are international
                    in scope and document AWH activities at home and abroad. Photographs taken in
                    Greece and France are particularly well represented in the collection as are
                    rural sections of the Blue Ridge Mountains, Kentucky, South Carolina, and
                    Tennessee. The majority of the non-United States photographs are of AWH members
                    treating patients suffering from the result of war. Many photographs are taken
                    "in the field" and in temporary facilities set up by AWH. The photographs from
                    the rural southern United States are mainly of patient care provided by AWH
                    members to poor families who otherwise would have had no care at all. Many of
                    the photographs were used in AWH appeal brochures. The photographs arrived from
                    the AWH office arranged by names of the Project countries. Not all of the
                    individual photographs are dated or identified in detail. There is not currently
                    a box list of these photographs.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Year acquired: 1980</p>
                <p>Accession number: 144</p>
            </acqinfo>







            <relatedmaterial>
                <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Drexel University:
                    American Women's Hospital Services, Medical Women's International Association,
                    American Medical Women's Association, Papers of Alma Dea Morani, and Papers of
                    Bertha Van Hoosen.</p>
            </relatedmaterial>


        </archdesc>
    </ead>