<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Anny Elston Collection <date type="inclusive">1944-1972</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Drexel University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Anny Elston Collection</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">DUSp.ACC539</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Drexel University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1944-1972</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Dr. Elston (nee Halpert) was a pediatrician born in 1895 and educated in Germany.
                    She received her medical degree in 1920 and was married in 1922 to Friedrich
                    (“Fritz” and “Fred”) Gustav Edelstein, an attorney. They had two sons in 1924
                    and 1928. She had a practice in Berlin from 1924 until 1938 when “Racial Laws”
                    prohibited her from practicing medicine. (Dr. Elston was Jewish, though she and
                    her husband considered themselves “racial Jews” only, as they were members of
                    the Lutheran Church. Her son Wolfgang says she didn’t have much of a practice in
                    those years, though as she was raising her children. She did however, do some
                    ground-breaking work at a pediatric institute in Berlin in the early 1920s.) In
                    1938 she had her necessary legal documents translated into English at the
                    American consulate. In 1939 they sent their sons (Gerhard - Gerd - and Wolfgang,
                    or Wolf) to stay in a boarding school for refugees in England. She and Fritz
                    immigrated to the U.S. in 1941. In 1942 she passed her NY state board exam and
                    began work at the New York Infirmary for Women and Children. They had changed
                    their name to Elston. Wolfgang and Gerhard came to the U.S. shortly before the
                    end of the war. Wolfgang earned a Ph.D. at Columbia University. (He is currently
                    Professor Emeritus at the University of New Mexico.) They lived at 242 E. 15th
                    St. and owned two undeveloped lots in Montauk on Long Island. Fritz was teaching
                    at Seton Hall College in New Jersey when he died in 1956. After her husband’s
                    death, Dr. Elston moved to Gramercy Park (1962), continued to practice medicine
                    and traveled extensively, throughout the world. (A significant portion of these
                    materials are in German.)</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>Two record cartons reflecting Dr. Elston's medical career in the United States.
                    Patient records, appointments and receipts, documents regarding her training and
                    background in Germany, correspondence regarding her work and credentials in New
                    York.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Originally donated by Marie Louise Elston; later weeded and DOG
                    issued to Wolfgang E. Elston.</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 1994</p>
                <p>Accession number: 1994.X.10</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>