<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>College of Engineering Records <date type="inclusive">1937-1979</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Drexel University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">College of Engineering Records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">DUSp.ACC663</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Drexel University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>9 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1937-1979</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Three of the Drexel Institute's original eleven departments taught programs that
                    would eventually become part of Drexel's early School of Engineering: the
                    scientific department, the technical department, and the mechanic arts program.
                    In 1914, President Hollis Godfrey consolidated these departments into the School
                    of Engineering, which was the first school at Drexel permitted to grant a
                    four-year degree (in 1915), first to implement a cooperative education program
                    (in 1919), and, later, first to extend the cooperative course from four years to
                    five (in 1925). In 1945, it became the College of Engineering. The college
                    offered its first graduate degrees in 1953. It was briefly consolidated with the
                    College of Science from 1964 to 1968, when it again became the College of
                    Engineering.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The collection consists largely of annual reports submitted by the dean of the
                    college to the president of Drexel, as well as manuscripts of annual reports. It
                    also includes the outgoing correspondence of college administrators and faculty
                    members from 1967 to 1973, faculty and department head meeting minutes from 1937
                    to 1968, records on individual departments within the college, and other
                    reports.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Received from the College of Engineering. </p>
                <p>Accession number: 2005.064</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>