<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Evening college records <date type="inclusive">1935-1988</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Drexel University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Evening college records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">DUSp.ACC682</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Drexel University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>30 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1935-1988</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The Evening School was one of the original departments established at the Drexel
                    Institute during the first year of classes in 1892. It offered purely technical,
                    non-degree courses of study until 1950, when the Evening College earned
                    accreditation to grant the B.S. degree. The Evening College's name was changed
                    to University College in 1993, and it was briefly discontinued in 1993, when its
                    programs were transferred to the College of Arts and Sciences. The Evening
                    College was re-established in 1997 as the College of Evening and Professional
                    Studies. </p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>The evening college collection is currently increasing, as a large volume of
                    records are being transferred to the archives from the college offices.
                    Currently, meeting minutes of the faculty heads, student and faculty guides, and
                    annual reports of the college comprise the majority of the collection. There is
                    also an assortment of unprocessed information relating to the Drexel Student's
                    Wives club and fraternal organizations. There is also extensive information on
                    academic programs and curricula. </p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Provenance: Collection donated by Kathy Woodford</p>
                <p>Year acquired: 2008</p>
                <p>Accession number: 2008.026</p>
            </acqinfo>










        </archdesc>
    </ead>