<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Library Records <date type="inclusive">1891-2002</date>
                        <date type="bulk"> 1929-2002</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Drexel University</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date>. Modified by Dot Porter in <date>2017</date>.</creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Library Records</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">DUSp.ACC674</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Drexel University<address>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>44 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1891-2002</unitdate>
                <unitdate type="bulk"> 1929-2002</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>The library and reading room of the Drexel Institute of Art, Science, and
                    Industry opened in 1892 under the direction of librarian Alice B. Kroeger. The
                    first library was housed in the Main Building and was also responsible for
                    running the library school until 1962. Within its first year of operation, it
                    had built a collection of nearly eight thousand volumes, chiefly through gifts
                    and donations from Anthony J. Drexel and his business partner, George W. Childs.
                    The Drexel Institute library was also responsible for running the library
                    school, which by 1900 was enrolling twenty students per year. A new library,
                    later called the Korman Center, opened in 1959, but planning for another new
                    library began shortly thereafter. The W. W. Hagerty Library opened in 1983.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This collection is actually made up of two collections, the Early library records
                    collection, and the Library records (1929-2002) collection. The early library
                    records collection consists of the minutes of the Trustees' Committee on the
                    Library from 1892 to 1917; accession and inventory books listing items received
                    and withdrawn from the collection, 1891-1947; library circulation statistics,
                    1891-1923, and card catalogs. It also includes a brief series of correspondence
                    by library director Anne Wallace Howland, 1923-1930.The later collection
                    contains drafts of the library building program for the construction of Hagerty
                    Library, 1970-1978, and annual reports from the library and its departments,
                    1964-1997. Other records include subject files compiled chiefly by library
                    director Richard Snyder, staff meeting minutes, some correspondence, and
                    pamphlets pertaining to library events and exhibits.</p>
            </scopecontent>


            <accessrestrict>
                <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>

            <acqinfo>
                <p>Accession number: 2006.001 &amp; 2008.006</p>
            </acqinfo>

            <otherfindaid>
                <p>An inventory is available in the repository.</p>
            </otherfindaid>








        </archdesc>
    </ead>