<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
        <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
            <eadid/>
            <filedesc>

                <titlestmt>
                    <titleproper>Herbert M. Hadley Quakers World Wide research and editorial papers
                            <date type="inclusive">1941-1992</date></titleproper>
                    <sponsor>This collection-level EAD record is a product of the Philadelphia Area
                        Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL) Consortial Survey
                        Initiative, which was funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
                </titlestmt>

                <publicationstmt>
                    <publisher>Swarthmore College, Friends Historical Library</publisher>
                    <date>2012</date>
                </publicationstmt>
            </filedesc>

            <profiledesc>
                <creation>Machine-readable finding aid generated in EAD from data in the PACSCL
                    Consortial Survey Database on <date>12/21/2012</date></creation>
                <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>


        <archdesc level="collection">
            <did>

                <unittitle label="Title">Herbert M. Hadley Quakers World Wide research and editorial
                    papers</unittitle>
                <unitid xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">SCFSp.ACC1200</unitid>
                <repository label="Repository">Swarthmore College, Friends Historical Library<address>
                        <addressline>Swarthmore, Pennsylvania 19081-1399 U.S.A.</addressline>
                        <addressline/>
                        <addressline/>
                    </address>
                </repository>
                <langmaterial>
                    <language langcode="eng"/>
                </langmaterial>
                <physdesc>
                    <extent>1 linear feet</extent>
                </physdesc>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1941-1992</unitdate>
            </did>

            <bioghist>
                <p>Herbert M. Hadley (d. 1998) was the son of a Quaker missionary and grew up in
                    Alaska and Kansas. He graduated in 1939 from Friends University in Wichita,
                    Kansas, and then became principal of the North Branch Friends Academy. During
                    World War II, he was a conscientious objector, and served for four years in
                    various units of the Civilian Public Service. After the war, he married Ruthanna
                    Davis. He received his master's degree in American civilization from the
                    University of Pennsylvania. In 1947 he became the secretary of the Friends
                    Meeting in Washington D.C. In 1956, he was appointed executive secretary of the
                    Friends World Committee for Consultation (FWCC), and traveled extensively around
                    the world. In 1962, Hadley returned to the United States and served as the head
                    of the American section of the FWCC. He was a long-time member of Germantown
                    Meeting and was a member of the Friends Historical Association. In 1969 he was
                    elected as a member of the Corporation of Haverford College. In 1991, he
                    published Quakers World Wide: A History of Friends World Committee for
                    Consultation.</p>
            </bioghist>

            <scopecontent>
                <p>This is a collection of Herbert M. Hadley's papers related to the research for
                    and production of his book, Quakers World Wide. Materials include
                    correspondence, biographical sketches of FWCC figures, articles, FWCC
                    newsletters, minutes of the Executive, Interim, and Advisory Committees of the
                    FWCC; records of Hadley's expenses; and documents related to reviews, marketing,
                    and distribution of the book.</p>
            </scopecontent>

            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Friends World Committee for
                    Consultation--History.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="610">Friends World Committee for Consultation.</corpname>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Society of Friends--History.</subject>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655">Research notes</genreform>

            </controlaccess>
            <admininfo>
                <accessrestrict>
                    <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
                </accessrestrict>

                <acqinfo>
                    <p>Provenance: Gift of Ruthanna Davis Hadley</p>
                    <p>Year acquired: 1999</p>
                    <p>Accession number: 99-007</p>
                </acqinfo>
            </admininfo>

            <add>






                <relatedmaterial>
                    <p>Related material may be found in the following collections: Friends
                        Historical Library, Swarthmore College: Friends World Committee for
                        Consultation (RG1).</p>
                </relatedmaterial>

            </add>

        </archdesc>
    </ead>